<ner>dh lib where the digital humanities and librarianship meet About About dh lib 2012 dh lib survey results Editor at Large Instructions Editor at <ORGANIZATION>Large Sign Up Features Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> In the Library Of the Library A dh lib Special Issue Data Praxis Series dh lib Mini Series Scene Reports Series Scene Reports dh lib Review CFP Event Jobs Opportunity Post Resource Recommended What Are You Reading Resources dh lib <ORGANIZATION>Registry Readings Library Research Guides TEI</ORGANIZATION> digital literacy recommended readings Calendar dh lib <ORGANIZATION>Features Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> in the Research Commons Precedents amp Prospects Previous Next <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> in the Research Commons Precedents amp Prospects 30 Jan 2014 Features Tags information commons management Editor s note dh lib is pleased to feature a mini series of three posts from <PERSON>Donald Beagle</PERSON> currently the Director of <ORGANIZATION>Library Services</ORGANIZATION> at <ORGANIZATION>Belmont Abbey College</ORGANIZATION> In his seminal 1999 article Conceptualizing an <ORGANIZATION>Information Commons Beagle</ORGANIZATION> applied the Strategic Alignment management theory developed for information technology to Information Commons a term which then referenced both integrated online library search environments and physical library facilities specifically designed to organize workspace and service delivery around the integrated digital environment 82 1 <ORGANIZATION>Beagle</ORGANIZATION> is a leader in the theory and practice of library commons which provide an approach and framing to libraries integration of new modes of information discovery use and sharing as a reviewer of <ORGANIZATION>Beagle</ORGANIZATION> s 2006 Information Commons Handbook wrote Although not the inventor of the information commons <ORGANIZATION>Beagle</ORGANIZATION> is a pioneer in the development of the concept and is perhaps the best known name in the field 2 The concept of the information commons has been transformative in research libraries particularly around the provision of services for undergraduates In this series Beagle unearths a personal history behind his theories and in so doing seeks to reconnect the commons movement to the research and collaboration needs of faculty and graduate students He identifies influences to this approach describing his experience leading the <ORGANIZATION>Charleston Multimedia Project</ORGANIZATION> an early digital project based in a public library along with collaborations and conversations with hypertext theorists <PERSON>Michael Joyce</PERSON> and <PERSON>Jay David Bolter He</PERSON> also theorizes on prospects for the research commons to serve dh in libraries As Beagle writes in his introduction below the posts were prompted by <PERSON>Trevor Mu</PERSON> oz s 2013 dh lib post which commented on similarities between the information commons and library dh service models What is an information commons IC and what relevance does it hold for dh In a history of ICs <PERSON>Elizabeth Milewicz</PERSON> inclusively characterizes the concept s emphasis to provide a collaborative conversational space that brings together technology services tools and resources to support teaching and learning and encourage innovative ideas 3 3 She observes The information commons visibly and functionally incorporates networked computer resources and collaborative work environments into libraries missions 5 The commons then has direct implications for how dh work is framed and undertaken in libraries and for the administrative approach needed to evolve services to support digital scholarship <PERSON>Sarah Potvin</PERSON> dh lib co editor Introduction <PERSON>Trevor Mu</PERSON> oz in his dh lib blog post In Service A Further Provocation on <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities Research</ORGANIZATION> in Libraries carries forward an important discussion about library management models with the potential to support the incubation of digital humanities Mu oz points out that my first articles on the Information Commons IC credit the influence of a management model called Strategic Alignment imported from private sector enterprise information technology planning 4 Connecting IC to ongoing DH endeavors Mu oz describes a DH center service model as a very close translation of the information commons idea to the realm of digital humanities My guest post here is not a rebuttal to Mu oz because I agree with much of his commentary but an attempt to provide further background and clarification I viewed Strategic Alignment from the beginning as vehicle to develop more sophisticated commons models for graduate student research and faculty knowledge creation needs including DH As formal assessments of first generation IC facilities have begun to accumulate since the late 1990s early 2000s such as <PERSON>Sherman</PERSON> s at <ORGANIZATION>North Carolina State University Fuller</ORGANIZATION> s at the <ORGANIZATION>University of Connecticut</ORGANIZATION> etc it has became clear that these ICs are 1 remarkably popular and successful sometimes increasing library doorcounts by 50 or more but yet have remained 2 most heavily used by undergraduates while graduate students and faculty tend to migrate elsewhere 5 This could lead to an understandable misperception that I employed Strategic Alignment to start <LOCATION>IC</LOCATION> development at the <ORGANIZATION>University of North Carolina Charlotte UNCC</ORGANIZATION> in 1997 exclusively to help meet the tech needs of undergraduates In reality I viewed Strategic Alignment from the beginning as vehicle to develop more sophisticated commons models for graduate student research and faculty knowledge creation needs including DH In 1995 96 I coordinated an ambitious digital humanities project with collaborating faculty graduate students and independent scholars by way of an Apple Library of Tomorrow grant The success of that project propelled me to <ORGANIZATION>UNCC</ORGANIZATION> in 1997 where my initial focus was frankly along the path of least resistance The fastest way to get change moving in a large university library in my opinion is to solve an identifiable and immediately urgent need In 1997 at <ORGANIZATION>UNCC</ORGANIZATION> this meant better IT and media support for undergraduate students But this was never intended to be the end point of that <ORGANIZATION>UNCC</ORGANIZATION> initiative my choice of Strategic Alignment to initiate the IC model was shaped from the outset by my plan to later extend it to establish a Research Commons that would draw upon my earlier experience producing a DH project My goal in these posts is to discuss how my choice of Strategic Alignment to initiate the IC model was shaped from the outset by my plan to later extend it to establish a Research Commons that would draw upon my earlier experience producing a DH project I also will discuss how this vision was shaped by my conversations with early hypertext theorists <PERSON>Michael Joyce</PERSON> and <PERSON>Jay David Bolter</PERSON> I believed then and now that faculty researchers and early adopters like <PERSON>Joyce</PERSON> and <PERSON>Bolter</PERSON> faced campus wide and library specific challenges in pursuing leading edge projects and that my 1990s experience as a library manager developing DH in collaboration with faculty graduate students and interagency scholars offered a valuable perspective on how libraries might be repositioned to help incubate and shape DH projects in the future Links to posts Part 1 The <ORGANIZATION>Charleston Multimedia Project A DH Public Library Case Study Part</ORGANIZATION> 2 Towards a Learning Commons The Influence of Hypertext Theorists of the 1980s 90s Part 3 The <ORGANIZATION>Research Commons</ORGANIZATION> in 2014 and Beyond Beagle Donald Conceptualizing an Information Commons The Journal of Academic Librarianship Vol 25 No 2 March 1999 82 89 <ORGANIZATION>Seal Robert A Review</ORGANIZATION> of The Information Commons Handbook portal Library and the <ORGANIZATION>Academy Vol</ORGANIZATION> 7 No 3 2007 389 90 <PERSON>Milewicz Elizabeth J Origin</PERSON> and Development of the <ORGANIZATION>Information Commons in Academic Libraries</ORGANIZATION> in A Field Guide to the Information Commons Edited by <PERSON>Charles Forrest</PERSON> and <PERSON>Martin Halbert Lanham</PERSON> MD Scarecrow Press 2009 1 17 Beagle Conceptualizing an Information Commons See Sherman <PERSON>Stephen</PERSON> C A User centered Evaluation of the <ORGANIZATION>North Carolina State University Libraries Learning Commons Master</ORGANIZATION> s Paper for the M S in L S degree April 2008 74 pages UNC Masters Papers Fuller Kate Learning Commons UConn Assessment Report Completed in fulfillment of the requirements of ILS 580 at <ORGANIZATION>Southern Connecticut State University</ORGANIZATION> Fall 2009 See also <PERSON>Harvey</PERSON> amp <PERSON>Lindstrom</PERSON> LibQUAL and the <ORGANIZATION>Information Commons Initiative</ORGANIZATION> at <ORGANIZATION>Buffalo State College</ORGANIZATION> 2003 to 2009 Evidence Based Library and <ORGANIZATION>Information Practice Vol</ORGANIZATION> 8 No 2 2013 <PERSON>Donald Beagle</PERSON> Graduated <ORGANIZATION>Oakland University English amp Linguistics 1975 University of Michigan Library amp Information Science 1977 Formerly Head of Main Library Charleston County Public Library SC</ORGANIZATION> 1989 1996 Associate Library Director amp Head of the <ORGANIZATION>Information Commons University of North Carolina Charlotte NC</ORGANIZATION> 1997 1999 Director of <ORGANIZATION>Library Services Belmont Abbey College NC</ORGANIZATION> 2000 current More Posts Previous Next Get Involved Contact Us Contribute Suggest a feed Tweets by DHandLib Recent Posts PROJECT Mapping Consumers in the <ORGANIZATION>Black South African Press POST Launching the Boston Research Center RESOURCE Mashups</ORGANIZATION> and Matters of Concern Generative Approaches to Digital Collections CFP Open Education Southern Symposium CFParticipation <ORGANIZATION>Digital Library Pedagogy Cookbook Archives Archives Select Month</ORGANIZATION> May 2018 April 2018 March 2018 February 2018 January 2018 December 2017 November 2017 October 2017 September 2017 August 2017 July 2017 June 2017 May 2017 April 2017 March 2017 February 2017 January 2017 December 2016 November 2016 October 2016 September 2016 August 2016 July 2016 June 2016 May 2016 April 2016 March 2016 February 2016 January 2016 December 2015 November 2015 October 2015 September 2015 August 2015 July 2015 June 2015 May 2015 April 2015 March 2015 February 2015 January 2015 December 2014 November 2014 October 2014 September 2014 August 2014 July 2014 June 2014 May 2014 April 2014 March 2014 February 2014 January 2014 December 2013 November 2013 October 2013 September 2013 August 2013 July 2013 June 2013 May 2013 April 2013 March 2013 February 2013 January 2013 December 2012 November 2012 Editor At <ORGANIZATION>Large Corner Instructions Log</ORGANIZATION> in dh lib <ORGANIZATION>Registry Middlebury College Bucknell University Case Western Reserve University Vanderbilt University Northeastern University Virginia Commonwealth University University of Virginia University of California Irvine Whittier College Southwestern University Washington State University Columbia University Georgetown University Northwestern University Bryn Mawr College Kansas State University University of Minnesota Ghent University University of Kansas Florida State University Contact Us Contribute Submission Guidelines Rights Permissions</ORGANIZATION> dh lib is a project of the <ORGANIZATION>ACRL Digital Humanities Interest Group</ORGANIZATION> ISSN 2380 1255 online</ner>
