<ner>Skip to main content <LOCATION>Canada</LOCATION> image Wiley Contact Help MY ACCOUNT CART AMERICAS <LOCATION>EUROPE ASIA PACIFIC AFRICA</LOCATION> AND MIDDLE EAST <LOCATION>Anguilla Antigua</LOCATION> and <ORGANIZATION>Barbuda Argentina Aruba Bahamas Barbados Belize Bermuda Bolivia Brazil Canada Cayman Islands Chile Colombia Costa Rica Cuba Cura</ORGANIZATION> ao <LOCATION>Dominican Republic Ecuador</LOCATION> El Salvador French <ORGANIZATION>Guiana Guadeloupe Guatemala Guyana Haiti Honduras Jamaica Martinique Mexico Nicaragua Panama Paraguay Peru Puerto Rico Saint Lucia Saint Vincent</ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION>Grenadines Suriname Trinidad</ORGANIZATION> and <LOCATION>Tobago United States Uruguay Venezuela Virgin Islands British Virgin Islands U S Aland Islands Albania</LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION>Andorra Armenia Austria Azerbaijan Belarus Belgium Bosnia and Herzegovina Bulgaria Croatia Cyprus Czech Republic Denmark Estonia Finland France Georgia Germany Gibraltar Greece Greenland Holy See Vatican City State Hungary Iceland Ireland Italy Latvia Liechtenstein Lithuania Luxembourg Macedonia Malta Moldova Monaco Montenegro Netherlands Norway Poland Portugal Romania Russia Serbia Slovakia Slovenia</ORGANIZATION> <LOCATION>Spain Sweden Switzerland Turkey Ukraine United Kingdom American Samoa Australia Bangladesh</LOCATION> Bhutan British <LOCATION>Indian Ocean Territory Brunei Cambodia China Christmas Island Cocos Keeling Islands Cook Islands Fiji</LOCATION> Guam <LOCATION>India Indonesia Japan Kazakhstan Korea</LOCATION> the <LOCATION>Republic of Kyrgyzstan Laos Malaysia Maldives Mongolia Myanmar Nepal New Zealand Pakistan Papua New Guinea Philippines Samoa Singapore Solomon Islands Sri Lanka</LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION>Tajikistan Thailand Timor Leste Tonga Turkmenistan Uzbekistan Vanuatu Vietnam</ORGANIZATION> <LOCATION>Afghanistan Algeria Angola Bahrain Benin Botswana Burkina Faso Burundi Cameroon Cape Verde Central African Republic Chad Comoros Congo</LOCATION> Cote d <ORGANIZATION>Ivoire Djibouti Egypt Equatorial Guinea Eritrea Ethiopia Gabon Gambia Ghana Guinea Guinea Bissau Iran Iraq Israel Jordan Kenya Kuwait Lebanon Lesotho Liberia Libya Madagascar Malawi Mali Mauritania Mauritius Morocco Mozambique Namibia Niger Nigeria Oman Palestine Qatar Reunion Rwanda Sao Tome</ORGANIZATION> and <LOCATION>Principe Saudi Arabia Senegal Sierra Leone Somalia South Africa South Sudan Sudan Swaziland Syria Tanzania Togo Tunisia Uganda United Arab Emirates Yemen Zambia Zimbabwe</LOCATION> Country Selector image Wiley Resources Authors Corporations Institutions Instructors Librarians Professionals Researchers Resellers Societies Students Subjects A C Accounting Agriculture Arts amp <ORGANIZATION>Architecture Business amp Management Chemistry Computing Culinary amp Hospitality E L Earth amp Space Sciences Education Engineering amp Materials Science Humanities Law amp Criminology Life Sciences Lifestyle M Z Mathematics amp Statistics Medicine Nursing amp Dentistry Physics amp Astronomy Psychology Reference Social amp Behavioral Sciences Veterinary Medicine World</ORGANIZATION> Languages About About Us Careers Corporate Citizenship Corporate Governance Investors Newsroom Search View All Related Content Products Other Undetected country Looks like you are currently in <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> but have requested a page in the <LOCATION>Canada</LOCATION> site Would you like to change to the <LOCATION>Canada</LOCATION> site NO YES bookmark maincontent Home Subjects Cultural Studies General Digital Culture amp the <ORGANIZATION>Information Age Digital Humanities Knowledge</ORGANIZATION> and Critique in a Digital Age image <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities Knowledge</ORGANIZATION> and Critique in a <ORGANIZATION>Digital Age Digital Humanities Knowledge</ORGANIZATION> and Critique in a Digital Age <PERSON>David M Berry Anders Fagerjord</PERSON> ISBN 978 0 745 69765 9 Jun 2017 Polity 248 pages Quantity 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 Select type Hardcover E Book CAD 23 99 In Stock Hardcover CAD 83 95 In Stock Paperback CAD 29 95 In Stock CAD 83 95 Added to Your Shopping Cart Add to cart Description As the twenty first century unfolds computers challenge the way in which we think about culture society and what it is to be human areas traditionally explored by the humanities In a world of automation Big Data algorithms <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> searches digital archives real time streams and social networks our use of culture has been changing dramatically The digital humanities give us powerful theories methods and tools for exploring new ways of being in a digital age <PERSON>Berry</PERSON> and <PERSON>Fagerjord</PERSON> provide a compelling guide exploring the history intellectual work key arguments and ideas of this emerging discipline They also offer an important critique suggesting ways in which the humanities can be enriched through computing but also how cultural critique can transform the digital humanities <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> will be an essential book for students and researchers in this new field but also related areas such as media and communications digital media sociology informatics and the humanities more broadly Related Resources Instructor Request an Evaluation Copy for this title About the Author <PERSON>David M Berry</PERSON> is Professor of <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> at the <ORGANIZATION>University of Sussex Anders Fagerjord</ORGANIZATION> is Associate Professor of Media and Communication at the <ORGANIZATION>University of Oslo Table</ORGANIZATION> of contents Reviews Acknowledgements 1 Introduction 2 Genealogies of the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> 3 Computational Thinking 4 <ORGANIZATION>Knowledge Representation and Archives</ORGANIZATION> 5 <ORGANIZATION>Research Infrastructures</ORGANIZATION> 6 Digital Methods and Tools 7 Digital Scholarship and Interface Criticism 8 Towards a Critical Digital Humanities Notes References Index This important book addresses significant questions about the role of digital humanities in scholarship today Concise and comprehensive it is essential reading and a major addition to the emerging critical appraisal of the field <ORGANIZATION>Lorna Hughes University of Glasgow This</ORGANIZATION> is a compelling and exciting analysis of the ways in which the encounter between the humanities and computers is reshaping and remediating our shared cultural and intellectual world <PERSON>David Berry</PERSON> and <PERSON>Anders Fagerjord</PERSON> present an inspiring manifesto for a pluralistic and critical digital humanities and provide an essential roadmap for anyone seeking to understand our emerging digital cultures <ORGANIZATION>Andrew Prescott University of Glasgow</ORGANIZATION> This book covers excellent ground It draws together and analyses developments and critical moments in the growth of <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> in ways that clearly show their importance and impact <ORGANIZATION>Kathryn Eccles University of Oxford Resources Authors Corporations Institutions Instructors Librarians Professionals Researchers Resellers Societies</ORGANIZATION> Students About About Us Careers Corporate Citizenship Corporate Governance Investors Newsroom Support Help Contact Us Privacy Policy Terms of Use Copyright 2000 2018 by <PERSON>John Wiley</PERSON> amp <ORGANIZATION>Sons Inc</ORGANIZATION> or related companies All rights reserved image <PERSON>Wiley</PERSON></ner>
