<ner>dhresourcesforprojectbuilding log inhelp Get a free wiki Try our free business product Wiki Pages amp Files View Edit To edit this page request access to the workspace Already have an account Log in Guides and Introductions redirected from Guides Page history last edited by <PERSON>Alan Liu</PERSON> 1 week 5 days ago image <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> projects collage DH <ORGANIZATION>Toychest Digital Humanities Resources for Project Building Guides</ORGANIZATION> to DH curated by <PERSON>Alan Liu DH Toychest</PERSON> started 2013 last update 2017 Guides to <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities Tutorials Tools Examples Data Collections amp Datasets Guides</ORGANIZATION> and Introductions to DH Guides and Introductions to <ORGANIZATION>DH Contents General Guides amp Resources Orientation</ORGANIZATION> on the Field Getting Started Creating and Maintaining an Online Scholarly Presence Academic Blogging Academic Twitter DH Project Making Digitization Citing Digital Resources Teaching Guides The Job Market for DH Graduate Students Evaluating DH Scholarship for Academic Promotion and <ORGANIZATION>Tenure General Guides amp Resources CUNY Digital Humanities Resource Guide Digital Humanities Keywords</ORGANIZATION> in progress online collection of essays on key concepts and words in DH Morgan Paige What Digital Humanists Do basic introduction to some of the major DH activities organized by project type 2013 <PERSON>Miriam Posner</PERSON> How Did They Make That 2013 Tutorials and Introductions to <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> 2014 <PERSON>Andrew Robichaud</PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION>Cameron Blevins Humanities</ORGANIZATION> 3 0 <ORGANIZATION>Tooling Up for Digital Humanities 2011 Simpson Center for the Humanities U Washington Resources for Digital Humanities UCLA Center for Digital Humanities Intro to Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> expansive resources based on <PERSON>Johanna Drucker</PERSON> and <PERSON>David Kim</PERSON> s DH 101 course at <ORGANIZATION>UCLA</ORGANIZATION> includes concepts amp readings tutorials exercises student projects and advanced topics TaDiRAH see also about TaDiRAH taxonomy of digital humanities activities objects and techniques Orientation on the Field selected A <ORGANIZATION>Companion to Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> ed <PERSON>Susan Schreibman Ray Siemens</PERSON> and <PERSON>John Unsworth Blackwell</PERSON> 2004 full text online A Companion to <ORGANIZATION>Digital Literary Studies</ORGANIZATION> ed <PERSON>Ray Siemens</PERSON> and <PERSON>Susan Schreibman Blackwell</PERSON> 2007 full text online Debates in the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities ed Matthew K Gold U Minnesota Press</ORGANIZATION> 2012 full text online DH and <ORGANIZATION>New Media</ORGANIZATION> friendly Journals journals known for publications related to digital humanities and new media studies <ORGANIZATION>History of Digital Humanities Field Susan Hockey</ORGANIZATION> The History of Humanities Computing 2004 <PERSON>John Unsworth</PERSON> What s <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> and How Did It Get Here 2012 <PERSON>Meredith Hindley</PERSON> The Rise of the <ORGANIZATION>Machines NEH</ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> The Early Years 2013 <PERSON>Matthew G Kirschenbaum</PERSON> What is <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> and What s It Doing in English Departments PDF 2010 Getting Started with <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities DevDH</ORGANIZATION> org lessons on getting started in <ORGANIZATION>DH Crystal S Anderson Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> for the Rest of Us 2016 on taking baby steps into <ORGANIZATION>DH Mary Axford Discipline Specific Tools Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> 2014 1 What s the <ORGANIZATION>Right Toolset for Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> 2 Literature 3 History Andrew Goldstone Notes on Using Digital Media for First Year Graduate Students 2016 My department asked me to meet with our first year Ph D students to talk about <ORGANIZATION>Using Digital Media</ORGANIZATION> in their scholarly lives It was interesting to try to sketch an outline of what I thought a starting English Ph D student should hear on the topic and I thought I d post a copy of that outline here <ORGANIZATION>Adeline Koh Introducing Digital Humanities Work</ORGANIZATION> to Undergraduates An Overview 2014 brief overview of an assortment of digital humanities projects that can be implemented in primarily undergraduate focused institutions Paige Morgan How to Get a Digital Humanities Project Off the Ground 2014 <PERSON>Trevor Owens</PERSON> Where to <ORGANIZATION>Start On Research Questions</ORGANIZATION> in The <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities 2014 Lisa Spiro Getting Started in Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> 2011 <PERSON>George H Williams</PERSON> The Question of Inclusion in the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> includes sections on Starting Places and Readings for beginners in DH Creating and Maintaining an Online Scholarly Presence <PERSON>Gerald R Lucas</PERSON> <ORGANIZATION>Social Media Top</ORGANIZATION> Ten Practices 2013 My list of best practices for faculty in higher education teaching with social media <PERSON>Kelli Marshall</PERSON> How to Curate Your Digital Identity as an Academic 2015 Academic Professional Blogging <PERSON>Tim Hitchcock</PERSON> Doing It In <ORGANIZATION>Public Impact Blogging Social Media</ORGANIZATION> and the Academy 2014 <PERSON>Rohan Maitzen</PERSON> Blogging Accept No Substitutes 2013 Ernesto Priego Some Tips for WordPress com Beginners 2014 Writing For Research How to Write a Blogpost From Your Journal Article 2015 See also <PERSON>Jenny Davis</PERSON> on citing blogs in academic research 2013 Academic Professional Twitter <PERSON>Ryan Cordell</PERSON> How to Start Tweeting and Why You Might Want To paywalled <PERSON>Dorothy Bishop</PERSON> A Gentle Introduction to Twitter for the Apprehensive Academic Christopher Long The Tweeting Graduate Student See also these posts and resources on academic tweeting <PERSON>Tim Hitchcock</PERSON> on the importance of the academic use of Twitter and blogs 2014 <PERSON>Carl Straumsheim</PERSON> Twitter Has the Chatter 2014 DH Project Making <PERSON>Johanna Drucker</PERSON> Workflow for Planning Digital Projects PDF 2014 <ORGANIZATION>Digitization Stephanie Routhier Perry Digitization and Digital Preservation A Review</ORGANIZATION> of the Literature 2014 introduction to concepts methods techniques for digitizing resources Guides and Introductions Page Tools Insert links Insert links to other pages or uploaded files Pages Images and files Insert a link to a new page Loading No images or files uploaded yet Insert image from URL Tip To turn text into a link highlight the text then click on a page or file from the list above Comments 0 bookmark comments You don t have permission to comment on this page Printable version PBworks Help Terms of use Privacy policy About this workspace Contact the owner RSS feed This workspace is public Join this workspace To join this workspace request access Already have an account Log in Navigator Loading SideBar Home Guides amp Intros Tutorials DH Tools <ORGANIZATION>DH Examples Data Collections amp Datasets Alan Liu s Recent Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> Courses English 149 Undergrad Fall 2014 English 197 Undergrad Spring 2015 English 236 Graduate Fall 2014 Recent Activity Show 0 new items Loading image Quantcast</ner>
