<ner>Skip to main content centerNet An international network of digital humanities centers Menu Main menu Home About Centers Contact Initiatives Join centerNet News About centerNet centerNet is an international network of digital humanities centers formed for cooperative and collaborative action to benefit digital humanities and allied fields in general and centers as humanities cyberinfrastructure in particular Anchored by its new publication DHCommons centerNet enables individual <ORGANIZATION>DH Centers</ORGANIZATION> to network internationally sharing and building on projects tools staff and expertise Through initiatives such as Day s of DH and Resources for Starting and Sustaining DH Centers centerNet provides a virtual DH center for isolated DH projects and platform for educating the broader scholarly community about <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities Read</ORGANIZATION> more centerNet News CFP Calling for Proposals to Host Day of DH in 2017 and 2018 Submitted by kdalziel2 unl edu on Mon 05 23 2016 10 47 A Day in the Life of the Digital Humanities Day of DH is an open community initiative sponsored by centerNet that each year brings together scholars interested in the digital humanities from around the world to document what they do on one day The goal is to create a website that weaves together a picture of the participants activities on the day and which answers the question Just what do digital humanists really do Participants document their day through photographs and text all of which is published on a community online platform forming a record of the day Read more about CFP Calling for Proposals to Host Day of DH in 2017 and 2018 News from centerNet Centers Call for Papers Call for Participation Information 2018 9 21 <ORGANIZATION>October University of Applied Sciences Potsdam FH Potsdam</ORGANIZATION> 21 26 October IEEE VIS <LOCATION>Berlin</LOCATION> Posted Monday May 7 2018 03 37 by <PERSON>Textgrid</PERSON> via Prof Dr <PERSON>Marian D</PERSON> rk <LOCATION>Potsdam</LOCATION> INFORMATION 2018 Interdisciplinary practices in information design amp visualization 19 21 October 2018 <ORGANIZATION>University of Applied Sciences Potsdam Potsdam Germany</ORGANIZATION> Following the success of the inaugural Information 2016 in <LOCATION>Vancouver</LOCATION> the biennial conference brings together researchers and practitioners in information design and information Read full post external link <ORGANIZATION>LDC</ORGANIZATION> at <ORGANIZATION>LREC</ORGANIZATION> 2018 Monday May 7 Posted Sunday May 6 2018 16 19 by <ORGANIZATION>Linguistic Data LDC</ORGANIZATION> is participating in a workshop and tutorial today at LREC 2018 During the Games4NLP Games and Gamification for Natural Language Processing Workshop from 9 00 13 00 in the Ivory Room LDC s <PERSON>Chris Cieri</PERSON> presents LingoBoingo Joining Forces to Promote Games for Linguistic Research and Technology Development Then in the afternoon from 14 00 18 00 in the <LOCATION>Crystal Room LDC</LOCATION> s Read full post external link Digital Classicist London Summer seminar series 2018 programme Posted Friday May 4 2018 16 15 by <ORGANIZATION>UCL Centre</ORGANIZATION> for The <ORGANIZATION>Digital Classicist London 2018</ORGANIZATION> seminar programme is now confirmed and published online The seminar series this year addresses the tension between standardisation and customisation in digital and other innovative and collaborative classics research The topic encompasses all areas of classics including ancient history archaeology and reception including cultures beyond the <LOCATION>Mediterranean Read</LOCATION> full post external link <PERSON>Stellenausschreibung Wiss Mitarbeiter</PERSON> in Digitale Edition an der HAB Wolfenb ttel Posted Friday May 4 2018 05 29 by <PERSON>Textgrid An der Herzog August Bibliothek</PERSON> ist zum n chstm glichen Zeitpunkt eine befristete <ORGANIZATION>Stelle</ORGANIZATION> 0 5 f r eine n wiss <PERSON>Mitarbeiter</PERSON> in zur technisch editorischen Betreuung einer Edition zu besetzen Es handelt sich um eine <PERSON>Stelle</PERSON> im Projekt Kritische Gesamtausgabe der Schriften und <PERSON>Briefe Andreas Bodensteins von Karlstadt Teil</PERSON> III Die vollst ndige Ausschreibung findet sich unter http www hab de de Read full post external link <ORGANIZATION>LDC</ORGANIZATION> at <ORGANIZATION>LREC</ORGANIZATION> 2018 Posted Thursday May 3 2018 09 54 by <ORGANIZATION>Linguistic Data LDC</ORGANIZATION> will attend the 11th Language Resource Evaluation Conference LREC2018 hosted by <ORGANIZATION>ELRA</ORGANIZATION> the <ORGANIZATION>European Language Resource Association</ORGANIZATION> The conference will be held in <LOCATION>Miyazaki Japan</LOCATION> from May 7 12 and features a broad range of sessions on language resource and human language technologies research Six LDC staff members will be presenting current work on topics including simple semantic Read full post external link Infrastructures of the Imagination Posted Wednesday May 2 2018 19 12 by Media Arts Pr Opening Reception May 17 5 30 9pmGallery Hours May 18 and May 21 23 10am 5pmLocation Firehouse Gallery <ORGANIZATION>USC School of Cinematic</ORGANIZATION> Arts639 <LOCATION>West 32nd Street Los Angeles</LOCATION> CA 90007 Facebook Event The post Infrastructures of the Imagination appeared first on <ORGANIZATION>USC Media Arts Practice Read</ORGANIZATION> full post external link IASSIST Quarterly Volume 41 available on a new web site Posted Wednesday May 2 2018 13 56 by IASSIS Welcome to the first issue of Volume 41 of the IASSIST Quarterly It has taken extra time for this issue to appear The cause of this is not that we have been extra lazy The paradoxical cause is that a great many people have been extra busy Thanks to the team of people in the editorial group of the IASSIST Quarterly and not least the great help from <PERSON>Sonya Betz</PERSON> working as <ORGANIZATION>Digital Read</ORGANIZATION> full post external link DARIAH DE Grand Tour 2018 Panels versprechen spannende Diskussionen Posted Wednesday May 2 2018 11 33 by Textgrid Zum abwechslungsreichen Programm der DARIAH DE Grand Tour 2018 19 bis 21 September an der <ORGANIZATION>TU Darmstadt</ORGANIZATION> geh ren nicht nur zahlreiche Workshops und die <ORGANIZATION>Keynote von Prof Marc Alexander University of Glasgow</ORGANIZATION> sondern ebenfalls zwei spannende Paneldiskussionen So werden die Teilnehmenden im Panel Geistes und kulturwissenschaftliche Forschungsdaten Konzepte und Read full post external link Workshopbericht Reisewege in <PERSON>Raum</PERSON> und <PERSON>Zeit K</PERSON> ln 27 02 2018 Posted Wednesday May 2 2018 10 10 by <ORGANIZATION>Textgrid Am</ORGANIZATION> 27 02 2018 fand der DARIAH DE Expertenworkshop Reisewege in <PERSON>Raum</PERSON> und Zeit im Rahmen der DHd Jahrestagung in K ln statt Der Workshop war dem Thema Reisewege historischer Akteure gewidmet und wurde gemeinsam vom <PERSON>Leibniz Institut</PERSON> f r <ORGANIZATION>Europ</ORGANIZATION> ische Geschichte <PERSON>Anna Aschauer Marco</PERSON> B chler und dem Lehrstuhl f r Medieninformatik der <PERSON>Otto Friedrich Universit</PERSON> t <PERSON>Bamberg Tobias Gradl Andreas Henrich Read</PERSON> full post external link UCLDH hosted BL Labs roadshow April 2018 Posted Tuesday May 1 2018 07 05 by UCL Centre for UCLDH were pleased to host the <ORGANIZATION>British Library Labs</ORGANIZATION> team on 24th April for their 2018 roadshow This is the third time <ORGANIZATION>UCLDH</ORGANIZATION> have hosted the <ORGANIZATION>BL Labs</ORGANIZATION> and the success and popularity of the now annual event continues to grow with over 70 people registered this year This year s event included a series of presentations exploring the British Library s digital collections how they have been used in Read full post external link Pages 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 next last Featured Centers <ORGANIZATION>Maryland Institute for Technology in the Humanities MITH College Park MD</ORGANIZATION> <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> http mith umd edu <ORGANIZATION>UCL Centre for Digital Humanities London United Kingdom</ORGANIZATION> http www ucl ac uk dh <ORGANIZATION>Electronic Textual Cultures Lab University of Victoria PO Box</ORGANIZATION> 1700 STN <ORGANIZATION>CSC Victoria BC Canada</ORGANIZATION> V8W 2Y2 http etcl uvic ca Centre d etudes superieures de la renaissance Tours <LOCATION>France</LOCATION> http cesr univ tours fr <ORGANIZATION>Digital Scholarship Lab Richmond VA United States</ORGANIZATION> http dsl richmond edu <ORGANIZATION>Institut des Sciences Sociales LaDHUL University of Lausanne Lausanne Switzerland</ORGANIZATION> http www unil ch ladhul fr home menuinst membres html Initiatives DHCommons centerNet s new publication DHCommons is merging with <ORGANIZATION>Arts Humanities</ORGANIZATION> net to create one large scale discovery and review publication for digital humanities projects Resources for Starting and Sustaining DH Centers The Resources page lists talks articles sample DH proposals and other sources of information about ways to start and sustain DH centers Day s of DH A Day of the Life of the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> an event where digital humanists from around the world document what they do Read more Becoming a Member If you think your center is a digital humanities center in whole or in part then we d be glad to have you join centerNet We leave the definition of digital humanities up to you but we intend to be inclusive and we know that there will be cross over into the social sciences media studies digital arts and other related areas This might include humanities centers with a strong interest in or focus on digital platforms One caveat a center should be larger than a single project and it should have some history or promise of persistence To see a list our Founding Centers from around the world click here Read more Search Search</ner>
