<ner>Skip to Content Skip to Table of Contents image Return to the <ORGANIZATION>MLA Commons Digital Pedagogy</ORGANIZATION> in the Humanities Concepts Models and Experiments Search for Log in Next page Welcome Site Home Page Title Page General Comments All Comments Comments by Commenter Blog Blog Archive Minimise Header Welcome image <PERSON>Angela Gibson</PERSON> Thursday July 2nd 2015 1 Leave a comment on paragraph 1 0 Welcome to the open peer review site for <ORGANIZATION>Digital Pedagogy</ORGANIZATION> in the Humanities Concepts Models and Experiments a curated collection of reusable and remixable pedagogical artifacts for humanities scholars in development by the <ORGANIZATION>Modern Language Association</ORGANIZATION> 2 Leave a comment on paragraph 2 0 Each keyword entry that you see on the right column of this site is curated by an experienced practitioner of digital pedagogy who briefly contextualizes a pedagogical concept and then provides ten supporting artifacts such as syllabi prompts exercises lesson plans and student work drawn from courses classrooms and projects across the humanities These artifacts are annotated and accompanied by lists of related materials for further reading The collection is published under a Creative Commons BY NC license to encourage circulation editing and repurposing by other practitioners 3 Leave a comment on paragraph 3 1 Eventually fifty keywords will compose the project which is currently undergoing public peer review New keywords will be added in batches throughout 2016 We invite you to read through and respond to each of these entries and we welcome feedback from a wide range of practitioners at all levels of experience When commenting on keywords please consider the following 4 Leave a comment on paragraph 4 0 Clarity of curator s statement Is the curator s rationale clear Do the artifacts below it fulfill the promises of the curatorial statement Selection and presentation of artifacts Does the keyword provide a broad range of sample artifacts Are those artifacts annotated well Are there any major gaps that should be addressed Applicability Does the keyword provide a wide range of starting points for a scholar interested in engaging in digital pedagogy work 5 Leave a comment on paragraph 5 0 While anyone may comment we hope you ll join the <ORGANIZATION>MLA</ORGANIZATION> and become part of the Commons community 6 Leave a comment on paragraph 6 0 Thank you in advance for your feedback Please visit our how to comment page if you have further questions about the process Page 1 Contents Comments Activity Comments 1 Comment on the whole Page image Www Bbkshopping com November 20 2017 at 9 12 pm Comment awaiting moderation Leave a comment on the whole Page 0 Comments on paragraph 1 Leave a comment on paragraph 1 0 Comments on paragraph 2 Leave a comment on paragraph 2 1 Comment on paragraph 3 image Vimala Pasupathi August 8 2017 at 10 36 am Comment awaiting moderation Leave a comment on paragraph 3 0 Comments on paragraph 4 Leave a comment on paragraph 4 0 Comments on paragraph 5 Leave a comment on paragraph 5 0 Comments on paragraph 6 Leave a comment on paragraph 6 Cancel Leave a Comment Your details Name required Mail will not be published required Website Your comment Comment Table of Contents Welcome Description How to Comment Keywords Access <PERSON>George H Williams</PERSON> Affect <ORGANIZATION>Elizabeth Losh Annotation Paul Schacht Archive Lauren Coats</ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON>Gabrielle Dean Assessment J Elizabeth Clark</PERSON> Authorship Augusta Rohrbach Blogging <PERSON>Diane K Jakacki Classroom Joyce R Walker Code Lauren Klein</PERSON> Collaboration <PERSON>Amanda Licastro Katina Rogers</PERSON> and <PERSON>Danica Savonick</PERSON> Community <PERSON>Bridget Draxler</PERSON> and <PERSON>Jon Winet</PERSON> Community College <PERSON>Anne B McGrail Dominique Zino Jaime Cardenas</PERSON> and <PERSON>Bethany Holmstrom</PERSON> Curation Julia Flanders Design <PERSON>Jennifer Sheppard</PERSON> and <PERSON>Kristin L Arola Diaspora Jessica Marie Johnson</PERSON> Digital Divides <PERSON>Annemarie Perez</PERSON> Disability <PERSON>Melanie Yergeau</PERSON> ePortfolio <PERSON>Kathleen Blake Yancey</PERSON> Failure <PERSON>Brian Croxall</PERSON> and <PERSON>Quinn Warnick</PERSON> Fiction <PERSON>Chris Forster Fieldwork Colette Colligan</PERSON> and <PERSON>Michelle Levy</PERSON> Future s Andr Carrington Gaming <PERSON>Amanda Phillips</PERSON> Gender <PERSON>Anne Cong Huyen Hacking William J Turkel Hashtag Marisa Parham</PERSON> History <PERSON>Shawn Graham</PERSON> Hybrid Jesse Stommel Indigenous <PERSON>David Gaertner Karyn Recollet Elizabeth LaPens</PERSON> e <ORGANIZATION>Information Tanya E Clement and Daniel Carter Interface Kathi Inman Berens Intersectionality Roopika Risam Iteration Annette Vee Labor Spencer D</ORGANIZATION> C Keralis Language Learning <PERSON>Ana Oskoz Makerspaces David M Rieder</PERSON> and <PERSON>Jessica Elam Handloff Mapping Diana</PERSON> S <ORGANIZATION>Sinton Multimodal Virginia Kuhn Network Maha Bali</ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON>Mia Zamora</PERSON> Online Amy Collier Open <PERSON>Michael Roy</PERSON> Play Mark Sample Poetry Chuck Rybak Praxis <PERSON>Bethany Nowviskie Jeremy Boggs</PERSON> and <PERSON>J K Purdom Lindblad Professionalization Jennifer Guiliano</PERSON> Project Management <PERSON>Lynne Siemens Prototype Stan Ruecker Celso Scaletsky Guilherme Meyer Chiara Del Gaudio Piotr Michura</PERSON> and <PERSON>Gerry Derksen</PERSON> Public <PERSON>Jeffrey W McClurken</PERSON> Queer <PERSON>Edmond Y Chang Race Adeline Koh</PERSON> Reading <PERSON>Rachel Sagner Buurma</PERSON> Remix <PERSON>Kim Middleton</PERSON> Rhetoric <PERSON>Douglas Eyman</PERSON> Sexuality <PERSON>Alexis Lothian</PERSON> <ORGANIZATION>Social Justice Toniesha Taylor Sound Steph Ceraso Storytelling Bryan Alexander Text Analysis Natalie M Houston Video</ORGANIZATION> <PERSON>Daniel Anderson</PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION>Jason Loan Visualization St</ORGANIZATION> fan <PERSON>Sinclair</PERSON> and <PERSON>Geoffrey Rockwell</PERSON> Activity Recent Comments in this Document image Polina Vinogradova February 8 2017 at 12 24 pm <PERSON>Ana</PERSON> when you write reject a negative identity do you mean negative self view or view of themselves It might be useful to clarify this as some identity scholars argue that we don t have multiple identities but rather multiple layers and aspects of our identities See in context image Philippe Seminet February 7 2017 at 6 53 pm One further artifact that might fit the bill nicely with what you have provided below even though it has been around for a decade or more is the use of Second Life for language learning purposes as this short piece in <LOCATION>Omniglot</LOCATION> attests http www omniglot com language articles secondlife php See in context image Polina Vinogradova February 7 2017 at 6 51 pm <PERSON>Ana</PERSON> you certainly make a clear connection between communicative competence and the availability of digital tools for language learning in paragraph 6 But I am wondering if it might be useful to redefine communicative competence here adding multiliteracies component the ability to critically interpret and convey multimodal messages There seems to be a bit of a disconnect here right now between the definition of communicative competence that language learning relies on and further discussion of resourcefulness and usefulness of digital tools I think it would strengthen the argument See in context image Philippe Seminet February 7 2017 at 6 49 pm While I agree on the whole with the move beyond linguistic elements given the awesome technology available great artifacts provided in this piece I do find problematic the notion that language learning is not about grammar While true for L1 I don t see why you d avoid explaining past tenses in L2 without referring to how it s done in L1 Why not use that resource Yes the goal is communication but grammar provides the shorthand whereby you can more readily communicate the desired meaning See in context image <PERSON>Kathryn Tomasek</PERSON> February 7 2017 at 3 45 pm Hi <PERSON>Julia</PERSON> Thank you for including us as an example Beyond that I appreciate the variety of examples offered here since they offer an idea of the range of possibilities with regard to disciplines and tools that might be used in curation assignments I also appreciate the range of educational levels covered in the examples See in context image <PERSON>John Martin</PERSON> February 7 2017 at 3 39 pm I could see this being taught alongside <PERSON>Melville</PERSON> s The Paradise of Bachelors and the Tartarus of Maids or <ORGANIZATION>Laurel Thatcher Ulrich</ORGANIZATION> s A Midwife s Tale in a course devoted to the history of unseen women s labor See in context image Truett Cates February 7 2017 at 3 35 pm perhaps better than pure linguistic would be simply morphological since there is no aspect of language not included in linguistic See in context image <PERSON>John Martin</PERSON> February 7 2017 at 3 30 pm This might also be paired with a visit from a Copyright Librarian or other staff member with special expertise in current copyright law author s rights publisher agreements etc to allow students to put these discussions into a contemporary setting that might be relevant to those who wish to author or publish their own works See in context image <PERSON>John Martin</PERSON> February 7 2017 at 3 23 pm I d be curious to hear more about how this complicating and questioning of the notion of authorship also impacts the notion of authority This is the only paragraph that overtly mentions them together but in moving away from the notion of the individual genius composing in isolation towards or back to more collective collaborative and even unintentional or multi intentional forms of authorship what are the implications for literary or interpretive authority See in context image <PERSON>John Martin</PERSON> February 7 2017 at 12 56 pm Do any of the resources below or the possible assignments using these resources attempt to measure the actual economic value or impact of digital labor While this is probably a fluid and relative value is it possible for students to look at various ways of measuring and attributing economic value either in terms of fair wages or just being able to articulate such value when dealing with institutions funding agencies grant applications budgeting etc See in context Recently Active Members image Profile picture of <PERSON>Melissa Ridley Elmes Melissa Ridley Elmes</PERSON> active 13 minutes ago Who s Online image Profile picture of <PERSON>Melissa Ridley Elmes Melissa Ridley Elmes</PERSON> active 13 minutes ago <ORGANIZATION>Modern Language Association</ORGANIZATION> 85 <LOCATION>Broad Street</LOCATION> suite 500 <LOCATION>New York NY</LOCATION> 10004 2434 This site is part of the <ORGANIZATION>MLA</ORGANIZATION> network on Humanities Commons Explore other sites on this network or register to build your own Source https hcommons org Insert edit link Close Enter the destination URL URL Link Text Open link in a new tab Or link to existing content Search No search term specified Showing recent items Search or use up and down arrow keys to select an item Cancel</ner>
