<ner>Menu Journals Division Contact Us Browse our journals Publish with us Subscribe to our journals <ORGANIZATION>Complete Chicago Package Permissions</ORGANIZATION> and reprints Statement of Publication Ethics Open access at <ORGANIZATION>Chicago Chicago Emerging Nations Initiative The University of Chicago Press Books Division Chicago Distribution Center</ORGANIZATION> image <ORGANIZATION>University of Chicago Press Journals</ORGANIZATION> SUBSCRIBE LOG IN SEARCH Search in This Journal Anywhere Advanced image Journals Lorem ipsum Lorem ipsum Lorem ipsum Lorem ipsum Lorem ipsum Lorem ipsum Books Lorem ipsum Lorem ipsum Lorem ipsum Lorem ipsum Lorem ipsum image Publication Cover Critical Inquiry Volume 31 Number 1 Autumn 2004 SUBSCRIBE RENEW Institutions Individual subscriptions Individual renewals Recommend to your library Purchase back issues BROWSE ISSUES All issues Online sample issue CONTRIBUTORS Submissions Manuscript preparation Authors rights Open access at <LOCATION>Chicago</LOCATION> Obtaining permissions ABOUT About CI Editorial Board Contact the editorial office Visit the CI website In the Moment blog Abstracting and indexing Advertise in CI Conference exhibits image image image Previous Article Next Article Transcendental Data Toward a Cultural History and Aesthetics of the New Encoded Discourse <PERSON>Alan Liu Alan Liu</PERSON> is professor of English at the <ORGANIZATION>University of California Santa Barbara</ORGANIZATION> and author of Laws of Cool Knowledge Work and the Culture of Information 2004 and Wordsworth The Sense of History 1989 He is the creator of Voice of the <ORGANIZATION>Shuttle Web Site for Humanities Research</ORGANIZATION> and director of the <ORGANIZATION>NEH</ORGANIZATION> funded project Transcriptions Literary History and the Culture of Information He is also a member of the board of directors of the <ORGANIZATION>Electronic Literature Organization ELO</ORGANIZATION> and chair of the <ORGANIZATION>Technology Software Committee</ORGANIZATION> of the <ORGANIZATION>ELO</ORGANIZATION> s PAD initiative <ORGANIZATION>Preservation Archiving Dissemination of Electronic Literature</ORGANIZATION> https doi org 10 1086 427302 First Page Full Text Cited by PDF image Free first page TOOLS Export Citation Track Citation Email A Friend Add To Favorites Permissions Reprints SHARE image ARTICLE CITATION <PERSON>Alan Liu</PERSON> Transcendental Data Toward a Cultural History and Aesthetics of the New Encoded Discourse Critical Inquiry 31 no 1 Autumn 2004 49 84 https doi org 10 1086 427302 MOST READ Of all published articles the following were the most read within the past 12 months Why Has Critique Run out of Steam From Matters of Fact to Matters of Concern Latour The Climate of History Four Theses Chakrabarty One Life Only Biological Resistance Political Resistance Malabou et al image image image Facebook image Twitter 1427 East 60th Street Chicago IL 60637 The <ORGANIZATION>University of Chicago Press Books Chicago Distribution Center The University of Chicago Contact us Media</ORGANIZATION> and advertising requests Terms and Conditions Privacy Policy Statement of Publication Ethics</ner>
