<ner>image Emeraldinsight Home Register Help Search Downloading to a Citation Manager Registration Access Account features Cart Admin Blog Advanced Search Jump to content image Emeraldinsight Log in Register Help Cart Mobile Pairing Admin Blog Emerald Resources For Authors For Librarians For Engineers Research Zone Learning Zone Teaching Zone Multimedia Zone Support Resources Resource areas Submit Home Journals amp Books Case Studies Open Access in Articles and Chapters Case studies This <ORGANIZATION>Journal Advanced Search Home Browse Journals amp Books Library Hi Tech Volume</ORGANIZATION> 19 Issue 3 Moving to XML Latin texts XML conversion project at the <ORGANIZATION>Center for Electronic Texts in the Humanities Moving</ORGANIZATION> to XML Latin texts XML conversion project at the <ORGANIZATION>Center for Electronic Texts</ORGANIZATION> in the Humanities Author s <PERSON>Brian Hancock Brian Hancock</PERSON> is <ORGANIZATION>Humanities Librarian Center for Electronic Texts in the Humanities at Alexander Library Rutgers University Libraries New Brunswick New Jersey USA</ORGANIZATION> <PERSON>Michael J Giarlo Michael J Giarlo</PERSON> is Systems Administrator Scholarly Communication Center both at <ORGANIZATION>Alexander Library Rutgers University Libraries New Brunswick New Jersey USA Show</ORGANIZATION> all authors Abstract The delivery of documents on the Web has moved beyond the restrictions of the traditional Web markup language HTML HTML s static tags cannot deal with the variety of data formats now beginning to be exchanged between various entities whether corporate or institutional XML solves many of the problems by allowing arbitrary tags which describe the content for a particular audience or group At the <ORGANIZATION>Center for Electronic Texts in the Humanities</ORGANIZATION> the Latin texts of <PERSON>Lector Longinquus</PERSON> are being transformed to XML in readiness for the expected new standard To allow existing browsers to render these texts a Java program is used to transform the XML to HTML on the fly Keywords Programming Knowledge management Internet Languages Type Case study Publisher <ORGANIZATION>MCB UP Ltd</ORGANIZATION> Copyright MCB UP Limited 2001 Published by <ORGANIZATION>MCB UP Ltd</ORGANIZATION> Citation <PERSON>Brian Hancock Michael J Giarlo</PERSON> 2001 Moving to XML Latin texts XML conversion project at the <ORGANIZATION>Center for Electronic Texts in the Humanities Library Hi Tech Vol</ORGANIZATION> 19 Issue 3 pp 257 264 https doi org 10 1108 07378830110405139 Downloads The fulltext of this document has been downloaded 227 times since 2013 Article Options and Tools image PDF image Full text Citation and Reference More image Download Citation image Track Citations image View References 8 image Save to Mendeley image Favourites Journal Information image Publication Cover Library Hi Tech ISSN 0737 8831 Online from 1983 Current Issue Available Issues Earlycite image RSS image ToC Alert image This journal is indexed by <ORGANIZATION>Clarivate Social Sciences Citation Index SSCI</ORGANIZATION> image This journal is indexed by <ORGANIZATION>Scopus</ORGANIZATION> image Most read Most cited Related The most popular papers from this title in the past 7 days Reducing noise in the academic library the effectiveness of installing noise meters Fake news belief in post truth Clear and present questions formulating questions for evidence based practice Search engine optimization A case study using the bibliographies of <ORGANIZATION>LG Science Land in Korea Marketing</ORGANIZATION> via social media a case study See more gt The most cited papers from this title published in the last 3 years Statistics are updated weekly using participating publisher data sourced exclusively from <LOCATION>Crossref Qualitative</LOCATION> research in evidence based practice a valuable partnership Web 2 0 applications usage and trends in top <LOCATION>US</LOCATION> academic libraries Libraries as coworking spaces Understanding user motivations and perceived barriers to social learning Android smartphone adoption and intention to pay for mobile internet Perspectives from software hardware design and value The cultivation of scientific data specialists Development of LIS education oriented to e science service requirements See more gt Find related content By Keyword Programming Knowledge management Internet Languages By Author <PERSON>Brian Hancock Michael J Giarlo</PERSON> Further Information About the Journal Sample Articles Purchase Information Editorial Team Write for this journal image Kudos service for authors <ORGANIZATION>About Emerald About Us Company Information Working for Emerald Contact</ORGANIZATION> Us How to Find Us Policies amp Information Cookie Policy Privacy Policy Copyright Policy Industry Standards End User Terms Digital Preservation Accessibility Text and Data Mining Licence Modern Slavery Act transparency statement <ORGANIZATION>Emerald Websites Emerald Publishing Emerald Group 50th Anniversary Emerald Management First Emerald Bookstore Emerald Careers The Emerald Foundation</ORGANIZATION> image Rights Link Logo image Project COUNTER Logo image CrossRef Logo Copyright Emerald Publishing Limited</ner>
