<ner>skip navigationLibrary of <ORGANIZATION>Congress Authorities amp Vocabularies</ORGANIZATION> image Library of <ORGANIZATION>Congress</ORGANIZATION> Ask a Librarian Digital Collections Library Catalogs Search GO The <ORGANIZATION>Library of Congress gt Linked Data Service Digital</ORGANIZATION> humanities From Library of <ORGANIZATION>Congress Subject Headings Details Visualization Suggest Terminology Digital</ORGANIZATION> humanities URI s http id loc gov authorities subjects sh2008122106 info lc authorities sh2008122106 http id loc gov authorities sh2008122106 concept Instance Of MADS RDF Topic MADS RDF Authority SKOS Concept image Offsite link Scheme Membership s Library of <ORGANIZATION>Congress Subject Headings Collection Membership</ORGANIZATION> s LCSH Collection Authorized Headings LCSH Collection General Collection Variants image us Humanities Information technology Broader Terms image us <ORGANIZATION>Humanities Earlier Established Forms Humanities Data</ORGANIZATION> processing Sources found Work cat Computer in den Geisteswissenschaften c1989 found In the shadows of the digital humanities c2014 p iv the contributors to this issue approach the digital humanities from radically different perspectives found Crompton Constance Doing digital humanities 2016 t p digital humanities found <ORGANIZATION>Oxford</ORGANIZATION> dictionaries viewed Jan 25 2016 Digital humanities An academic field concerned with the application of computational tools and methods to traditional humanities disciplines such as literature history and philosophy found <PERSON>Getty</PERSON> art and architecture thesaurus Jan 25 2016 <ORGANIZATION>Digital humanities Research</ORGANIZATION> study teaching publication and other dissemination of information in the humanities that is mediated through digital technology It is an evolving area of study using computing technologies to investigate questions and areas of research that are both traditional and new to the humanities found Flanders Julia Encyclopedia of library and information science 3rd ed 2011 digital humanities article abstract <ORGANIZATION>Digital</ORGANIZATION> humanities is a recent and rapidly evolving field It includes the range of activities and projects associated with the use of digital technologies for humanities research Change Notes 2008 04 25 new 2016 05 11 revised Alternate Formats RDF XML MADS and <ORGANIZATION>SKOS N Triples MADS</ORGANIZATION> and SKOS JSON MADS <ORGANIZATION>RDF</ORGANIZATION> and SKOS RDF MADS RDF XML MADS N Triples MADS RDF JSON SKOS RDF XML SKOS N Triples SKOS JSON MADS XML MARC XML Suggest terminology The <ORGANIZATION>LC Linked Data Service</ORGANIZATION> welcomes any suggestions you might have about terminology used for a given heading or concept Would you like to suggest a change to this heading <ORGANIZATION>Digital</ORGANIZATION> humanities Please provide your name email and your suggestion so that we can begin assessing any terminology changes Fields denoted with an asterisk are required Name E mail Suggested terminology I recommend changing the terminology for http id loc gov authorities subjects sh2008122106 from <ORGANIZATION>Digital</ORGANIZATION> humanities to How many floors does a one story house have Privacy policy Connect with the Library All ways to connect Find Us On image Facebook image Twitter image YouTube image Flickr Subscribe amp Comment RSS amp E Mail Blogs Download amp Play Podcasts Webcasts iTunesU external link Questions Ask a Librarian Contact Us About Press Jobs Donate Inspector General Legal Accessibility External Link Disclaimer <LOCATION>USA</LOCATION> gov Speech Enabled</ner>
