<ner>The <ORGANIZATION>University of Chicago Search</ORGANIZATION> site The Neubauer Collegium for Culture and <ORGANIZATION>Society About Us Leadership Faculty Research</ORGANIZATION> Projects Application Process Visiting Fellows Exhibitions Events News Make a Gift Media Gallery About Us Leadership Faculty Research Projects Application Process Visiting Fellows Exhibitions Events News Make a Gift Media Gallery In this Section Calendar of <ORGANIZATION>Events Archives Facebook Twitter YouTube Email Cultural Analytics Computational Approaches</ORGANIZATION> to the Study of Culture image Free and open to the public Friday May 22 Saturday May 23 Neubauer Collegium for Culture and <ORGANIZATION>Society Room</ORGANIZATION> 103 5701 S <LOCATION>Woodlawn Avenue Chicago Illinois</LOCATION> 60637 This event brought together faculty and graduate students working at the intersection of literary studies and applied computational analysis This field has been growing for some time but there have been few opportunities for a sustained discussion of the methodological challenges and opportunities afforded by new digital and data driven tools and techniques Existing work in cultural analytics by <PERSON>Lev Manovich</PERSON> and others provides a useful framework to think about what this research might be In this conference brought together scholars who specialize in a range of literatures and periods to galvanize the formation of a cultural analytics sub field for textual studies specifically <ORGANIZATION>Participants Include Global Literary Networks Group Hoyt Long University of Chicago Tom McEnaney Cornell University Richard Jean So University of Chicago Stanford Literary Lab Mark Algee Hewitt Stanford University Ryan Heuser Stanford University Viral Texts Group Ryan Cordell Northeastern University Elizabeth Maddock Dillon Northeastern University David Smith Northeastern University Tanya Clement University of Texas Austin Marissa Gemma Max Planck Institute Natalie Houston University of Houston Matthew Jockers University of Nebraska Meredith Martin Princeton University Andrew Piper McGill University Ted Underwood University of Illinois Urbana Champaign Matthew Wilkens University of Notre Dame Conference Schedule</ORGANIZATION> Friday May 22 9 00 a m 10 00 a m Viral Texts Team Reconstructing Nineteenth Century Virality from <ORGANIZATION>Unstructured Newspaper Archives</ORGANIZATION> 10 00 a m 11 00 a m <ORGANIZATION>Matthew Wilkens Literature and Economic Change</ORGANIZATION> in the Twentieth Century 11 00 a m 12 00 p m Global Literary Networks Team Patterns Taken for Wonder Computational Approaches to Global Modernism 12 00 p m 1 00 p m Lunch Break 1 00 p m 2 00 p m <PERSON>Natalie Houston</PERSON> Material Form Towards a Sociological Poetics 2 00 p m 3 00 p m <ORGANIZATION>Meredith Martin Meagan Wilson Jean Bauer Center for Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> at <ORGANIZATION>Princeton Princeton Prosody Archive</ORGANIZATION> 3 00 p m 4 00 p m <PERSON>Ted Underwood</PERSON> The Unreasonable Influence of Poetry 4 00 p m 5 00 p m <PERSON>Marissa Gemma</PERSON> Narrative Talk A Historical Study of Speech Based Forms in Fictional Narration Saturday May 23 9 00 a m 10 00 a m <PERSON>Matthew Jockers</PERSON> A Computational Morphology of Plot 10 00 a m 11 00 a m <PERSON>Andrew Piper Fictionality</PERSON> 11 00 a m 12 00 p m <ORGANIZATION>Stanford</ORGANIZATION> Literary Lab Between Suspense and Fear Two Digital Approaches to Recovering Traces of Textual Affect 12 00 p m 1 00 p m <PERSON>Tanya Clement</PERSON> HiPSTAS High Performance Sound Technologies for Access and Scholarship 1 00 p m 2 00 p m Lunch Break 2 00 p m 3 30 p m Graduate Student Caucus Response and Discussion The event is presented by the Global Literary Networks a project of the <ORGANIZATION>Neubauer Collegium for Culture and Society Additional</ORGANIZATION> support by the <ORGANIZATION>Karla Scherer Center for the Study of American Culture and the Humanities Without Walls Consortium</ORGANIZATION> based at the <ORGANIZATION>IPRH</ORGANIZATION> at <ORGANIZATION>UIUC</ORGANIZATION> Download the flier The <ORGANIZATION>University of Chicago 2018 The University of Chicago</ORGANIZATION> The <ORGANIZATION>Neubauer Collegium for Culture and Society 5701 S Woodlawn Avenue Chicago Illinois</ORGANIZATION> 60637 773 795 2329 773 926 0962 fax collegium uchicago edu <ORGANIZATION>Facebook Twitter YouTube Email</ORGANIZATION></ner>
