<ner>image logo ABOUT RESEARCH PROJECTS LEARN PEOPLE CONTACT Search <ORGANIZATION>Harvard University Arts amp Humanities Research Computing</ORGANIZATION> image Digital Humanities An Afternoon Symposium March 8 2018Event Partner Event Friday April 6 2 45 5 30 PM <ORGANIZATION>Harvard Hall</ORGANIZATION> 102 1465 <LOCATION>Massachusetts Avenue</LOCATION> This event is free and open to the public The following invited speakers image by <PERSON>Cole Crawford</PERSON> image 24 Hour Hackathon New Search Methods in the Humanities March 7 2018Event <ORGANIZATION>Harvard Library</ORGANIZATION> is hosting a 24 hour hackathon It s free and open to everyone not just coders so mark your calendars for March 29th and 30th image by <PERSON>Cole Crawford</PERSON> image ArtTechPsyche IV February 20 2018Event Partner Event Returning for a fourth year ArtTechPsyche celebrates human expression at the intersection of technology and the arts This annual symposium run by image by <PERSON>Cole Crawford</PERSON> image IIIF New England Meetup February 20 2018Event Research Computing The International Image Interoperability Framework IIIF is a set of shared application programming interface API specifications for interoperable image by <PERSON>Cole Crawford</PERSON> image Using Web APIs with Python February 20 2018Event Partner Event Instruction Comfortable with basic <PERSON>Python</PERSON> and want to expand your digital toolkit Interested in querying and analyzing real time data or faceted big data Want image by Cole Crawford image Fundamentals of Digital Scholarship Spring 2018 February 20 2018Partner Event Instruction March 6 7 2018 9am 2pm Lamont Library B 30 Fundamentals of Digital Scholarship presented by the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Scholarship Support Group</ORGANIZATION> is a two day image by Cole Crawford image Race and Distant Reading January 13 2018Event Partner Event <PERSON>Richard Jean</PERSON> So Assistant Professor of English amp <ORGANIZATION>Cultural Analytics McGill University</ORGANIZATION> Tuesday January 30 2018 5 pm Barker Hall 114 image by <PERSON>Cole Crawford</PERSON> image Inset image from <PERSON>Gabriel Harvey</PERSON> work Note to Self How <PERSON>Gabriel Harvey</PERSON> Read His Renaissance Library January 3 2018annotations digitization encoding Renaissance <PERSON>Gabriel Harvey</PERSON> marginalia book history <ORGANIZATION>Earle HavensEvent Partner Event Earle Havens Nancy H Hall Curator of Rare Books amp Manuscripts Johns Hopkins University</ORGANIZATION> Tuesday January 30 2018 6 pm Barker Hall 133 Book image by <PERSON>Cole Crawford</PERSON> image Visual Eloquence Workshops Jan 2018 January 2 2018data visualization d3 TableauEvent Partner Event Instruction January 9 or 10 2018 10 00am 12 30am Lamont Library B 30 Collaborative Learning Space Join the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Futures Consortium</ORGANIZATION> for a participatory image by <PERSON>Cole Crawford</PERSON> image Mapping the Movida May 9 2017Focus Mapping the <ORGANIZATION>Movida A Digital Humanities Projectby Vanessa Ceia Mapping the Movida</ORGANIZATION> is an open web image by <ORGANIZATION>DARTH</ORGANIZATION> 1 2 3 8 image hvdlogo Copyright 2017 <ORGANIZATION>Harvard University Arts amp Humanities Research Computing</ORGANIZATION></ner>
