<ner>Digital humanities From Wikipedia the free encyclopedia Jump to navigation search image Example of a textual analysis program being used to study a novel with <PERSON>Jane Austen</PERSON> s Pride and Prejudice in <ORGANIZATION>Voyant Tools Digital</ORGANIZATION> humanities DH is an area of scholarly activity at the intersection of computing or digital technologies and the disciplines of the humanities It includes the systematic use of digital resources in the humanities as well as the reflection on their application 1 2 DH can be defined as new ways of doing scholarship that involve collaborative transdisciplinary and computationally engaged research teaching and publishing 3 It brings digital tools and methods to the study of the humanities with the recognition that the printed word is no longer the main medium for knowledge production and distribution 3 By producing and using new applications and techniques DH makes new kinds of teaching and research possible while at the same time studying and critiquing how these impact cultural heritage and digital culture 2 Thus a distinctive feature of DH is its cultivation of a two way relationship between the humanities and the digital the field both employs technology in the pursuit of humanities research and subjects technology to humanistic questioning and interrogation often simultaneously Contents 1 Definition 2 History 3 Values and methods 4 Tools 5 Projects 5 1 Digital archives 5 2 Cultural analytics 5 3 Textual mining analysis and visualization 5 4 Analysis of macroscopic trends in cultural change 5 5 Online publishing 6 Criticism 6 1 Negative publicity 6 2 Black box 6 3 Diversity 6 4 Issues of access 6 5 Cultural criticism 6 6 Difficulty of evaluation 6 7 Lack of focus on pedagogy 7 <ORGANIZATION>Organizations</ORGANIZATION> 7 1 Centers and institutes 7 2 Conferences 7 3 Journals and publications 8 See also 9 References 10 Bibliography 11 Further reading 12 External links Definition edit The definition of the digital humanities is being continually formulated by scholars and practitioners Since the field is constantly growing and changing specific definitions can quickly become outdated or unnecessarily limit future potential 4 The second volume of Debates in the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities 2016</ORGANIZATION> acknowledges the difficulty in defining the field Along with the digital archives quantitative analyses and tool building projects that once characterized the field DH now encompasses a wide range of methods and practices visualizations of large image sets 3D modeling of historical artifacts born digital dissertations hashtag activism and the analysis thereof alternate reality games mobile makerspaces and more In what has been called big tent DH it can at times be difficult to determine with any specificity what precisely digital humanities work entails 5 Historically the digital humanities developed out of humanities computing and has become associated with other fields such as humanistic computing social computing and media studies In concrete terms the digital humanities embraces a variety of topics from curating online collections of primary sources primarily textual to the data mining of large cultural data sets to topic modeling <ORGANIZATION>Digital</ORGANIZATION> humanities incorporates both digitized remediated and born digital materials and combines the methodologies from traditional humanities disciplines such as history philosophy linguistics literature art archaeology music and cultural studies and social sciences 6 with tools provided by computing such as hypertext hypermedia data visualisation information retrieval data mining statistics text mining digital mapping and digital publishing Related subfields of digital humanities have emerged like software studies platform studies and critical code studies Fields that parallel the digital humanities include new media studies and information science as well as media theory of composition game studies particularly in areas related to digital humanities project design and production and cultural analytics History edit <ORGANIZATION>Digital</ORGANIZATION> humanities descends from the field of humanities computing whose origins reach back to the late 1940s in the pioneering work of Jesuit scholar <PERSON>Roberto Busa</PERSON> and the women he employed 7 8 In collaboration with <ORGANIZATION>IBM</ORGANIZATION> they created a computer generated concordance to <PERSON>Thomas Aquinas</PERSON> writings known as the Index Thomisticus 3 Other scholars began using mainframe computers to automate tasks like word searching sorting and counting which was much faster than processing information from texts with handwritten or typed index cards 3 In the decades which followed archaeologists classicists historians literary scholars and a broad array of humanities researchers in other disciplines applied emerging computational methods to transform humanities scholarship 9 10 As <PERSON>Tara McPherson</PERSON> has pointed out the digital humanities also inherit practices and perspectives developed through many artistic and theoretical engagements with electronic screen culture beginning the late 1960s and 1970s These range from research developed by organizations such as <ORGANIZATION>SIGGRAPH</ORGANIZATION> to creations by artists such as <PERSON>Charles</PERSON> and <PERSON>Ray Eames</PERSON> and the members of E A T Experiments in Art and Technology The <PERSON>Eames</PERSON> and E A T explored nascent computer culture and intermediality in creative works that dovetailed technological innovation with art 11 The first specialized journal in the digital humanities was Computers and the Humanities which debuted in 1966 The <ORGANIZATION>Association for Literary and Linguistic Computer ALLC</ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION>Association for Computers</ORGANIZATION> and the Humanities ACH were then founded in 1977 and 1978 respectively 3 Soon there was a need for a standardized protocol for tagging digital texts and the Text Encoding Initiative TEI was developed 3 The TEI project was launched in 1987 and published the first full version of the TEI Guidelines in May 1994 8 TEI helped shape the field of electronic textual scholarship and led to Extensible Markup Language XML which is a tag scheme for digital editing Researchers also began experimenting with databases and hypertextual editing which are structured around links and nodes as opposed to the standard linear convention of print 3 In the nineties major digital text and image archives emerged at centers of humanities computing in the U S e g the Women Writers Project the <PERSON>Rossetti</PERSON> Archive 12 and The <PERSON>William Blake</PERSON> Archive 13 which demonstrated the sophistication and robustness of text encoding for literature 14 The advent of personal computing and the World Wide Web meant that <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> work could become less centered on text and more on design The multimedia nature of the internet has allowed <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> work to incorporate audio video and other components in addition to text 3 The terminological change from humanities computing to digital humanities has been attributed to <PERSON>John Unsworth Susan Schreibman</PERSON> and <PERSON>Ray Siemens</PERSON> who as editors of the anthology A Companion to Digital Humanities 2004 tried to prevent the field from being viewed as mere digitization 15 Consequently the hybrid term has created an overlap between fields like rhetoric and composition which use the methods of contemporary humanities in studying digital objects 15 and digital humanities which uses digital technology in studying traditional humanities objects 15 The use of computational systems and the study of computational media within the arts and humanities more generally has been termed the computational turn 16 In 2006 the <ORGANIZATION>National Endowment for the Humanities NEH</ORGANIZATION> launched the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities Initiative</ORGANIZATION> renamed <ORGANIZATION>Office of Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> in 2008 which made widespread adoption of the term digital humanities all but irreversible in the <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> 17 <ORGANIZATION>Digital</ORGANIZATION> humanities emerged from its former niche status and became big news 17 at the 2009 MLA convention in <LOCATION>Philadelphia</LOCATION> where digital humanists made some of the liveliest and most visible contributions 18 and had their field hailed as the first next big thing in a long time 19 Values and methods edit Although digital humanities projects and initiatives are diverse they often reflect common values and methods 20 These can help in understanding this hard to define field 21 <ORGANIZATION>Values Critical amp Theoretical Iterative amp Experimental Collaborative amp Distributed Multimodal amp Performative Open</ORGANIZATION> amp Accessible Methods Enhanced Critical Curation Augmented Editions and Fluid Textuality Scale The Law of Large Numbers Distant Close Macro Micro Surface Depth Cultural Analytics Aggregation and Data Mining Visualization and Data Design Locative Investigation and Thick Mapping The Animated Archive Distributed Knowledge Production and Performative Access Humanities Gaming Code Software and Platform Studies Database Documentaries Repurposable Content and Remix Culture Pervasive Infrastructure Ubiquitous Scholarship 20 In keeping with the value of being open and accessible many digital humanities projects and journals are open access and or under Creative Commons licensing showing the field s commitment to open standards and open source 22 Open access is designed to enable anyone with an internet enabled device and internet connection to view a website or read an article without having to pay as well as share content with the appropriate permissions <ORGANIZATION>Digital</ORGANIZATION> humanities scholars use computational methods either to answer existing research questions or to challenge existing theoretical paradigms generating new questions and pioneering new approaches One goal is to systematically integrate computer technology into the activities of humanities scholars 23 as is done in contemporary empirical social sciences Yet despite the significant trend in digital humanities towards networked and multimodal forms of knowledge a substantial amount of digital humanities focuses on documents and text in ways that differentiate the field s work from digital research in media studies information studies communication studies and sociology Another goal of digital humanities is to create scholarship that transcends textual sources This includes the integration of multimedia metadata and dynamic environments see The Valley of the Shadow project at the <ORGANIZATION>University of Virginia the Vectors Journal of Culture and Technology</ORGANIZATION> in a Dynamic Vernacular at <ORGANIZATION>University of Southern California</ORGANIZATION> or <ORGANIZATION>Digital Pioneers</ORGANIZATION> projects at <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> 24 A growing number of researchers in digital humanities are using computational methods for the analysis of large cultural data sets such as the <ORGANIZATION>Google Books</ORGANIZATION> corpus 25 Examples of such projects were highlighted by the Humanities High Performance Computing competition sponsored by the <ORGANIZATION>Office of Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> in 2008 26 and also by the <ORGANIZATION>Digging Into Data</ORGANIZATION> challenge organized in 2009 27 and 2011 28 by <ORGANIZATION>NEH</ORGANIZATION> in collaboration with <ORGANIZATION>NSF</ORGANIZATION> 29 and in partnership with JISC in the <LOCATION>UK</LOCATION> and SSHRC in <LOCATION>Canada</LOCATION> 30 In addition to books historical newspapers can also be analyzed with big data methods The analysis of vast quantities of historical newspaper content has showed how periodic structures can be automatically discovered and a similar analysis was performed on social media 31 32 As part of the big data revolution Gender bias readability content similarity reader preferences and even mood have been analyzed based on text mining methods over millions of documents 33 34 35 36 37 and historical documents written in literary Chinese 38 <ORGANIZATION>Digital</ORGANIZATION> humanities is also involved in the creation of software providing environments and tools for producing curating and interacting with knowledge that is born digital and lives in various digital contexts 39 In this context the field is sometimes known as computational humanities image Narrative network of <LOCATION>US</LOCATION> Elections 2012 40 Tools edit <ORGANIZATION>Digital</ORGANIZATION> humanities scholars use a variety of digital tools for their research which may take place in an environment as small as a mobile device or as large as a virtual reality lab Environments for creating publishing and working with digital scholarship include everything from personal equipment to institutes and software to cyberspace 41 Some scholars use advanced programming languages and databases while others use less complex tools depending on their needs DiRT <ORGANIZATION>Digital Research Tools Directory</ORGANIZATION> 42 offers a registry of digital research tools for scholars <ORGANIZATION>TAPoR Text Analysis Portal for Research</ORGANIZATION> 43 is a gateway to text analysis and retrieval tools An accessible free example of an online textual analysis program is <ORGANIZATION>Voyant Tools</ORGANIZATION> 44 which only requires the user to copy and paste either a body of text or a URL and then click the reveal button to run the program There is also an online list 45 of online or downloadable <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> tools that are largely free aimed toward helping students and others who lack access to funding or institutional servers Free open source web publishing platforms like WordPress and Omeka are also popular tools image Example of a visualization tool used to study poetry in a new way with Poemage Projects edit <ORGANIZATION>Digital</ORGANIZATION> humanities projects are more likely than traditional humanities work to involve a team or a lab which may be composed of faculty staff graduate or undergraduate students information technology specialists and partners in galleries libraries archives and museums Credit and authorship are often given to multiple people to reflect this collaborative nature which is different from the sole authorship model in the traditional humanities and more like the natural sciences 3 There are thousands of digital humanities projects ranging from small scale ones with limited or no funding to large scale ones with multi year financial support Some are continually updated while others may not be due to loss of support or interest though they may still remain online in either a beta version or a finished form The following are a few examples of the variety of projects in the field 46 Digital archives edit The Women Writers Project begun in 1988 is a long term research project to make pre Victorian women writers more accessible through an electronic collection of rare texts The Walt Whitman Archive 47 begun in the 1990s sought to create a hypertext and scholarly edition of <PERSON>Whitman</PERSON> s works and now includes photographs sounds and the only comprehensive current bibliography of <PERSON>Whitman</PERSON> criticism The <ORGANIZATION>Emily Dickinson Archive</ORGANIZATION> begun in 2013 48 is a collection of high resolution images of <PERSON>Dickinson</PERSON> s poetry manuscripts as well as a searchable lexicon of over 9 000 words that appear in the poems image Example of network analysis as an archival tool at the League of Nations 49 The <ORGANIZATION>Slave Societies Digital Archive</ORGANIZATION> 50 formerly Ecclesiastical and Secular Sources for Slave Societies directed by <PERSON>Jane Landers</PERSON> 51 and hosted at <ORGANIZATION>Vanderbilt University</ORGANIZATION> preserves endangered ecclesiastical and secular documents related to Africans and African descended peoples in slave societies This Digital Archive currently holds 500 000 unique images dating from the 16th to the 20th centuries and documents the history of between 6 and 8 million individuals They are the most extensive serial records for the history of Africans in the <LOCATION>Atlantic World</LOCATION> and also include valuable information on the indigenous European and Asian populations who lived alongside them Cultural analytics edit Cultural analytics refers to the use of computational method for exploration and analysis of large visual collections and also contemporary digital media The concept was developed in 2005 by <PERSON>Lev Manovich</PERSON> who then established the <ORGANIZATION>Cultural Analytics Lab</ORGANIZATION> in 2007 at <ORGANIZATION>Qualcomm Institute</ORGANIZATION> at <ORGANIZATION>California Institute for Telecommunication and Information</ORGANIZATION> Calit2 The lab has been using methods from the field of computer science called Computer Vision many types of both historical and contemporary visual media for example all covers of <ORGANIZATION>Time magazine</ORGANIZATION> published between 1923 and 2009 52 20 000 historical art photographs from the collection in <LOCATION>Museum of Modern Art MoMA</LOCATION> in <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> 53 one million pages from Manga books 54 and 16 million images shared on Instagram in 17 global cities 55 Cultural analytics also includes using methods from media design and data visualization to create interactive visual interfaces for exploration of large visual collections e g Selfiecity and On <ORGANIZATION>Broadway Cultural Analytics</ORGANIZATION> research is also addressing a number of theoretical questions How can we observe giant cultural universes of both user generated and professional media content created today without reducing them to averages outliers or pre existing categories How can work with large cultural data help us question our stereotypes and assumptions about cultures What new theoretical cultural concepts and models are required for studying global digital culture with its new mega scale speed and connectivity The term cultural analytics or culture analytics is now used by many other researchers as exemplified by two academic symposiums 56 a four month long research program at <ORGANIZATION>UCLA</ORGANIZATION> that brought together 120 leading researchers from university and industry labs 57 an academic peer review <ORGANIZATION>Journal of Cultural Analytics</ORGANIZATION> CA established in 2016 58 and academic job listings Textual mining analysis and visualization edit WordHoard begun in 2004 is a free application that enables scholarly but non technical users to read and analyze in new ways deeply tagged texts including the canon of Early Greek epic <PERSON>Chaucer Shakespeare</PERSON> and Spenser The Republic of Letters begun in 2008 59 seeks to visualize the social network of Enlightenment writers through an interactive map and visualization tools Network analysis and data visualization is also used for reflections on the field itself researchers may produce network maps of social media interactions or infographics from data on digital humanities scholars and projects image Network analysis graph of <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities Twitter</ORGANIZATION> users Analysis of macroscopic trends in cultural change edit Culturomics is a form of computational lexicology that studies human behavior and cultural trends through the quantitative analysis of digitized texts 60 61 Researchers data mine large digital archives to investigate cultural phenomena reflected in language and word usage 62 The term is an American neologism first described in a 2010 Science article called Quantitative Analysis of Culture Using Millions of Digitized Books co authored by <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> researchers <PERSON>Jean Baptiste Michel</PERSON> and <PERSON>Erez Lieberman Aiden</PERSON> 63 A 2017 study 37 published in the Proceedings of the <ORGANIZATION>National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America</ORGANIZATION> compared the trajectory of n grams over time in both digitised books from the 2010 Science article 63 with those found in a large corpus of regional newspapers from the <LOCATION>United Kingdom</LOCATION> over the course of 150 years The study further went on to use more advanced Natural language processing techniques to discover macroscopic trends in history and culture including gender bias geographical focus technology and politics along with accurate dates for specific events Online publishing edit The <ORGANIZATION>Stanford Encyclopedia of Philosophy</ORGANIZATION> begun in 1995 is a dynamic reference work of terms concepts and people from philosophy maintained by scholars in the field MLA Commons offers an open peer review site where anyone can comment for their ongoing curated collection of teaching artifacts in <ORGANIZATION>Digital Pedagogy</ORGANIZATION> in the Humanities Concepts Models and Experiments 2016 The Debates in the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> platform contains volumes of the open access book of the same title 2012 and 2016 editions and allows readers to interact with material by marking sentences as interesting or adding terms to a crowdsourced index Criticism edit <PERSON>Lauren F Klein</PERSON> and <PERSON>Matthew K Gold</PERSON> have identified a range of criticisms in the digital humanities field a lack of attention to issues of race class gender and sexuality a preference for research driven projects over pedagogical ones an absence of political commitment an inadequate level of diversity among its practitioners an inability to address texts under copyright and an institutional concentration in well funded research universities 64 Some of the concerns have given rise to the emergent subfield of <ORGANIZATION>Critical Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> CDH Negative publicity edit <PERSON>Klein</PERSON> and Gold note that many appearances of the digital humanities in public media are often in a critical fashion <PERSON>Armand Leroi</PERSON> writing in The <ORGANIZATION>New York Times</ORGANIZATION> discusses the contrast between the algorithmic analysis of themes in literary texts and the work of <PERSON>Harold Bloom</PERSON> who qualitatively and phenomenologically analyzes the themes of literature over time <PERSON>Leroi</PERSON> questions whether or not the digital humanities can provide a truly robust analysis of literature and social phenomenon or offer a novel alternative perspective on them The literary theorist Stanley Fish claims that the digital humanities pursue a revolutionary agenda and thereby undermine the conventional standards of pre eminence authority and disciplinary power 65 However digital humanities scholars note that <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> is an extension of traditional knowledge skills and methods not a replacement for them Its distinctive contributions do not obliterate the insights of the past but add and supplement the humanities long standing commitment to scholarly interpretation informed research structured argument and dialogue within communities of practice 3 Some have hailed the digital humanities as a solution to the apparent problems within the humanities namely a decline in funding a repeat of debates and a fading set of theoretical claims and methodological arguments 66 <PERSON>Adam Kirsch</PERSON> writing in the <LOCATION>New Republic</LOCATION> calls this the False Promise of the digital humanities 67 While the rest of humanities and many social science departments are seeing a decline in funding or prestige the digital humanities has been seeing increasing funding and prestige Burdened with the problems of novelty the digital humanities is discussed as either a revolutionary alternative to the humanities as it is usually conceived or as simply new wine in old bottles <PERSON>Kirsch</PERSON> believes that digital humanities practitioners suffer from problems of being marketers rather than scholars who attest to the grand capacity of their research more than actually performing new analysis and when they do so only performing trivial parlor tricks of research This form of criticism has been repeated by others such as in <PERSON>Carl Staumshein</PERSON> writing in Inside Higher Education who calls it a <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities Bubble</ORGANIZATION> 68 Later in the same publication <PERSON>Straumshein</PERSON> alleges that the digital humanities is a Corporatist Restructuring of the Humanities 69 Some see the alliance of the digital humanities with business to be a positive turn that causes the business world to pay more attention thus bringing needed funding and attention to the humanities 70 If it were not burdened by the title of digital humanities it could escape the allegations that it is elitist and unfairly funded 71 Black box edit There has also been critique of the use of digital humanities tools by scholars who do not fully understand what happens to the data they input and place too much trust in the black box of software that cannot be sufficiently examined for errors 72 <PERSON>Johanna Drucker</PERSON> a professor at <ORGANIZATION>UCLA Department of Information Studies</ORGANIZATION> has criticized the epistemological fallacies prevalent in popular visualization tools and technologies such as <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> s n gram graph used by digital humanities scholars and the general public calling some network diagramming and topic modeling tools just too crude for humanistic work 73 The lack of transparency in these programs obscures the subjective nature of the data and its processing she argues as these programs generate standard diagrams based on conventional algorithms for screen display mak ing it very difficult for the semantics of the data processing to be made evident 73 Diversity edit There has also been some recent controversy among practitioners of digital humanities around the role that race and or identity politics plays <PERSON>Tara McPherson</PERSON> attributes some of the lack of racial diversity in digital humanities to the modality of UNIX and computers themselves 74 An open thread on DHpoco org recently garnered well over 100 comments on the issue of race in digital humanities with scholars arguing about the amount that racial and other biases affect the tools and texts available for digital humanities research 75 <PERSON>McPherson</PERSON> posits that there needs to be an understanding and theorizing of the implications of digital technology and race even when the subject for analysis appears not to be about race <PERSON>Amy E Earhart</PERSON> criticizes what has become the new digital humanities canon in the shift from websites using simple HTML to the usage of the TEI and visuals in textual recovery projects 76 Works that has been previously lost or excluded were afforded a new home on the internet but much of the same marginalizing practices found in traditional humanities also took place digitally According to <PERSON>Earhart</PERSON> there is a need to examine the canon that we as digital humanists are constructing a canon that skews toward traditional texts and excludes crucial work by women people of color and the GLBTQ community 76 Issues of access edit Practitioners in digital humanities are also failing to meet the needs of users with disabilities <PERSON>George H Williams</PERSON> argues that universal design is imperative for practitioners to increase usability because many of the otherwise most valuable digital resources are useless for people who are for example deaf or hard of hearing as well as for people who are blind have low vision or have difficulty distinguishing particular colors 77 In order to provide accessibility successfully and productive universal design it is important to understand why and how users with disabilities are using the digital resources while remembering that all users approach their informational needs differently 77 Cultural criticism edit <ORGANIZATION>Digital</ORGANIZATION> humanities have been criticized for not only ignoring traditional questions of lineage and history in the humanities but lacking the fundamental cultural criticism that defines the humanities However it remains to be seen whether or not the humanities have to be tied to cultural criticism per se in order to be the humanities 78 10 The sciences vague see the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> as a welcome improvement over the non quantitative and repetitive historically popular methods of the humanities and social sciences 79 80 Difficulty of evaluation edit As the field matures there has been a recognition that the standard model of academic peer review of work may not be adequate for digital humanities projects which often involve website components databases and other non print objects Evaluation of quality and impact thus require a combination of old and new methods of peer review 3 One response has been the creation of the DHCommons Journal This accepts non traditional submissions especially mid stage digital projects and provides an innovative model of peer review more suited for the multimedia transdisciplinary and milestone driven nature of <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> projects Other professional humanities organizations such as the <ORGANIZATION>American Historical Association</ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION>Modern Language Association</ORGANIZATION> have developed guidelines for evaluating academic digital scholarship 81 82 Lack of focus on pedagogy edit The 2012 edition of Debates in the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> recognized the fact that pedagogy was the neglected stepchild of DH and included an entire section on teaching the digital humanities 5 Part of the reason is that grants in the humanities are geared more toward research with quantifiable results rather than teaching innovations which are harder to measure 5 In recognition of a need for more scholarship on the area of teaching <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities Pedagogy</ORGANIZATION> was published and offered case studies and strategies to address how to teach digital humanities methods in various disciplines Organizations edit The <ORGANIZATION>Alliance of Digital Humanities Organizations ADHO</ORGANIZATION> is an umbrella organization that supports digital research and teaching as a consultative and advisory force for its constituent organizations Its governance was approved in 2005 and it has overseen the annual <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> conference since 2006 83 The current members of ADHO are <ORGANIZATION>Australasian Association for Digital Humanities aaDH Association for Computers and the Humanities ACH Canadian Society for Digital Humanities Soci</ORGANIZATION> t canadienne des humanit s num riques CSDH SCHN centerNet an international network of digital humanities centers The <ORGANIZATION>European Association for Digital Humanities EADH Japanese Association for Digital Humanities JADH Humanistica L association</ORGANIZATION> francophone des humanit s num riques digitales Humanistica ADHO funds a number of projects such as the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities Quarterly</ORGANIZATION> journal and the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Scholarship in the Humanities DSH</ORGANIZATION> journal supports the Text Encoding Initiative and sponsors workshops and conferences as well as funding small projects awards and bursaries 84 <ORGANIZATION>HASTAC Humanities Arts Science and Technology Alliance</ORGANIZATION> and Collaboratory is a free and open access virtual interdisciplinary community focused on changing teaching and learning through the sharing of news tools methods and pedagogy including digital humanities scholarship 85 It is reputed to be the world s first and oldest academic social network 85 Centers and institutes edit <ORGANIZATION>Department of Digital Humanities King s College London UK Humanities Advanced Technology and Information Institute University of Glasgow Scotland Sussex Humanities Lab University of Sussex UK Humlab Ume University Sweden Digital Humanities Summer Institute DHSI University of Victoria Canada Heidelberg Centre for Digital Humanities Heidelberg University Germany The European Summer University in Digital Humanities Leipzig University Germany Cultural Analytics Lab The Graduate Center City University of New York USA</ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION>Qualcomm Institute USA Center for Digital Research</ORGANIZATION> in the <ORGANIZATION>Humanities University of Nebraska Lincoln USA Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities University of Virginia USA Maryland Institute for Technology in the Humanities University of Maryland USA Roy Rosenzweig Center for History and New Media George Mason University Virginia USA UCL Centre for Digital Humanities University College London UK Center for Public History and Digital Humanities Cleveland State University USA Center for Digital Scholarship and Curation Washington State University USA Scholars Lab University of Virginia USA Centre for Digital Humanities Research Australian National University AU Helsinki Centre for Digital Humanities HELDIG University of Helsinki Finland Laboratory</ORGANIZATION> for digital cultures and humanities of the <ORGANIZATION>University of Lausanne LaDHUL University of Lausanne Switzerland Centre for Information Modeling Austrian Centre for Digital Humanities ZIM ACDH University of Graz Austria Conferences</ORGANIZATION> edit <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> conference THATCamp Text Encoding Initiative TEI conference Journals and publications edit <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> Quarterly DHQ image open access publication free to read DHCommons <ORGANIZATION>Digital Literary Studies Digital Medievalist Digital Scholarship</ORGANIZATION> in the Humanities DSH formerly Literary and Linguistic Computing Digital Studies Le champ num rique DS CN image open access publication free to read Humanit s num riques Humanistica image open access publication free to read <ORGANIZATION>Journal of Digital Archives and Digital Humanities Journal of Digital and Media Literacy Journal of Digital Humanities JDH Journal of Interactive Technology and Pedagogy Journal of the Japanese Association for Digital Humanities JJADH Journal</ORGANIZATION> of the Text Encoding Initiative Kairos Southern Spaces Umanistica Digitale AIUCD image open access publication free to read See also edit Cyborg anthropology <ORGANIZATION>Digital</ORGANIZATION> anthropology References edit <PERSON>Drucker Johanna</PERSON> September 2013 Intro to <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities Introduction UCLA Center for Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> Retrieved December 26 2016 a b Terras Melissa December 2011 Quantifying Digital Humanities PDF <ORGANIZATION>UCL Centre for Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> Retrieved December 26 2016 a b c d e f g h i j k <PERSON>Burdick Anne Drucker Johanna Lunenfeld Peter Presner Todd Schnapp Jeffrey</PERSON> November 2012 Digital_Humanities PDF Open Access eBook MIT Press ISBN 9780262312097 <PERSON>Warwick Claire Terras Melissa Nyhan Julianne</PERSON> 2012 10 09 <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities in Practice Facet Publishing ISBN</ORGANIZATION> 9781856047661 a b c Debates in the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> dhdebates gc cuny edu Retrieved 2016 12 29 <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities Network University of Cambridge Retrieved</ORGANIZATION> 27 December 2012 <PERSON>Svensson Patrik</PERSON> 2009 Humanities Computing as <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities Digital Humanities Quarterly</ORGANIZATION> 3 3 ISSN 1938 4122 Retrieved 2012 05 30 a b <PERSON>Hockney Susan</PERSON> 2004 The History of Humanities Computing In <PERSON>Susan Schreibman Ray Siemens John Unsworth</PERSON> eds <ORGANIZATION>Companion to Digital Humanities Blackwell Companions to Literature and Culture Oxford Blackwell ISBN</ORGANIZATION> 1405103213 CS1 maint Uses editors parameter link <PERSON>Feeney Mary</PERSON> amp <ORGANIZATION>Ross Seamus 1994 Information Technology</ORGANIZATION> in Humanities Scholarship British Achievements Prospects and <ORGANIZATION>Barriers Historical Social Research</ORGANIZATION> 19 1 69 3 59 JSTOR 20755828 a b <PERSON>Berry David</PERSON> M <ORGANIZATION>Fagerjord Anders 2017 Digital Humanities Knowledge</ORGANIZATION> and Critique in a <ORGANIZATION>Digital Age Cambridge Polity</ORGANIZATION> ISBN 978 0 7456 9765 9 <PERSON>McPherson Tara</PERSON> DH by Design Feminism aesthetics the digital <ORGANIZATION>Congress of the Social Science and Humanities University of Calgary 2016</ORGANIZATION> 05 31 Keynote <PERSON>Jerome J McGann</PERSON> ed <ORGANIZATION>Rossetti Archive Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities University of Virginia</ORGANIZATION> retrieved 2012 06 16 Morris Eaves <PERSON>Robert Essick</PERSON> and <PERSON>Joseph Viscomi</PERSON> eds The <PERSON>William Blake</PERSON> Archive retrieved 2012 06 16 CS1 maint Uses editors parameter link <PERSON>Liu Alan</PERSON> 2004 Transcendental Data Toward a Cultural History and Aesthetics of the New Encoded Discourse Critical Inquiry 31 1 49 84 doi 10 1086 427302 ISSN 0093 1896 JSTOR 10 1086 427302 a b c <PERSON>Fitzpatrick Kathleen</PERSON> 2011 05 08 The humanities done digitally The Chronicle of Higher Education Retrieved 2011 07 10 <PERSON>Berry David</PERSON> 2011 06 01 The Computational Turn Thinking About the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities Culture Machine</ORGANIZATION> Retrieved 2012 01 31 a b <PERSON>Kirschenbaum Matthew</PERSON> G 2010 What is <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> and What s it Doing in English Departments PDF ADE Bulletin 150 <PERSON>Howard Jennifer</PERSON> 2009 12 31 The MLA Convention in Translation The <ORGANIZATION>Chronicle</ORGANIZATION> of Higher Education ISSN 0009 5982 Retrieved 2012 05 31 Pannapacker William 2009 12 28 The MLA and the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities The Chronicle</ORGANIZATION> of Higher Education Brainstorm Retrieved 2012 05 30 a b <PERSON>Honn Josh</PERSON> A Guide to <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities Values Methods Northwestern University Library Archived</ORGANIZATION> from the original on 19 September 2015 Retrieved 19 September 2015 Find accessible brief descriptions of each at A Guide to <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> archived site Bradley John 2012 No job for techies Technical contributions to research in digital humanities In <PERSON>Marilyn Deegan</PERSON> and <PERSON>Willard McCarty</PERSON> eds <ORGANIZATION>Collaborative Research</ORGANIZATION> in the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities Farnham</ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION>Burlington Ashgate</ORGANIZATION> pp 11 26 14 ISBN 9781409410683 CS1 maint Uses editors parameter link <ORGANIZATION>Grant Opportunities National Endowment for the Humanities Office of Digital Humanities Grant Opportunities Retrieved</ORGANIZATION> 25 January 2012 permanent dead link <ORGANIZATION>Harvard University Arts amp Humanities Research Computing Harvard University Arts amp Humanities Research Computing Harvard University Arts amp Humanities Research Computing Roth</ORGANIZATION> S 2014 Fashionable functions A <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> n gram view of trends in functional differentiation 1800 2000 International Journal of Technology and Human Interaction Band 10 Nr 2 S 34 58 online http ssrn com abstract 2491422 Bobley Brett December 1 2008 <ORGANIZATION>Grant Announcement for Humanities High Performance Computing Program National Endowment for the Humanities Retrieved</ORGANIZATION> May 1 2012 Awardees of 2009 Digging into Data Challenge Digging into Data 2009 Archived from the original on May 17 2012 Retrieved May 1 2012 NEH Announces Winners of 2011 <ORGANIZATION>Digging Into Data Challenge National Endowment for the Humanities January</ORGANIZATION> 3 2012 Retrieved May 1 2012 <PERSON>Cohen Patricia</PERSON> 2010 11 16 <ORGANIZATION>Humanities Scholars Embrace Digital Technology The New York Times New York</ORGANIZATION> ISSN 0362 4331 Retrieved 2012 06 07 <ORGANIZATION>Williford Christa Henry Charles June 2012 Computationally Intensive Research</ORGANIZATION> in the Humanities and Social Sciences A Report on the Experiences of First Respondents to the <ORGANIZATION>Digging Into Data Challenge Council on Library and Information Resources</ORGANIZATION> ISBN 978 1 932326 40 6 <ORGANIZATION>Dzogang Fabon Lansdall Welfare Thomas Team</ORGANIZATION> FindMyPast Newspaper Cristianini Nello 2016 11 08 Discovering Periodic Patterns in Historical News PLOS ONE 11 11 e0165736 doi 10 1371 journal pone 0165736 ISSN 1932 6203 PMC 5100883 image Freely accessible PMID 27824911 Seasonal Fluctuations in Collective Mood Revealed by <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia Searches and Twitter Posts F Dzogang T Lansdall Welfare N Cristianini</ORGANIZATION> 2016 IEEE International Conference on <ORGANIZATION>Data Mining Workshop on Data Mining</ORGANIZATION> in Human Activity Analysis Flaounas I <PERSON>Turchi</PERSON> M <PERSON>Ali O Fyson N Bie</PERSON> T De Mosdell N <PERSON>Lewis J Cristianini</PERSON> N 2010 The Structure of <ORGANIZATION>EU Mediasphere PLoS ONE</ORGANIZATION> 5 12 e14243 doi 10 1371 journal pone 0014243 PMC 2999531 image Freely accessible PMID 21170383 Lampos V Cristianini N Nowcasting Events from the Social Web with Statistical Learning ACM Transactions on <ORGANIZATION>Intelligent Systems and Technology TIST</ORGANIZATION> 3 4 72 doi 10 1145 2337542 2337557 NOAM news outlets analysis and monitoring system I Flaounas O <PERSON>Ali M Turchi</PERSON> T <PERSON>Snowsill</PERSON> F <ORGANIZATION>Nicart T De Bie N Cristianini Proc</ORGANIZATION> of the 2011 ACM SIGMOD international conference on Management of data Automatic discovery of patterns in media content N Cristianini Combinatorial Pattern Matching 2 13 2011 a b <PERSON>Lansdall Welfare Thomas Sudhahar Saatviga Thompson James Lewis Justin Team</PERSON> FindMyPast Newspaper Cristianini Nello 2017 01 09 Content analysis of 150 years of British periodicals Proceedings of the <ORGANIZATION>National Academy of Sciences</ORGANIZATION> 201606380 doi 10 1073 pnas 1606380114 ISSN 0027 8424 PMID 28069962 Bol P K C L <PERSON>Liu</PERSON> and H Wang 2015 Mining and discovering biographical information in <LOCATION>Difangzhi</LOCATION> with a language model based approach Proceedings of the 2015 <ORGANIZATION>International Conference on Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> https arxiv org abs 1504 02148 <ORGANIZATION>Presner Todd 2010 Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> 2 0 A Report on Knowledge Connexions Retrieved 2012 06 09 Automated analysis of the <LOCATION>US</LOCATION> presidential elections using <ORGANIZATION>Big Data</ORGANIZATION> and network analysis S <ORGANIZATION>Sudhahar GA Veltri N Cristianini Big Data amp Society</ORGANIZATION> 2 1 1 28 2015 <PERSON>Gardiner Eileen</PERSON> and <PERSON>Ronald G Musto</PERSON> 2015 The <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities A Primer for Students and Scholars Cambridge Cambridge University Press</ORGANIZATION> p 83 Welcome DiRT Directory dirtdirectory org TAPoR tapor test artsrn ualberta ca <ORGANIZATION>Voyant Tools</ORGANIZATION> voyant tools org dhresourcesforprojectbuilding licensed for non commercial use only <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities Tools</ORGANIZATION> dhresourcesforprojectbuilding pbworks com See CUNY Academic Commons Wiki Archive for more The <ORGANIZATION>Walt Whitman Archive</ORGANIZATION> www whitmanarchive org <PERSON>Emily Dickinson</PERSON> From Fascicle to Open Access <ORGANIZATION>Harvard University Press</ORGANIZATION> www hup harvard edu Retrieved 2016 12 26 See <ORGANIZATION>Emily Dickinson Archive</ORGANIZATION> website League of Nations archives <ORGANIZATION>United Nations Office in Geneva Network</ORGANIZATION> visualization and analysis published in <PERSON>Grandjean Martin</PERSON> 2014 La connaissance est un r seau <PERSON>Les Cahiers</PERSON> du Num rique 10 3 37 54 doi 10 3166 lcn 10 3 37 54 Retrieved 2014 10 15 <ORGANIZATION>Homepage Slave Societies Digital Archive People Department</ORGANIZATION> of History Timeline 4535 Time Magazine Covers 1923 2009 A View from Above Exploratory Visualizations of <ORGANIZATION>MoMA</ORGANIZATION> Photography Collection Exploring One Million Manga Pages with Supercomputers and HIPerSpace Manovich Lev 2017 Instagram and <ORGANIZATION>Contemporary Image Cultural Analytics Computational Approaches</ORGANIZATION> to the Study of Culture the <ORGANIZATION>University of Chicago</ORGANIZATION> May 2015 and <ORGANIZATION>Cultural Analytics</ORGANIZATION> symposium <ORGANIZATION>Notre Dame University May 2017 Culture Analytics</ORGANIZATION> program Institute for Pure and Applied Mathematics IPAM UCLA March 7 June 10 2016 Journal of Cultural Analytics CA Mapping the Republic of Letters National Endowment for the Humanities Retrieved 2016 12 26 <PERSON>Cohen Patricia</PERSON> 16 December 2010 In 500 Billion Words New Window on <ORGANIZATION>Culture New York Times Hayes Brian</ORGANIZATION> May June 2011 Bit Lit American Scientist 99 3 190 doi 10 1511 2011 90 190 Letcher <PERSON>David</PERSON> W April 6 2011 Cultoromics A New Way to See Temporal Changes in the <ORGANIZATION>Prevalence of Words and Phrases PDF American Institute of Higher Education</ORGANIZATION> 6th International Conference Proceedings 4 1 228 a b <PERSON>Michel Jean Baptiste Liberman Aiden Erez</PERSON> 16 December 2010 Quantitative Analysis of Culture Using Millions of Digitized Books Science 331 6014 176 82 doi 10 1126 science 1199644 PMC 3279742 image Freely accessible PMID 21163965 Debates in the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities Fish Stanley</ORGANIZATION> 2012 01 09 The <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> and the Transcending of Mortality The <ORGANIZATION>New York Times New York</ORGANIZATION> Retrieved 2012 05 30 <ORGANIZATION>Leroi Armand Digitizing the Humanities The New York Times Online The New York Times</ORGANIZATION> Retrieved 14 May 2016 Kirsch Adam Technology Is Taking Over English Departments The New Republic The New Republic Retrieved 14 May 2016 <ORGANIZATION>Straumshein Carl Digital Humanities Bubble Inside Higher Education Retrieved</ORGANIZATION> 14 May 2016 <ORGANIZATION>Straumshein Carl Digital Humanities as Corporatist Restructuring Inside Higher Education Inside Higher Education Retrieved</ORGANIZATION> 14 May 2016 <ORGANIZATION>Carlson Tracy Humanities</ORGANIZATION> and business go hand in hand <ORGANIZATION>The Boston Globe</ORGANIZATION> Retrieved 14 May 2016 Pannapacker William Stop Calling It <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities Chronicle</ORGANIZATION> of Higher Education Retrieved 14 May 2016 <PERSON>Dobson James</PERSON> E 2015 Can an Algorithm be Disturbed Machine Learning Intrinsic Criticism and the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities College Literature</ORGANIZATION> 42 4 543 564 a b <PERSON>Johanna Drucker</PERSON> UCLA Lecture Should Humanists Visualize Knowledge Vimeo Retrieved 2016 01 25 Debates in the Digital Humanities Open Thread The <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> as a Historical Refuge from Race Class Gender Sexuality Disability Archived from the original on 2013 12 03 a b Debates in the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> dhdebates gc cuny edu a b <PERSON>George H Williams</PERSON> Disability Universal Design and the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities Debates</ORGANIZATION> in the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities Liu Alan Where</ORGANIZATION> is Cultural Criticism in the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities UCSB</ORGANIZATION> Retrieved 14 May 2016 Poetry in Motion Nature Nature Retrieved 14 May 2016 Kirschenbaum Matthew What Is <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> and Why Are They Saying Such Terrible Things about It PDF Wordpress <PERSON>Matthew Kirschenbaum</PERSON> Retrieved 14 May 2016 Guidelines for Evaluating Work in <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities and Digital Modern Language Association</ORGANIZATION> Retrieved 2017 02 13 Guidelines for the Professional Evaluation of Digital Scholarship by Historians AHA www historians org Retrieved 2017 02 13 About ADHO adho org Retrieved 2016 12 26 Vanhoutte Edward 2011 04 01 Editorial Literary and Linguistic Computing 26 1 3 4 doi 10 1093 llc fqr002 Retrieved 2011 07 11 a b About HASTAC HASTAC Retrieved 2016 12 26 Bibliography edit <ORGANIZATION>Beagle Donald 2014 Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> in the <ORGANIZATION>Research Commons Precedents amp Prospects Association of College amp Research Libraries</ORGANIZATION> dh lib <PERSON>Benzon William Hays David</PERSON> 1976 Computational Linguistics and the <ORGANIZATION>Humanist Computers</ORGANIZATION> and the Humanities 10 265 274 doi 10 1007 bf02420060 <PERSON>Berry</PERSON> D M ed 2012 <ORGANIZATION>Understanding Digital Humanities Basingstoke Palgrave Macmillan Burdick</ORGANIZATION> <PERSON>Anne Johanna Drucker Peter Lunenfeld Todd Presner</PERSON> amp <PERSON>Jeffrey Schnap</PERSON> 2012 Digital_Humanities The <ORGANIZATION>MIT Press Busa Roberto</ORGANIZATION> 1980 The Annals of Humanities Computing The Index Thomisticus in Computers and the Humanities vol 14 pp 83 90 Computers and the Humanities 1966 2004 <PERSON>Celentano</PERSON> A Cortesi A amp <PERSON>Mastandrea</PERSON> P 2004 Informatica Umanistica una disciplina di confine <ORGANIZATION>Mondo Digitale</ORGANIZATION> vol 4 pp 44 55 <PERSON>Classen Christoph Kinnebrock Susanne</PERSON> amp L blich <PERSON>Maria</PERSON> eds 2012 Towards Web History Sources Methods and Challenges in the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Age Historical Social Research</ORGANIZATION> 37 4 97 188 <ORGANIZATION>Condron Frances Fraser Michael amp Sutherland Stuart</ORGANIZATION> eds 2001 <ORGANIZATION>Oxford University Computing Services Guide to Digital Resources for the Humanities West Virginia University Press</ORGANIZATION> Fitzpatrick Kathleen 2011 Planned Obsolescence Publishing Technology and the Future of the <ORGANIZATION>Academy New York NYU Press ISBN</ORGANIZATION> 9780814727874 <PERSON>Gardiner Eileen</PERSON> and <PERSON>Ronald G Musto</PERSON> 2015 The <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities A Primer for Students and Scholars Cambridge Cambridge University Press Gold Matthew K</ORGANIZATION> ed 2012 Debates In the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities Minneapolis University of Minnesota Press Grandjean Martin</ORGANIZATION> 2016 A social network analysis of Twitter Mapping the digital humanities community <ORGANIZATION>Cogent Arts amp Humanities</ORGANIZATION> 3 1 1171458 doi 10 1080 23311983 2016 1171458 Hancock B Giarlo M J 2001 Moving to XML Latin texts XML conversion project at the <ORGANIZATION>Center for Electronic Texts in the Humanities Library Hi Tech</ORGANIZATION> 19 3 257 264 doi 10 1108 07378830110405139 Heftberger Adelheid 2016 Kollision der <PERSON>Kader Dziga Vertovs Filme</PERSON> die Visualisierung ihrer Strukturen und die <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities Munich</ORGANIZATION> edition text kritik Hockey Susan 2001 Electronic Text in the <ORGANIZATION>Humanities Principles and Practice Oxford Oxford University Press</ORGANIZATION> Honing Henkjan 2008 The role of <ORGANIZATION>ICT</ORGANIZATION> in music research A bridge too far <ORGANIZATION>International Journal of Humanities and Arts Computing</ORGANIZATION> 1 1 67 75 <PERSON>Inman James Reed Cheryl</PERSON> amp <LOCATION>Sands Peter</LOCATION> eds 2003 Electronic Collaboration in the Humanities Issues and Options Mahwah NJ <PERSON>Lawrence Erlbaum Kenna Stephanie</PERSON> amp <PERSON>Ross Seamus</PERSON> eds 1995 Networking in the humanities Proceedings of the Second Conference on Scholarship and Technology in the Humanities held at <LOCATION>Elvetham Hall Hampshire UK</LOCATION> 13 16 April 1994 <LOCATION>London</LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION>Bowker Saur Kirschenbaum Matthew 2008 Mechanisms New Media</ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION>Forensic Imagination Cambridge Mass MIT Press Manovich</ORGANIZATION> Lev 2013 Software Takes Command <LOCATION>London</LOCATION> and <ORGANIZATION>New York Bloomsbury Academic McCarty Willard 2005 Humanities Computing Basingstoke Palgrave Macmillan Moretti</ORGANIZATION> Franco 2007 Graphs Maps Trees Abstract Models for Literary History New York Verso Mullings <PERSON>Christine Kenna Stephanie Deegan Marilyn</PERSON> amp <PERSON>Ross Seamus</PERSON> eds 1996 <ORGANIZATION>New Technologies for the Humanities London Bowker Saur Newell William H</ORGANIZATION> ed 1998 Interdisciplinarity Essays from the <ORGANIZATION>Literature New York College Entrance Examination Board</ORGANIZATION> Ramsay Steve 2011 Reading Machines Toward an Algorithmic Criticism <ORGANIZATION>Urbana University of Illinois Press</ORGANIZATION> <PERSON>Schreibman Susan Siemens Ray</PERSON> amp <PERSON>Unsworth John</PERSON> eds 2004 A Companion To <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities Blackwell Publishers Selfridge Field Eleanor</ORGANIZATION> ed 1997 Beyond MIDI The <ORGANIZATION>Handbook of Musical Codes Cambridge MA</ORGANIZATION> The MIT Press Thaller Manfred 2012 Controversies around the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities Historical Social Research</ORGANIZATION> 37 3 7 229 permanent dead link <PERSON>Swirski</PERSON> Peter 2013 From Literature to Biterature <PERSON>Lem Turing Darwin</PERSON> and Explorations in Computer Literature Philosophy of Mind and Cultural Evolution MQUP T t sy de <ORGANIZATION>Zepetnek Steven 2013 Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> and the Study of <ORGANIZATION>Intermediality in Comparative Cultural Studies Ed Steven T t sy de Zepetnek West Lafayette Purdue Scholarly Publishing Services Unsworth John</ORGANIZATION> 2005 Scholarly Primitives What methods do humanities researchers have in common and how might our tools reflect this Lansdall Welfare T Sudhahar S <PERSON>Thompson J Lewis J Cristianini</PERSON> N Content analysis of 150 years of British periodicals Proc Natl Acad Sci U S A 201606380 doi 10 1073 pnas 1606380114 PMID 28069962 Warwick C Terras M amp <PERSON>Nyhan</PERSON> J eds 2012 <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> in Practice Facet Publishing <PERSON>YOSHIDA Yukihiko Leni Riefenstahl</PERSON> and German Expressionism A Study of Visual Cultural Studies Using Transdisciplinary Semantic Space of Specialized Dictionaries Technoetic Arts a journal of speculative research Editor <PERSON>Roy Ascott</PERSON> Volume 8 Issue3 intellect 2008 Further reading edit Introductory guides Intro to <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> by <ORGANIZATION>UCLA Center for Digital Humanities CUNY Digital Humanities Resource Guide</ORGANIZATION> by <ORGANIZATION>CUNY Digital Humanities Initiative</ORGANIZATION> DH Toychest Guides and Introductions curated by DH scholar <PERSON>Alan Liu How</PERSON> did they make that by DH scholar <PERSON>Miriam Posner</PERSON> The <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> A Primer for Students and Scholars 2015 <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> in Practice 2012 External links edit image Wikimedia Commons has media related to <ORGANIZATION>Digital</ORGANIZATION> humanities What is digital humanities a critical project highlighting the diversity of DH definitions The <ORGANIZATION>Alliance of Digital Humanities Organizations</ORGANIZATION> the main international alliance of DH programs CenterNet Mapping of DH centers v t e <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities Computers</ORGANIZATION> and writing Computational archaeology Cybertext Cultural analytics <ORGANIZATION>Digital Classicist Digital library Digital Medievalist Digital</ORGANIZATION> history <ORGANIZATION>Digitizing Digital</ORGANIZATION> rhetoric <ORGANIZATION>Digital</ORGANIZATION> scholarship Electronic literature E research Humanistic informatics Multimedia literacy New media Semantic Web Systems theory Text Encoding Initiative <ORGANIZATION>Transliteracy</ORGANIZATION> v <ORGANIZATION>t e Humanities Anthropology Digital Humanities History Law Literature Performing</ORGANIZATION> arts Politics Philosophy Religious studies Visual arts <ORGANIZATION>Authority</ORGANIZATION> control LCCN sh2008122106 GND 1038714850 image Retrieved from https en wikipedia org w index php title Digital_humanities amp oldid 839783684 <ORGANIZATION>Categories Digital</ORGANIZATION> humanities Hidden categories CS1 maint Uses editors parameter All articles with dead external links Articles with dead external links from December 2016 Articles with permanently dead external links All <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> articles needing clarification <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> articles needing clarification from June 2017 <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> articles with LCCN identifiers <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> articles with GND identifiers Navigation menu Personal tools Not logged in Talk Contributions Create account Log in Namespaces Article Talk Variants Views Read Edit View history More Search Navigation Main page Contents Featured content Current events Random article Donate to <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> store Interaction Help About Wikipedia Community portal Recent changes Contact page Tools What links here Related changes Upload file Special pages Permanent link Page information Wikidata item Cite this page Print export Create a book Download as PDF Printable version In other projects Wikimedia Commons Languages Catal Cymraeg Deutsch Espa ol Euskara Fran ais <ORGANIZATION>Italiano Latina Magyar Polski Sloven ina Srpskohrvatski Suomi Svenska Ti ng Vi</ORGANIZATION> t Edit links This page was last edited on 5 May 2018 at 17 00 Text is available under the Creative Commons Attribution ShareAlike License additional terms may apply By using this site you agree to the Terms of Use and <ORGANIZATION>Privacy Policy Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> is a registered trademark of the <ORGANIZATION>Wikimedia Foundation Inc</ORGANIZATION> a non profit organization Privacy policy <ORGANIZATION>About Wikipedia Disclaimers Contact Wikipedia Developers Cookie</ORGANIZATION> statement Mobile view image <ORGANIZATION>Wikimedia Foundation</ORGANIZATION> image Powered by <PERSON>MediaWiki</PERSON></ner>
