<ner>Skip navigation image Home Books Browse by Discipline Architecture The <ORGANIZATION>Arts Bioethics Business Management Innovation Cognition Brain amp Behavior Computer Science and Intelligent Systems Design and Design Theory Economics and Finance Engineering Environment and Urban Studies Game Studies Humanities Internet Studies Information Communication Linguistics and Language Mathematics and Physics MIT</ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION>Regional Interest Neuroscience New Media and Digital Humanities Philosophy Political Science amp Public Policy Science Science Technology and Society Browse All Disciplines</ORGANIZATION> container New Titles Coming Soon Textbooks eTextbooks Rental Catalogs Series Authors Distribution and Services BITS Journals Open About Giving Help image image Prev image Taming the Sun By <PERSON>Varun Sivaram</PERSON> How solar could spark a clean energy transition through transformative innovation creative financing revolutionary technologies and flexible energy systems image Post Truth By <PERSON>Lee McIntyre How</PERSON> we arrived in a post truth era when alternative facts replace actual facts and feelings have more weight than evidence image Chaos and Awe Edited by <PERSON>Mark W Scala Fifty</PERSON> paintings reproduced in color by an international array of contemporary artists show the aptness and relevance of painting in an era of uncertainty image Rock Bone and Ruin By <PERSON>Adrian Currie An</PERSON> argument that we should be optimistic about the capacity of methodologically omnivorous geologists paleontologists and archaeologists to uncover truths about the deep past image Practice Edited by <PERSON>Marcus Boon Gabriel Levine</PERSON> The first anthology to investigate what contemporary notions of practice mean for art tracing their development and speculating on where this leads image The Qualified Self By <PERSON>Lee Humphreys</PERSON> How sharing the mundane details of daily life did not start with <ORGANIZATION>Facebook Twitter</ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION>YouTube</ORGANIZATION> but with pocket diaries photo albums and baby books image Machine Learning for Data Streams By <PERSON>Albert Bifet Ricard Gavald</PERSON> A hands on approach to tasks and techniques in data stream mining and real time analytics with examples in MOA a popular freely available open source software framework image Families at Play By <PERSON>Sinem Siyahhan Elisabeth Gee How</PERSON> family video game play promotes intergenerational communication connection and learning image Energy and Civilization By <PERSON>Vaclav Smil</PERSON> A comprehensive account of how energy has shaped society throughout history from pre agricultural foraging societies through today s fossil fuel driven civilization image The Dialogues By <PERSON>Clifford V Johnson</PERSON> A series of conversations about science in graphic form on subjects that range from the science of cooking to the multiverse image Taming the Sun Varun Sivaram image Post Truth <PERSON>Lee McIntyre</PERSON> image Chaos and Awe <PERSON>Mark W Scala</PERSON> image Rock Bone and Ruin <PERSON>Adrian Currie</PERSON> image Practice <PERSON>Marcus Boon Gabriel Levine</PERSON> image The Qualified Self <PERSON>Lee Humphreys</PERSON> image Machine Learning for Data Streams <PERSON>Albert Bifet Ricard Gavald</PERSON> image Families at Play Sinem Siyahhan Elisabeth Gee image Energy and Civilization <PERSON>Vaclav Smil</PERSON> image The Dialogues Clifford V Johnson Next MIT Press Journals image ARTMargins February June October image Global Environmental Politics February May August November <ORGANIZATION>Browse More Journals Facebook MIT Press</ORGANIZATION> on <ORGANIZATION>Facebook Twitter Tweets</ORGANIZATION> by mitpress <ORGANIZATION>MIT Press</ORGANIZATION> on Twitter image Open Data The Global Effort for Open Access to Satellite Data <PERSON>Mariel Borowitz</PERSON> s new book Open Space The Global Effort for Open Access to <ORGANIZATION>Environmental Satellite Data</ORGANIZATION> traces the history of environmental satellite data image image image Journals 2018 image Spring 2018 US One <ORGANIZATION>Rogers Street Cambridge MA</ORGANIZATION> 02142 1209 UK Suite 2 1 <ORGANIZATION>Duchess Street London</ORGANIZATION> W1W 6AN <LOCATION>UK</LOCATION> Contact Us The MIT Press About Bookstore Catalogs Events Internships Jobs Location Newsletter Staff Site Help Accessibility FAQ Privacy Policy Sitemap Terms of Use Services Current Authors Prospective Authors Book Sales Distribution and Services Exam and Desk Copies How to <ORGANIZATION>Order Journals Customer Service MIT Discounts Rights Permissions MIT Press Digital Arteca CogNet Digital Partners Idea Commons MIT Press eBooks Facebook Twitter Instagram</ORGANIZATION> New Titles RSS 2018 The MIT Press</ner>
