<ner>Skip to content CUNY Academic Commons Wiki Archive Menu Home Contents From CUNY Academic Commons image Welcome to the <ORGANIZATION>CUNY Digital Humanities Resource Guide</ORGANIZATION> a collaboratively produced introduction to the field of <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> The guide is a project of the <ORGANIZATION>CUNY Digital Humanities Initiative DHI</ORGANIZATION> a new working group aimed at building connections and community among those at CUNY who are or would like to be applying digital technologies to research and pedagogy in the humanities image image Centernet Summit and THATCamp <LOCATION>London</LOCATION> shared CC by <ORGANIZATION>Marin Dacos amp Revues</ORGANIZATION> org bookmark Introduction Introduction Using This Guide bookmark The_Digital_Humanities The <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities Defining the Digital Humanities Sample</ORGANIZATION> Projects Some Reading Hot Topics bookmark The_Resource_Guide The Resource Guide Online Communities Discussion Forums DH on <ORGANIZATION>Twitter Blogs to Follow Journals Conferences amp Events Training Professional Development Scholarships Fellowships Funding Awards Competitions Centers for DH Work Organizations Associations Tools amp Methods Data Management Tools Research amp Citation Management Tools Writing Process Tools and Methods DH Programs</ORGANIZATION> and Syllabi Git and GitHub Jobs Tips Other Resources bookmark Hackathon_Resources Hackathon Resources HTML and <ORGANIZATION>CSS</ORGANIZATION> Credits The <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities Resource Guide</ORGANIZATION> was created by <PERSON>Charlie Edwards</PERSON> a graduate student in the Ph D Program in English and the <ORGANIZATION>Interactive Technology and Pedagogy Certificate Program</ORGANIZATION> at The <LOCATION>CUNY Graduate Center</LOCATION> in consultation with <ORGANIZATION>ITP</ORGANIZATION> faculty member <PERSON>Matthew K Gold</PERSON> CUNY Academic Commons Wiki Wrangler <PERSON>Scott Voth</PERSON> helped format it for the wiki Future versions of the guide will be produced collaboratively by the members of the CUNY DHI community and we hope by the DH community at large Previous The <ORGANIZATION>CUNY Digital</ORGANIZATION> Humanities Initiative Next Using This Guide Want to make a suggestion or correction Please visit Using This Guide for more information Search for Categories <ORGANIZATION>ADA Compliance</ORGANIZATION> 2 Art 2 Art on the Commons 1 Assessment 5 <ORGANIZATION>Blackboard</ORGANIZATION> 19 Blogging 8 Capitalism 1 <ORGANIZATION>CCRC</ORGANIZATION> 8 Citation Managers 2 Composition 15 Copyright 4 Course Development 4 <ORGANIZATION>Course Management Systems</ORGANIZATION> 1 Course Site Assessment 2 Creative practices 2 CUNY Academic Commons 2 CUNY ITunes U 32 <ORGANIZATION>CUNY ITunes U Campus Home Pages</ORGANIZATION> 18 <ORGANIZATION>CUNYDHI</ORGANIZATION> 24 <ORGANIZATION>DH Guide 23 Digital Humanities 23 Directory of Academic Commons Group Wikis</ORGANIZATION> 11 Distance Learning 6 E Learning 4 <ORGANIZATION>Educational Technology</ORGANIZATION> 10 <ORGANIZATION>Eportfolios</ORGANIZATION> 25 ESL 2 <ORGANIZATION>Faculty Development</ORGANIZATION> 3 Featured 4 <ORGANIZATION>FERPA</ORGANIZATION> 1 <ORGANIZATION>FYE</ORGANIZATION> 2 <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> 2 <ORGANIZATION>Gravatars</ORGANIZATION> 1 <ORGANIZATION>Help 41 Information Literacy</ORGANIZATION> 3 <ORGANIZATION>Intellectual Property</ORGANIZATION> 2 Librarians 10 <ORGANIZATION>Libraries 11 Library Science</ORGANIZATION> 3 <ORGANIZATION>Lincoln Center</ORGANIZATION> 1 Literature 1 Math 1 Math on the Commons 1 <ORGANIZATION>Metadata</ORGANIZATION> 2 <ORGANIZATION>Moodle</ORGANIZATION> 4 <ORGANIZATION>NCC</ORGANIZATION> 9 <ORGANIZATION>Omeka</ORGANIZATION> 4 On Line Lectures 5 Online Program Assessment 1 Open Access OA 7 Open Source 9 Philosophy 2 Plugin 1 Podcasting 6 Poetry 1 Political Science 1 Politics 1 Powerpoint 1 Privacy 3 Resources 4 Rhetoric 9 Sample online courses 2 <ORGANIZATION>Sandbox</ORGANIZATION> 1 <ORGANIZATION>Social Bookmarking</ORGANIZATION> 2 <ORGANIZATION>Social Networking</ORGANIZATION> 2 Suggestions 3 Teaching and Learning with Technology 71 The Arts CUNY 1 Twitter 4 Web 2 0 32 Web Publishing 19 Wikis 8 WordPress 8 Built with Make Your friendly WordPress page builder theme image css php Need help with the Commons Visit our help page Send us a message Skip to toolbar CUNY Academic Commons Home People Groups Sites Papers Events News Help About About the Commons Contact Us Publications on the <ORGANIZATION>Commons Image Credits Privacy Policy Project Staff Terms of Service</ORGANIZATION> Log in Register Help This site is part of the CUNY Academic Commons an academic social network for the entire 24 campus CUNY system Unless otherwise stated all content on the <ORGANIZATION>CUNY Academic Commons</ORGANIZATION> is licensed under a Creative Commons license image Help Contact Us Privacy Policy Terms of Service Image Credits image CUNY Logo Built with WordPress Protected by Akismet Powered by CUNY</ner>
