<ner>This website uses cookies By using our website and agreeing to our cookies policy you consent to our use of cookies in accordance with the terms of this policy Read more Loading Your cart is empty you ll find more products in the shopping cart Total 239 99 View cart Login Register My Account My <ORGANIZATION>Bookshelf Login Subjects Business amp Economics Humanities Politics amp International Studies Social Science Publishing With Us Book Authors Journal Authors</ORGANIZATION> Get 40 off print amp eBooks in <ORGANIZATION>Politics Humanities amp Social Science FREE</ORGANIZATION> shipping Stock up today gt gt Free Preview image image 2012 Understanding Digital Humanities Editors <PERSON>Berry</PERSON> D Ed Buy this book eBook 19 99 price for <LOCATION>USA</LOCATION> gross Buy eBook ISBN 978 0 230 37193 4 Digitally watermarked DRM free Included format PDF EPUB ebooks can be used on all reading devices Immediate eBook download after purchase Hardcover 169 99 price for <LOCATION>USA</LOCATION> Buy Hardcover ISBN 978 0 230 29264 2 Free shipping for individuals worldwide Usually dispatched within 3 to 5 business days Softcover 30 00 price for <LOCATION>USA</LOCATION> Buy Softcover ISBN 978 0 230 29265 9 Free shipping for individuals worldwide Usually dispatched within 3 to 5 business days FAQ Policy About this book Confronting the digital revolution in academia this book examines the application of new computational techniques and visualisation technologies in the <ORGANIZATION>Arts amp Humanities Uniting</ORGANIZATION> differing perspectives leading and emerging scholars discuss the theoretical and practical challenges that computation raises for these disciplines Show all About the authors <PERSON>DAVID BERRY</PERSON> is Lecturer in Media and Communication at the <ORGANIZATION>University of Swansea He</ORGANIZATION> is the author of Understanding Softward in the Digital Age Code Mediation and Computation Palgrave forthcoming Copy Rip Burn The Politics of Copyleft and Open Source Pluto 2008 and co editor of <ORGANIZATION>Libre Culture Pygmalion Books Canada</ORGANIZATION> 2008 He has also published in journals such as Theory Culture and Society Critical Discourse Studies and The Journal of Internet Research Show all Reviews <PERSON>Berry</PERSON> and colleagues present us with several current and future trajectories of the digital humanities both building and questioning its trends Through the last 40 years of computational research the humanities have appropriated and developed many techniques for doing their work computationally but only in the last ten years has the excess of computational capacity begun to bring central questions about the nature of the humanities to light <PERSON>David Berry</PERSON> and his colleagues sit on the cutting edges of these questions and their work will inform those debates for years to come <ORGANIZATION>Jeremy Hunsinger Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University</ORGANIZATION> <LOCATION>USA</LOCATION> This book introduces and debates important questions regarding the use of digital technologies in numerous academic approaches in humanities and social sciences These new media technologies are impacting across the disciplinary spectrum and pose challenges to traditional scholarship Dr <PERSON>Berry</PERSON> s book gives us a timely insight into these various challenges and into the kinds of new digital humanities that are emerging Clearly written and providing a wide range of examples and case studies it is an important contribution to the growing literature on digital humanities <ORGANIZATION>Christian De Cock University of Essex UK Show</ORGANIZATION> all Buy this book eBook 19 99 price for <LOCATION>USA</LOCATION> gross Buy eBook ISBN 978 0 230 37193 4 Digitally watermarked DRM free Included format PDF EPUB ebooks can be used on all reading devices Immediate eBook download after purchase Hardcover 169 99 price for <LOCATION>USA</LOCATION> Buy Hardcover ISBN 978 0 230 29264 2 Free shipping for individuals worldwide Usually dispatched within 3 to 5 business days Softcover 30 00 price for <LOCATION>USA</LOCATION> Buy Softcover ISBN 978 0 230 29265 9 Free shipping for individuals worldwide Usually dispatched within 3 to 5 business days <ORGANIZATION>FAQ Policy Services</ORGANIZATION> for this book Download High Resolution Cover image Loading Facebook Twitter LinkedIn <ORGANIZATION>Google Bibliographic Information Bibliographic Information Book Title Understanding Digital Humanities Editors</ORGANIZATION> D Berry Copyright 2012 Publisher <PERSON>Palgrave Macmillan</PERSON> <LOCATION>UK</LOCATION> Copyright Holder <PERSON>Palgrave Macmillan</PERSON> a division of <ORGANIZATION>Macmillan Publishers Limited</ORGANIZATION> eBook ISBN 978 0 230 37193 4 DOI 10 1057 9780230371934 Hardcover ISBN 978 0 230 29264 2 Softcover ISBN 978 0 230 29265 9 Edition Number 1 Number of Pages XVIII 318 Topics Computers and Society CLOSE PAGE 1 image PAGE 2 image Help with Accessibility Contacting editors Contacting sales reps eBook collections Help overview Rights and permissions <ORGANIZATION>Newsletter Information for Affiliates Authors Book</ORGANIZATION> reviewers Booksellers Customers Journalists Lecturers Librarians Other sites and products <ORGANIZATION>Macmillan Education Palgrave Australia Palgrave Higher Education Palgrave Journals Springer Link Springer Nature Palgrave Macmillan</ORGANIZATION> publishes journals monographs and reference books in print and online About Us Springer Nature Terms of usePrivacy PolicyCookies Policy JavaScript is currently disabled this site works much better if you enable JavaScript in your browser</ner>
