<ner>Skip to main content bookmark image Main menu Home About SIGs Publications Conference Awards Committees News Resources ADHO image ADHO logo Membership options Our Mission The <ORGANIZATION>Alliance of Digital Humanities Organizations ADHO</ORGANIZATION> promotes and supports digital research and teaching across all arts and humanities disciplines acting as a community based advisory force and supporting excellence in research publication collaboration and training The following organizations are current members of ADHO The <ORGANIZATION>European Association for Digital Humanities EADH Association for Computers and the Humanities ACH Canadian Society for Digital Humanities Soci</ORGANIZATION> t canadienne des humanit s num riques <ORGANIZATION>CSDH SCHN centerNet Australasian Association for Digital Humanities aaDH Japanese Association for Digital Humanites JADH Humanistica L association</ORGANIZATION> francophone des humanit s num riques digitales Humanistica News Apply Now for ADHO s <ORGANIZATION>Travel Bursaries</ORGANIZATION> for DH2018 The <ORGANIZATION>Alliance of Digital Humanities Organisations ADHO</ORGANIZATION> makes bursary awards to 14 or more students and young scholars who have submissions accepted for presentation at the annual <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> international conference These awards are to encourage new contributions to scholarship in the digital humanities from our diverse global constituency and to involve new participants in the application of information technology in humanities research Paper poster and panel submissions qualify for consideration authored or co authored by an applicant Read more Implementation Committee Proposed Governance Scenarios available for public comment As part of ADHO s official change to the new structure the <ORGANIZATION>Implementation Committee IC</ORGANIZATION> has already suggested a draft roadmap and earlier last month has published the Proposed Financial Scenarios both open for public comment Read more image Subscribe to ADHO news Follow us on <ORGANIZATION>Google Facebook Twitter YouTube Event Calendar Search</ORGANIZATION> form Search Current Issue of DHCommons Journal From Documents to Structured Data First Milestones of the <PERSON>Garzoni</PERSON> GO DH Translation Toolkit Creating a <ORGANIZATION>Digital Community Radio Station</ORGANIZATION> in an informal <LOCATION>Refugee Camp</LOCATION> in <ORGANIZATION>Calais France Advance Issue of Digital Scholarship</ORGANIZATION> in the Humanities formerly LLC Attesting similarity Supporting the organization and study of art image collections with computer vision Rho grams and rho sets Significant links in the web of words <PERSON>Christopher Marlowe</PERSON> Hype and <ORGANIZATION>Hoax Advance Issue of Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> Quarterly DHQ Introducci n de los editoresEditors Introduction <PERSON>Cartograf</PERSON> as de la sociedad redCartographies of the <ORGANIZATION>Network Society Laboratorios</ORGANIZATION> ciudadanos y humanidades digitalesCitizen Laboratories and <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities Geograf</ORGANIZATION> as digitales Iluminando las relaciones espaciales en una colecci n de blogs literariosDigital Geographies Illuminating Spatial Relationships in a Collection of Literary Blogs Retorno a trazos de mil historiasA Return to the Traces of a Thousand Stories image ADHO logo ADHO Constituent Organizations The <ORGANIZATION>European Association for Digital Humanities EADH Association for Computers and the Humanities ACH Canadian Society for Digital Humanities Soci</ORGANIZATION> t canadienne des humanit s num riques <ORGANIZATION>CSDH SCHN centerNet Australasian Association for Digital Humanities aaDH Japanese Association for Digital Humanities JADH Humanistica L association</ORGANIZATION> francophone des humanit s num riques digitales <ORGANIZATION>Humanistica Contact Contact</ORGANIZATION> form Email web digitalhumanities org <ORGANIZATION>Google Facebook Twitter YouTube</ORGANIZATION> Events Calendar image Creative Commons Attribution License This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3 0 Unported License</ner>
