<ner>Home About By Image By Work Sign Up Sign In Email Password Remember me Forgot your password <ORGANIZATION>Emily Dickinson Archive</ORGANIZATION> makes high resolution images of <PERSON>Dickinson</PERSON> s surviving manuscripts available in open access and provides readers with a website through which they can view images of manuscripts held in multiple libraries and archives This first phase of the <ORGANIZATION>EDA</ORGANIZATION> includes images for the corpus of poems identified in The Poems of Emily Dickinson Variorum Edition edited by <ORGANIZATION>R W Franklin Cambridge Belknap Press</ORGANIZATION> of the <ORGANIZATION>Harvard University Press</ORGANIZATION> 1998 Read more <PERSON>Emily Dickinson</PERSON> 1830 1886 was well known as a poet to the many correspondents with whom she shared her manuscript writings Only a handful of her poems appeared in print during her lifetime however and none under her own name those few poems were sent to publishers by friends and she did not have an opportunity to review them before they were printed At her death in 1886 <PERSON>Dickinson</PERSON> left behind a wealth of writings that had never been printed hundreds of manuscript poems in her personal effects and hundreds more poems and letters sent to her correspondents we will never know exactly how many since some were destroyed or lost Many poems were preserved in multiple manuscript versions or with variant choices for words within a single poem without indication of whether a particular version or word choice was <PERSON>Dickinson</PERSON> s final intention <PERSON>Dickinson</PERSON> did not leave behind explicit instructions about how or even whether her manuscripts should be reproduced in print Her first editors reflecting the conventions of print and the traditions of late nineteenth century poetry sometimes changed her words and regularized her grammar syntax and rhyme as well as punctuation and capitalization They added titles to poems sometimes deleted entire stanzas and did not convey <PERSON>Dickinson</PERSON> s variant word choices They transcribed poems as metrical stanzas rather than replicating the visual arrangement of words exactly as found in <PERSON>Dickinson</PERSON> s manuscripts While their methods differed from modern editorial principles it was thanks to their efforts that <PERSON>Dickinson</PERSON> s work reached a wide public audience Since those first editorial transcriptions there has been debate about the importance of the manuscript page to our understanding of <PERSON>Dickinson</PERSON> s poetry Some critics argue that <PERSON>Dickinson</PERSON> s manuscript pages are mediated primarily by metrical and stanzaic conventions Other critics assert that her manuscript page with its spaces between words lines and stanzas its ambiguous capitalization and idiosyncratic punctuation represents <PERSON>Dickinson</PERSON> s radical revision of these conventions Some critics believe that <PERSON>Dickinson</PERSON> over the course of her writing life came to conceive of her poems as fully realized in their manuscript condition rather than as drafts designed with the printed page in mind This range of critical opinion provides a compelling reason to make access to images of those manuscript pages more easily and widely available <PERSON>Dickinson</PERSON> s manuscript page is the focus of <PERSON>Emily Dickinson</PERSON> Archive A search of the full text or first line from a poem produces images of all the manuscript versions of the poem where multiple versions survive Readers have the option of selecting from a historical array of editors transcriptions of these autograph materials into printed form and of viewing a transcription by physical line or by poetic line depending upon the editor s choice Additionally readers can use the site s tools to create their own transcriptions annotate images or by zooming in look closely at <PERSON>Dickinson</PERSON> s handwriting Search for Manuscript Images Search for Search Search options Edition All Single Hound 1914 Poems 1896 Poems 1890 Poems 1891 Johnson Poems 1955 Franklin Variorum 1998 Search Within Work Text Title First Line Work Metadata image Browse for Manuscript Images Browse for Manuscript ImagesView images by library collection View by first line date recipient or edition image Lexicon LexiconFind definitions from <PERSON>Dickinson</PERSON> s dictionary and find poems using lexicon words Partners amp Credits Copyright amp Terms of Use Privacy Contact Us</ner>
