<ner>NYTimes com no longer supports Internet Explorer 9 or earlier Please upgrade your browser LEARN MORE Sections Home Search Skip to content Skip to navigation View mobile version The <ORGANIZATION>New York Times</ORGANIZATION> Books In 500 Billion Words New Window on Culture Search Subscribe Now Log In 0 Settings Close search Site Search Navigation Search NYTimes com Clear this text input Go Loading See next articles See previous articles Site Navigation Site Mobile Navigation Advertisement Supported by <ORGANIZATION>Books Humanities</ORGANIZATION> 2 0 In 500 Billion Words New Window on Culture By <ORGANIZATION>PATRICIA COHENDEC</ORGANIZATION> 16 2010 Continue reading the main story Share This Page Continue reading the main story With little fanfare <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> has made a mammoth database culled from nearly 5 2 million digitized books available to the public for free downloads and online searches opening a new landscape of possibilities for research and education in the humanities The digital storehouse which comprises words and short phrases as well as a year by year count of how often they appear represents the first time a data set of this magnitude and searching tools are at the disposal of Ph D s middle school students and anyone else who likes to spend time in front of a small screen It consists of the 500 billion words contained in books published between 1500 and 2008 in English French Spanish German Chinese and Russian The intended audience is scholarly but a simple online tool allows anyone with a computer to plug in a string of up to five words and see a graph that charts the phrase s use over time a diversion that can quickly become as addictive as the habit forming game Angry Birds With a click you can see that women in comparison with men is rarely mentioned until the early 1970s when feminism gained a foothold The lines eventually cross paths about 1986 Advertisement Continue reading the main story You can also learn that <PERSON>Mickey Mouse</PERSON> and <PERSON>Marilyn Monroe</PERSON> don t get nearly as much attention in print as <PERSON>Jimmy Carter</PERSON> compare the many more references in English than in Chinese to <LOCATION>Tiananmen Square</LOCATION> after 1989 or follow the ascent of grilling from the late 1990s until it outpaced roasting and frying in 2004 Continue reading the main story Advertisement Continue reading the main story The goal is to give an 8 year old the ability to browse cultural trends throughout history as recorded in books said <PERSON>Erez Lieberman Aiden</PERSON> a junior fellow at the Society of Fellows at <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> Mr <PERSON>Lieberman Aiden</PERSON> and <PERSON>Jean Baptiste Michel</PERSON> a postdoctoral fellow at <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> assembled the data set with <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> and spearheaded a research project to demonstrate how vast digital databases can transform our understanding of language culture and the flow of ideas Their study to be published in the journal Science on Friday offers a tantalizing taste of the rich buffet of research opportunities now open to literature history and other liberal arts professors who may have previously avoided quantitative analysis Science is taking the unusual step of making the paper available online to nonsubscribers We wanted to show what becomes possible when you apply very high turbo data analysis to questions in the humanities said Mr <PERSON>Lieberman Aiden</PERSON> whose expertise is in applied mathematics and genomics He called the method culturomics Photo image <PERSON>Jean Baptiste Michel</PERSON> and <PERSON>Erez Lieberman</PERSON> are co authors of a Science paper coming about culturomics <ORGANIZATION>Credit Kris Snibbe Harvard University</ORGANIZATION> The data set can be downloaded and users can build their own search tools Working with a version of the data set that included Hebrew and started in 1800 the researchers measured the endurance of fame finding that written references to celebrities faded twice as quickly in the mid 20th century as they did in the early 19th In the future everyone will be famous for 7 5 minutes they write Looking at inventions they found technological advances took on average 66 years to be adopted by the larger culture in the early 1800s and only 27 years between 1880 and 1920 They tracked the way eccentric English verbs that did not add ed at the end for past tense i e learnt evolved to conform to the common pattern learned They figured that the English lexicon has grown by 70 percent to more than a million words in the last 50 years and they demonstrated how dictionaries could be updated more rapidly by pinpointing newly popular words and obsolete ones <PERSON>Steven Pinker</PERSON> a linguist at <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> who collaborated on the Science paper s section about language evolution has been studying changes in grammar and past tense forms for 20 years Advertisement Continue reading the main story When I saw they had this database I was quite energized he said There is so much ignorance We ve had to speculate what might have happened to the language The information about verb changes makes the results more convincing and more complete Mr <PERSON>Pinker</PERSON> added What we report in this paper is just the beginning Newsletter Sign Up Continue reading the main story Please verify you re not a robot by clicking the box Invalid email address Please re enter You must select a newsletter to subscribe to Sign Up You agree to receive occasional updates and special offers for The <ORGANIZATION>New York Times</ORGANIZATION> s products and services Thank you for subscribing An error has occurred Please try again later You are already subscribed to this email View all <ORGANIZATION>New York Times</ORGANIZATION> newsletters See Sample Manage Email Preferences Not you Privacy Policy Opt out or contact us anytime Despite the frequent resistance to quantitative analysis in some corners of the humanities Mr <PERSON>Pinker</PERSON> said he was confident that the use of this and similar tools would become universal Reactions from humanities scholars who quickly reviewed the article were more muted In general it s a great thing to have <PERSON>Louis Menand</PERSON> an English professor at <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> said particularly for linguists But he warned that in the realm of cultural history obviously some of the claims are a little exaggerated He was also troubled that among the paper s 13 named authors there was not a single humanist involved There s not even a historian of the book connected to the project Mr <PERSON>Menand</PERSON> noted <PERSON>Alan Brinkley</PERSON> the former provost at <ORGANIZATION>Columbia</ORGANIZATION> and a professor of American history said it was too early to tell what the impact of word and phrase searches would be I could imagine lots of interesting uses I just don t know enough about what they re trying to do statistically he said Photo image Credit The <ORGANIZATION>New York Times Aware</ORGANIZATION> of concerns raised by humanists that the essence of their art is a search for meaning Mr <PERSON>Michel</PERSON> and Mr <PERSON>Lieberman Aiden</PERSON> emphasized that culturomics simply provided information Interpretation remains essential I don t want humanists to accept any specific claims we re just throwing a lot of interesting pieces on the table Mr <PERSON>Lieberman Aiden</PERSON> said The question is Are you willing to examine this data Mr <PERSON>Michel</PERSON> and Mr <PERSON>Lieberman Aiden</PERSON> first started their research in 2004 on irregular verbs <ORGANIZATION>Google Books</ORGANIZATION> did not exist then and they had to scrutinize stacks of <ORGANIZATION>Anglo Saxon</ORGANIZATION> texts page by page The process took 18 months We were exhausted Mr <PERSON>Lieberman Aiden</PERSON> said That painstaking work was a total Hail <PERSON>Mary</PERSON> pass we could have collected this data set and proved nothing Advertisement Continue reading the main story Then they read about <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> s plan to create a digital library and store of every book ever published and recognized that it could revolutionize their research They approached <PERSON>Peter Norvig</PERSON> the director of research at <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> about using the collection to do statistical analyses He realized this was a great opportunity for science and for <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> Mr <PERSON>Michel</PERSON> said We spent the next four years dealing with the many many complicated issues that arose including legal complications and computational constraints A proposed class action settlement pertaining to copyright and compensation brought by writers and publishers as a result of <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> s digitization plans is pending in the courts <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> says the culturomics project raises no copyright issue because the books themselves or even sections of them cannot be read So far <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> has scanned more than 11 percent of the entire corpus of published books about two trillion words The data analyzed in the paper contains about 4 percent of the corpus The warehouse of words makes it possible to analyze cultural influences statistically in a way previously not possible Cultural references tend to appear in print much less frequently than everyday words said Mr <PERSON>Michel</PERSON> whose expertise is in applied math and systems biology An accurate picture needs a huge sample Checking if sasquatch has infiltrated the culture requires a supply of at least a billion words a year he said As for culturomics In 20 years type the word into an updated version of the database and see what happens Humanities 2 0 Articles in this series examine how digital tools are changing scholarship in history literature and the arts A version of this article appears in print on December 17 2010 on Page A3 of the <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> edition with the headline HUMANITIES 2 0 In 500 Billion Words New Window on Culture Order Reprints Today s Paper Subscribe Continue reading the main story We re interested in your feedback on this page Tell us what you think Related Coverage image HUMANITIES 2 0 Victorian Literature Statistically Analyzed With New Process <ORGANIZATION>DEC</ORGANIZATION> 3 2010 Related Coverage HUMANITIES 2 0 Victorian Literature Statistically Analyzed With New Process DEC 3 2010 image What s Next Loading Go to Home Page Site Index The <ORGANIZATION>New York Times Site Index Navigation News World U S Politics N Y Business Tech Science Health Sports Education Obituaries Today</ORGANIZATION> s Paper Corrections Opinion Today s Opinion Op Ed Columnists Editorials Op Ed Contributors Letters Sunday Review Video Opinion Arts Today s Arts Art amp Design Books Dance Movies Music N Y <ORGANIZATION>C Events Guide Television Theater Video Arts Living Automobiles Crossword Food Education Fashion amp Style Health Jobs Magazine N Y C Events Guide Real Estate T Magazine Travel Weddings amp Celebrations Listings amp More Reader Center Classifieds Tools amp Services N Y C Events Guide Multimedia</ORGANIZATION> Photography Video NYT Store Times Journeys Subscribe Manage My Account NYTCo Subscribe Subscribe Home Delivery Digital Subscriptions Crossword Email Newsletters Alerts Gift Subscriptions Group Subscriptions Education Rate Mobile Applications Replica Edition Site Information Navigation 2018 The <ORGANIZATION>New York Times Company Home</ORGANIZATION> Search Accessibility concerns Email us at accessibility nytimes com We would love to hear from you Contact Us Work With Us Advertise Your Ad Choices Privacy Terms of Service Terms of Sale Site Information Navigation Site Map Help Site Feedback Subscriptions</ner>
