<ner>Skip to main content image Science Logo Home News Journals Topics Careers Search Search Toggle menu Search Search Log in My account Contact Us image Magazine Cover Become a member Renew my subscription Sign up for newsletters image Science Logo image <ORGANIZATION>AAAS Logo Facebook Twitter Google</ORGANIZATION> Rss Authors Members Librarians Advertisers Home Recent Videos Latest Podcasts Photo Galleries Dance Your Ph D Contest Data Stories Contest News Latest News ScienceInsider ScienceShots Sifter From the <ORGANIZATION>Magazine About News Quizzes Journals Science Science Advances Science Immunology Science Robotics Science Signaling Science Translational Medicine Science Partner Journals Topics All Topics Special Issues Custom Publishing Careers Articles Find Jobs Career Resources Forum For Employers Employer Profiles Graduate Programs Booklets Advertising Features About Careers Search Search</ORGANIZATION> share <ORGANIZATION>Research Article Quantitative Analysis of Culture Using Millions of Digitized Books Jean Baptiste Michel1</ORGANIZATION> 2 3 4 <ORGANIZATION>Yuan Kui Shen5 Aviva</ORGANIZATION> P Aiden6 Adrian Veres7 <PERSON>Matthew K</PERSON> Gray8 The <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> Books Team8 <PERSON>Joseph P Pickett9 Dale Hoiberg10 Dan Clancy8 Peter Norvig8 Jon Orwant8 Steven Pinker4 Martin</PERSON> A Nowak1 11 12 and <PERSON>Erez Lieberman</PERSON> Aiden1 12 13 14 15 16 bookmark aff 1 1Program for <ORGANIZATION>Evolutionary Dynamics Harvard University Cambridge MA 02138 USA</ORGANIZATION> bookmark aff 2 2Institute for <ORGANIZATION>Quantitative Social Sciences Harvard University Cambridge MA 02138 USA</ORGANIZATION> bookmark aff 3 <ORGANIZATION>3Department of Psychology Harvard University Cambridge MA 02138 USA</ORGANIZATION> bookmark aff 4 4Department of <ORGANIZATION>Systems Biology Harvard Medical School Boston MA 02115 USA</ORGANIZATION> bookmark aff 5 <ORGANIZATION>5Computer Science and Artificial Intelligence Laboratory MIT Cambridge MA</ORGANIZATION> 02139 <LOCATION>USA</LOCATION> bookmark aff 6 <ORGANIZATION>6Harvard Medical School Boston MA 02115 USA</ORGANIZATION> bookmark aff 7 <ORGANIZATION>7Harvard College Cambridge MA</ORGANIZATION> 02138 <LOCATION>USA</LOCATION> bookmark aff 8 <ORGANIZATION>8Google Inc Mountain View CA</ORGANIZATION> 94043 <LOCATION>USA</LOCATION> bookmark aff 9 <ORGANIZATION>9Houghton Mifflin Harcourt Boston MA 02116 USA</ORGANIZATION> bookmark aff 10 <ORGANIZATION>10Encyclopaedia Britannica Inc Chicago IL</ORGANIZATION> 60654 <LOCATION>USA</LOCATION> bookmark aff 11 11Department of Organismic and <ORGANIZATION>Evolutionary Biology Harvard University Cambridge MA 02138 USA</ORGANIZATION> bookmark aff 12 12Department of <ORGANIZATION>Mathematics Harvard University Cambridge MA 02138 USA</ORGANIZATION> bookmark aff 13 <ORGANIZATION>13Broad Institute of Harvard</ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION>MIT Harvard University Cambridge MA 02138 USA</ORGANIZATION> bookmark aff 14 14School of Engineering and <ORGANIZATION>Applied Sciences Harvard University Cambridge MA 02138 USA</ORGANIZATION> bookmark aff 15 <ORGANIZATION>15Harvard Society of Fellows Harvard University Cambridge MA 02138 USA</ORGANIZATION> bookmark aff 16 16Laboratory at <ORGANIZATION>Large Harvard University Cambridge MA</ORGANIZATION> 02138 USA To whom correspondence should be addressed E mail jb michel at gmail com J B M erez at erez com E A These authors contributed equally to this work See allHide authors and affiliations Science 16 Dec 2010 1199644 DOI 10 1126 science 1199644 <ORGANIZATION>Jean Baptiste Michel Find</ORGANIZATION> this author on <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> Scholar Find this author on PubMed Search for this author on this site Yuan Kui Shen Find this author on <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> Scholar Find this author on PubMed Search for this author on this site Aviva P Aiden Find this author on <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> Scholar Find this author on PubMed Search for this author on this site Adrian Veres Find this author on <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> Scholar Find this author on PubMed Search for this author on this site Matthew K Gray Find this author on <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> Scholar Find this author on PubMed Search for this author on this site <PERSON>Joseph</PERSON> P Pickett Find this author on <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> Scholar Find this author on PubMed Search for this author on this site Dale Hoiberg Find this author on <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> Scholar Find this author on PubMed Search for this author on this site Dan Clancy Find this author on <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> Scholar Find this author on PubMed Search for this author on this site Peter Norvig Find this author on <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> Scholar Find this author on PubMed Search for this author on this site Jon Orwant Find this author on <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> Scholar Find this author on PubMed Search for this author on this site Steven Pinker Find this author on <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> Scholar Find this author on PubMed Search for this author on this site Martin A Nowak Find this author on <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> Scholar Find this author on PubMed Search for this author on this site Erez Lieberman Aiden Find this author on <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> Scholar Find this author on PubMed Search for this author on this site Article Figures amp Data Info amp Metrics eLetters PDF image Loading Abstract We constructed a corpus of digitized texts containing about 4 of all books ever printed Analysis of this corpus enables us to investigate cultural trends quantitatively We survey the vast terrain of culturomics focusing on linguistic and cultural phenomena that were reflected in the English language between 1800 and 2000 We show how this approach can provide insights about fields as diverse as lexicography the evolution of grammar collective memory the adoption of technology the pursuit of fame censorship and historical epidemiology Culturomics extends the boundaries of rigorous quantitative inquiry to a wide array of new phenomena spanning the social sciences and the humanities Article Tools Email Thank you for your interest in spreading the word about Science NOTE We only request your email address so that the person you are recommending the page to knows that you wanted them to see it and that it is not junk mail We do not capture any email address Your Email Your Name Send To Enter multiple addresses on separate lines or separate them with commas You are going to email the following Quantitative Analysis of Culture Using Millions of Digitized Books Message Subject Your Name has forwarded a page to you from Science Message Body Your Name thought you would like to see this page from the Science web site Your Personal Message Send Message Print Save to my folders User Name Password Remember my user name amp password Submit Alerts Please log in to add an alert for this article Username Enter your Sciencemag org username Password Enter the password that accompanies your username Log in Citation tools Quantitative Analysis of Culture Using Millions of Digitized Books By <PERSON>Jean Baptiste Michel Yuan Kui Shen Aviva P Aiden Adrian Veres Matthew K Gray</PERSON> The <ORGANIZATION>Google Books Team Joseph</ORGANIZATION> P <PERSON>Pickett Dale Hoiberg Dan Clancy Peter Norvig Jon Orwant Steven Pinker Martin</PERSON> A Nowak Erez <PERSON>Lieberman Aiden</PERSON> Published Online16 Dec 2010 DOI 10 1126 science 1199644 Citation Manager Formats BibTeX Bookends EasyBib EndNote tagged EndNote 8 xml Medlars Mendeley Papers RefWorks Tagged Ref Manager RIS Zotero Share Quantitative Analysis of Culture Using Millions of Digitized Books By <PERSON>Jean Baptiste Michel Yuan Kui Shen Aviva P Aiden Adrian Veres Matthew K Gray</PERSON> The <ORGANIZATION>Google Books Team Joseph</ORGANIZATION> P <PERSON>Pickett Dale Hoiberg Dan Clancy Peter Norvig Jon Orwant Steven Pinker Martin</PERSON> A Nowak Erez <PERSON>Lieberman Aiden</PERSON> Published Online16 Dec 2010 DOI 10 1126 science 1199644 Share This Article Copy image CiteULike logo image Connotea logo image del icio us logo image Digg logo image <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> logo image <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> logo image Mendeley logo image <LOCATION>Reddit</LOCATION> logo image Twitter logo Related Content Similar Articles in Citing Articles in Science 6 April 2018 Vol 360 Issue 6384 image Magazine Cover Feature A delicate balance Education Testing international education assessments Field Research Revisiting a tragedy at <LOCATION>Gombe</LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION>SCI COMMUN News</ORGANIZATION> at a glance Pollution Microplastics research from sink to source Working Life No one is an island Table of <ORGANIZATION>Contents About us Journals Leadership Team</ORGANIZATION> members Work at <ORGANIZATION>AAAS Advertise Advertising</ORGANIZATION> kits Custom publishing For subscribers Site license info For members International Chinese Japanese Help Access amp subscriptions Order a Single Issue Reprints amp permissions Contact us Accessibility Stay Connected Facebook Twitter GooglePlus RSS Feeds image Science AAAS 2018 American Association for the Advancement of Science All rights reserved <ORGANIZATION>AAAS</ORGANIZATION> is a partner of HINARI AGORA OARE CHORUS CLOCKSS CrossRef and COUNTER Science ISSN 1095 9203 Terms of Service Privacy Policy Contact Us</ner>
