<ner>Skip to main content image <ORGANIZATION>National Endowment for the Humanities logo Secondary Menu Events Humanities Magazine Staff Directory Search</ORGANIZATION> this site <ORGANIZATION>YouTube Twitter Facebook</ORGANIZATION> Instagram Snapchat NEH Gov Delivery Main Menu Home About NEH Grants Divisions and Offices News Explore You are here Home Divisions and <ORGANIZATION>Offices Office of Digital Humanities Office of Digital Humanities Grant News Grant Announcement for Humanities High Performance Computing Program</ORGANIZATION> December 1 2008 By <PERSON>Brett Bobley</PERSON> image PRINT PRINT Email On November 18 I gave a presentation at the Supercomputing 2008 conference in <LOCATION>Austin Texas</LOCATION> and announced the winners of the <ORGANIZATION>NEH Department of Energy Humanities High Performance Computing</ORGANIZATION> program These grants provide computer time on <ORGANIZATION>DOE</ORGANIZATION> machines at the <ORGANIZATION>National Energy Research Scientific Computing Center NERSC</ORGANIZATION> at <ORGANIZATION>DOE s Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory</ORGANIZATION> as well as training and support to enable scholars to take full advantage of those resources in accordance with the DOE High End Computing Revitalization Act of 2004 P L 108 423 which authorized the Department to provide for sustained access by the research community in the <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> to high end computing systems and to Leadership Systems including provision of technical support for users of such systems The grants announced were The Perseus Digital Library at <ORGANIZATION>Tufts University</ORGANIZATION> for its project Large Scale Learning and the Automatic Analysis of Historical Texts The Perseus project will be using advanced computational linguistic technologies to experiment with the analysis of ancient texts for the study of classics and other fields The <ORGANIZATION>University of California San Diego</ORGANIZATION> for its project Visualizing Patterns in Databases of Cultural Images and <ORGANIZATION>Video UC San Diego</ORGANIZATION> will be creating computerized visualizations of large databases of digitized cultural heritage materials and performing statistical analyses on the data to discover new ways of studying art and culture The <ORGANIZATION>Institute for Advanced Technology</ORGANIZATION> in the Humanities at the <ORGANIZATION>University of Virginia</ORGANIZATION> for its project <ORGANIZATION>High Performance Computing for Processing and Analysis of Digitized</ORGANIZATION> 3 <ORGANIZATION>D Models of Cultural Heritage IATH</ORGANIZATION> will process previously acquired raw datasets of culturally valuable objects such as artistic statuary archaeological artifacts and historical architecture in order to create highly accurate 3 D models for the study of art and architecture I was very impressed with the Supercomputing 2008 conference There was a huge turnout nearly 10 000 attendees I believe <PERSON>Kevin Franklin</PERSON> from I CHASS was kind enough to introduce me to a number of people from various supercomputing centers that were in attendance I must say that I was happy to hear so many people talking about the humanities and how high performance computing might be a useful tool for some of the work that humanists do In fact after my talk the <ORGANIZATION>NCSA National Center for Supercomputing Applications</ORGANIZATION> at the <ORGANIZATION>University of Illinois</ORGANIZATION> announced that they will also be making one million hours available for the humanities There seems to be a lot of excitement in this space Keywords high performance computing image PRINT PRINT Email Divisions and <ORGANIZATION>Offices Home Education Programs Preservation and Access Public Programs Research Programs Federal State Partnership Challenge Grants Office of Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> About ODH ODH Staff Featured Projects Grant News In the Field Institutes ODH Resources Resource Library HHPC Subscribe Keep up to date with Division news <ORGANIZATION>Grant Programs Current Passed Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> Advancement Grants Deadline June 5 2018 Humanities Open Book Program Deadline September 26 2018 Institutes for Advanced Topics in the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> Deadline March 12 2019 View All Digging Into Data Challenge Deadline June 29 2016 View All Contact Information Email odh neh gov <ORGANIZATION>Edsitement Standing Together Chronicling America Created Equal About NEH Contact NEH National Council on the Humanities State Humanities</ORGANIZATION> Councils Awards and Honors Budget Performance and Legal Information Plain Writing at <ORGANIZATION>NEH Office of the Inspector General Equal Employment Opportunities Career</ORGANIZATION> Opportunities Website Disclaimers Grants Search for a Grant Not sure what to do Let us help you Become a Peer Reviewer Manage Your Grant The Application Review Process Brand Materials Divisions and <ORGANIZATION>Offices Education Programs Preservation and Access Public Programs Research Programs Federal State Partnership Office of Challenge Grants Office of Digital Humanities News Press Releases News Archive NEH</ORGANIZATION> in the <ORGANIZATION>News NEH Impact Reports Events Humanities Back Issues Subscribe Magazine Staff Explore Contact Us National Endowment</ORGANIZATION> for the Humanities 400 <ORGANIZATION>7th Street SW Washington DC</ORGANIZATION> 20506 General Information 1 800 NEH 1121 202 606 8400 Federal Relay TTY Users 800 877 8399 questions at neh dot gov Connect With Us <ORGANIZATION>YouTube Twitter Facebook NEH Social Media</ORGANIZATION> www neh gov FOIA No Fear Act Office of the Inspector General Accessibility Privacy Policy and Terms of Use Website Disclaimers Open Gov Plain Writing at <ORGANIZATION>NEH</ORGANIZATION></ner>
