<ner><ORGANIZATION>University of Illinois Press Facebook Page Instagram</ORGANIZATION> span gt UIP Blog Twitter Page Join Our Email List Shopping Cart Home About Us Mission Statement History of the Press Staff Directory Submission Guidelines Faculty Board Privacy Policy Annual Report Employment Books Browse Books Browse by title Browse by author Browse by subject Browse by series Browse by catalog Browse by course adoption Ordering For Instructors For Authors For the <ORGANIZATION>Media Rights amp Permissions</ORGANIZATION> RSS Feeds Events Calendar Recent Award Winners E Books E Book Ordering Browse E Books Browse by title Browse by author Browse by subject Browse by series E Book Heritage Projects Women in Print series Journals Browse Journals Subscribe Journals Online News Advertise Contact Publish Your Journal Calls for Papers Common Threads For Authors Welcome start here Submit a Proposal Submit a Manuscript for Review Preparing the Final Materials Marketing Your Book with Us Contact Staff Directory Book Orders Book Publicity review copies author interviews etc Desk Exam Copy Requests Journals Contacts Rights and <ORGANIZATION>Permissions Information for Authors General Inquiries Support</ORGANIZATION> our Press Nothing Cloth 95 00 978 0 252 03641 5 Paper 27 00 978 0 252 07820 0 <ORGANIZATION>Ebook</ORGANIZATION> 24 30 978 0 252 09344 9 Author <PERSON>Stephen Ramsay</PERSON> Pub Date December 2011 Pages 112 pages Dimensions 6 x 9 in Illustrations 3 line drawings 3 tables Cloth edition is unjacketed Series Topics in the Digital Humanities Critical Theory Literary Studies See all Subjects Table of Contents Exam and Desk Copies Rights and Permissions Media Review Copies Alternate Format Request Print a Flyer image Cover for ramsay Reading Machines Toward an Algorithmic Criticism Click for larger image Close Previewx image Ebook Information Reading Machines Toward an Algorithmic Criticism Rethinking digital literary criticism by situating computational work within the broader context of the humanities Besides familiar and now commonplace tasks that computers do all the time what else are they capable of <PERSON>Stephen Ramsay</PERSON> s intriguing study of computational text analysis examines how computers can be used as reading machines to open up entirely new possibilities for literary critics Computer based text analysis has been employed for the past several decades as a way of searching collating and indexing texts Despite this the digital revolution has not penetrated the core activity of literary studies interpretive analysis of written texts Computers can handle vast amounts of data allowing for the comparison of texts in ways that were previously too overwhelming for individuals but they may also assist in enhancing the entirely necessary role of subjectivity in critical interpretation <ORGANIZATION>Reading Machines</ORGANIZATION> discusses the importance of this new form of text analysis conducted with the assistance of computers <PERSON>Ramsay</PERSON> suggests that the rigidity of computation can be enlisted by intuition subjectivity and play This significant book by the progenitor o the term algorithmic criticism packs a lot into its slender binding Pithy readable and full of striking turns of phrase it reaches for a broader audience for the debates over the application of computers to the critical enterprise Literary and Linguistic Computing Anchored by his incisive prescient and influential essay Toward an Algorithmic Criticism <PERSON>Stephen Ramsay</PERSON> s book is filled with trenchant critical arguments and paradigmatic examples that traverse contemporary literary computing to argue that doing technology is now not necessarily different from doing humanities it is in fact another humanities activity Human beings live work feel express and reflect Speech writing images and now text mining are ways of doing and understanding the literature of the human <PERSON>Ramsay</PERSON> makes his case to both digital humanities scholars and the broader audience of the humanities with a unique blend of technical authority and open ended accessible humanistic inquiry <PERSON>Alan Liu</PERSON> author of Local Transcendence Essays on Postmodern Historicism and the <ORGANIZATION>Database Reading Machines</ORGANIZATION> makes an important and provocative contribution to the fields of literary criticism and digital humanities With sound scholarship and lucid argumentation this book will stir up debate among both traditionalists and digital humanities scholars <PERSON>David L Hoover</PERSON> author of <ORGANIZATION>Stylistics Prospect</ORGANIZATION> and Retrospect <PERSON>Stephen Ramsay</PERSON> is an associate professor of English at the <ORGANIZATION>University of Nebraska</ORGANIZATION> and has written and lectured widely on subjects related to literary theory and software design for humanities To order online www press uillinois edu books catalog 75tms2pw9780252036415 html To order by phone 800 621 2736 <LOCATION>USA Canada</LOCATION> 773 702 7000 International Related Titles previous book next book image Reading Ronell Cover Reading Ronell Edited by <PERSON>Diane Davis</PERSON> image Eight Women Philosophers Cover Eight Women Philosophers Theory Politics and Feminism <PERSON>Jane Duran</PERSON> image Private Prisons in <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> Cover Private Prisons in <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> A Critical Race Perspective <PERSON>Michael A Hallett</PERSON> image Racial Blackness and the Discontinuity of Western Modernity Cover Racial Blackness and the Discontinuity of Western Modernity <PERSON>Lindon Barrett</PERSON> image Philosophy Crime and Criminology Cover Philosophy Crime and Criminology Edited by <PERSON>Bruce A Arrigo</PERSON> and <PERSON>Christopher R Williams</PERSON> image <ORGANIZATION>Democracy Inc Cover Democracy Inc</ORGANIZATION> The Press and Law in the Corporate Rationalization of the Public Sphere <PERSON>David S Allen</PERSON> image American Literary Realism Cover American Literary Realism Edited by <PERSON>Gary Scharnhorst</PERSON> image Dictations Cover Dictations On Haunted Writing <PERSON>Avital Ronell</PERSON> image Normative Theories of the Media Cover Normative Theories of the <ORGANIZATION>Media Journalism in Democratic Societies Clifford G Christians Theodore</ORGANIZATION> L <PERSON>Glasser Denis McQuail Kaarle Nordenstreng</PERSON> and <PERSON>Robert A White</PERSON> image Redesigning Women Cover Redesigning Women Television after the Network Era <ORGANIZATION>Amanda D Lotz University of Illinois</ORGANIZATION> Copyright 2018 by the <ORGANIZATION>Board of Trustees of the University of Illinois 1325 South Oak Street Champaign</ORGANIZATION> IL 61820 6903 217 333 0950 Privacy Policy Annual Report Website Feedback image Close Reading Machines ebook is available for immediate download from the following vendors <LOCATION>Amazon</LOCATION> com <PERSON>Barnes</PERSON> amp Noble Kobo Google Play</ner>
