<ner>digital humanities Q1026962 From Wikidata Jump to navigation search An area of scholarly activity at the intersection of computing or digital technologies and the disciplines of the humanities <ORGANIZATION>Digital</ORGANIZATION> humanities DH edit Language Label Description Also known as English digital humanities An area of scholarly activity at the intersection of computing or digital technologies and the disciplines of the humanities <ORGANIZATION>Digital</ORGANIZATION> humanities DH Statements instance of branch of science 0 references subclass of humanities 0 references Commons category <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> 0 references topic s main category <ORGANIZATION>Category Digital</ORGANIZATION> humanities 0 references Identifiers Freebase ID m 0b5yht 1 reference stated in Freebase Data Dumps publication date 28 October 2013 GND ID 1038714850 1 reference imported from German <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia Quora</ORGANIZATION> topic <ORGANIZATION>ID Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> 1 reference imported from Quora JSTOR topic ID digital humanities 0 references <ORGANIZATION>Library of Congress</ORGANIZATION> authority ID sh2008122106 0 references <ORGANIZATION>Sitelinks Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> 24 entries edit arwiki cawiki Humanitats digitals cywiki Dyniaethau digidol dewiki <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> enwiki <ORGANIZATION>Digital</ORGANIZATION> humanities eswiki Humanidades digitales euwiki Humanitate digitalak fiwiki Digitaaliset ihmistieteet frwiki Humanit s num riques hewiki huwiki Digit lis b lcs szet itwiki Informatica umanistica jawiki kowiki lawiki Humanitates digitales plwiki Humanistyka cyfrowa ruwiki shwiki slwiki Digitalna humanistika svwiki <ORGANIZATION>Digital</ORGANIZATION> humaniora tawiki thwiki viwiki Nh n v n s zhwiki Wikibooks 0 entries edit <ORGANIZATION>Wikinews</ORGANIZATION> 0 entries edit Wikiquote 0 entries edit <ORGANIZATION>Wikisource</ORGANIZATION> 0 entries edit <ORGANIZATION>Wikiversity</ORGANIZATION> 0 entries edit <ORGANIZATION>Wikivoyage</ORGANIZATION> 0 entries edit <ORGANIZATION>Wiktionary</ORGANIZATION> 0 entries edit Other sites 0 entries edit image Retrieved from https www wikidata org w index php title Q1026962 amp oldid 656004725 Navigation menu Personal tools English Not logged in Talk Contributions Create account Log in Namespaces Item Discussion Variants Views Read View history More Search Navigation Main page Community portal Project chat Create a new item Recent changes Random item Query Service Nearby Help Donate Print export Download as PDF Tools What links here Related changes Special pages Permanent link Page information Concept URI Cite this page This page was last edited on 24 March 2018 at 17 04 All structured data from the main and property namespace is available under the Creative Commons CC0 License text in the other namespaces is available under the Creative Commons Attribution ShareAlike License additional terms may apply By using this site you agree to the Terms of Use and Privacy Policy Privacy policy About Wikidata Disclaimers Developers Cookie statement Mobile view Data access image <ORGANIZATION>Wikimedia Foundation</ORGANIZATION> image Powered by <PERSON>MediaWiki</PERSON></ner>
