<ner>Advanced Search About amp Contact Browse Subjects Catalogs eBooks <ORGANIZATION>News Order Rights Permissions Cart</ORGANIZATION> 0 <ORGANIZATION>Resources for Authors Booksellers</ORGANIZATION> amp Librarians Educators Journalists Readers <PERSON>Emily Dickinson</PERSON> From Fascicle to Open Access <PERSON>Emily Dickinson</PERSON> 1830 1886 bequeathed to us nearly 1 800 poems in some passionate years she wrote almost a poem a day Like all capacious writers she baffles complete understanding to enter her poetics entirely a reader would have to know by heart and by ear all her poems Ideally too her reader should possess the King <PERSON>James Bible</PERSON> as firmly as she did and should have read the poetry of the English past as fervently as she had Yet readers worldwide even when they have lacked her background have flocked to her poems responding to her candor her grief and her wit <PERSON>Helen Vendler Dickinson</PERSON> Selected Poems and Commentaries image <PERSON>Emily Dickinson</PERSON> s writing table and chair on display in the <LOCATION>Houghton Library</LOCATION> s <PERSON>Dickinson Room Emily Dickinson</PERSON> s writing table and chair on display in the <LOCATION>Houghton Library</LOCATION> s Dickinson Room In 1950 <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> s <ORGANIZATION>Houghton Library</ORGANIZATION> received its world renowned <PERSON>Dickinson</PERSON> Collection as a gift from the poet s heirs together with publication rights Soon thereafter the well known literary historian <PERSON>Thomas H Johnson</PERSON> was chosen as editor and the three volume Poems of <PERSON>Emily Dickinson</PERSON> was published by <ORGANIZATION>Harvard University Press</ORGANIZATION> in 1955 This landmark edition presented for the first time transcriptions of all of <PERSON>Dickinson</PERSON> s known poems noting variant words and including multiple versions of poems In 1958 the <ORGANIZATION>Press</ORGANIZATION> followed up with a three volume edition of <PERSON>Dickinson</PERSON> s letters edited by <PERSON>Johnson</PERSON> and <PERSON>Theodora Ward</PERSON> In 1998 R W <PERSON>Franklin</PERSON> and the <ORGANIZATION>Press</ORGANIZATION> published a new three volume edition containing 1 789 of <PERSON>Dickinson</PERSON> s poems the largest number ever assembled Arranged chronologically based on new dating analysis The Poems of <ORGANIZATION>Emily Dickinson Variorum Edition</ORGANIZATION> transcribed the entire known corpus of approximately 2 500 textual sources giving as many as seven versions of some poems In 1999 the <ORGANIZATION>Press</ORGANIZATION> published <ORGANIZATION>Franklin</ORGANIZATION> s The Poems of <ORGANIZATION>Emily Dickinson Reading Edition</ORGANIZATION> which follows the same numbering system as the <ORGANIZATION>Variorum</ORGANIZATION> but offers in one volume a single version of each poem In 2016 the Press published <PERSON>Cristanne Miller</PERSON> s edition of <PERSON>Emily Dickinson</PERSON> s Poems As She Preserved Them This is the only major edition of the complete poems to distinguish in easy visual form the approximately 1 100 poems <PERSON>Dickinson</PERSON> took pains to copy carefully onto folded sheets and gather with string into booklets fascicles arguably to preserve them for posterity from the poems she kept in rougher form or apparently did not retain <PERSON>Miller</PERSON> s Introduction describes <PERSON>Dickinson</PERSON> s practices in copying and circulating poems and summarizes contentious debates within <PERSON>Dickinson</PERSON> scholarship HUP s long engagement with the works of <PERSON>Emily Dickinson</PERSON> extends to the <ORGANIZATION>Emily Dickinson Archive</ORGANIZATION> which makes high resolution images of manuscripts of <PERSON>Dickinson</PERSON> s poetry and letters available in open access along with transcriptions and annotations from historical and scholarly editions The first release in Fall 2013 focuses on the corpus of poems that <PERSON>Franklin</PERSON> identified in his Variorum but includes transcriptions by <PERSON>Johnson</PERSON> and other editors who published <PERSON>Dickinson</PERSON> s poems in collections starting shortly after her death Under the guidance of General Editor <PERSON>Leslie Morris</PERSON> with an <ORGANIZATION>Advisory Board</ORGANIZATION> of distinguished scholars EDA is a growing collaboration that includes <ORGANIZATION>Amherst College Beinecke Library</ORGANIZATION> at <ORGANIZATION>Yale University the Berkman Center for Internet and Society</ORGANIZATION> at <ORGANIZATION>Harvard Boston Public Library Digital Public Library of America Emily Dickinson Lexicon</ORGANIZATION> at <ORGANIZATION>Brigham Young University Harvard Library Harvard University Press</ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION>Houghton Library</ORGANIZATION> at <ORGANIZATION>Harvard Key Features of Emily Dickinson</ORGANIZATION> Archive Find poems easily with multiple index and reference tools Study the poet s own handwriting variants and arrangement of her work Read and compare editions word choice and transcriptions through time Engage in new scholarship using tools for creating annotations transcriptions and reading lists image Cover <PERSON>Emily Dickinson</PERSON> s Poems As She Preserved Them <PERSON>Emily Dickinson</PERSON> s Poems As She Preserved Them Edited by <PERSON>Cristanne Miller</PERSON> image Cover Dickinson Selected Poems and Commentaries Dickinson Selected Poems and Commentaries <PERSON>Helen Vendler</PERSON> image Cover The Gardens of <PERSON>Emily Dickinson</PERSON> <LOCATION>The Gardens</LOCATION> of <PERSON>Emily Dickinson Judith Farr</PERSON> image Cover The Poems of Emily Dickinson Reading Edition The Poems of Emily Dickinson Reading Edition Edited by R W Franklin View additional works by and about <PERSON>Emily Dickinson</PERSON> from <ORGANIZATION>Harvard University Press Back</ORGANIZATION> to top image HUP on YouTube abstract logo design Recent News The <ORGANIZATION>Economist</ORGANIZATION> used data from <PERSON>Richard</PERSON> H Sander et al s Moving toward Integration The Past and Future of Fair Housing in a report on how class based has quietly replaced race based segregation in <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> and in an associated interactive feature <PERSON>Samuel Moyn</PERSON> author of Not Enough Human Rights in an Unequal World argued in Foreign Policy that it is shortsighted for the U S to promote basic rights without a broader effort to combat the entrenched economic inequality that endangers them <PERSON>Vera Tobin</PERSON> author of Elements of Surprise Our Mental Limits and the Satisfactions of Plot discussed how our brains process surprises in real life and in the juiciest genre fiction on the podcast Smart Bitches Trashy Books <PERSON>Henry Greely</PERSON> author of The End of Sex and the Future of Human Reproduction spoke with <PERSON>Maclean</PERSON> s about the legal ethical and moral issues that will arise once lab grown human embryos become the norm rather than the exception Stay Posted image Cover of current seasonal catalog Browse our interactive Spring Summer 2018 catalog Now Available The digital Loeb Classical Library loebclassics com extends the founding mission of <PERSON>James Loeb</PERSON> with an interconnected fully searchable perpetually growing virtual library of all that is important in Greek and Latin literature Find new facing page translations of classic works from the <ORGANIZATION>Dumbarton Oaks Medieval Library I Tatti Renaissance Library Loeb Classical Library</ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION>Murty Classical Library of India Booksellers</ORGANIZATION> and Librarians Our recent titles are available via Edelweiss Off the Page Visit our multimedia page for video about recent projects and interviews with HUP authors Join Our Mailing List Subscribe to receive information about forthcoming books seasonal catalogs and more in newsletters tailored to your interests Blog image Blockchain and the Law April 10 The Rule of Code vs The Rule of Law When <PERSON>Satoshi Nakamoto</PERSON> released <PERSON>Bitcoin</PERSON> to the world he had a clear idea in mind which was reflected in the message he included in <PERSON>Bitcoin</PERSON> s genesis block The <ORGANIZATION>Times</ORGANIZATION> 03 Jan 2009 Chancellor on brink of second bailout for banks <PERSON>Nakamoto</PERSON> released the <ORGANIZATION>Bitcoin</ORGANIZATION> network in the middle of a financial crisis as a reaction to an unstable international banking system In doing so he gave birth to a new currency one controlled not by any government or central bank but only by cryptography and code As a global and decentralized payment system that operates without centralized control <PERSON>Bitcoin</PERSON> held out the hope of newfound economic freedom for those dubious of governmental authority Early Bitcoin adopters subscribed to the notion of vires in numeris strength in numbers a motto About amp Contact Awards Browse Catalogs Conference Exhibits eBooks Exam Copies News Order Rights Permissions Search Shopping Cart Resources for Authors Booksellers amp Librarians Educators Journalists Readers <ORGANIZATION>Harvard University Press</ORGANIZATION> offices are located at 79 <LOCATION>Garden Street Cambridge MA</LOCATION> 02138 <LOCATION>USA</LOCATION> amp <ORGANIZATION>Vernon House</ORGANIZATION> 23 Sicilian Avenue <LOCATION>London</LOCATION> WC1A 2QS <LOCATION>UK</LOCATION> 2018 President and Fellows of <ORGANIZATION>Harvard College Read</ORGANIZATION> our Privacy Policy</ner>
