<ner>Toggle navigation POEMAGEA Visualization Tool in Support of Close Reading Overview Video Downloads Publications Team NEH 2016 Poemage is a visualization system for exploring the sonic topology of a poem We define sonic topology as the complex structures formed via the interaction of sonic patterns words connected through some sonic or linguistic resemblance across the space of the poem Poemage was developed at the <ORGANIZATION>University of Utah</ORGANIZATION> as part of an ongoing highly exploratory collaboration between data visualization experts and poets poetry scholars Additional details are provided in the companion paper image Video Downloads Poemage Poemage is open source Please check back periodically for updates Web version coming soon Executables Executables are no longer supported Please check back soon for a web version of the tool If you would like to be notified when the web version is up and running please send email to nina cs utah edu Source <PERSON>Poemage</PERSON> was developed using the Processing language v 2 2 1 The source code is publicly available to run in the Processing environment The code has been tested for Processing version 2 2 1 source RhymeDesign As part of this collaboration we have also developed a system called RhymeDesign for querying complex rhyme in a poem RhymeDesign provides the back end for Poemage For more information about the system and to download the application source please visit RhymeDesign org Publications N <PERSON>McCurdy J Lein K Coles</PERSON> M Meyer Poemage Visualizing the Sonic Topology of a Poem IEEE Transactions on Visualization and Computer Graphics Proceedings of InfoVis 2015 pages 439 448 January 2016 K Coles Slippage spillage pillage bliss Close reading uncertainty and machines <ORGANIZATION>Wester Humanities Review</ORGANIZATION> pages 39 65 Fall 2014 J <PERSON>Lein</PERSON> Sounding the surfaces Computers context and poetic consequence <ORGANIZATION>Wester Humanities Review</ORGANIZATION> pages 84 109 Fall 2014 N <PERSON>McCurdy V Srikumar</PERSON> and M Meyer Rhymedesign A tool for analyzing sonic devices in poetry In Proceedings of Computational Linguistics for Literature 2015 Selected Talks Presentations N <PERSON>McCurdy</PERSON> Making Poemage The Critical Visualization Event GC CUNY <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> NY June 2016 N <PERSON>McCurdy</PERSON> The Poemage project exploring the true value of computation to poetry scholarship DH U1 The First Utah Symposium on the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities Utah Valley University Orem UT</ORGANIZATION> Feb 2016 K <PERSON>Coles</PERSON> and N <PERSON>McCurdy</PERSON> Developing and <ORGANIZATION>Sustaining Collaborative Research</ORGANIZATION> in the Humanities Panel Discussion MLA2016 Austin TX Jan 2016 K <PERSON>Coles</PERSON> I Don t <ORGANIZATION>Care About Data Data Driven Research</ORGANIZATION> in the <ORGANIZATION>Social Sciences and Humanities Increasing Research Potential</ORGANIZATION> through Interdisciplinary Working Panel Discussion Round Three Digging Into Data Challenge Conference <LOCATION>Glasgow UK</LOCATION> Jan 2016 K Coles Ghost in the <ORGANIZATION>Machine Melbourne</ORGANIZATION> Oct 2015 K Coles Poetry and Exploration In Motion in the <ORGANIZATION>Machine Canberra</ORGANIZATION> Oct 2015 N <PERSON>McCurdy J Gonnering Lein</PERSON> A Hurtado Deep in Poetry Improvisations in Tech in Text in Time IEEE VISAP2 15 <LOCATION>Chicago</LOCATION> IL Oct 2015 N <PERSON>McCurdy</PERSON> Visualizing the Sonic Topology of a Poem IEEE VIS <LOCATION>Chicago</LOCATION> IL Oct 2015 J Gonnering Lein Computers in my Classes A Pedagogy Round Table on Workshopping With the Digital Panel Discussion AWP2015 <LOCATION>Minneapolis</LOCATION> MN April 2015 N <PERSON>McCurdy</PERSON> Visualizing the Sonic Topology of a Poem CRA W Grad Cohort Workshop <LOCATION>San Francisco</LOCATION> CA April 2015 Poster presentation <ORGANIZATION>J Lein Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON>Dickinson</PERSON> s Tell Recounting Poetic Encounter New Work on <ORGANIZATION>Dickinson Flash Talks Modern Language Association Vancouver BC</ORGANIZATION> Jan 2015 K <PERSON>Coles</PERSON> and <PERSON>J Lein</PERSON> Turbulence and temporality re visualizing poetic time Things my computer taught me about poems In MLA2014 <LOCATION>Chicago</LOCATION> IL Jan 2014 <ORGANIZATION>The Team Nina McCurdy Doctoral Student School of Computing University of Utah Julie Gonnering Lein Postdoctoral Fellow Department of English University of Utah Katharine Coles Professor</ORGANIZATION> and Director of <ORGANIZATION>Creative Writing Department of English University of Utah Miriah Meyer Assistant Professor School of Computing University of Utah This</ORGANIZATION> work was funded in part by <ORGANIZATION>NSF</ORGANIZATION> grant IIS 1350896 and <ORGANIZATION>NEH</ORGANIZATION> grant HD 229002 Please contact nina cs utah edu with feedback</ner>
