<ner>Skip to Main Content Skip to content x Join MQUP s Mailing List Sign up for our newsletter about new books in your discipline and exclusive offers image Shopping Cart image Checkout Welcome Guest image Login Lock Login image Create Account Icon Create Account image Change Currancy Canadian Store CAD You are currently shopping in our Canadian store For orders outside of <LOCATION>Canada</LOCATION> please switch to our international store International and <LOCATION>US</LOCATION> orders are billed in US dollars x No thanks continue shopping in our Canadian store 0 Items image <ORGANIZATION>McGill Queen s University Press Logo Home</ORGANIZATION> About The Press Browse Books Ordering Info Publishing With Us Permissions Distribution Our Series Awards Blog Events Programme Fran ais Media Inquiries Contact Us Stay Connected Looking for more MQUP Sign up for our newsletter about new books and exclusive offers Course Adoption We are pleased to provide examination or desk copies to professors Click for more information back to filtered results image From Literature to Biterature zoom cover image From Literature to <PERSON>Biterature Lem Turing Darwin</PERSON> and Explorations in Computer Literature Philosophy of Mind and Cultural Evolution By <PERSON>Peter Swirski</PERSON> Cultural Studies Literary Theory amp Criticism Philosophy Mind amp Language image <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> Preview 9780773589926 Quantity Price 29 95 CAD 10 off 26 96 eBook Available <ORGANIZATION>Amazon CA Google</ORGANIZATION> Play Kobo CA Email Print Add to Wishlist Overview Reviews Author Bio Table of Contents More by Author The ultimate future of literature and literary studies in the age of thinking and evolving machines From Literature to <LOCATION>Biterature</LOCATION> is based on the premise that in the foreseeable future computers will become capable of creating works of literature Among hundreds of other questions it considers Under which conditions would machines become capable of creative writing Given that computer evolution will exceed the pace of natural evolution a million fold what will such a state of affairs entail in terms of art culture social life and even nonhuman rights Drawing a map of impending literary cultural social and technological revolutions <PERSON>Peter Swirski</PERSON> boldly assumes that computers will leap from mere syntax driven processing to semantically rich understanding He argues that acknowledging biterature as a species of literature will involve adopting the same range of attitudes to computer authors computhors as to human ones and that it will be necessary to approach them as agents with internal states and creative intentions Ranging from the metafiction of <PERSON>Stanislaw Lem</PERSON> to the Turing test familiar to scientists working in Artificial Intelligence and the philosophy of mind to the evolutionary trends of culture and machines <PERSON>Swirski</PERSON> s scenarios lay the groundwork for a new area of study on the cusp of literary futurology evolutionary cognition and philosophy of the future Details 252 Pages 6 x 9 ISBN 9780773542952 October 2013 Formats Cloth eBook Recommend to Library Ordering eBooks Rights and Permissions Course Adoption Media Inquiries Other Ordering Options Tweet <PERSON>Swirski</PERSON> s work is an accessible introduction to the domain of Artificial Intelligence and its impact on the presumed emergence of computer generated literature a thought provoking concept <PERSON>Tomasz Lem</PERSON> author of Adventures in the Field of Universal Gravitation From Literature to Biterature is the best thing that s appeared since Future Shock by <PERSON>Alvin Toffler</PERSON> At points fascinating unsettling and profound <PERSON>Swirski</PERSON> effortlessly integrates philosophy of mind robotics literary studies cultural trends futurology evolution and many other areas of intellectual analysis There is no other book like it <PERSON>Waclaw</PERSON> M <ORGANIZATION>Osadnik Department of Modern Languages and Cultural Studies University of Alberta Once</ORGANIZATION> I had a chess playing computer that was programmed to comment on my moves The greatest praise it could bestow on one of them was to inquire Are you also a computer Is this an omen of our literary future Will computers one day win not only chess tournaments but Pulitzer Prizes Will biterature overcome literature <PERSON>Peter Swirski</PERSON> thinks so and he also thinks that Turing and <PERSON>Darwin</PERSON> have told us how it can happen If his book inspires and provokes you as much as it did me reading it is a move that even my chess computer would complement <ORGANIZATION>Jaakko Hintikka Department of Philosophy Boston University Overall</ORGANIZATION> a stimulating enjoyable read Choice However beautiful or ugly computer code may be it is still written by humans In From Literature to Biterature <PERSON>Peter Swirski</PERSON> a professor of American studies and the culture at the <ORGANIZATION>University of Missouri Saint Louis</ORGANIZATION> proposes a new version of the Turing Test can computers write literature it is fascinating to imagine machines that operate on their own creative terms working outside the scripts humans write for them and beyond the boundaries of what we now recognize as creativity Times Literary Supplement This latest book confirms <PERSON>Swirski</PERSON> s skill in handling transdisciplinary studies blending in the proposed route from literature to biterature issues of science mind philosophy and society <PERSON>Leonardo Peter Swirski</PERSON> is professor of American literature and culture at the <ORGANIZATION>University of Missouri Saint Louis</ORGANIZATION> and former research director at the <ORGANIZATION>Helsinki Collegium</ORGANIZATION> for Advanced Studies He is the author of twelve books including <ORGANIZATION>Ars Americana Ars Politica Partisan Expression in Contemporary American Literature</ORGANIZATION> and Culture Lemmata Narrative Intelligence Test of Time Avocados or <ORGANIZATION>Wombats Institute for Advanced Studies Builtware</ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION>Bitware Paignton Zoo</ORGANIZATION> 3 part one 1 Biterature Toscanelli s Map Bloomsday Titan Manchester <PERSON>Mark Manglers</PERSON> and Mashers Suits for the Dawn Patrol Charabia Short for Raconteur I Gave Myself an Electric Current Abe s Saloon Humming to Itself 17 2 <ORGANIZATION>Computhors Poetic Licence Devotchka Analytical Engine</ORGANIZATION> EZ Writer M bius Like <ORGANIZATION>JFK One Armed Bandit Homeostat Sapiens</ORGANIZATION> As It Sees Fit Brainstorm A1 B2 C3 Black Boxes 35 3 Bibliosophy La Chanson de Roland The Motherboard of All Problems Little Endian Algo Trading Father <PERSON>Roberto Busa</PERSON> <LOCATION>Riverside Shakespeare Death</LOCATION> in <LOCATION>Holbein Zettabyte</LOCATION> A Hamlet Every Eight Seconds A Pill That Makes Me Feel Loved 53 4 <ORGANIZATION>Transhumana Non</ORGANIZATION> Serviam Collective Loss of Morale Slippery Slope Artificial Stupidity Prometheus and Dolus L Homme Machine DARPA Nobel Prize in Biterature Chatbots in Chatter 71 part two 5 tt Supercalifragilistic Adroit Android Imitation Game Parry Exit Human Enter Machine I Object I Always Avoid a Kangaroo Reverse Turing Test Ultimatest Aramis 89 6 qed Troubles with Functionalism Print This Trompe l Oeil Like the Pope A Bevy of Pigeons No More No Less Dicty Operational Definition Flugblogs On Being Mental 111 7 ToM Kismet PaPeRo Guilty as Charged Eureka Meaning Elementary Dear <ORGANIZATION>Wason Biology in Action Driving Range Insula Cortex</ORGANIZATION> On Being Redundant 130 8 Y2K Methuselah Yes An Amphibian with a Stick Ellipses in This Picture Software for the Soul Parallel Paradigm Erlang and <ORGANIZATION>Mira DelFlies Eruntics Cogito Paradox</ORGANIZATION> 149 part three 9 How to Make War and Assassinate People Ice Pick and Ricin A Small African Country Licence to Kill Solsects Sunsects Synsects Fires at the <ORGANIZATION>Sun Candy Anyone Bacteriology Safe Investment</ORGANIZATION> 171 10 Biologic or the Philosophy of Error Axiomatic Givens Nature s Greatest Error Wandering Jew Critique of Pure Reason Manna from Heaven What Is <PERSON>Rosencrantz</PERSON> and Guildenstern 183 11 Mind Your Business 100 000 Years You re Flying Low Mac Neuromancer See Further The Making of a Fly 197 Notes 205 Bibliography 209 Index 225 image Ars Americana Ars Politica Ars Americana Ars Politica By <PERSON>Peter Swirski</PERSON> 9780773537668 27 95 CAD Paperback image I Sing the Body Politic I Sing the Body Politic Edited by <PERSON>Peter Swirski</PERSON> 9780773536333 24 95 CAD Paperback image Art and Science of <PERSON>Stanislaw Lem</PERSON> The The Art and Science of <PERSON>Stanislaw Lem</PERSON> Edited by <PERSON>Peter Swirski</PERSON> 9780773530461 110 00 CAD Cloth image From Lowbrow to Nobrow From Lowbrow to Nobrow By <PERSON>Peter Swirski</PERSON> 9780773529922 110 00 CAD Cloth image Between Literature and Science Between Literature and Science By <PERSON>Peter Swirski</PERSON> 9780773520431 110 00 CAD Cloth back to filtered results <ORGANIZATION>McGill Queen s University Press</ORGANIZATION> is a scholarly publisher of books that engage in public debate current events politics contemporary thought and the arts image Follow Us on Facebook image Follow Us on Twitter image Follow Us on Tumblr image Follow Us on Pinterest image Watch Us on YouTube image Follow Us on Instagram Home The Press Browse All Titles Ordering Publishing With <ORGANIZATION>Us Distribution Acknowledgements Authors Media amp Course Adoption Forms News amp Events Course Adoption Contact</ORGANIZATION> Us Copyright 2018 <ORGANIZATION>McGill Queen University Press</ORGANIZATION> All Rights Reserved Sitemap Legal Website by Orbit</ner>
