<ner>Home About the Archive Exhibits amp Objects Search Engine Bibliography NINES The Complete Writings and Pictures of <PERSON>Dante Gabriel Rossetti</PERSON> A Hypermedia Archive T HE Rossetti Archive facilitates the scholarly study of <PERSON>Dante Gabriel Rossetti</PERSON> the painter designer writer and translator who was according to both <PERSON>John Ruskin</PERSON> and <PERSON>Walter Pater</PERSON> the most important and original artistic force in the second half of the nineteenth century in <LOCATION>Great Britain</LOCATION> In <LOCATION>Whistler</LOCATION> s famous comment He was a king Completed in 2008 to the plan laid out in 1993 the Archive provides students and scholars with access to all of <ORGANIZATION>DGR</ORGANIZATION> s pictorial and textual works and to a large contextual corpus of materials most drawn from the period when <ORGANIZATION>DGR</ORGANIZATION> s work first appeared and established its reputation approximately 1848 1920 but some stretching back to the 14th century sources of his Italian translations All documents are encoded for structured search and analysis The <ORGANIZATION>Rossetti Archive</ORGANIZATION> aims to include high quality digital images of every surviving documentary state of <ORGANIZATION>DGR</ORGANIZATION> s works all the manuscripts proofs and original editions as well as the drawings paintings and designs of various kinds including his collaborative photographic and craft works These primary materials are transacted with a substantial body of editorial commentary notes and glosses Recent additions to the Rossetti Archive are discussed here image Get Firefox image Creative Commons License The Complete Writings and Pictures of <PERSON>Dante Gabriel Rossetti</PERSON> edited by <PERSON>Jerome J McGann</PERSON> is freely distributed by <ORGANIZATION>IATH</ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION>NINES</ORGANIZATION> consortium under a Creative Commons License Supported web browsers include <ORGANIZATION>Mozilla Firefox</ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION>Mac Safari</ORGANIZATION> o uommibatto</ner>
