<ner>The Project Gutenberg EBook of Sense and Sensibility by <PERSON>Jane Austen</PERSON> This eBook is for the use of anyone anywhere at no cost and with almost no restrictions whatsoever You may copy it give it away or re use it under the terms of the <ORGANIZATION>Project Gutenberg License</ORGANIZATION> included with this eBook or online at www gutenberg org Title Sense and Sensibility Author <PERSON>Jane Austen</PERSON> Commentator <PERSON>Austin Dobson Illustrator Hugh Thomson</PERSON> Release Date June 15 2007 EBook 21839 Last updated February 11 2015 Language English START OF THIS PROJECT GUTENBERG EBOOK SENSE AND SENSIBILITY Produced by <PERSON>Fritz Ohrenschall</PERSON> and <PERSON>Sankar Viswanathan</PERSON> This book was produced from scanned images of public domain material from the Google Print project Transcriber s Note The Table of Contents is not part of the original book The illustration on page 290 is missing from the book The Introduction ends abruptly Seems incomplete Illustration _Mr <PERSON>Dashwood</PERSON> introduced him _ P 219 SENSE amp SENSIBILITY BY <PERSON>JANE AUSTEN</PERSON> WITH AN INTRODUCTION BY AUSTIN <PERSON>DOBSON</PERSON> ILLUSTRATED BY <PERSON>HUGH THOMSON LONDON MACMILLAN</PERSON> AND CO LIMITED NEW YORK THE MACMILLAN COMPANY 1902 _First Edition with <PERSON>Hugh Thomson</PERSON> s Illustrations_ 1896 CONTENTS INTRODUCTION LIST OF ILLUSTRATIONS CHAPTER I CHAPTER II CHAPTER III CHAPTER IV CHAPTER V CHAPTER VI CHAPTER VII CHAPTER VIII CHAPTER IX CHAPTER X CHAPTER XI CHAPTER XII CHAPTER XIII CHAPTER XIV CHAPTER XV CHAPTER XVI CHAPTER XVII CHAPTER XVIII CHAPTER XIX CHAPTER XX CHAPTER XXI CHAPTER XXII CHAPTER XXIII CHAPTER XXIV CHAPTER XXV CHAPTER XXVI CHAPTER XXVII CHAPTER XXVIII CHAPTER XXIX CHAPTER XXX CHAPTER XXXI CHAPTER XXXII CHAPTER XXXIII CHAPTER XXXIV CHAPTER XXXV CHAPTER XXXVI CHAPTER XXXVII CHAPTER XXXVIII CHAPTER XXXIX CHAPTER XL CHAPTER XLI CHAPTER XLII CHAPTER XLIII CHAPTER XLIV CHAPTER XLV CHAPTER XLVI CHAPTER XLVII CHAPTER XLVIII CHAPTER XLIX CHAPTER L INTRODUCTION With the title of _Sense and Sensibility_ is connected one of those minor problems which delight the cummin splitters of criticism In the _<PERSON>Cecilia</PERSON>_ of <PERSON>Madame D Arblay</PERSON> the forerunner if not the model of Miss <PERSON>Austen</PERSON> is a sentence which at first sight suggests some relationship to the name of the book which in the present series inaugurated Miss <PERSON>Austen</PERSON> s novels The whole of this unfortunate business says a certain didactic Dr <PERSON>Lyster</PERSON> talking in capitals towards the end of volume three of _<PERSON>Cecilia</PERSON>_ has been the result of PRIDE and PREJUDICE and looking to the admitted familiarity of Miss <PERSON>Austen</PERSON> with <PERSON>Madame D Arblay</PERSON> s work it has been concluded that Miss <PERSON>Austen</PERSON> borrowed from _<PERSON>Cecilia</PERSON>_ the title of her second novel But here comes in the little problem to which we have referred _Pride and Prejudice_ it is true was written and finished before _Sense and Sensibility_ its original title for several years being _First Impressions_ Then in 1797 the author fell to work upon an older essay in letters _ la_ <PERSON>Richardson</PERSON> called _<PERSON>Elinor</PERSON> and <PERSON>Marianne</PERSON>_ which she re christened _Sense and Sensibility _ This as we know was her first published book and whatever may be the connection between the title of _Pride and Prejudice_ and the passage in _<PERSON>Cecilia</PERSON>_ there is an obvious connection between the title of _Pride and Prejudice_ and the _title of Sense and Sensibility_ If Miss <PERSON>Austen</PERSON> re christened _<PERSON>Elinor</PERSON> and <PERSON>Marianne</PERSON>_ before she changed the title of _First Impressions_ as she well may have it is extremely unlikely that the name of _Pride and Prejudice_ has anything to do with _<PERSON>Cecilia</PERSON>_ which besides had been published at least twenty years before Upon the whole therefore it is most likely that the passage in Madame D Arblay is a mere coincidence and that in _Sense and Sensibility_ as well as in the novel that succeeded it in publication Miss <PERSON>Austen</PERSON> after the fashion of the old morality plays simply substituted the leading characteristics of her principal personages for their names Indeed in _Sense and Sensibility_ the sense of <PERSON>Elinor</PERSON> and the sensibility or rather _sensiblerie_ of <PERSON>Marianne</PERSON> are markedly emphasised in the opening pages of the book But Miss <PERSON>Austen</PERSON> subsequently and as we think wisely discarded in her remaining efforts the cheap attraction of an alliterative title _<PERSON>Emma</PERSON>_ and _Persuasion Northanger Abbey_ and _<LOCATION>Mansfield Park</LOCATION>_ are names far more in consonance with the quiet tone of her easy and unobtrusive art _<PERSON>Elinor</PERSON> and <PERSON>Marianne</PERSON>_ was originally written about 1792 After the completion or partial completion for it was again revised in 1811 of _First Impressions_ subsequently _Pride and Prejudice_ Miss <PERSON>Austen</PERSON> set about recasting _<PERSON>Elinor</PERSON> and <PERSON>Marianne</PERSON>_ then composed in the form of letters and she had no sooner accomplished this task than she began _<ORGANIZATION>Northanger Abbey</ORGANIZATION>_ It would be interesting to know to what extent she remodelled _Sense and Sensibility_ in 1797 98 for we are told that previous to its publication in 1811 she again devoted a considerable time to its preparation for the press and it is clear that this does not mean the correction of proofs alone but also a preliminary revision of MS Especially would it be interesting if we could ascertain whether any of its more finished passages _e g _ the admirable conversation between the Miss Dashwoods and <PERSON>Willoughby</PERSON> in chapter x were the result of those fallow and apparently barren years at Bath and <LOCATION>Southampton</LOCATION> or whether they were already part of the second version of 1797 98 But upon this matter the records are mute A careful examination of the correspondence published by Lord Brabourne in 1884 only reveals two definite references to _Sense and Sensibility_ and these are absolutely unfruitful in suggestion In April 1811 she speaks of having corrected two sheets of S and S which she has scarcely a hope of getting out in the following June and in September an extract from the diary of another member of the family indirectly discloses the fact that the book had by that time been published This extract is a brief reference to a letter which had been received from <PERSON>Cassandra Austen</PERSON> begging her correspondent not to mention that <PERSON>Aunt Jane</PERSON> wrote _Sense and Sensibility _ Beyond these minute items of information and the statement already referred to in the Introduction to _Pride and Prejudice_ that she considered herself overpaid for the labour she had bestowed upon it absolutely nothing seems to have been preserved by her descendants respecting her first printed effort In the absence of particulars some of her critics have fallen to speculate upon the reason which made her select it and not _Pride and Prejudice_ for her d but and they have perhaps naturally found in the fact a fresh confirmation of that traditional blindness of authors to their own best work which is one of the commonplaces of literary history But this is to premise that she _did_ regard it as her masterpiece a fact which apart from this accident of priority of issue is as far as we are aware nowhere asserted A simpler solution is probably that of the three novels she had written or sketched by 1811 _Pride and Prejudice_ was languishing under the stigma of having been refused by one bookseller without the formality of inspection while _Northanger Abbey_ was lying _perdu_ in another bookseller s drawer at Bath In these circumstances it is intelligible that she should turn to _Sense and Sensibility_ when at length upon the occasion of a visit to her brother in <LOCATION>London</LOCATION> in the spring of 1811 Mr <PERSON>T Egerton</PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION>Military Library Whitehall</ORGANIZATION> dawned upon the horizon as a practicable publisher By the time _Sense and Sensibility_ left the press Miss <PERSON>Austen</PERSON> was again domiciled at <LOCATION>Chawton Cottage</LOCATION> For those accustomed to the swarming reviews of our day with their Babel of notices it may seem strange that there should be no record of the effect produced seeing that as already stated the book sold well enough to enable its putter forth to hand over to its author what Mr Gargery in _Great Expectations_ would have described as a cool 150 Surely Mr <PERSON>Egerton</PERSON> who had visited Miss <PERSON>Austen</PERSON> at <LOCATION>Sloane Street</LOCATION> must have later conveyed to her some intelligence of the way in which her work had been welcomed by the public But if he did it is no longer discoverable Mr <PERSON>Austen Leigh</PERSON> her first and best biographer could find no account either of the publication or of the author s feelings thereupon As far as it is possible to judge the critical verdicts she obtained were mainly derived from her own relatives and intimate friends and some of these latter if one may trust a little anthology which she herself collected and from which Mr <PERSON>Austen Leigh</PERSON> prints extracts must have been more often exasperating than sympathetic The long chorus of intelligent approval by which she was afterwards greeted did not begin to be really audible before her death and her fit audience during her lifetime must have been emphatically few Of two criticisms which came out in the _Quarterly_ early in the century she could only have seen one that of 1815 the other by Archbishop Whately the first which treated her in earnest did not appear until she had been three years dead Dr Whately deals mainly with _<LOCATION>Mansfield Park</LOCATION>_ and _Persuasion_ his predecessor professed to review _<PERSON>Emma</PERSON>_ though he also gives brief summaries of _Sense and Sensibility_ and _Pride and Prejudice_ Mr <PERSON>Austen Leigh</PERSON> we think speaks too contemptuously of this initial notice of 1815 If at certain points it is half hearted and inadequate it is still fairly accurate in its recognition of Miss <PERSON>Austen</PERSON> s supreme merit as contrasted with her contemporaries to wit her skill in investing the fortunes of ordinary characters and the narrative of common occurrences with all the sustained excitement of romance The Reviewer points out very justly that this kind of work being deprived of all that according to <PERSON>Bayes</PERSON> goes to elevate and surprise must make amends by displaying depth of knowledge and dexterity of execution And in these qualities even with such living competitors of her own sex as Miss <PERSON>Edgeworth</PERSON> and Miss <PERSON>Brunton</PERSON> whose _Self control_ came out in the same year as _Sense and Sensibility_ he does not scruple to declare that Miss <PERSON>Austen</PERSON> stands almost alone If he omits to lay stress upon her judgment her nice sense of fitness her restraint her fine irony and the delicacy of her artistic touch something must be allowed for the hesitations and reservations which invariably beset the critical pioneer To contend however for a moment that the present volume is Miss <PERSON>Austen</PERSON> s greatest as it was her first published novel would be a mere exercise in paradox There are who swear by _Persuasion_ there are who prefer _<PERSON>Emma</PERSON>_ and _<LOCATION>Mansfield Park</LOCATION>_ there is a large contingent for _Pride and Prejudice_ and there is even a section which advocates the pre eminence of _Northanger Abbey_ But no one as far as we can remember has ever put _Sense and Sensibility_ first nor can we believe that its author did so herself And yet it is she herself who has furnished the standard by which we judge it and it is by comparison with _Pride and Prejudice_ in which the leading characters are also two sisters that we assess and depress its merit The <PERSON>Elinor</PERSON> and <PERSON>Marianne</PERSON> of _Sense and Sensibility_ are only inferior when they are contrasted with the <PERSON>Elizabeth</PERSON> and <PERSON>Jane</PERSON> of _Pride and Prejudice_ and even then it is probably because we personally like the handsome and amiable <PERSON>Jane Bennet</PERSON> rather better than the obsolete survival of the sentimental novel represented by <PERSON>Marianne Dashwood Darcy</PERSON> and <PERSON>Bingley</PERSON> again are much more likeable to use Lady Queensberry s word than the colourless <PERSON>Edward Ferrars</PERSON> and the stiff jointed Colonel Brandon Yet it might not unfairly be contended that there is more fidelity to what Mr <PERSON>Thomas Hardy</PERSON> has termed life s little ironies in Miss <PERSON>Austen</PERSON> s disposal of the two Miss Dashwoods than there is in her disposal of the heroines of _Pride and Prejudice_ Every one does not get a Bingley or a Darcy with a park but a good many sensible girls like <PERSON>Elinor</PERSON> pair off contentedly with poor creatures like <PERSON>Edward Ferrars</PERSON> while not a few enthusiasts like <PERSON>Marianne</PERSON> decline at last upon middle aged colonels with flannel waistcoats <PERSON>George Eliot</PERSON> we fancy would have held that the fates of <PERSON>Elinor</PERSON> and <PERSON>Marianne</PERSON> were more probable than the fortunes of <PERSON>Jane</PERSON> and <PERSON>Eliza Bennet</PERSON> That of the remaining characters there is certainly none to rival Mr <PERSON>Bennet</PERSON> or Lady <PERSON>Catherine de Bourgh</PERSON> or the ineffable Mr <PERSON>Collins</PERSON> of _Pride and Prejudice_ is true but we confess to a kindness for vulgar matchmaking Mrs Jennings with her still room parmaceti for an inward bruise in the shape of a glass of old <ORGANIZATION>Constantia</ORGANIZATION> and for the diluted Squire Western Sir <PERSON>John Middleton</PERSON> whose horror of being alone carries him to the point of rejoicing in the acquisition of _two_ to the population of <LOCATION>London</LOCATION> Excellent again are Mr <PERSON>Palmer</PERSON> and his wife excellent in their sordid veracity the self seeking figures of the Miss Steeles But the pearls of the book must be allowed to be that egregious amateur in toothpick cases Mr <PERSON>Robert Ferrars</PERSON> with his excursus in chapter xxxvi on life in a cottage and the admirably matched Mr and Mrs <PERSON>John Dashwood Miss Austen</PERSON> herself has never done anything better than the inimitable and oft quoted chapter wherein is debated between the last named pair the momentous matter of the amount to be devoted to <PERSON>Mrs Dashwood</PERSON> and her daughters while the suggestion in chapters xxxiii and xxxiv that the owner of <LOCATION>Norland</LOCATION> was once within some thousands of having to sell out at a loss deserves to be remembered with that other memorable escape of Sir <PERSON>Roger de Coverley</PERSON> s ancestor who was only not killed in the civil wars because he was sent out of the field upon a private message the day before the battle of <LOCATION>Worcester</LOCATION> Of local colouring there is as little in _Sense and Sensibility_ as in _Pride and Prejudice_ It is not unlikely that some memories of <LOCATION>Steventon</LOCATION> may survive in <LOCATION>Norland</LOCATION> and it may be noted that there is actually a <LOCATION>Barton Place</LOCATION> to the north of <LOCATION>Exeter</LOCATION> not far from Lord <PERSON>Iddesleigh</PERSON> s well known seat of <LOCATION>Upton Pynes</LOCATION> It is scarcely possible also not to believe that in Mrs <PERSON>Jennings</PERSON> s description of <LOCATION>Delaford</LOCATION> a nice place I can tell you exactly what I call a nice old fashioned place full of comforts and conveniences quite shut in with great garden walls that are covered with the best fruit trees in the country and such a mulberry tree in one corner Miss <PERSON>Austen</PERSON> had in mind some real <LOCATION>Hampshire</LOCATION> or <LOCATION>Devonshire</LOCATION> country house In any case it comes nearer a picture than what we usually get from her pen Then there is a dovecote some delightful stew ponds and a very pretty canal and everything in short that one could wish for and moreover it is close to the church and only a quarter of a mile from the turnpike road so tis never dull for if you only go and sit up in an old yew arbour behind the house you may see all the carriages that pass along The last lines suggest those quaint gazebos and alcoves which in the coaching days were so often to be found perched at the roadside where one might sit and watch the Dover or <ORGANIZATION>Canterbury</ORGANIZATION> stage go whirling by Of genteel accomplishments there is a touch In the landscape in coloured silks which <PERSON>Charlotte Palmer</PERSON> had worked at school chap xxvi and of old remedies for the lost art of swooning in the lavender drops of chapter xxix The mention of a dance as a little hop in chapter ix reads like a premature instance of middle Victorian slang But nothing is new even in a novel and hop in this sense is at least as old as _<PERSON>Joseph Andrews</PERSON>_ LIST OF ILLUSTRATIONS Mr <PERSON>Dashwood</PERSON> introduced him _Frontispiece_ His son s son a child of four years old I cannot imagine how they will spend half of it So shy before company They sang together He cut off a long lock of her hair I have found you out in spite of all your tricks Apparently In violent affliction Begging her to stop Came to take a survey of the guest I declare they are quite charming Mischievous tricks Drinking to her best affections Amiably bashful I can answer for it said <PERSON>Mrs Jennings</PERSON> At that moment she first perceived him How fond he was of it Offered him one of Folly s puppies A very smart beau Introduced to <PERSON>Mrs Jennings Mrs Jennings</PERSON> assured him directly that she should not stand upon ceremony <PERSON>Mrs Ferrars</PERSON> Drawing him a little aside In a whisper You have heard I suppose Talking over the business She put in the feather last night Listening at the door Both gained considerable amusement Of one thing I may assure you Showing her child to the housekeeper The gardener s lamentations Opened a window shutter I entreat you to stay I was formally dismissed I have entered many a shop to avoid your sight And see how the children go on I suppose you know ma am that Mr <PERSON>Ferrars</PERSON> is married It _was_ <PERSON>Edward Everything</PERSON> in such respectable condition CHAPTER I The family of <PERSON>Dashwood</PERSON> had long been settled in <ORGANIZATION>Sussex</ORGANIZATION> Their estate was large and their residence was at <LOCATION>Norland Park</LOCATION> in the centre of their property where for many generations they had lived in so respectable a manner as to engage the general good opinion of their surrounding acquaintance The late owner of this estate was a single man who lived to a very advanced age and who for many years of his life had a constant companion and housekeeper in his sister But her death which happened ten years before his own produced a great alteration in his home for to supply her loss he invited and received into his house the family of his nephew Mr <PERSON>Henry Dashwood</PERSON> the legal inheritor of the <LOCATION>Norland</LOCATION> estate and the person to whom he intended to bequeath it In the society of his nephew and niece and their children the old Gentleman s days were comfortably spent His attachment to them all increased The constant attention of Mr and <PERSON>Mrs Henry Dashwood</PERSON> to his wishes which proceeded not merely from interest but from goodness of heart gave him every degree of solid comfort which his age could receive and the cheerfulness of the children added a relish to his existence By a former marriage Mr <PERSON>Henry Dashwood</PERSON> had one son by his present lady three daughters The son a steady respectable young man was amply provided for by the fortune of his mother which had been large and half of which devolved on him on his coming of age By his own marriage likewise which happened soon afterwards he added to his wealth To him therefore the succession to the <LOCATION>Norland</LOCATION> estate was not so really important as to his sisters for their fortune independent of what might arise to them from their father s inheriting that property could be but small Their mother had nothing and their father only seven thousand pounds in his own disposal for the remaining moiety of his first wife s fortune was also secured to her child and he had only a life interest in it The old gentleman died his will was read and like almost every other will gave as much disappointment as pleasure He was neither so unjust nor so ungrateful as to leave his estate from his nephew but he left it to him on such terms as destroyed half the value of the bequest Mr <PERSON>Dashwood</PERSON> had wished for it more for the sake of his wife and daughters than for himself or his son but to his son and his son s son a child of four years old it was secured in such a way as to leave to himself no power of providing for those who were most dear to him and who most needed a provision by any charge on the estate or by any sale of its valuable woods The whole was tied up for the benefit of this child who in occasional visits with his father and mother at <LOCATION>Norland</LOCATION> had so far gained on the affections of his uncle by such attractions as are by no means unusual in children of two or three years old an imperfect articulation an earnest desire of having his own way many cunning tricks and a great deal of noise as to outweigh all the value of all the attention which for years he had received from his niece and her daughters He meant not to be unkind however and as a mark of his affection for the three girls he left them a thousand pounds a piece Mr <PERSON>Dashwood</PERSON> s disappointment was at first severe but his temper was cheerful and sanguine and he might reasonably hope to live many years and by living economically lay by a considerable sum from the produce of an estate already large and capable of almost immediate improvement But the fortune which had been so tardy in coming was his only one twelvemonth He survived his uncle no longer and ten thousand pounds including the late legacies was all that remained for his widow and daughters His son was sent for as soon as his danger was known and to him Mr <PERSON>Dashwood</PERSON> recommended with all the strength and urgency which illness could command the interest of his mother in law and sisters Mr <PERSON>John Dashwood</PERSON> had not the strong feelings of the rest of the family but he was affected by a recommendation of such a nature at such a time and he promised to do every thing in his power to make them comfortable His father was rendered easy by such an assurance and Mr <PERSON>John Dashwood</PERSON> had then leisure to consider how much there might prudently be in his power to do for them Illustration _His son s son a child of four years old _ He was not an ill disposed young man unless to be rather cold hearted and rather selfish is to be ill disposed but he was in general well respected for he conducted himself with propriety in the discharge of his ordinary duties Had he married a more amiable woman he might have been made still more respectable than he was he might even have been made amiable himself for he was very young when he married and very fond of his wife But Mrs <PERSON>John Dashwood</PERSON> was a strong caricature of himself more narrow minded and selfish When he gave his promise to his father he meditated within himself to increase the fortunes of his sisters by the present of a thousand pounds a piece He then really thought himself equal to it The prospect of four thousand a year in addition to his present income besides the remaining half of his own mother s fortune warmed his heart and made him feel capable of generosity Yes he would give them three thousand pounds it would be liberal and handsome It would be enough to make them completely easy Three thousand pounds he could spare so considerable a sum with little inconvenience He thought of it all day long and for many days successively and he did not repent No sooner was his father s funeral over than Mrs <PERSON>John Dashwood</PERSON> without sending any notice of her intention to her mother in law arrived with her child and their attendants No one could dispute her right to come the house was her husband s from the moment of his father s decease but the indelicacy of her conduct was so much the greater and to a woman in <PERSON>Mrs Dashwood</PERSON> s situation with only common feelings must have been highly unpleasing But in _her_ mind there was a sense of honor so keen a generosity so romantic that any offence of the kind by whomsoever given or received was to her a source of immovable disgust Mrs <PERSON>John Dashwood</PERSON> had never been a favourite with any of her husband s family but she had had no opportunity till the present of showing them with how little attention to the comfort of other people she could act when occasion required it So acutely did <PERSON>Mrs Dashwood</PERSON> feel this ungracious behaviour and so earnestly did she despise her daughter in law for it that on the arrival of the latter she would have quitted the house for ever had not the entreaty of her eldest girl induced her first to reflect on the propriety of going and her own tender love for all her three children determined her afterwards to stay and for their sakes avoid a breach with their brother <PERSON>Elinor</PERSON> this eldest daughter whose advice was so effectual possessed a strength of understanding and coolness of judgment which qualified her though only nineteen to be the counsellor of her mother and enabled her frequently to counteract to the advantage of them all that eagerness of mind in Mrs Dashwood which must generally have led to imprudence She had an excellent heart her disposition was affectionate and her feelings were strong but she knew how to govern them it was a knowledge which her mother had yet to learn and which one of her sisters had resolved never to be taught <PERSON>Marianne</PERSON> s abilities were in many respects quite equal to <PERSON>Elinor</PERSON> s She was sensible and clever but eager in everything her sorrows her joys could have no moderation She was generous amiable interesting she was everything but prudent The resemblance between her and her mother was strikingly great <PERSON>Elinor</PERSON> saw with concern the excess of her sister s sensibility but by <PERSON>Mrs Dashwood</PERSON> it was valued and cherished They encouraged each other now in the violence of their affliction The agony of grief which overpowered them at first was voluntarily renewed was sought for was created again and again They gave themselves up wholly to their sorrow seeking increase of wretchedness in every reflection that could afford it and resolved against ever admitting consolation in future <PERSON>Elinor</PERSON> too was deeply afflicted but still she could struggle she could exert herself She could consult with her brother could receive her sister in law on her arrival and treat her with proper attention and could strive to rouse her mother to similar exertion and encourage her to similar forbearance <PERSON>Margaret</PERSON> the other sister was a good humored well disposed girl but as she had already imbibed a good deal of <PERSON>Marianne</PERSON> s romance without having much of her sense she did not at thirteen bid fair to equal her sisters at a more advanced period of life CHAPTER II Mrs <PERSON>John Dashwood</PERSON> now installed herself mistress of <LOCATION>Norland</LOCATION> and her mother and sisters in law were degraded to the condition of visitors As such however they were treated by her with quiet civility and by her husband with as much kindness as he could feel towards anybody beyond himself his wife and their child He really pressed them with some earnestness to consider <ORGANIZATION>Norland</ORGANIZATION> as their home and as no plan appeared so eligible to <PERSON>Mrs Dashwood</PERSON> as remaining there till she could accommodate herself with a house in the neighbourhood his invitation was accepted A continuance in a place where everything reminded her of former delight was exactly what suited her mind In seasons of cheerfulness no temper could be more cheerful than hers or possess in a greater degree that sanguine expectation of happiness which is happiness itself But in sorrow she must be equally carried away by her fancy and as far beyond consolation as in pleasure she was beyond alloy Mrs <PERSON>John Dashwood</PERSON> did not at all approve of what her husband intended to do for his sisters To take three thousand pounds from the fortune of their dear little boy would be impoverishing him to the most dreadful degree She begged him to think again on the subject How could he answer it to himself to rob his child and his only child too of so large a sum And what possible claim could the Miss Dashwoods who were related to him only by half blood which she considered as no relationship at all have on his generosity to so large an amount It was very well known that no affection was ever supposed to exist between the children of any man by different marriages and why was he to ruin himself and their poor little <PERSON>Harry</PERSON> by giving away all his money to his half sisters It was my father s last request to me replied her husband that I should assist his widow and daughters He did not know what he was talking of I dare say ten to one but he was light headed at the time Had he been in his right senses he could not have thought of such a thing as begging you to give away half your fortune from your own child He did not stipulate for any particular sum my dear Fanny he only requested me in general terms to assist them and make their situation more comfortable than it was in his power to do Perhaps it would have been as well if he had left it wholly to myself He could hardly suppose I should neglect them But as he required the promise I could not do less than give it at least I thought so at the time The promise therefore was given and must be performed Something must be done for them whenever they leave <LOCATION>Norland</LOCATION> and settle in a new home Well then _let_ something be done for them but _that_ something need not be three thousand pounds Consider she added that when the money is once parted with it never can return Your sisters will marry and it will be gone for ever If indeed it could be restored to our poor little boy Why to be sure said her husband very gravely that would make great difference The time may come when <PERSON>Harry</PERSON> will regret that so large a sum was parted with If he should have a numerous family for instance it would be a very convenient addition To be sure it would Perhaps then it would be better for all parties if the sum were diminished one half Five hundred pounds would be a prodigious increase to their fortunes Oh beyond anything great What brother on earth would do half so much for his sisters even if _really_ his sisters And as it is only half blood But you have such a generous spirit I would not wish to do any thing mean he replied One had rather on such occasions do too much than too little No one at least can think I have not done enough for them even themselves they can hardly expect more There is no knowing what _they_ may expect said the lady but we are not to think of their expectations the question is what you can afford to do Certainly and I think I may afford to give them five hundred pounds a piece As it is without any addition of mine they will each have about three thousand pounds on their mother s death a very comfortable fortune for any young woman To be sure it is and indeed it strikes me that they can want no addition at all They will have ten thousand pounds divided amongst them If they marry they will be sure of doing well and if they do not they may all live very comfortably together on the interest of ten thousand pounds That is very true and therefore I do not know whether upon the whole it would not be more advisable to do something for their mother while she lives rather than for them something of the annuity kind I mean My sisters would feel the good effects of it as well as herself A hundred a year would make them all perfectly comfortable His wife hesitated a little however in giving her consent to this plan To be sure said she it is better than parting with fifteen hundred pounds at once But then if <PERSON>Mrs Dashwood</PERSON> should live fifteen years we shall be completely taken in Fifteen years my dear Fanny her life cannot be worth half that purchase Certainly not but if you observe people always live for ever when there is an annuity to be paid them and she is very stout and healthy and hardly forty An annuity is a very serious business it comes over and over every year and there is no getting rid of it You are not aware of what you are doing I have known a great deal of the trouble of annuities for my mother was clogged with the payment of three to old superannuated servants by my father s will and it is amazing how disagreeable she found it Twice every year these annuities were to be paid and then there was the trouble of getting it to them and then one of them was said to have died and afterwards it turned out to be no such thing My mother was quite sick of it Her income was not her own she said with such perpetual claims on it and it was the more unkind in my father because otherwise the money would have been entirely at my mother s disposal without any restriction whatever It has given me such an abhorrence of annuities that I am sure I would not pin myself down to the payment of one for all the world It is certainly an unpleasant thing replied Mr <PERSON>Dashwood</PERSON> to have those kind of yearly drains on one s income One s fortune as your mother justly says is _not_ one s own To be tied down to the regular payment of such a sum on every rent day is by no means desirable it takes away one s independence Undoubtedly and after all you have no thanks for it They think themselves secure you do no more than what is expected and it raises no gratitude at all If I were you whatever I did should be done at my own discretion entirely I would not bind myself to allow them any thing yearly It may be very inconvenient some years to spare a hundred or even fifty pounds from our own expenses I believe you are right my love it will be better that there should be no annuity in the case whatever I may give them occasionally will be of far greater assistance than a yearly allowance because they would only enlarge their style of living if they felt sure of a larger income and would not be sixpence the richer for it at the end of the year It will certainly be much the best way A present of fifty pounds now and then will prevent their ever being distressed for money and will I think be amply discharging my promise to my father To be sure it will Indeed to say the truth I am convinced within myself that your father had no idea of your giving them any money at all The assistance he thought of I dare say was only such as might be reasonably expected of you for instance such as looking out for a comfortable small house for them helping them to move their things and sending them presents of fish and game and so forth whenever they are in season I ll lay my life that he meant nothing farther indeed it would be very strange and unreasonable if he did Do but consider my dear Mr <PERSON>Dashwood</PERSON> how excessively comfortable your mother in law and her daughters may live on the interest of seven thousand pounds besides the thousand pounds belonging to each of the girls which brings them in fifty pounds a year a piece and of course they will pay their mother for their board out of it Altogether they will have five hundred a year amongst them and what on earth can four women want for more than that They will live so cheap Their housekeeping will be nothing at all They will have no carriage no horses and hardly any servants they will keep no company and can have no expenses of any kind Only conceive how comfortable they will be Five hundred a year I am sure I cannot imagine how they will spend half of it and as to your giving them more it is quite absurd to think of it They will be much more able to give _you_ something Upon my word said Mr <PERSON>Dashwood</PERSON> I believe you are perfectly right My father certainly could mean nothing more by his request to me than what you say I clearly understand it now and I will strictly fulfil my engagement by such acts of assistance and kindness to them as you have described When my mother removes into another house my services shall be readily given to accommodate her as far as I can Some little present of furniture too may be acceptable then Certainly returned Mrs <PERSON>John Dashwood</PERSON> But however _one_ thing must be considered When your father and mother moved to <LOCATION>Norland</LOCATION> though the furniture of <PERSON>Stanhill</PERSON> was sold all the china plate and linen was saved and is now left to your mother Her house will therefore be almost completely fitted up as soon as she takes it That is a material consideration undoubtedly A valuable legacy indeed And yet some of the plate would have been a very pleasant addition to our own stock here Yes and the set of breakfast china is twice as handsome as what belongs to this house A great deal too handsome in my opinion for any place _they_ can ever afford to live in But however so it is Your father thought only of _them_ And I must say this that you owe no particular gratitude to him nor attention to his wishes for we very well know that if he could he would have left almost everything in the world to _them _ This argument was irresistible It gave to his intentions whatever of decision was wanting before and he finally resolved that it would be absolutely unnecessary if not highly indecorous to do more for the widow and children of his father than such kind of neighbourly acts as his own wife pointed out CHAPTER III <PERSON>Mrs Dashwood</PERSON> remained at <LOCATION>Norland</LOCATION> several months not from any disinclination to move when the sight of every well known spot ceased to raise the violent emotion which it produced for a while for when her spirits began to revive and her mind became capable of some other exertion than that of heightening its affliction by melancholy remembrances she was impatient to be gone and indefatigable in her inquiries for a suitable dwelling in the neighbourhood of <LOCATION>Norland</LOCATION> for to remove far from that beloved spot was impossible But she could hear of no situation that at once answered her notions of comfort and ease and suited the prudence of her eldest daughter whose steadier judgment rejected several houses as too large for their income which her mother would have approved Illustration _I cannot imagine how they will spend half of it _ Mrs <PERSON>Dashwood</PERSON> had been informed by her husband of the solemn promise on the part of his son in their favour which gave comfort to his last earthly reflections She doubted the sincerity of this assurance no more than he had doubted it himself and she thought of it for her daughters sake with satisfaction though as for herself she was persuaded that a much smaller provision than 7000L would support her in affluence For their brother s sake too for the sake of his own heart she rejoiced and she reproached herself for being unjust to his merit before in believing him incapable of generosity His attentive behaviour to herself and his sisters convinced her that their welfare was dear to him and for a long time she firmly relied on the liberality of his intentions The contempt which she had very early in their acquaintance felt for her daughter in law was very much increased by the farther knowledge of her character which half a year s residence in her family afforded and perhaps in spite of every consideration of politeness or maternal affection on the side of the former the two ladies might have found it impossible to have lived together so long had not a particular circumstance occurred to give still greater eligibility according to the opinions of <PERSON>Mrs Dashwood</PERSON> to her daughters continuance at <ORGANIZATION>Norland</ORGANIZATION> This circumstance was a growing attachment between her eldest girl and the brother of Mrs <PERSON>John Dashwood</PERSON> a gentlemanlike and pleasing young man who was introduced to their acquaintance soon after his sister s establishment at <LOCATION>Norland</LOCATION> and who had since spent the greatest part of his time there Some mothers might have encouraged the intimacy from motives of interest for <PERSON>Edward Ferrars</PERSON> was the eldest son of a man who had died very rich and some might have repressed it from motives of prudence for except a trifling sum the whole of his fortune depended on the will of his mother But <PERSON>Mrs Dashwood</PERSON> was alike uninfluenced by either consideration It was enough for her that he appeared to be amiable that he loved her daughter and that <PERSON>Elinor</PERSON> returned the partiality It was contrary to every doctrine of her s that difference of fortune should keep any couple asunder who were attracted by resemblance of disposition and that <PERSON>Elinor</PERSON> s merit should not be acknowledged by every one who knew her was to her comprehension impossible <PERSON>Edward Ferrars</PERSON> was not recommended to their good opinion by any peculiar graces of person or address He was not handsome and his manners required intimacy to make them pleasing He was too diffident to do justice to himself but when his natural shyness was overcome his behaviour gave every indication of an open affectionate heart His understanding was good and his education had given it solid improvement But he was neither fitted by abilities nor disposition to answer the wishes of his mother and sister who longed to see him distinguished as they hardly knew what They wanted him to make a fine figure in the world in some manner or other His mother wished to interest him in political concerns to get him into parliament or to see him connected with some of the great men of the day Mrs <PERSON>John Dashwood</PERSON> wished it likewise but in the mean while till one of these superior blessings could be attained it would have quieted her ambition to see him driving a barouche But <PERSON>Edward</PERSON> had no turn for great men or barouches All his wishes centered in domestic comfort and the quiet of private life Fortunately he had a younger brother who was more promising <PERSON>Edward</PERSON> had been staying several weeks in the house before he engaged much of <PERSON>Mrs Dashwood</PERSON> s attention for she was at that time in such affliction as rendered her careless of surrounding objects She saw only that he was quiet and unobtrusive and she liked him for it He did not disturb the wretchedness of her mind by ill timed conversation She was first called to observe and approve him farther by a reflection which <PERSON>Elinor</PERSON> chanced one day to make on the difference between him and his sister It was a contrast which recommended him most forcibly to her mother It is enough said she to say that he is unlike <PERSON>Fanny</PERSON> is enough It implies everything amiable I love him already I think you will like him said <PERSON>Elinor</PERSON> when you know more of him Like him replied her mother with a smile I feel no sentiment of approbation inferior to love You may esteem him I have never yet known what it was to separate esteem and love <PERSON>Mrs Dashwood</PERSON> now took pains to get acquainted with him Her manners were attaching and soon banished his reserve She speedily comprehended all his merits the persuasion of his regard for <PERSON>Elinor</PERSON> perhaps assisted her penetration but she really felt assured of his worth and even that quietness of manner which militated against all her established ideas of what a young man s address ought to be was no longer uninteresting when she knew his heart to be warm and his temper affectionate No sooner did she perceive any symptom of love in his behaviour to <PERSON>Elinor</PERSON> than she considered their serious attachment as certain and looked forward to their marriage as rapidly approaching In a few months my dear <PERSON>Marianne</PERSON> said she <PERSON>Elinor</PERSON> will in all probability be settled for life We shall miss her but _she_ will be happy Oh <PERSON>Mamma</PERSON> how shall we do without her My love it will be scarcely a separation We shall live within a few miles of each other and shall meet every day of our lives You will gain a brother a real affectionate brother I have the highest opinion in the world of <PERSON>Edward</PERSON> s heart But you look grave <PERSON>Marianne</PERSON> do you disapprove your sister s choice Perhaps said <PERSON>Marianne</PERSON> I may consider it with some surprise <PERSON>Edward</PERSON> is very amiable and I love him tenderly But yet he is not the kind of young man there is something wanting his figure is not striking it has none of that grace which I should expect in the man who could seriously attach my sister His eyes want all that spirit that fire which at once announce virtue and intelligence And besides all this I am afraid Mamma he has no real taste Music seems scarcely to attract him and though he admires <PERSON>Elinor</PERSON> s drawings very much it is not the admiration of a person who can understand their worth It is evident in spite of his frequent attention to her while she draws that in fact he knows nothing of the matter He admires as a lover not as a connoisseur To satisfy me those characters must be united I could not be happy with a man whose taste did not in every point coincide with my own He must enter into all my feelings the same books the same music must charm us both Oh mama how spiritless how tame was <PERSON>Edward</PERSON> s manner in reading to us last night I felt for my sister most severely Yet she bore it with so much composure she seemed scarcely to notice it I could hardly keep my seat To hear those beautiful lines which have frequently almost driven me wild pronounced with such impenetrable calmness such dreadful indifference He would certainly have done more justice to simple and elegant prose I thought so at the time but you _would_ give him <PERSON>Cowper Nay Mamma</PERSON> if he is not to be animated by <PERSON>Cowper</PERSON> but we must allow for difference of taste <PERSON>Elinor</PERSON> has not my feelings and therefore she may overlook it and be happy with him But it would have broke _my_ heart had I loved him to hear him read with so little sensibility Mama the more I know of the world the more am I convinced that I shall never see a man whom I can really love I require so much He must have all <PERSON>Edward</PERSON> s virtues and his person and manners must ornament his goodness with every possible charm Remember my love that you are not seventeen It is yet too early in life to despair of such a happiness Why should you be less fortunate than your mother In one circumstance only my Marianne may your destiny be different from her s CHAPTER IV What a pity it is <PERSON>Elinor</PERSON> said <PERSON>Marianne</PERSON> that <PERSON>Edward</PERSON> should have no taste for drawing No taste for drawing replied <PERSON>Elinor</PERSON> why should you think so He does not draw himself indeed but he has great pleasure in seeing the performances of other people and I assure you he is by no means deficient in natural taste though he has not had opportunities of improving it Had he ever been in the way of learning I think he would have drawn very well He distrusts his own judgment in such matters so much that he is always unwilling to give his opinion on any picture but he has an innate propriety and simplicity of taste which in general direct him perfectly right <PERSON>Marianne</PERSON> was afraid of offending and said no more on the subject but the kind of approbation which <PERSON>Elinor</PERSON> described as excited in him by the drawings of other people was very far from that rapturous delight which in her opinion could alone be called taste Yet though smiling within herself at the mistake she honoured her sister for that blind partiality to <PERSON>Edward</PERSON> which produced it I hope <PERSON>Marianne</PERSON> continued <PERSON>Elinor</PERSON> you do not consider him as deficient in general taste Indeed I think I may say that you cannot for your behaviour to him is perfectly cordial and if _that_ were your opinion I am sure you could never be civil to him <PERSON>Marianne</PERSON> hardly knew what to say She would not wound the feelings of her sister on any account and yet to say what she did not believe was impossible At length she replied Do not be offended <PERSON>Elinor</PERSON> if my praise of him is not in every thing equal to your sense of his merits I have not had so many opportunities of estimating the minuter propensities of his mind his inclinations and tastes as you have but I have the highest opinion in the world of his goodness and sense I think him every thing that is worthy and amiable I am sure replied <PERSON>Elinor</PERSON> with a smile that his dearest friends could not be dissatisfied with such commendation as that I do not perceive how you could express yourself more warmly <PERSON>Marianne</PERSON> was rejoiced to find her sister so easily pleased Of his sense and his goodness continued <PERSON>Elinor</PERSON> no one can I think be in doubt who has seen him often enough to engage him in unreserved conversation The excellence of his understanding and his principles can be concealed only by that shyness which too often keeps him silent You know enough of him to do justice to his solid worth But of his minuter propensities as you call them you have from peculiar circumstances been kept more ignorant than myself He and I have been at times thrown a good deal together while you have been wholly engrossed on the most affectionate principle by my mother I have seen a great deal of him have studied his sentiments and heard his opinion on subjects of literature and taste and upon the whole I venture to pronounce that his mind is well informed enjoyment of books exceedingly great his imagination lively his observation just and correct and his taste delicate and pure His abilities in every respect improve as much upon acquaintance as his manners and person At first sight his address is certainly not striking and his person can hardly be called handsome till the expression of his eyes which are uncommonly good and the general sweetness of his countenance is perceived At present I know him so well that I think him really handsome or at least almost so What say you <PERSON>Marianne</PERSON> I shall very soon think him handsome <PERSON>Elinor</PERSON> if I do not now When you tell me to love him as a brother I shall no more see imperfection in his face than I now do in his heart <PERSON>Elinor</PERSON> started at this declaration and was sorry for the warmth she had been betrayed into in speaking of him She felt that <PERSON>Edward</PERSON> stood very high in her opinion She believed the regard to be mutual but she required greater certainty of it to make <PERSON>Marianne</PERSON> s conviction of their attachment agreeable to her She knew that what <PERSON>Marianne</PERSON> and her mother conjectured one moment they believed the next that with them to wish was to hope and to hope was to expect She tried to explain the real state of the case to her sister I do not attempt to deny said she that I think very highly of him that I greatly esteem that I like him <PERSON>Marianne</PERSON> here burst forth with indignation Esteem him Like him Cold hearted Elinor Oh worse than cold hearted Ashamed of being otherwise Use those words again and I will leave the room this moment <PERSON>Elinor</PERSON> could not help laughing Excuse me said she and be assured that I meant no offence to you by speaking in so quiet a way of my own feelings Believe them to be stronger than I have declared believe them in short to be such as his merit and the suspicion the hope of his affection for me may warrant without imprudence or folly But farther than this you must not believe I am by no means assured of his regard for me There are moments when the extent of it seems doubtful and till his sentiments are fully known you cannot wonder at my wishing to avoid any encouragement of my own partiality by believing or calling it more than it is In my heart I feel little scarcely any doubt of his preference But there are other points to be considered besides his inclination He is very far from being independent What his mother really is we cannot know but from <PERSON>Fanny</PERSON> s occasional mention of her conduct and opinions we have never been disposed to think her amiable and I am very much mistaken if <PERSON>Edward</PERSON> is not himself aware that there would be many difficulties in his way if he were to wish to marry a woman who had not either a great fortune or high rank <PERSON>Marianne</PERSON> was astonished to find how much the imagination of her mother and herself had outstripped the truth And you really are not engaged to him said she Yet it certainly soon will happen But two advantages will proceed from this delay I shall not lose you so soon and <PERSON>Edward</PERSON> will have greater opportunity of improving that natural taste for your favourite pursuit which must be so indispensably necessary to your future felicity Oh if he should be so far stimulated by your genius as to learn to draw himself how delightful it would be <PERSON>Elinor</PERSON> had given her real opinion to her sister She could not consider her partiality for <PERSON>Edward</PERSON> in so prosperous a state as <PERSON>Marianne</PERSON> had believed it There was at times a want of spirits about him which if it did not denote indifference spoke of something almost as unpromising A doubt of her regard supposing him to feel it need not give him more than inquietude It would not be likely to produce that dejection of mind which frequently attended him A more reasonable cause might be found in the dependent situation which forbade the indulgence of his affection She knew that his mother neither behaved to him so as to make his home comfortable at present nor to give him any assurance that he might form a home for himself without strictly attending to her views for his aggrandizement With such a knowledge as this it was impossible for <PERSON>Elinor</PERSON> to feel easy on the subject She was far from depending on that result of his preference of her which her mother and sister still considered as certain Nay the longer they were together the more doubtful seemed the nature of his regard and sometimes for a few painful minutes she believed it to be no more than friendship But whatever might really be its limits it was enough when perceived by his sister to make her uneasy and at the same time which was still more common to make her uncivil She took the first opportunity of affronting her mother in law on the occasion talking to her so expressively of her brother s great expectations of <PERSON>Mrs Ferrars</PERSON> s resolution that both her sons should marry well and of the danger attending any young woman who attempted to _draw him in_ that <PERSON>Mrs Dashwood</PERSON> could neither pretend to be unconscious nor endeavor to be calm She gave her an answer which marked her contempt and instantly left the room resolving that whatever might be the inconvenience or expense of so sudden a removal her beloved <PERSON>Elinor</PERSON> should not be exposed another week to such insinuations In this state of her spirits a letter was delivered to her from the post which contained a proposal particularly well timed It was the offer of a small house on very easy terms belonging to a relation of her own a gentleman of consequence and property in <LOCATION>Devonshire</LOCATION> The letter was from this gentleman himself and written in the true spirit of friendly accommodation He understood that she was in need of a dwelling and though the house he now offered her was merely a cottage he assured her that everything should be done to it which she might think necessary if the situation pleased her He earnestly pressed her after giving the particulars of the house and garden to come with her daughters to <PERSON>Barton Park</PERSON> the place of his own residence from whence she might judge herself whether <LOCATION>Barton Cottage</LOCATION> for the houses were in the same parish could by any alteration be made comfortable to her He seemed really anxious to accommodate them and the whole of his letter was written in so friendly a style as could not fail of giving pleasure to his cousin more especially at a moment when she was suffering under the cold and unfeeling behaviour of her nearer connections She needed no time for deliberation or inquiry Her resolution was formed as she read The situation of <PERSON>Barton</PERSON> in a county so far distant from <ORGANIZATION>Sussex</ORGANIZATION> as <LOCATION>Devonshire</LOCATION> which but a few hours before would have been a sufficient objection to outweigh every possible advantage belonging to the place was now its first recommendation To quit the neighbourhood of <LOCATION>Norland</LOCATION> was no longer an evil it was an object of desire it was a blessing in comparison of the misery of continuing her daughter in law s guest and to remove for ever from that beloved place would be less painful than to inhabit or visit it while such a woman was its mistress She instantly wrote Sir <PERSON>John Middleton</PERSON> her acknowledgment of his kindness and her acceptance of his proposal and then hastened to show both letters to her daughters that she might be secure of their approbation before her answer were sent <PERSON>Elinor</PERSON> had always thought it would be more prudent for them to settle at some distance from <ORGANIZATION>Norland</ORGANIZATION> than immediately amongst their present acquaintance On _that_ head therefore it was not for her to oppose her mother s intention of removing into Devonshire The house too as described by Sir <PERSON>John</PERSON> was on so simple a scale and the rent so uncommonly moderate as to leave her no right of objection on either point and therefore though it was not a plan which brought any charm to her fancy though it was a removal from the vicinity of <LOCATION>Norland</LOCATION> beyond her wishes she made no attempt to dissuade her mother from sending a letter of acquiescence CHAPTER V No sooner was her answer dispatched than <PERSON>Mrs Dashwood</PERSON> indulged herself in the pleasure of announcing to her son in law and his wife that she was provided with a house and should incommode them no longer than till every thing were ready for her inhabiting it They heard her with surprise Mrs <PERSON>John Dashwood</PERSON> said nothing but her husband civilly hoped that she would not be settled far from <LOCATION>Norland</LOCATION> She had great satisfaction in replying that she was going into <PERSON>Devonshire Edward</PERSON> turned hastily towards her on hearing this and in a voice of surprise and concern which required no explanation to her repeated Devonshire Are you indeed going there So far from hence And to what part of it She explained the situation It was within four miles northward of <LOCATION>Exeter</LOCATION> It is but a cottage she continued but I hope to see many of my friends in it A room or two can easily be added and if my friends find no difficulty in travelling so far to see me I am sure I will find none in accommodating them She concluded with a very kind invitation to Mr and Mrs <PERSON>John Dashwood</PERSON> to visit her at <LOCATION>Barton</LOCATION> and to <PERSON>Edward</PERSON> she gave one with still greater affection Though her late conversation with her daughter in law had made her resolve on remaining at <LOCATION>Norland</LOCATION> no longer than was unavoidable it had not produced the smallest effect on her in that point to which it principally tended To separate <PERSON>Edward</PERSON> and <PERSON>Elinor</PERSON> was as far from being her object as ever and she wished to show Mrs <PERSON>John Dashwood</PERSON> by this pointed invitation to her brother how totally she disregarded her disapprobation of the match Mr <PERSON>John Dashwood</PERSON> told his mother again and again how exceedingly sorry he was that she had taken a house at such a distance from <LOCATION>Norland</LOCATION> as to prevent his being of any service to her in removing her furniture He really felt conscientiously vexed on the occasion for the very exertion to which he had limited the performance of his promise to his father was by this arrangement rendered impracticable The furniture was all sent around by water It chiefly consisted of household linen plate china and books with a handsome pianoforte of <PERSON>Marianne</PERSON> s Mrs <PERSON>John Dashwood</PERSON> saw the packages depart with a sigh she could not help feeling it hard that as <PERSON>Mrs Dashwood</PERSON> s income would be so trifling in comparison with their own she should have any handsome article of furniture <PERSON>Mrs Dashwood</PERSON> took the house for a twelvemonth it was ready furnished and she might have immediate possession No difficulty arose on either side in the agreement and she waited only for the disposal of her effects at <LOCATION>Norland</LOCATION> and to determine her future household before she set off for the west and this as she was exceedingly rapid in the performance of everything that interested her was soon done The horses which were left her by her husband had been sold soon after his death and an opportunity now offering of disposing of her carriage she agreed to sell that likewise at the earnest advice of her eldest daughter For the comfort of her children had she consulted only her own wishes she would have kept it but the discretion of <PERSON>Elinor</PERSON> prevailed _Her_ wisdom too limited the number of their servants to three two maids and a man with whom they were speedily provided from amongst those who had formed their establishment at <ORGANIZATION>Norland</ORGANIZATION> The man and one of the maids were sent off immediately into <LOCATION>Devonshire</LOCATION> to prepare the house for their mistress s arrival for as Lady <PERSON>Middleton</PERSON> was entirely unknown to <PERSON>Mrs Dashwood</PERSON> she preferred going directly to the cottage to being a visitor at <LOCATION>Barton Park</LOCATION> and she relied so undoubtingly on Sir <PERSON>John</PERSON> s description of the house as to feel no curiosity to examine it herself till she entered it as her own Her eagerness to be gone from <LOCATION>Norland</LOCATION> was preserved from diminution by the evident satisfaction of her daughter in law in the prospect of her removal a satisfaction which was but feebly attempted to be concealed under a cold invitation to her to defer her departure Now was the time when her son in law s promise to his father might with particular propriety be fulfilled Since he had neglected to do it on first coming to the estate their quitting his house might be looked on as the most suitable period for its accomplishment But Mrs <PERSON>Dashwood</PERSON> began shortly to give over every hope of the kind and to be convinced from the general drift of his discourse that his assistance extended no farther than their maintenance for six months at <ORGANIZATION>Norland</ORGANIZATION> He so frequently talked of the increasing expenses of housekeeping and of the perpetual demands upon his purse which a man of any consequence in the world was beyond calculation exposed to that he seemed rather to stand in need of more money himself than to have any design of giving money away In a very few weeks from the day which brought Sir <PERSON>John Middleton</PERSON> s first letter to <ORGANIZATION>Norland</ORGANIZATION> every thing was so far settled in their future abode as to enable <PERSON>Mrs Dashwood</PERSON> and her daughters to begin their journey Many were the tears shed by them in their last adieus to a place so much beloved Dear dear <ORGANIZATION>Norland</ORGANIZATION> said <PERSON>Marianne</PERSON> as she wandered alone before the house on the last evening of their being there when shall I cease to regret you when learn to feel a home elsewhere Oh happy house could you know what I suffer in now viewing you from this spot from whence perhaps I may view you no more And you ye well known trees but you will continue the same No leaf will decay because we are removed nor any branch become motionless although we can observe you no longer No you will continue the same unconscious of the pleasure or the regret you occasion and insensible of any change in those who walk under your shade But who will remain to enjoy you CHAPTER VI The first part of their journey was performed in too melancholy a disposition to be otherwise than tedious and unpleasant But as they drew towards the end of it their interest in the appearance of a country which they were to inhabit overcame their dejection and a view of <LOCATION>Barton Valley</LOCATION> as they entered it gave them cheerfulness It was a pleasant fertile spot well wooded and rich in pasture After winding along it for more than a mile they reached their own house A small green court was the whole of its demesne in front and a neat wicket gate admitted them into it As a house <LOCATION>Barton Cottage</LOCATION> though small was comfortable and compact but as a cottage it was defective for the building was regular the roof was tiled the window shutters were not painted green nor were the walls covered with honeysuckles A narrow passage led directly through the house into the garden behind On each side of the entrance was a sitting room about sixteen feet square and beyond them were the offices and the stairs Four bedrooms and two garrets formed the rest of the house It had not been built many years and was in good repair In comparison of <LOCATION>Norland</LOCATION> it was poor and small indeed but the tears which recollection called forth as they entered the house were soon dried away They were cheered by the joy of the servants on their arrival and each for the sake of the others resolved to appear happy It was very early in September the season was fine and from first seeing the place under the advantage of good weather they received an impression in its favour which was of material service in recommending it to their lasting approbation The situation of the house was good High hills rose immediately behind and at no great distance on each side some of which were open downs the others cultivated and woody The village of <LOCATION>Barton</LOCATION> was chiefly on one of these hills and formed a pleasant view from the cottage windows The prospect in front was more extensive it commanded the whole of the valley and reached into the country beyond The hills which surrounded the cottage terminated the valley in that direction under another name and in another course it branched out again between two of the steepest of them With the size and furniture of the house <PERSON>Mrs Dashwood</PERSON> was upon the whole well satisfied for though her former style of life rendered many additions to the latter indispensable yet to add and improve was a delight to her and she had at this time ready money enough to supply all that was wanted of greater elegance to the apartments As for the house itself to be sure said she it is too small for our family but we will make ourselves tolerably comfortable for the present as it is too late in the year for improvements Perhaps in the spring if I have plenty of money as I dare say I shall we may think about building These parlors are both too small for such parties of our friends as I hope to see often collected here and I have some thoughts of throwing the passage into one of them with perhaps a part of the other and so leave the remainder of that other for an entrance this with a new drawing room which may be easily added and a bed chamber and garret above will make it a very snug little cottage I could wish the stairs were handsome But one must not expect every thing though I suppose it would be no difficult matter to widen them I shall see how much I am before hand with the world in the spring and we will plan our improvements accordingly In the mean time till all these alterations could be made from the savings of an income of five hundred a year by a woman who never saved in her life they were wise enough to be contented with the house as it was and each of them was busy in arranging their particular concerns and endeavoring by placing around them books and other possessions to form themselves a home <PERSON>Marianne</PERSON> s pianoforte was unpacked and properly disposed of and <PERSON>Elinor</PERSON> s drawings were affixed to the walls of their sitting room In such employments as these they were interrupted soon after breakfast the next day by the entrance of their landlord who called to welcome them to <PERSON>Barton</PERSON> and to offer them every accommodation from his own house and garden in which theirs might at present be deficient Sir <PERSON>John Middleton</PERSON> was a good looking man about forty He had formerly visited at <LOCATION>Stanhill</LOCATION> but it was too long for his young cousins to remember him His countenance was thoroughly good humoured and his manners were as friendly as the style of his letter Their arrival seemed to afford him real satisfaction and their comfort to be an object of real solicitude to him He said much of his earnest desire of their living in the most sociable terms with his family and pressed them so cordially to dine at <LOCATION>Barton Park</LOCATION> every day till they were better settled at home that though his entreaties were carried to a point of perseverance beyond civility they could not give offence His kindness was not confined to words for within an hour after he left them a large basket full of garden stuff and fruit arrived from the park which was followed before the end of the day by a present of game He insisted moreover on conveying all their letters to and from the post for them and would not be denied the satisfaction of sending them his newspaper every day Lady <PERSON>Middleton</PERSON> had sent a very civil message by him denoting her intention of waiting on <PERSON>Mrs Dashwood</PERSON> as soon as she could be assured that her visit would be no inconvenience and as this message was answered by an invitation equally polite her ladyship was introduced to them the next day Illustration _So shy before company _ They were of course very anxious to see a person on whom so much of their comfort at <LOCATION>Barton</LOCATION> must depend and the elegance of her appearance was favourable to their wishes <PERSON>Lady Middleton</PERSON> was not more than six or seven and twenty her face was handsome her figure tall and striking and her address graceful Her manners had all the elegance which her husband s wanted But they would have been improved by some share of his frankness and warmth and her visit was long enough to detract something from their first admiration by showing that though perfectly well bred she was reserved cold and had nothing to say for herself beyond the most common place inquiry or remark Conversation however was not wanted for Sir <PERSON>John</PERSON> was very chatty and <PERSON>Lady Middleton</PERSON> had taken the wise precaution of bringing with her their eldest child a fine little boy about six years old by which means there was one subject always to be recurred to by the ladies in case of extremity for they had to enquire his name and age admire his beauty and ask him questions which his mother answered for him while he hung about her and held down his head to the great surprise of her ladyship who wondered at his being so shy before company as he could make noise enough at home On every formal visit a child ought to be of the party by way of provision for discourse In the present case it took up ten minutes to determine whether the boy were most like his father or mother and in what particular he resembled either for of course every body differed and every body was astonished at the opinion of the others An opportunity was soon to be given to the Dashwoods of debating on the rest of the children as Sir <PERSON>John</PERSON> would not leave the house without securing their promise of dining at the park the next day CHAPTER VII <LOCATION>Barton Park</LOCATION> was about half a mile from the cottage The ladies had passed near it in their way along the valley but it was screened from their view at home by the projection of a hill The house was large and handsome and the <ORGANIZATION>Middletons</ORGANIZATION> lived in a style of equal hospitality and elegance The former was for Sir <PERSON>John</PERSON> s gratification the latter for that of his lady They were scarcely ever without some friends staying with them in the house and they kept more company of every kind than any other family in the neighbourhood It was necessary to the happiness of both for however dissimilar in temper and outward behaviour they strongly resembled each other in that total want of talent and taste which confined their employments unconnected with such as society produced within a very narrow compass Sir <PERSON>John</PERSON> was a sportsman <PERSON>Lady Middleton</PERSON> a mother He hunted and shot and she humoured her children and these were their only resources <PERSON>Lady Middleton</PERSON> had the advantage of being able to spoil her children all the year round while Sir <PERSON>John</PERSON> s independent employments were in existence only half the time Continual engagements at home and abroad however supplied all the deficiencies of nature and education supported the good spirits of Sir <PERSON>John</PERSON> and gave exercise to the good breeding of his wife <PERSON>Lady Middleton</PERSON> piqued herself upon the elegance of her table and of all her domestic arrangements and from this kind of vanity was her greatest enjoyment in any of their parties But Sir <PERSON>John</PERSON> s satisfaction in society was much more real he delighted in collecting about him more young people than his house would hold and the noisier they were the better was he pleased He was a blessing to all the juvenile part of the neighbourhood for in summer he was for ever forming parties to eat cold ham and chicken out of doors and in winter his private balls were numerous enough for any young lady who was not suffering under the insatiable appetite of fifteen The arrival of a new family in the country was always a matter of joy to him and in every point of view he was charmed with the inhabitants he had now procured for his cottage at <LOCATION>Barton The Miss Dashwoods</LOCATION> were young pretty and unaffected It was enough to secure his good opinion for to be unaffected was all that a pretty girl could want to make her mind as captivating as her person The friendliness of his disposition made him happy in accommodating those whose situation might be considered in comparison with the past as unfortunate In showing kindness to his cousins therefore he had the real satisfaction of a good heart and in settling a family of females only in his cottage he had all the satisfaction of a sportsman for a sportsman though he esteems only those of his sex who are sportsmen likewise is not often desirous of encouraging their taste by admitting them to a residence within his own manor <PERSON>Mrs Dashwood</PERSON> and her daughters were met at the door of the house by Sir <PERSON>John</PERSON> who welcomed them to <LOCATION>Barton Park</LOCATION> with unaffected sincerity and as he attended them to the drawing room repeated to the young ladies the concern which the same subject had drawn from him the day before at being unable to get any smart young men to meet them They would see he said only one gentleman there besides himself a particular friend who was staying at the park but who was neither very young nor very gay He hoped they would all excuse the smallness of the party and could assure them it should never happen so again He had been to several families that morning in hopes of procuring some addition to their number but it was moonlight and every body was full of engagements Luckily Lady <PERSON>Middleton</PERSON> s mother had arrived at <LOCATION>Barton</LOCATION> within the last hour and as she was a very cheerful agreeable woman he hoped the young ladies would not find it so very dull as they might imagine The young ladies as well as their mother were perfectly satisfied with having two entire strangers of the party and wished for no more Mrs Jennings Lady <PERSON>Middleton</PERSON> s mother was a good humoured merry fat elderly woman who talked a great deal seemed very happy and rather vulgar She was full of jokes and laughter and before dinner was over had said many witty things on the subject of lovers and husbands hoped they had not left their hearts behind them in <LOCATION>Sussex</LOCATION> and pretended to see them blush whether they did or not <PERSON>Marianne</PERSON> was vexed at it for her sister s sake and turned her eyes towards <PERSON>Elinor</PERSON> to see how she bore these attacks with an earnestness which gave <PERSON>Elinor</PERSON> far more pain than could arise from such common place raillery as Mrs <PERSON>Jennings</PERSON> s Colonel <PERSON>Brandon</PERSON> the friend of Sir <PERSON>John</PERSON> seemed no more adapted by resemblance of manner to be his friend than <PERSON>Lady Middleton</PERSON> was to be his wife or <PERSON>Mrs Jennings</PERSON> to be Lady <PERSON>Middleton</PERSON> s mother He was silent and grave His appearance however was not unpleasing in spite of his being in the opinion of <PERSON>Marianne</PERSON> and <PERSON>Margaret</PERSON> an absolute old bachelor for he was on the wrong side of five and thirty but though his face was not handsome his countenance was sensible and his address was particularly gentlemanlike There was nothing in any of the party which could recommend them as companions to the Dashwoods but the cold insipidity of <PERSON>Lady Middleton</PERSON> was so particularly repulsive that in comparison of it the gravity of Colonel <PERSON>Brandon</PERSON> and even the boisterous mirth of Sir <PERSON>John</PERSON> and his mother in law was interesting Lady <PERSON>Middleton</PERSON> seemed to be roused to enjoyment only by the entrance of her four noisy children after dinner who pulled her about tore her clothes and put an end to every kind of discourse except what related to themselves In the evening as <PERSON>Marianne</PERSON> was discovered to be musical she was invited to play The instrument was unlocked every body prepared to be charmed and <PERSON>Marianne</PERSON> who sang very well at their request went through the chief of the songs which <PERSON>Lady Middleton</PERSON> had brought into the family on her marriage and which perhaps had lain ever since in the same position on the pianoforte for her ladyship had celebrated that event by giving up music although by her mother s account she had played extremely well and by her own was very fond of it <PERSON>Marianne</PERSON> s performance was highly applauded Sir <PERSON>John</PERSON> was loud in his admiration at the end of every song and as loud in his conversation with the others while every song lasted <PERSON>Lady Middleton</PERSON> frequently called him to order wondered how any one s attention could be diverted from music for a moment and asked <PERSON>Marianne</PERSON> to sing a particular song which <PERSON>Marianne</PERSON> had just finished Colonel <PERSON>Brandon</PERSON> alone of all the party heard her without being in raptures He paid her only the compliment of attention and she felt a respect for him on the occasion which the others had reasonably forfeited by their shameless want of taste His pleasure in music though it amounted not to that ecstatic delight which alone could sympathize with her own was estimable when contrasted against the horrible insensibility of the others and she was reasonable enough to allow that a man of five and thirty might well have outlived all acuteness of feeling and every exquisite power of enjoyment She was perfectly disposed to make every allowance for the colonel s advanced state of life which humanity required CHAPTER VIII Mrs <PERSON>Jennings</PERSON> was a widow with an ample jointure She had only two daughters both of whom she had lived to see respectably married and she had now therefore nothing to do but to marry all the rest of the world In the promotion of this object she was zealously active as far as her ability reached and missed no opportunity of projecting weddings among all the young people of her acquaintance She was remarkably quick in the discovery of attachments and had enjoyed the advantage of raising the blushes and the vanity of many a young lady by insinuations of her power over such a young man and this kind of discernment enabled her soon after her arrival at <PERSON>Barton</PERSON> decisively to pronounce that Colonel <PERSON>Brandon</PERSON> was very much in love with <PERSON>Marianne Dashwood</PERSON> She rather suspected it to be so on the very first evening of their being together from his listening so attentively while she sang to them and when the visit was returned by the <ORGANIZATION>Middletons</ORGANIZATION> dining at the cottage the fact was ascertained by his listening to her again It must be so She was perfectly convinced of it It would be an excellent match for _he_ was rich and _she_ was handsome <PERSON>Mrs Jennings</PERSON> had been anxious to see Colonel <PERSON>Brandon</PERSON> well married ever since her connection with Sir <PERSON>John</PERSON> first brought him to her knowledge and she was always anxious to get a good husband for every pretty girl The immediate advantage to herself was by no means inconsiderable for it supplied her with endless jokes against them both At the park she laughed at the colonel and in the cottage at Marianne To the former her raillery was probably as far as it regarded only himself perfectly indifferent but to the latter it was at first incomprehensible and when its object was understood she hardly knew whether most to laugh at its absurdity or censure its impertinence for she considered it as an unfeeling reflection on the colonel s advanced years and on his forlorn condition as an old bachelor <PERSON>Mrs Dashwood</PERSON> who could not think a man five years younger than herself so exceedingly ancient as he appeared to the youthful fancy of her daughter ventured to clear <PERSON>Mrs Jennings</PERSON> from the probability of wishing to throw ridicule on his age But at least Mamma you cannot deny the absurdity of the accusation though you may not think it intentionally ill natured Colonel <PERSON>Brandon</PERSON> is certainly younger than <PERSON>Mrs Jennings</PERSON> but he is old enough to be _my_ father and if he were ever animated enough to be in love must have long outlived every sensation of the kind It is too ridiculous When is a man to be safe from such wit if age and infirmity will not protect him Infirmity said <PERSON>Elinor</PERSON> do you call Colonel <PERSON>Brandon</PERSON> infirm I can easily suppose that his age may appear much greater to you than to my mother but you can hardly deceive yourself as to his having the use of his limbs Did not you hear him complain of the rheumatism and is not that the commonest infirmity of declining life My dearest child said her mother laughing at this rate you must be in continual terror of _my_ decay and it must seem to you a miracle that my life has been extended to the advanced age of forty Mamma you are not doing me justice I know very well that Colonel <PERSON>Brandon</PERSON> is not old enough to make his friends yet apprehensive of losing him in the course of nature He may live twenty years longer But thirty five has nothing to do with matrimony Perhaps said <PERSON>Elinor</PERSON> thirty five and seventeen had better not have any thing to do with matrimony together But if there should by any chance happen to be a woman who is single at seven and twenty I should not think Colonel <PERSON>Brandon</PERSON> s being thirty five any objection to his marrying _her_ A woman of seven and twenty said <PERSON>Marianne</PERSON> after pausing a moment can never hope to feel or inspire affection again and if her home be uncomfortable or her fortune small I can suppose that she might bring herself to submit to the offices of a nurse for the sake of the provision and security of a wife In his marrying such a woman therefore there would be nothing unsuitable It would be a compact of convenience and the world would be satisfied In my eyes it would be no marriage at all but that would be nothing To me it would seem only a commercial exchange in which each wished to be benefited at the expense of the other It would be impossible I know replied <PERSON>Elinor</PERSON> to convince you that a woman of seven and twenty could feel for a man of thirty five anything near enough to love to make him a desirable companion to her But I must object to your dooming Colonel <PERSON>Brandon</PERSON> and his wife to the constant confinement of a sick chamber merely because he chanced to complain yesterday a very cold damp day of a slight rheumatic feel in one of his shoulders But he talked of flannel waistcoats said <PERSON>Marianne</PERSON> and with me a flannel waistcoat is invariably connected with aches cramps rheumatisms and every species of ailment that can afflict the old and the feeble Had he been only in a violent fever you would not have despised him half so much Confess <PERSON>Marianne</PERSON> is not there something interesting to you in the flushed cheek hollow eye and quick pulse of a fever Soon after this upon <PERSON>Elinor</PERSON> s leaving the room <PERSON>Mamma</PERSON> said <PERSON>Marianne</PERSON> I have an alarm on the subject of illness which I cannot conceal from you I am sure <PERSON>Edward Ferrars</PERSON> is not well We have now been here almost a fortnight and yet he does not come Nothing but real indisposition could occasion this extraordinary delay What else can detain him at <LOCATION>Norland</LOCATION> Had you any idea of his coming so soon said <PERSON>Mrs Dashwood</PERSON> I had none On the contrary if I have felt any anxiety at all on the subject it has been in recollecting that he sometimes showed a want of pleasure and readiness in accepting my invitation when I talked of his coming to <PERSON>Barton</PERSON> Does <PERSON>Elinor</PERSON> expect him already I have never mentioned it to her but of course she must I rather think you are mistaken for when I was talking to her yesterday of getting a new grate for the spare bed chamber she observed that there was no immediate hurry for it as it was not likely that the room would be wanted for some time How strange this is what can be the meaning of it But the whole of their behaviour to each other has been unaccountable How cold how composed were their last adieus How languid their conversation the last evening of their being together In <PERSON>Edward</PERSON> s farewell there was no distinction between <PERSON>Elinor</PERSON> and me it was the good wishes of an affectionate brother to both Twice did I leave them purposely together in the course of the last morning and each time did he most unaccountably follow me out of the room And <PERSON>Elinor</PERSON> in quitting <LOCATION>Norland</LOCATION> and <PERSON>Edward</PERSON> cried not as I did Even now her self command is invariable When is she dejected or melancholy When does she try to avoid society or appear restless and dissatisfied in it CHAPTER IX The Dashwoods were now settled at <LOCATION>Barton</LOCATION> with tolerable comfort to themselves The house and the garden with all the objects surrounding them were now become familiar and the ordinary pursuits which had given to <LOCATION>Norland</LOCATION> half its charms were engaged in again with far greater enjoyment than <ORGANIZATION>Norland</ORGANIZATION> had been able to afford since the loss of their father Sir <PERSON>John Middleton</PERSON> who called on them every day for the first fortnight and who was not in the habit of seeing much occupation at home could not conceal his amazement on finding them always employed Their visitors except those from <LOCATION>Barton Park</LOCATION> were not many for in spite of Sir <PERSON>John</PERSON> s urgent entreaties that they would mix more in the neighbourhood and repeated assurances of his carriage being always at their service the independence of <PERSON>Mrs Dashwood</PERSON> s spirit overcame the wish of society for her children and she was resolute in declining to visit any family beyond the distance of a walk There were but few who could be so classed and it was not all of them that were attainable About a mile and a half from the cottage along the narrow winding valley of <LOCATION>Allenham</LOCATION> which issued from that of <PERSON>Barton</PERSON> as formerly described the girls had in one of their earliest walks discovered an ancient respectable looking mansion which by reminding them a little of <LOCATION>Norland</LOCATION> interested their imagination and made them wish to be better acquainted with it But they learnt on enquiry that its possessor an elderly lady of very good character was unfortunately too infirm to mix with the world and never stirred from home The whole country about them abounded in beautiful walks The high downs which invited them from almost every window of the cottage to seek the exquisite enjoyment of air on their summits were a happy alternative when the dirt of the valleys beneath shut up their superior beauties and towards one of these hills did <PERSON>Marianne</PERSON> and <PERSON>Margaret</PERSON> one memorable morning direct their steps attracted by the partial sunshine of a showery sky and unable longer to bear the confinement which the settled rain of the two preceding days had occasioned The weather was not tempting enough to draw the two others from their pencil and their book in spite of <PERSON>Marianne</PERSON> s declaration that the day would be lastingly fair and that every threatening cloud would be drawn off from their hills and the two girls set off together They gaily ascended the downs rejoicing in their own penetration at every glimpse of blue sky and when they caught in their faces the animating gales of a high south westerly wind they pitied the fears which had prevented their mother and <PERSON>Elinor</PERSON> from sharing such delightful sensations Is there a felicity in the world said <PERSON>Marianne</PERSON> superior to this <PERSON>Margaret</PERSON> we will walk here at least two hours <PERSON>Margaret</PERSON> agreed and they pursued their way against the wind resisting it with laughing delight for about twenty minutes longer when suddenly the clouds united over their heads and a driving rain set full in their face Chagrined and surprised they were obliged though unwillingly to turn back for no shelter was nearer than their own house One consolation however remained for them to which the exigence of the moment gave more than usual propriety it was that of running with all possible speed down the steep side of the hill which led immediately to their garden gate They set off <PERSON>Marianne</PERSON> had at first the advantage but a false step brought her suddenly to the ground and <PERSON>Margaret</PERSON> unable to stop herself to assist her was involuntarily hurried along and reached the bottom in safety A gentleman carrying a gun with two pointers playing round him was passing up the hill and within a few yards of <PERSON>Marianne</PERSON> when her accident happened He put down his gun and ran to her assistance She had raised herself from the ground but her foot had been twisted in her fall and she was scarcely able to stand The gentleman offered his services and perceiving that her modesty declined what her situation rendered necessary took her up in his arms without farther delay and carried her down the hill Then passing through the garden the gate of which had been left open by <PERSON>Margaret</PERSON> he bore her directly into the house whither <PERSON>Margaret</PERSON> was just arrived and quitted not his hold till he had seated her in a chair in the parlour <PERSON>Elinor</PERSON> and her mother rose up in amazement at their entrance and while the eyes of both were fixed on him with an evident wonder and a secret admiration which equally sprung from his appearance he apologized for his intrusion by relating its cause in a manner so frank and so graceful that his person which was uncommonly handsome received additional charms from his voice and expression Had he been even old ugly and vulgar the gratitude and kindness of <PERSON>Mrs Dashwood</PERSON> would have been secured by any act of attention to her child but the influence of youth beauty and elegance gave an interest to the action which came home to her feelings She thanked him again and again and with a sweetness of address which always attended her invited him to be seated But this he declined as he was dirty and wet <PERSON>Mrs Dashwood</PERSON> then begged to know to whom she was obliged His name he replied was <PERSON>Willoughby</PERSON> and his present home was at <LOCATION>Allenham</LOCATION> from whence he hoped she would allow him the honour of calling tomorrow to enquire after Miss Dashwood The honour was readily granted and he then departed to make himself still more interesting in the midst of a heavy rain His manly beauty and more than common gracefulness were instantly the theme of general admiration and the laugh which his gallantry raised against <PERSON>Marianne</PERSON> received particular spirit from his exterior attractions <PERSON>Marianne</PERSON> herself had seen less of his person than the rest for the confusion which crimsoned over her face on his lifting her up had robbed her of the power of regarding him after their entering the house But she had seen enough of him to join in all the admiration of the others and with an energy which always adorned her praise His person and air were equal to what her fancy had ever drawn for the hero of a favourite story and in his carrying her into the house with so little previous formality there was a rapidity of thought which particularly recommended the action to her Every circumstance belonging to him was interesting His name was good his residence was in their favourite village and she soon found out that of all manly dresses a shooting jacket was the most becoming Her imagination was busy her reflections were pleasant and the pain of a sprained ankle was disregarded Sir <PERSON>John</PERSON> called on them as soon as the next interval of fair weather that morning allowed him to get out of doors and <PERSON>Marianne</PERSON> s accident being related to him he was eagerly asked whether he knew any gentleman of the name of <PERSON>Willoughby</PERSON> at <PERSON>Allenham Willoughby</PERSON> cried Sir <PERSON>John</PERSON> what is _he_ in the country That is good news however I will ride over tomorrow and ask him to dinner on Thursday You know him then said <PERSON>Mrs Dashwood Know</PERSON> him to be sure I do Why he is down here every year And what sort of a young man is he As good a kind of fellow as ever lived I assure you A very decent shot and there is not a bolder rider in <LOCATION>England</LOCATION> And is that all you can say for him cried <PERSON>Marianne</PERSON> indignantly But what are his manners on more intimate acquaintance What his pursuits his talents and genius Sir <PERSON>John</PERSON> was rather puzzled Upon my soul said he I do not know much about him as to all _that _ But he is a pleasant good humoured fellow and has got the nicest little black bitch of a pointer I ever saw Was she out with him today But <PERSON>Marianne</PERSON> could no more satisfy him as to the colour of Mr <PERSON>Willoughby</PERSON> s pointer than he could describe to her the shades of his mind But who is he said <PERSON>Elinor Where</PERSON> does he come from Has he a house at <LOCATION>Allenham</LOCATION> On this point Sir <PERSON>John</PERSON> could give more certain intelligence and he told them that Mr <PERSON>Willoughby</PERSON> had no property of his own in the country that he resided there only while he was visiting the old lady at <ORGANIZATION>Allenham Court</ORGANIZATION> to whom he was related and whose possessions he was to inherit adding Yes yes he is very well worth catching I can tell you Miss <PERSON>Dashwood</PERSON> he has a pretty little estate of his own in <LOCATION>Somersetshire</LOCATION> besides and if I were you I would not give him up to my younger sister in spite of all this tumbling down hills Miss <PERSON>Marianne</PERSON> must not expect to have all the men to herself <PERSON>Brandon</PERSON> will be jealous if she does not take care I do not believe said <PERSON>Mrs Dashwood</PERSON> with a good humoured smile that Mr <PERSON>Willoughby</PERSON> will be incommoded by the attempts of either of _my_ daughters towards what you call _catching him _ It is not an employment to which they have been brought up Men are very safe with us let them be ever so rich I am glad to find however from what you say that he is a respectable young man and one whose acquaintance will not be ineligible He is as good a sort of fellow I believe as ever lived repeated Sir <PERSON>John</PERSON> I remember last Christmas at a little hop at the park he danced from eight o clock till four without once sitting down Did he indeed cried <PERSON>Marianne</PERSON> with sparkling eyes and with elegance with spirit Yes and he was up again at eight to ride to covert That is what I like that is what a young man ought to be Whatever be his pursuits his eagerness in them should know no moderation and leave him no sense of fatigue Aye aye I see how it will be said Sir <PERSON>John</PERSON> I see how it will be You will be setting your cap at him now and never think of poor <PERSON>Brandon That</PERSON> is an expression Sir <PERSON>John</PERSON> said <PERSON>Marianne</PERSON> warmly which I particularly dislike I abhor every common place phrase by which wit is intended and setting one s cap at a man or making a conquest are the most odious of all Their tendency is gross and illiberal and if their construction could ever be deemed clever time has long ago destroyed all its ingenuity Sir <PERSON>John</PERSON> did not much understand this reproof but he laughed as heartily as if he did and then replied Ay you will make conquests enough I dare say one way or other Poor <PERSON>Brandon</PERSON> he is quite smitten already and he is very well worth setting your cap at I can tell you in spite of all this tumbling about and spraining of ankles CHAPTER X <PERSON>Marianne</PERSON> s preserver as <PERSON>Margaret</PER