<ner>The Project Gutenberg EBook of <PERSON>Shirley</PERSON> by <ORGANIZATION>Charlotte Bront</ORGANIZATION> This eBook is for the use of anyone anywhere at no cost and with almost no restrictions whatsoever You may copy it give it away or re use it under the terms of the <ORGANIZATION>Project Gutenberg License</ORGANIZATION> included with this eBook or online at www gutenberg net Title Shirley Author Charlotte Bront Release Date November 16 2009 EBook 30486 Last updated July 16 2011 Language English Character set encoding UTF 8 START OF THIS PROJECT GUTENBERG EBOOK SHIRLEY Produced by <PERSON>Brenda Lewis Fox</PERSON> in the Stars and the <ORGANIZATION>Online Distributed Proofreading Canada Team</ORGANIZATION> at http www pgdpcanada net Illustration <PERSON>Moore</PERSON> placed his hand on his cousin s shoulder stooped and left a kiss on her forehead <PERSON>SHIRLEY</PERSON> BY <ORGANIZATION>CHARLOTTE BRONT T Nelson amp Sons</ORGANIZATION> CONTENTS I LEVITICAL 3 II THE WAGONS 16 III <PERSON>MR YORKE</PERSON> 31 IV <PERSON>MR YORKE</PERSON> CONTINUED 40 V HOLLOW S COTTAGE 51 <ORGANIZATION>VI CORIOLANUS</ORGANIZATION> 66 VII THE CURATES AT TEA 85 VIII NOAH AND MOSES 110 IX BRIARMAINS 125 X OLD MAIDS 147 XI FIELDHEAD 164 XII <PERSON>SHIRLEY</PERSON> AND <PERSON>CAROLINE</PERSON> 181 XIII FURTHER COMMUNICATIONS ON BUSINESS 201 XIV <PERSON>SHIRLEY</PERSON> SEEKS TO BE SAVED BY WORKS 226 XV <PERSON>MR DONNE</PERSON> S EXODUS 239 XVI WHITSUNTIDE 253 XVII THE SCHOOL FEAST 264 XVIII WHICH THE GENTEEL READER IS RECOMMENDED TO SKIP LOW PERSONS BEING HERE INTRODUCED 279 XIX A SUMMER NIGHT 290 XX TO MORROW 306 XXI MRS PRYOR 319 XXII TWO LIVES 336 XXIII AN EVENING OUT 346 XXIV THE VALLEY OF THE SHADOW OF DEATH 365 XXV THE WEST WIND BLOWS 384 XXVI OLD COPY BOOKS 392 XXVII THE FIRST BLUESTOCKING 410 XXVIII PH BE 433 XXIX <PERSON>LOUIS MOORE</PERSON> 453 XXX RUSHEDGE A CONFESSIONAL 461 XXXI UNCLE AND NIECE 475 XXXII THE SCHOOLBOY AND THE WOOD NYMPH 491 XXXIII MARTIN S TACTICS 502 XXXIV CASE OF DOMESTIC PERSECUTION REMARKABLE INSTANCE OF PIOUS PERSEVERANCE IN THE DISCHARGE OF RELIGIOUS DUTIES 513 XXXV WHEREIN MATTERS MAKE SOME PROGRESS BUT NOT MUCH 521 XXXVI WRITTEN IN THE SCHOOLROOM 534 XXXVII THE WINDING UP 555 SHIRLEY CHAPTER I LEVITICAL Of late years an abundant shower of curates has fallen upon the north of <LOCATION>England</LOCATION> they lie very thick on the hills every parish has one or more of them they are young enough to be very active and ought to be doing a great deal of good But not of late years are we about to speak we are going back to the beginning of this century late years present years are dusty sunburnt hot arid we will evade the noon forget it in siesta pass the midday in slumber and dream of dawn If you think from this prelude that anything like a romance is preparing for you reader you never were more mistaken Do you anticipate sentiment and poetry and reverie Do you expect passion and stimulus and melodrama Calm your expectations reduce them to a lowly standard Something real cool and solid lies before you something unromantic as Monday morning when all who have work wake with the consciousness that they must rise and betake themselves thereto It is not positively affirmed that you shall not have a taste of the exciting perhaps towards the middle and close of the meal but it is resolved that the first dish set upon the table shall be one that a Catholic ay even an <ORGANIZATION>Anglo Catholic</ORGANIZATION> might eat on Good Friday in Passion Week it shall be cold lentils and vinegar without oil it shall be unleavened bread with bitter herbs and no roast lamb Of late years I say an abundant shower of curates has fallen upon the north of <LOCATION>England</LOCATION> but in eighteen hundred eleven twelve that affluent rain had not descended Curates were scarce then there was no Pastoral Aid no Additional Curates Society to stretch a helping hand to worn out old rectors and incumbents and give them the wherewithal to pay a vigorous young colleague from <LOCATION>Oxford</LOCATION> or <LOCATION>Cambridge</LOCATION> The present successors of the apostles disciples of Dr <PERSON>Pusey</PERSON> and tools of the Propaganda were at that time being hatched under cradle blankets or undergoing regeneration by nursery baptism in wash hand basins You could not have guessed by looking at any one of them that the Italian ironed double frills of its net cap surrounded the brows of a preordained specially sanctified successor of <ORGANIZATION>St Paul St Peter</ORGANIZATION> or St John nor could you have foreseen in the folds of its long night gown the white surplice in which it was hereafter cruelly to exercise the souls of its parishioners and strangely to nonplus its old fashioned vicar by flourishing aloft in a pulpit the shirt like raiment which had never before waved higher than the reading desk Yet even in those days of scarcity there were curates the precious plant was rare but it might be found A certain favoured district in the <LOCATION>West Riding of Yorkshire</LOCATION> could boast three rods of <PERSON>Aaron</PERSON> blossoming within a circuit of twenty miles You shall see them reader Step into this neat garden house on the skirts of <LOCATION>Whinbury</LOCATION> walk forward into the little parlour There they are at dinner Allow me to introduce them to you Mr <PERSON>Donne</PERSON> curate of Whinbury Mr <PERSON>Malone</PERSON> curate of Briarfield Mr Sweeting curate of Nunnely These are Mr <PERSON>Donne</PERSON> s lodgings being the habitation of one <PERSON>John Gale</PERSON> a small clothier Mr <PERSON>Donne</PERSON> has kindly invited his brethren to regale with him You and I will join the party see what is to be seen and hear what is to be heard At present however they are only eating and while they eat we will talk aside These gentlemen are in the bloom of youth they possess all the activity of that interesting age an activity which their moping old vicars would fain turn into the channel of their pastoral duties often expressing a wish to see it expended in a diligent superintendence of the schools and in frequent visits to the sick of their respective parishes But the youthful <PERSON>Levites</PERSON> feel this to be dull work they prefer lavishing their energies on a course of proceeding which though to other eyes it appear more heavy with _ennui_ more cursed with monotony than the toil of the weaver at his loom seems to yield them an unfailing supply of enjoyment and occupation I allude to a rushing backwards and forwards amongst themselves to and from their respective lodgings not a round but a triangle of visits which they keep up all the year through in winter spring summer and autumn Season and weather make no difference with unintelligible zeal they dare snow and hail wind and rain mire and dust to go and dine or drink tea or sup with each other What attracts them it would be difficult to say It is not friendship for whenever they meet they quarrel It is not religion the thing is never named amongst them theology they may discuss occasionally but piety never It is not the love of eating and drinking each might have as good a joint and pudding tea as potent and toast as succulent at his own lodgings as is served to him at his brother s <PERSON>Mrs Gale Mrs Hogg</PERSON> and <PERSON>Mrs Whipp</PERSON> their respective landladies affirm that it is just for naught else but to give folk trouble By folk the good ladies of course mean themselves for indeed they are kept in a continual fry by this system of mutual invasion Mr <PERSON>Donne</PERSON> and his guests as I have said are at dinner <PERSON>Mrs Gale</PERSON> waits on them but a spark of the hot kitchen fire is in her eye She considers that the privilege of inviting a friend to a meal occasionally without additional charge a privilege included in the terms on which she lets her lodgings has been quite sufficiently exercised of late The present week is yet but at Thursday and on Monday Mr <PERSON>Malone</PERSON> the curate of <LOCATION>Briarfield</LOCATION> came to breakfast and stayed dinner on Tuesday Mr <PERSON>Malone</PERSON> and Mr <PERSON>Sweeting</PERSON> of Nunnely came to tea remained to supper occupied the spare bed and favoured her with their company to breakfast on Wednesday morning now on Thursday they are both here at dinner and she is almost certain they will stay all night C en est trop she would say if she could speak French Mr <PERSON>Sweeting</PERSON> is mincing the slice of roast beef on his plate and complaining that it is very tough Mr <PERSON>Donne</PERSON> says the beer is flat Ay that is the worst of it if they would only be civil <PERSON>Mrs Gale</PERSON> wouldn t mind it so much if they would only seem satisfied with what they get she wouldn t care but these young parsons is so high and so scornful they set everybody beneath their fit They treat her with less than civility just because she doesn t keep a servant but does the work of the house herself as her mother did afore her then they are always speaking against <ORGANIZATION>Yorkshire</ORGANIZATION> ways and <ORGANIZATION>Yorkshire</ORGANIZATION> folk and by that very token <PERSON>Mrs Gale</PERSON> does not believe one of them to be a real gentleman or come of gentle kin The old parsons is worth the whole lump of college lads they know what belongs to good manners and is kind to high and low More bread cries Mr <PERSON>Malone</PERSON> in a tone which though prolonged but to utter two syllables proclaims him at once a native of the land of shamrocks and potatoes <PERSON>Mrs Gale</PERSON> hates Mr <PERSON>Malone</PERSON> more than either of the other two but she fears him also for he is a tall strongly built personage with real Irish legs and arms and a face as genuinely national not the Milesian face not <PERSON>Daniel O Connell</PERSON> s style but the high featured North American Indian sort of visage which belongs to a certain class of the Irish gentry and has a petrified and proud look better suited to the owner of an estate of slaves than to the landlord of a free peasantry Mr <PERSON>Malone</PERSON> s father termed himself a gentleman he was poor and in debt and besottedly arrogant and his son was like him <PERSON>Mrs Gale</PERSON> offered the loaf Cut it woman said her guest and the woman cut it accordingly Had she followed her inclinations she would have cut the parson also her <ORGANIZATION>Yorkshire</ORGANIZATION> soul revolted absolutely from his manner of command The curates had good appetites and though the beef was tough they ate a great deal of it They swallowed too a tolerable allowance of the flat beer while a dish of <ORGANIZATION>Yorkshire</ORGANIZATION> pudding and two tureens of vegetables disappeared like leaves before locusts The cheese too received distinguished marks of their attention and a spice cake which followed by way of dessert vanished like a vision and was no more found Its elegy was chanted in the kitchen by <PERSON>Abraham Mrs Gale</PERSON> s son and heir a youth of six summers he had reckoned upon the reversion thereof and when his mother brought down the empty platter he lifted up his voice and wept sore The curates meantime sat and sipped their wine a liquor of unpretending vintage moderately enjoyed Mr <PERSON>Malone</PERSON> indeed would much rather have had whisky but Mr <PERSON>Donne</PERSON> being an Englishman did not keep the beverage While they sipped they argued not on politics nor on philosophy nor on literature these topics were now as ever totally without interest for them not even on theology practical or doctrinal but on minute points of ecclesiastical discipline frivolities which seemed empty as bubbles to all save themselves Mr <PERSON>Malone</PERSON> who contrived to secure two glasses of wine when his brethren contented themselves with one waxed by degrees hilarious after his fashion that is he grew a little insolent said rude things in a hectoring tone and laughed clamorously at his own brilliancy Each of his companions became in turn his butt <PERSON>Malone</PERSON> had a stock of jokes at their service which he was accustomed to serve out regularly on convivial occasions like the present seldom varying his wit for which indeed there was no necessity as he never appeared to consider himself monotonous and did not at all care what others thought Mr <PERSON>Donne</PERSON> he favoured with hints about his extreme meagreness allusions to his turned up nose cutting sarcasms on a certain threadbare chocolate surtout which that gentleman was accustomed to sport whenever it rained or seemed likely to rain and criticisms on a choice set of cockney phrases and modes of pronunciation Mr <PERSON>Donne</PERSON> s own property and certainly deserving of remark for the elegance and finish they communicated to his style Mr <PERSON>Sweeting</PERSON> was bantered about his stature he was a little man a mere boy in height and breadth compared with the athletic <PERSON>Malone</PERSON> rallied on his musical accomplishments he played the flute and sang hymns like a seraph some young ladies of his parish thought sneered at as the ladies pet teased about his mamma and sisters for whom poor Mr <PERSON>Sweeting</PERSON> had some lingering regard and of whom he was foolish enough now and then to speak in the presence of the priestly Paddy from whose anatomy the bowels of natural affection had somehow been omitted The victims met these attacks each in his own way Mr <PERSON>Donne</PERSON> with a stilted self complacency and half sullen phlegm the sole props of his otherwise somewhat rickety dignity Mr <PERSON>Sweeting</PERSON> with the indifference of a light easy disposition which never professed to have any dignity to maintain When <PERSON>Malone</PERSON> s raillery became rather too offensive which it soon did they joined in an attempt to turn the tables on him by asking him how many boys had shouted Irish <PERSON>Peter</PERSON> after him as he came along the road that day <PERSON>Malone</PERSON> s name was <PERSON>Peter the Rev Peter Augustus Malone</PERSON> requesting to be informed whether it was the mode in <LOCATION>Ireland</LOCATION> for clergymen to carry loaded pistols in their pockets and a shillelah in their hands when they made pastoral visits inquiring the signification of such words as vele firrum hellum storrum so Mr <PERSON>Malone</PERSON> invariably pronounced veil firm helm storm and employing such other methods of retaliation as the innate refinement of their minds suggested This of course would not do <PERSON>Malone</PERSON> being neither good natured nor phlegmatic was presently in a towering passion He vociferated gesticulated <PERSON>Donne</PERSON> and <PERSON>Sweeting</PERSON> laughed He reviled them as Saxons and snobs at the very top pitch of his high Celtic voice they taunted him with being the native of a conquered land He menaced rebellion in the name of his counthry vented bitter hatred against English rule they spoke of rags beggary and pestilence The little parlour was in an uproar you would have thought a duel must follow such virulent abuse it seemed a wonder that Mr and <PERSON>Mrs Gale</PERSON> did not take alarm at the noise and send for a constable to keep the peace But they were accustomed to such demonstrations they well knew that the curates never dined or took tea together without a little exercise of the sort and were quite easy as to consequences knowing that these clerical quarrels were as harmless as they were noisy that they resulted in nothing and that on whatever terms the curates might part to night they would be sure to meet the best friends in the world to morrow morning As the worthy pair were sitting by their kitchen fire listening to the repeated and sonorous contact of <PERSON>Malone</PERSON> s fist with the mahogany plane of the parlour table and to the consequent start and jingle of decanters and glasses following each assault to the mocking laughter of the allied English disputants and the stuttering declamation of the isolated Hibernian as they thus sat a foot was heard on the outer door step and the knocker quivered to a sharp appeal Mr <PERSON>Gale</PERSON> went and opened Whom have you upstairs in the parlour asked a voice a rather remarkable voice nasal in tone abrupt in utterance O Mr Helstone is it you sir I could hardly see you for the darkness it is so soon dark now Will you walk in sir I want to know first whether it is worth my while walking in Whom have you upstairs The curates sir What all of them Yes sir Been dining here Yes sir That will do With these words a person entered a middle aged man in black He walked straight across the kitchen to an inner door opened it inclined his head forward and stood listening There was something to listen to for the noise above was just then louder than ever Hey he ejaculated to himself then turning to Mr <PERSON>Gale</PERSON> Have you often this sort of work Mr <PERSON>Gale</PERSON> had been a churchwarden and was indulgent to the clergy They re young you know sir they re young said he deprecatingly Young They want caning Bad boys bad boys And if you were a Dissenter <PERSON>John Gale</PERSON> instead of being a good Churchman they d do the like they d expose themselves but I ll By way of finish to this sentence he passed through the inner door drew it after him and mounted the stair Again he listened a few minutes when he arrived at the upper room Making entrance without warning he stood before the curates And they were silent they were transfixed and so was the invader He a personage short of stature but straight of port and bearing on broad shoulders a hawk s head beak and eye the whole surmounted by a Rehoboam or shovel hat which he did not seem to think it necessary to lift or remove before the presence in which he then stood _he_ folded his arms on his chest and surveyed his young friends if friends they were much at his leisure What he began delivering his words in a voice no longer nasal but deep more than deep a voice made purposely hollow and cavernous what has the miracle of <LOCATION>Pentecost</LOCATION> been renewed Have the cloven tongues come down again Where are they The sound filled the whole house just now I heard the seventeen languages in full action Parthians and Medes and Elamites the dwellers in <LOCATION>Mesopotamia</LOCATION> and in <LOCATION>Judea</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Cappadocia</LOCATION> in Pontus and <LOCATION>Asia Phrygia</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Pamphylia</LOCATION> in <LOCATION>Egypt</LOCATION> and in the parts of <LOCATION>Libya</LOCATION> about <LOCATION>Cyrene</LOCATION> strangers of <LOCATION>Rome</LOCATION> Jews and proselytes Cretes and Arabians every one of these must have had its representative in this room two minutes since I beg your pardon Mr <PERSON>Helstone</PERSON> began Mr <PERSON>Donne</PERSON> take a seat pray sir Have a glass of wine His civilities received no answer The falcon in the black coat proceeded What do I talk about the gift of tongues Gift indeed I mistook the chapter and book and Testament gospel for law Acts for Genesis the city of <LOCATION>Jerusalem</LOCATION> for the plain of Shinar It was no gift but the confusion of tongues which has gabbled me deaf as a post _You_ apostles What you three Certainly not three presumptuous Babylonish masons neither more nor less I assure you sir we were only having a little chat together over a glass of wine after a friendly dinner settling the Dissenters Oh settling the Dissenters were you Was <PERSON>Malone</PERSON> settling the Dissenters It sounded to me much more like settling his co apostles You were quarrelling together making almost as much noise you three alone as <PERSON>Moses Barraclough</PERSON> the preaching tailor and all his hearers are making in the Methodist chapel down yonder where they are in the thick of a revival I know whose fault it is It is yours Malone Mine sir Yours sir <PERSON>Donne</PERSON> and <PERSON>Sweeting</PERSON> were quiet before you came and would be quiet if you were gone I wish when you crossed the Channel you had left your Irish habits behind you <LOCATION>Dublin</LOCATION> student ways won t do here The proceedings which might pass unnoticed in a wild bog and mountain district in <LOCATION>Connaught</LOCATION> will in a decent English parish bring disgrace on those who indulge in them and what is far worse on the sacred institution of which they are merely the humble appendages There was a certain dignity in the little elderly gentleman s manner of rebuking these youths though it was not perhaps quite the dignity most appropriate to the occasion Mr <PERSON>Helstone</PERSON> standing straight as a ramrod looking keen as a kite presented despite his clerical hat black coat and gaiters more the air of a veteran officer chiding his subalterns than of a venerable priest exhorting his sons in the faith Gospel mildness apostolic benignity never seemed to have breathed their influence over that keen brown visage but firmness had fixed the features and sagacity had carved her own lines about them I met <PERSON>Supplehough</PERSON> he continued plodding through the mud this wet night going to preach at <LOCATION>Milldean</LOCATION> opposition shop As I told you I heard <PERSON>Barraclough</PERSON> bellowing in the midst of a conventicle like a possessed bull and I find _you_ gentlemen tarrying over your half pint of muddy port wine and scolding like angry old women No wonder <PERSON>Supplehough</PERSON> should have dipped sixteen adult converts in a day which he did a fortnight since no wonder <PERSON>Barraclough</PERSON> scamp and hypocrite as he is should attract all the weaver girls in their flowers and ribbons to witness how much harder are his knuckles than the wooden brim of his tub as little wonder that _you_ when you are left to yourselves without your rectors myself and <PERSON>Hall</PERSON> and <LOCATION>Boultby</LOCATION> to back you should too often perform the holy service of our church to bare walls and read your bit of a dry discourse to the clerk and the organist and the beadle But enough of the subject I came to see <PERSON>Malone</PERSON> I have an errand unto thee O captain What is it inquired <PERSON>Malone</PERSON> discontentedly There can be no funeral to take at this time of day Have you any arms about you Arms sir yes and legs And he advanced the mighty members Bah weapons I mean I have the pistols you gave me yourself I never part with them I lay them ready cocked on a chair by my bedside at night I have my blackthorn Very good Will you go to Hollow s Mill What is stirring at Hollow s Mill Nothing as yet nor perhaps will be but <PERSON>Moore</PERSON> is alone there He has sent all the workmen he can trust to <LOCATION>Stilbro</LOCATION> there are only two women left about the place It would be a nice opportunity for any of his well wishers to pay him a visit if they knew how straight the path was made before them I am none of his well wishers sir I don t care for him <PERSON>Soh Malone</PERSON> you are afraid You know me better than that If I really thought there was a chance of a row I would go but <PERSON>Moore</PERSON> is a strange shy man whom I never pretend to understand and for the sake of his sweet company only I would not stir a step But there _is_ a chance of a row if a positive riot does not take place of which indeed I see no signs yet it is unlikely this night will pass quite tranquilly You know <PERSON>Moore</PERSON> has resolved to have new machinery and he expects two wagon loads of frames and shears from <LOCATION>Stilbro</LOCATION> this evening Scott the overlooker and a few picked men are gone to fetch them They will bring them in safely and quietly enough sir <PERSON>Moore</PERSON> says so and affirms he wants nobody Some one however he must have if it were only to bear evidence in case anything should happen I call him very careless He sits in the counting house with the shutters unclosed he goes out here and there after dark wanders right up the hollow down <LOCATION>Fieldhead Lane</LOCATION> among the plantations just as if he were the darling of the neighbourhood or being as he is its detestation bore a charmed life as they say in tale books He takes no warning from the fate of <PERSON>Pearson</PERSON> nor from that of <PERSON>Armitage</PERSON> shot one in his own house and the other on the moor But he should take warning sir and use precautions too interposed Mr <PERSON>Sweeting</PERSON> and I think he would if he heard what I heard the other day What did you hear <PERSON>Davy You</PERSON> know <PERSON>Mike Hartley</PERSON> sir The Antinomian weaver Yes When <PERSON>Mike</PERSON> has been drinking for a few weeks together he generally winds up by a visit to Nunnely vicarage to tell Mr <PERSON>Hall</PERSON> a piece of his mind about his sermons to denounce the horrible tendency of his doctrine of works and warn him that he and all his hearers are sitting in outer darkness Well that has nothing to do with <PERSON>Moore</PERSON> Besides being an Antinomian he is a violent Jacobin and leveller sir I know When he is very drunk his mind is always running on regicide <PERSON>Mike</PERSON> is not unacquainted with history and it is rich to hear him going over the list of tyrants of whom as he says the revenger of blood has obtained satisfaction The fellow exults strangely in murder done on crowned heads or on any head for political reasons I have already heard it hinted that he seems to have a queer hankering after <PERSON>Moore</PERSON> Is that what you allude to Sweeting You use the proper term sir Mr <PERSON>Hall</PERSON> thinks <PERSON>Mike</PERSON> has no personal hatred of <PERSON>Moore Mike</PERSON> says he even likes to talk to him and run after him but he has a _hankering_ that <PERSON>Moore</PERSON> should be made an example of He was extolling him to Mr <PERSON>Hall</PERSON> the other day as the mill owner with the most brains in <LOCATION>Yorkshire</LOCATION> and for that reason he affirms <PERSON>Moore</PERSON> should be chosen as a sacrifice an oblation of a sweet savour Is <PERSON>Mike Hartley</PERSON> in his right mind do you think sir inquired <PERSON>Sweeting</PERSON> simply Can t tell <PERSON>Davy He</PERSON> may be crazed or he may be only crafty or perhaps a little of both He talks of seeing visions sir Ay He is a very <PERSON>Ezekiel</PERSON> or <PERSON>Daniel</PERSON> for visions He came just when I was going to bed last Friday night to describe one that had been revealed to him in <LOCATION>Nunnely Park</LOCATION> that very afternoon Tell it sir What was it urged <PERSON>Sweeting Davy</PERSON> thou hast an enormous organ of wonder in thy cranium <PERSON>Malone</PERSON> you see has none Neither murders nor visions interest him See what a big vacant <ORGANIZATION>Saph</ORGANIZATION> he looks at this moment <ORGANIZATION>Saph</ORGANIZATION> Who was <ORGANIZATION>Saph</ORGANIZATION> sir I thought you would not know You may find it out It is biblical I know nothing more of him than his name and race but from a boy upwards I have always attached a personality to <ORGANIZATION>Saph</ORGANIZATION> Depend on it he was honest heavy and luckless He met his end at Gob by the hand of Sibbechai But the vision sir <PERSON>Davy</PERSON> thou shalt hear <PERSON>Donne</PERSON> is biting his nails and <PERSON>Malone</PERSON> yawning so I will tell it but to thee <PERSON>Mike</PERSON> is out of work like many others unfortunately Mr Grame Sir <PERSON>Philip Nunnely</PERSON> s steward gave him a job about the priory According to his account <PERSON>Mike</PERSON> was busy hedging rather late in the afternoon but before dark when he heard what he thought was a band at a distance bugles fifes and the sound of a trumpet it came from the forest and he wondered that there should be music there He looked up All amongst the trees he saw moving objects red like poppies or white like may blossom The wood was full of them they poured out and filled the park He then perceived they were soldiers thousands and tens of thousands but they made no more noise than a swarm of midges on a summer evening They formed in order he affirmed and marched regiment after regiment across the park He followed them to Nunnely Common the music still played soft and distant On the common he watched them go through a number of evolutions A man clothed in scarlet stood in the centre and directed them They extended he declared over fifty acres They were in sight half an hour then they marched away quite silently The whole time he heard neither voice nor tread nothing but the faint music playing a solemn march Where did they go sir Towards <PERSON>Briarfield Mike</PERSON> followed them They seemed passing <PERSON>Fieldhead</PERSON> when a column of smoke such as might be vomited by a park of artillery spread noiseless over the fields the road the common and rolled he said blue and dim to his very feet As it cleared away he looked again for the soldiers but they were vanished he saw them no more <PERSON>Mike</PERSON> like a wise <PERSON>Daniel</PERSON> as he is not only rehearsed the vision but gave the interpretation thereof It signifies he intimated bloodshed and civil conflict Do you credit it sir asked Sweeting Do you Davy But come <PERSON>Malone</PERSON> why are you not off I am rather surprised sir you did not stay with <PERSON>Moore</PERSON> yourself You like this kind of thing So I should have done had I not unfortunately happened to engage <LOCATION>Boultby</LOCATION> to sup with me on his way home from the Bible Society meeting at Nunnely I promised to send you as my substitute for which by the bye he did not thank me He would much rather have had me than you <PERSON>Peter Should</PERSON> there be any real need of help I shall join you The mill bell will give warning Meantime go unless turning suddenly to <PERSON>Messrs Sweeting</PERSON> and <PERSON>Donne</PERSON> unless <PERSON>Davy Sweeting</PERSON> or <PERSON>Joseph Donne</PERSON> prefers going What do you say gentlemen The commission is an honourable one not without the seasoning of a little real peril for the country is in a queer state as you all know and <PERSON>Moore</PERSON> and his mill and his machinery are held in sufficient odium There are chivalric sentiments there is high beating courage under those waistcoats of yours I doubt not Perhaps I am too partial to my favourite <PERSON>Peter Little David</PERSON> shall be the champion or spotless <PERSON>Joseph Malone</PERSON> you are but a great floundering <PERSON>Saul</PERSON> after all good only to lend your armour Out with your firearms fetch your shillelah It is there in the corner With a significant grin <PERSON>Malone</PERSON> produced his pistols offering one to each of his brethren They were not readily seized on With graceful modesty each gentleman retired a step from the presented weapon I never touch them I never did touch anything of the kind said Mr <PERSON>Donne</PERSON> I am almost a stranger to Mr <PERSON>Moore</PERSON> murmured <PERSON>Sweeting</PERSON> If you never touched a pistol try the feel of it now great satrap of <LOCATION>Egypt</LOCATION> As to the little minstrel he probably prefers encountering the <LOCATION>Philistines</LOCATION> with no other weapon than his flute Get their hats Peter They ll both of em go No sir no Mr Helstone My mother wouldn t like it pleaded Sweeting And I make it a rule never to get mixed up in affairs of the kind observed <PERSON>Donne Helstone</PERSON> smiled sardonically <PERSON>Malone</PERSON> laughed a horse laugh He then replaced his arms took his hat and cudgel and saying that he never felt more in tune for a shindy in his life and that he wished a score of greasy cloth dressers might beat up <PERSON>Moore</PERSON> s quarters that night he made his exit clearing the stairs at a stride or two and making the house shake with the bang of the front door behind him CHAPTER II THE WAGONS The evening was pitch dark star and moon were quenched in gray rain clouds gray they would have been by day by night they looked sable <PERSON>Malone</PERSON> was not a man given to close observation of nature her changes passed for the most part unnoticed by him He could walk miles on the most varying April day and never see the beautiful dallying of earth and heaven never mark when a sunbeam kissed the hill tops making them smile clear in green light or when a shower wept over them hiding their crests with the low hanging dishevelled tresses of a cloud He did not therefore care to contrast the sky as it now appeared a muffled streaming vault all black save where towards the east the furnaces of <LOCATION>Stilbro</LOCATION> ironworks threw a tremulous lurid shimmer on the horizon with the same sky on an unclouded frosty night He did not trouble himself to ask where the constellations and the planets were gone or to regret the black blue serenity of the air ocean which those white islets stud and which another ocean of heavier and denser element now rolled below and concealed He just doggedly pursued his way leaning a little forward as he walked and wearing his hat on the back of his head as his Irish manner was Tramp tramp he went along the causeway where the road boasted the privilege of such an accommodation splash splash through the mire filled cart ruts where the flags were exchanged for soft mud He looked but for certain landmarks the spire of <ORGANIZATION>Briarfield Church</ORGANIZATION> farther on the lights of Redhouse This was an inn and when he reached it the glow of a fire through a half curtained window a vision of glasses on a round table and of revellers on an oaken settle had nearly drawn aside the curate from his course He thought longingly of a tumbler of whisky and water In a strange place he would instantly have realized the dream but the company assembled in that kitchen were Mr <PERSON>Helstone</PERSON> s own parishioners they all knew him He sighed and passed on The highroad was now to be quitted as the remaining distance to Hollow s Mill might be considerably reduced by a short cut across fields These fields were level and monotonous <PERSON>Malone</PERSON> took a direct course through them jumping hedge and wall He passed but one building here and that seemed large and hall like though irregular You could see a high gable then a long front then a low gable then a thick lofty stack of chimneys There were some trees behind it It was dark not a candle shone from any window It was absolutely still the rain running from the eaves and the rather wild but very low whistle of the wind round the chimneys and through the boughs were the sole sounds in its neighbourhood This building passed the fields hitherto flat declined in a rapid descent Evidently a vale lay below through which you could hear the water run One light glimmered in the depth For that beacon <PERSON>Malone</PERSON> steered He came to a little white house you could see it was white even through this dense darkness and knocked at the door A fresh faced servant opened it By the candle she held was revealed a narrow passage terminating in a narrow stair Two doors covered with crimson baize a strip of crimson carpet down the steps contrasted with light coloured walls and white floor made the little interior look clean and fresh Mr <PERSON>Moore</PERSON> is at home I suppose Yes sir but he is not in Not in Where is he then At the mill in the counting house Here one of the crimson doors opened Are the wagons come <PERSON>Sarah</PERSON> asked a female voice and a female head at the same time was apparent It might not be the head of a goddess indeed a screw of curl paper on each side the temples quite forbade that supposition but neither was it the head of a <ORGANIZATION>Gorgon</ORGANIZATION> yet <PERSON>Malone</PERSON> seemed to take it in the latter light Big as he was he shrank bashfully back into the rain at the view thereof and saying I ll go to him hurried in seeming trepidation down a short lane across an obscure yard towards a huge black mill The work hours were over the hands were gone The machinery was at rest the mill shut up <PERSON>Malone</PERSON> walked round it Somewhere in its great sooty flank he found another chink of light he knocked at another door using for the purpose the thick end of his shillelah with which he beat a rousing tattoo A key turned the door unclosed Is it <PERSON>Joe Scott</PERSON> What news of the wagons Joe No it s myself Mr <PERSON>Helstone</PERSON> would send me Oh Mr <PERSON>Malone</PERSON> The voice in uttering this name had the slightest possible cadence of disappointment After a moment s pause it continued politely but a little formally I beg you will come in Mr <PERSON>Malone</PERSON> I regret extremely Mr <PERSON>Helstone</PERSON> should have thought it necessary to trouble you so far There was no necessity I told him so and on such a night but walk forwards Through a dark apartment of aspect undistinguishable <PERSON>Malone</PERSON> followed the speaker into a light and bright room within very light and bright indeed it seemed to eyes which for the last hour had been striving to penetrate the double darkness of night and fog but except for its excellent fire and for a lamp of elegant design and vivid lustre burning on a table it was a very plain place The boarded floor was carpetless the three or four stiff backed green painted chairs seemed once to have furnished the kitchen of some farm house a desk of strong solid formation the table aforesaid and some framed sheets on the stone coloured walls bearing plans for building for gardening designs of machinery etc completed the furniture of the place Plain as it was it seemed to satisfy <PERSON>Malone</PERSON> who when he had removed and hung up his wet surtout and hat drew one of the rheumatic looking chairs to the hearth and set his knees almost within the bars of the red grate Comfortable quarters you have here Mr <PERSON>Moore</PERSON> and all snug to yourself Yes but my sister would be glad to see you if you would prefer stepping into the house Oh no The ladies are best alone I never was a lady s man You don t mistake me for my friend <PERSON>Sweeting</PERSON> do you Mr <PERSON>Moore Sweeting Which</PERSON> of them is that The gentleman in the chocolate overcoat or the little gentleman The little one he of Nunnely the cavalier of the Misses <PERSON>Sykes</PERSON> with the whole six of whom he is in love ha ha Better be generally in love with all than specially with one I should think in that quarter But he is specially in love with one besides for when I and <PERSON>Donne</PERSON> urged him to make a choice amongst the fair bevy he named which do you think With a queer quiet smile Mr <PERSON>Moore</PERSON> replied <PERSON>Dora</PERSON> of course or Harriet Ha ha you ve an excellent guess But what made you hit on those two Because they are the tallest the handsomest and <PERSON>Dora</PERSON> at least is the stoutest and as your friend Mr <PERSON>Sweeting</PERSON> is but a little slight figure I concluded that according to a frequent rule in such cases he preferred his contrast You are right <PERSON>Dora</PERSON> it is But he has no chance has he Moore What has Mr <PERSON>Sweeting</PERSON> besides his curacy This question seemed to tickle <PERSON>Malone</PERSON> amazingly He laughed for full three minutes before he answered it What has Sweeting Why <PERSON>David</PERSON> has his harp or flute which comes to the same thing He has a sort of pinchbeck watch ditto ring ditto eyeglass That s what he has How would he propose to keep Miss <PERSON>Sykes</PERSON> in gowns only Ha ha Excellent I ll ask him that next time I see him I ll roast him for his presumption But no doubt he expects old <PERSON>Christopher Sykes</PERSON> would do something handsome He is rich is he not They live in a large house <PERSON>Sykes</PERSON> carries on an extensive concern Therefore he must be wealthy eh Therefore he must have plenty to do with his wealth and in these times would be about as likely to think of drawing money from the business to give dowries to his daughters as I should be to dream of pulling down the cottage there and constructing on its ruins a house as large as Fieldhead Do you know what I heard <PERSON>Moore</PERSON> the other day No Perhaps that I _was_ about to effect some such change Your Briarfield gossips are capable of saying that or sillier things That you were going to take <PERSON>Fieldhead</PERSON> on a lease I thought it looked a dismal place by the bye to night as I passed it and that it was your intention to settle a Miss <PERSON>Sykes</PERSON> there as mistress to be married in short ha ha Now which is it <PERSON>Dora</PERSON> I am sure You said she was the handsomest I wonder how often it has been settled that I was to be married since I came to Briarfield They have assigned me every marriageable single woman by turns in the district Now it was the two Misses <PERSON>Wynns</PERSON> first the dark then the light one now the red haired Miss <PERSON>Armitage</PERSON> then the mature <PERSON>Ann Pearson</PERSON> At present you throw on my shoulders all the tribe of the Misses Sykes On what grounds this gossip rests God knows I visit nowhere I seek female society about as assiduously as you do Mr <PERSON>Malone</PERSON> If ever I go to <LOCATION>Whinbury</LOCATION> it is only to give <PERSON>Sykes</PERSON> or <PERSON>Pearson</PERSON> a call in their counting house where our discussions run on other topics than matrimony and our thoughts are occupied with other things than courtships establishments dowries The cloth we can t sell the hands we can t employ the mills we can t run the perverse course of events generally which we cannot alter fill our hearts I take it pretty well at present to the tolerably complete exclusion of such figments as love making etc I go along with you completely <PERSON>Moore</PERSON> If there is one notion I hate more than another it is that of marriage I mean marriage in the vulgar weak sense as a mere matter of sentiment two beggarly fools agreeing to unite their indigence by some fantastic tie of feeling Humbug But an advantageous connection such as can be formed in consonance with dignity of views and permanency of solid interests is not so bad eh No responded <PERSON>Moore</PERSON> in an absent manner The subject seemed to have no interest for him he did not pursue it After sitting for some time gazing at the fire with a preoccupied air he suddenly turned his head <PERSON>Hark</PERSON> said he Did you hear wheels Rising he went to the window opened it and listened He soon closed it It is only the sound of the wind rising he remarked and the rivulet a little swollen rushing down the hollow I expected those wagons at six it is near nine now Seriously do you suppose that the putting up of this new machinery will bring you into danger inquired <PERSON>Malone Helstone</PERSON> seems to think it will I only wish the machines the frames were safe here and lodged within the walls of this mill Once put up I defy the frame breakers Let them only pay me a visit and take the consequences My mill is my castle One despises such low scoundrels observed <PERSON>Malone</PERSON> in a profound vein of reflection I almost wish a party would call upon you to night but the road seemed extremely quiet as I came along I saw nothing astir You came by the Redhouse Yes There would be nothing on that road It is in the direction of Stilbro the risk lies And you think there is risk What these fellows have done to others they may do to me There is only this difference most of the manufacturers seem paralyzed when they are attacked <PERSON>Sykes</PERSON> for instance when his dressing shop was set on fire and burned to the ground when the cloth was torn from his tenters and left in shreds in the field took no steps to discover or punish the miscreants he gave up as tamely as a rabbit under the jaws of a ferret Now I if I know myself should stand by my trade my mill and my machinery <PERSON>Helstone</PERSON> says these three are your gods that the Orders in Council are with you another name for the seven deadly sins that <PERSON>Castlereagh</PERSON> is your <PERSON>Antichrist</PERSON> and the war party his legions Yes I abhor all these things because they ruin me They stand in my way I cannot get on I cannot execute my plans because of them I see myself baffled at every turn by their untoward effects But you are rich and thriving <PERSON>Moore</PERSON> I am very rich in cloth I cannot sell You should step into my warehouse yonder and observe how it is piled to the roof with pieces Roakes and <PERSON>Pearson</PERSON> are in the same condition <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> used to be their market but the <ORGANIZATION>Orders in Council</ORGANIZATION> have cut that off <PERSON>Malone</PERSON> did not seem prepared to carry on briskly a conversation of this sort He began to knock the heels of his boots together and to yawn And then to think continued Mr <PERSON>Moore</PERSON> who seemed too much taken up with the current of his own thoughts to note the symptoms of his guest s _ennui_ to think that these ridiculous gossips of <LOCATION>Whinbury</LOCATION> and <PERSON>Briarfield</PERSON> will keep pestering one about being married As if there was nothing to be done in life but to pay attention as they say to some young lady and then to go to church with her and then to start on a bridal tour and then to run through a round of visits and then I suppose to be having a family Oh que le diable emporte He broke off the aspiration into which he was launching with a certain energy and added more calmly I believe women talk and think only of these things and they naturally fancy men s minds similarly occupied Of course of course assented <PERSON>Malone</PERSON> but never mind them And he whistled looked impatiently round and seemed to feel a great want of something This time <PERSON>Moore</PERSON> caught and it appeared comprehended his demonstrations Mr <PERSON>Malone</PERSON> said he you must require refreshment after your wet walk I forget hospitality Not at all rejoined <PERSON>Malone</PERSON> but he looked as if the right nail was at last hit on the head nevertheless <PERSON>Moore</PERSON> rose and opened a cupboard It is my fancy said he to have every convenience within myself and not to be dependent on the feminity in the cottage yonder for every mouthful I eat or every drop I drink I often spend the evening and sup here alone and sleep with <PERSON>Joe Scott</PERSON> in the mill Sometimes I am my own watchman I require little sleep and it pleases me on a fine night to wander for an hour or two with my musket about the hollow Mr <PERSON>Malone</PERSON> can you cook a mutton chop Try me I ve done it hundreds of times at college There s a dishful then and there s the gridiron Turn them quickly You know the secret of keeping the juices in Never fear me you shall see Hand a knife and fork please The curate turned up his coat cuffs and applied himself to the cookery with vigour The manufacturer placed on the table plates a loaf of bread a black bottle and two tumblers He then produced a small copper kettle still from the same well stored recess his cupboard filled it with water from a large stone jar in a corner set it on the fire beside the hissing gridiron got lemons sugar and a small china punch bowl but while he was brewing the punch a tap at the door called him away Is it you <PERSON>Sarah</PERSON> Yes sir Will you come to supper please sir No I shall not be in to night I shall sleep in the mill So lock the doors and tell your mistress to go to bed He returned You have your household in proper order observed <PERSON>Malone</PERSON> approvingly as with his fine face ruddy as the embers over which he bent he assiduously turned the mutton chops You are not under petticoat government like poor <PERSON>Sweeting</PERSON> a man whew how the fat spits it has burnt my hand destined to be ruled by women Now you and I <PERSON>Moore</PERSON> there s a fine brown one for you and full of gravy you and I will have no gray mares in our stables when we marry I don t know I never think about it If the gray mare is handsome and tractable why not The chops are done Is the punch brewed There is a glassful Taste it When <PERSON>Joe Scott</PERSON> and his minions return they shall have a share of this provided they bring home the frames intact <PERSON>Malone</PERSON> waxed very exultant over the supper He laughed aloud at trifles made bad jokes and applauded them himself and in short grew unmeaningly noisy His host on the contrary remained quiet as before It is time reader that you should have some idea of the appearance of this same host I must endeavour to sketch him as he sits at table He is what you would probably call at first view rather a strange looking man for he is thin dark sallow very foreign of aspect with shadowy hair carelessly streaking his forehead It appears that he spends but little time at his toilet or he would arrange it with more taste He seems unconscious that his features are fine that they have a southern symmetry clearness regularity in their chiselling nor does a spectator become aware of this advantage till he has examined him well for an anxious countenance and a hollow somewhat haggard outline of face disturb the idea of beauty with one of care His eyes are large and grave and gray their expression is intent and meditative rather searching than soft rather thoughtful than genial When he parts his lips in a smile his physiognomy is agreeable not that it is frank or cheerful even then but you feel the influence of a certain sedate charm suggestive whether truly or delusively of a considerate perhaps a kind nature of feelings that may wear well at home patient forbearing possibly faithful feelings He is still young not more than thirty his stature is tall his figure slender His manner of speaking displeases He has an outlandish accent which notwithstanding a studied carelessness of pronunciation and diction grates on a British and especially on a <LOCATION>Yorkshire</LOCATION> ear Mr <PERSON>Moore</PERSON> indeed was but half a Briton and scarcely that He came of a foreign ancestry by the mother s side and was himself born and partly reared on a foreign soil A hybrid in nature it is probable he had a hybrid s feeling on many points patriotism for one it is likely that he was unapt to attach himself to parties to sects even to climes and customs it is not impossible that he had a tendency to isolate his individual person from any community amidst which his lot might temporarily happen to be thrown and that he felt it to be his best wisdom to push the interests of <PERSON>Robert G rard Moore</PERSON> to the exclusion of philanthropic consideration for general interests with which he regarded the said <PERSON>G rard Moore</PERSON> as in a great measure disconnected Trade was Mr <PERSON>Moore</PERSON> s hereditary calling the G rards of <LOCATION>Antwerp</LOCATION> had been merchants for two centuries back Once they had been wealthy merchants but the uncertainties the involvements of business had come upon them disastrous speculations had loosened by degrees the foundations of their credit The house had stood on a tottering base for a dozen years and at last in the shock of the French Revolution it had rushed down a total ruin In its fall was involved the English and <ORGANIZATION>Yorkshire</ORGANIZATION> firm of <PERSON>Moore</PERSON> closely connected with the <LOCATION>Antwerp</LOCATION> house and of which one of the partners resident in <LOCATION>Antwerp</LOCATION> <PERSON>Robert Moore</PERSON> had married <PERSON>Hortense G</PERSON> rard with the prospect of his bride inheriting her father <PERSON>Constantine G</PERSON> rard s share in the business She inherited as we have seen but his share in the liabilities of the firm and these liabilities though duly set aside by a composition with creditors some said her son <PERSON>Robert</PERSON> accepted in his turn as a legacy and that he aspired one day to discharge them and to rebuild the fallen house of G rard and <PERSON>Moore</PERSON> on a scale at least equal to its former greatness It was even supposed that he took by past circumstances much to heart and if a childhood passed at the side of a saturnine mother under foreboding of coming evil and a manhood drenched and blighted by the pitiless descent of the storm could painfully impress the mind _his_ probably was impressed in no golden characters If however he had a great end of restoration in view it was not in his power to employ great means for its attainment He was obliged to be content with the day of small things When he came to <ORGANIZATION>Yorkshire</ORGANIZATION> he whose ancestors had owned warehouses in this seaport and factories in that inland town had possessed their town house and their country seat saw no way open to him but to rent a cloth mill in an out of the way nook of an out of the way district to take a cottage adjoining it for his residence and to add to his possessions as pasture for his horse and space for his cloth tenters a few acres of the steep rugged land that lined the hollow through which his mill stream brawled All this he held at a somewhat high rent for these war times were hard and everything was dear of the trustees of the Fieldhead estate then the property of a minor At the time this history commences <PERSON>Robert Moore</PERSON> had lived but two years in the district during which period he had at least proved himself possessed of the quality of activity The dingy cottage was converted into a neat tasteful residence Of part of the rough land he had made garden ground which he cultivated with singular even with Flemish exactness and care As to the mill which was an old structure and fitted up with old machinery now become inefficient and out of date he had from the first evinced the strongest contempt for all its arrangements and appointments His aim had been to effect a radical reform which he had executed as fast as his very limited capital would allow and the narrowness of that capital and consequent check on his progress was a restraint which galled his spirit sorely <PERSON>Moore</PERSON> ever wanted to push on Forward was the device stamped upon his soul but poverty curbed him Sometimes figuratively he foamed at the mouth when the reins were drawn very tight In this state of feeling it is not to be expected that he would deliberate much as to whether his advance was or was not prejudicial to others Not being a native nor for any length of time a resident of the neighbourhood he did not sufficiently care when the new inventions threw the old workpeople out of employ He never asked himself where those to whom he no longer paid weekly wages found daily bread and in this negligence he only resembled thousands besides on whom the starving poor of <ORGANIZATION>Yorkshire</ORGANIZATION> seemed to have a closer claim The period of which I write was an overshadowed one in British history and especially in the history of the northern provinces War was then at its height <LOCATION>Europe</LOCATION> was all involved therein <LOCATION>England</LOCATION> if not weary was worn with long resistance yes and half her people were weary too and cried out for peace on any terms National honour was become a mere empty name of no value in the eyes of many because their sight was dim with famine and for a morsel of meat they would have sold their birthright The Orders in Council provoked by <PERSON>Napoleon</PERSON> s <LOCATION>Milan</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Berlin</LOCATION> decrees and forbidding neutral powers to trade with <LOCATION>France</LOCATION> had by offending <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> cut off the principal market of the <ORGANIZATION>Yorkshire</ORGANIZATION> woollen trade and brought it consequently to the verge of ruin Minor foreign markets were glutted and would receive no more The Brazils <LOCATION>Portugal Sicily</LOCATION> were all overstocked by nearly two years consumption At this crisis certain inventions in machinery were introduced into the staple manufactures of the north which greatly reducing the number of hands necessary to be employed threw thousands out of work and left them without legitimate means of sustaining life A bad harvest supervened Distress reached its climax Endurance overgoaded stretched the hand of fraternity to sedition The throes of a sort of moral earthquake were felt heaving under the hills of the northern counties But as is usual in such cases nobody took much notice When a food riot broke out in a manufacturing town when a gig mill was burnt to the ground or a manufacturer s house was attacked the furniture thrown into the streets and the family forced to flee for their lives some local measures were or were not taken by the local magistracy A ringleader was detected or more frequently suffered to elude detection newspaper paragraphs were written on the subject and there the thing stopped As to the sufferers whose sole inheritance was labour and who had lost that inheritance who could not get work and consequently could not get wages and consequently could not get bread they were left to suffer on perhaps inevitably left It would not do to stop the progress of invention to damage science by discouraging its improvements the war could not be terminated efficient relief could not be raised There was no help then so the unemployed underwent their destiny ate the bread and drank the waters of affliction Misery generates hate These sufferers hated the machines which they believed took their bread from them they hated the buildings which contained those machines they hated the manufacturers who owned those buildings In the parish of <LOCATION>Briarfield</LOCATION> with which we have at present to do Hollow s Mill was the place held most abominable G rard <PERSON>Moore</PERSON> in his double character of semi foreigner and thorough going progressist the man most abominated And it perhaps rather agreed with <PERSON>Moore</PERSON> s temperament than otherwise to be generally hated especially when he believed the thing for which he was hated a right and an expedient thing and it was with a sense of warlike excitement he on this night sat in his counting house waiting the arrival of his frame laden wagons <PERSON>Malone</PERSON> s coming and company were it may be most unwelcome to him He would have preferred sitting alone for he liked a silent sombre unsafe solitude His watchman s musket would have been company enough for him the full flowing beck in the den would have delivered continuously the discourse most genial to his ear With the queerest look in the world had the manufacturer for some ten minutes been watching the Irish curate as the latter made free with the punch when suddenly that steady gray eye changed as if another vision came between it and <PERSON>Malone Moore</PERSON> raised his hand <PERSON>Chut</PERSON> he said in his French fashion as <PERSON>Malone</PERSON> made a noise with his glass He listened a moment then rose put his hat on and went out at the counting house door The night was still dark and stagnant the water yet rushed on full and fast its flow almost seemed a flood in the utter silence <PERSON>Moore</PERSON> s ear however caught another sound very distant but yet dissimilar broken and rugged in short a sound of heavy wheels crunching a stony road He returned to the counting house and lit a lantern with which he walked down the mill yard and proceeded to open the gates The big wagons were coming on the dray horses huge hoofs were heard splashing in the mud and water <PERSON>Moore</PERSON> hailed them Hey <PERSON>Joe Scott</PERSON> Is all right Probably <PERSON>Joe Scott</PERSON> was yet at too great a distance to hear the inquiry He did not answer it Is all right I say again asked <PERSON>Moore</PERSON> when the elephant like leader s nose almost touched his Some one jumped out from the foremost wagon into the road a voice cried aloud Ay ay divil all s raight We ve smashed em And there was a run The wagons stood still they were now deserted <PERSON>Joe Scott No Joe Scott</PERSON> answered <ORGANIZATION>Murgatroyd Pighills Sykes No</ORGANIZATION> reply Mr <PERSON>Moore</PERSON> lifted his lantern and looked into the vehicles There was neither man nor machinery they were empty and abandoned Now <PERSON>Mr Moore</PERSON> loved his machinery He had risked the last of his capital on the purchase of these frames and shears which to night had been expected Speculations most important to his interests depended on the results to be wrought by them Where were they The words we ve smashed em rang in his ears How did the catastrophe affect him By the light of the lantern he held were his features visible relaxing to a singular smile the smile the man of determined spirit wears when he reaches a juncture in his life where this determined spirit is to feel a demand on its strength when the strain is to be made and the faculty must bear or break Yet he remained silent and even motionless for at the instant he neither knew what to say nor what to do He placed the lantern on the ground and stood with his arms folded gazing down and reflecting An impatient trampling of one of the horses made him presently look up His eye in the moment caught the gleam of something white attached to a part of the harness Examined by the light of the lantern this proved to be a folded paper a billet It bore no address without within was the superscription To the Divil of Hollow s Miln We will not copy the rest of the orthography which was very peculiar but translate it into legible English It ran thus Your hellish machinery is shivered to smash on <PERSON>Stilbro Moor</PERSON> and your men are lying bound hand and foot in a ditch by the roadside Take this as a warning from men that are starving and have starving wives and children to go home to when they have done this deed If you get new machines or if you otherwise go on as you have done you shall hear from us again Beware Hear from you again Yes I ll hear from you again and you shall hear from me I ll speak to you directly On Stilbro Moor you shall hear from me in a moment Having led the wagons within the gates he hastened towards the cottage Opening the door he spoke a few words quickly but quietly to two females who ran to meet him in the passage He calmed the seeming alarm of one by a brief palliative account of what had taken place to the other he said Go into the mill <PERSON>Sarah</PERSON> there is the key and ring the mill bell as loud as you can Afterwards you will get another lantern and help me to light up the front Returning to his horses he unharnessed fed and stabled them with equal speed and care pausing occasionally while so occupied as if to listen for the mill bell It clanged out presently with irregular but loud and alarming din The hurried agitated peal seemed more urgent than if the summons had been steadily given by a practised hand On that still night at that unusual hour it was heard a long way round The guests in the kitchen of the Redhouse were startled by the clamour and declaring that there must be summat more nor common to do at Hollow s <PERSON>Miln</PERSON> they called for lanterns and hurried to the spot in a body And scarcely had they thronged into the yard with their gleaming lights when the tramp of horses was heard and a little man in a shovel hat sitting erect on the back of a shaggy pony rode lightly in followed by an aide de camp mounted on a larger steed Mr <PERSON>Moore</PERSON> meantime after stabling his dray horses had saddled his hackney and with the aid of <PERSON>Sarah</PERSON> the servant lit up his mill whose wide and long front now glared one great illumination throwing a sufficient light on the yard to obviate all fear of confusion arising from obscurity Already a deep hum of voices became audible Mr <PERSON>Malone</PERSON> had at length issued from the counting house previously taking the precaution to dip his head and face in the stone water jug and this precaution together with the sudden alarm had nearly restored to him the possession of those senses which the punch had partially scattered He stood with his hat on the back of his head and his shillelah grasped in his dexter fist answering much at random the questions of the newly arrived party from the Redhouse Mr <PERSON>Moore</PERSON> now appeared and was immediately confronted by the shovel hat and the shaggy pony Well <PERSON>Moore</PERSON> what is your business with us I thought you would want us to night me and the hetman here patting his pony s neck and <PERSON>Tom</PERSON> and his charger When I heard your mill bell I could sit still no longer so I left <LOCATION>Boultby</LOCATION> to finish his supper alone But where is the enemy I do not see a mask or a smutted face present and there is not a pane of glass broken in your windows Have you had an attack or do you expect one Oh not at all I have neither had one nor expect one answered <PERSON>Moore</PERSON> coolly I only ordered the bell to be rung because I want two or three neighbours to stay here in the Hollow while I and a couple or so more go over to <LOCATION>Stilbro Moor</LOCATION> To Stilbro Moor What to do To meet the wagons The wagons are come home an hour ago Then all s right What more would you have They came home empty and <PERSON>Joe Scott</PERSON> and company are left on the moor and so are the frames Read that scrawl Mr <PERSON>Helstone</PERSON> received and perused the document of which the contents have before been given Hum They ve only served you as they serve others But however the poor fellows in the ditch will be expecting help with some impatience This is a wet night for such a berth I and <PERSON>Tom</PERSON> will go with you <PERSON>Malone</PERSON> may stay behind and take care of the mill What is the matter with him His eyes seem starting out of his head He has been eating a mutton chop Indeed <PERSON>Peter Augustus</PERSON> be on your guard Eat no more mutton chops to night You are left here in command of these premises an honourable post Is anybody to stay with me As many of the present assemblage as choose My lads how many of you will remain here and how many will go a little way with me and Mr <PERSON>Moore</PERSON> on the <LOCATION>Stilbro</LOCATION> road to meet some men who have been waylaid and assaulted by frame breakers The small number of three volunteered to go the rest preferred staying behind As Mr <PERSON>Moore</PERSON> mounted his horse the rector asked him in a low voice whether he had locked up the mutton chops so that <PERSON>Peter Augustus</PERSON> could not get at them The manufacturer nodded an affirmative and the rescue party set out CHAPTER III <PERSON>MR YORKE</PERSON> Cheerfulness it would appear is a matter which depends fully as much on the state of things within as on the state of things without and around us I make this trite remark because I happen to know that <PERSON>Messrs Helstone</PERSON> and <PERSON>Moore</PERSON> trotted forth from the mill yard gates at the head of their very small company in the best possible spirits When a ray from a lantern the three pedestrians of the party carried each one fell on Mr <PERSON>Moore</PERSON> s face you could see an unusual because a lively spark dancing in his eyes and a new found vivacity mantling on his dark physiognomy and when the rector s visage was illuminated his hard features were revealed all agrin and ashine with glee Yet a drizzling night a somewhat perilous expedition you would think were not circumstances calculated to enliven those exposed to the wet and engaged in the adventure If any member or members of the crew who had been at work on <LOCATION>Stilbro Moor</LOCATION> had caught a view of this party they would have had great pleasure in shooting either of the leaders from behind a wall and the leaders knew this and the fact is being both men of steely nerves and steady beating hearts were elate with the knowledge I am aware reader and you need not remind me that it is a dreadful thing for a parson to be warlike I am aware that he should be a man of peace I have some faint outline of an idea of what a clergyman s mission is amongst mankind and I remember distinctly whose servant he is whose message he delivers whose example he should follow yet with all this if you are a parson hater you need not expect me to go along with you every step of your dismal downward tending unchristian road you need not expect me to join in your deep anathemas at once so narrow and so sweeping in your poisonous rancour so intense and so absurd against the cloth to lift up my eyes and hands with a Supplehough or to inflate my lungs with a <PERSON>Barraclough</PERSON> in horror and denunciation of the diabolical rector of Briarfield He was not diabolical at all The evil simply was he had missed his vocation He should have been a soldier and circumstances had made him a priest For the rest he was a conscientious hard headed hard handed brave stern implacable faithful little man a man almost without sympathy ungentle prejudiced and rigid but a man true to principle honourable sagacious and sincere It seems to me reader that you cannot always cut out men to fit their profession and that you ought not to curse them because their profession sometimes hangs on them ungracefully Nor will I curse Helstone clerical <PERSON>Cossack</PERSON> as he was Yet he _was_ cursed and by many of his own parishioners as by others he was adored which is the frequent fate of men who show partiality in friendship and bitterness in enmity who are equally attached to principles and adherent to prejudices <PERSON>Helstone</PERSON> and <PERSON>Moore</PERSON> being both in excellent spirits and united for the present in one cause you would expect that as they rode side by side they would converse amicably Oh no These two men of hard bilious natures both rarely came into contact but they chafed each other s moods Their frequent bone of contention was the war <PERSON>Helstone</PERSON> was a high Tory there were Tories in those days and <PERSON>Moore</PERSON> was a bitter Whig a Whig at least as far as opposition to the war party was concerned that being the question which affected his own interest and only on that question did he profess any British politics at all He liked to infuriate <PERSON>Helstone</PERSON> by declaring his belief in the invincibility of <PERSON>Bonaparte</PERSON> by taunting <LOCATION>England</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Europe</LOCATION> with the impotence of their efforts to withstand him and by coolly advancing the opinion that it was as well to yield to him soon as late since he must in the end crush every antagonist and reign supreme <PERSON>Helstone</PERSON> could not bear these sentiments It was only on the consideration of <PERSON>Moore</PERSON> being a sort of outcast and alien and having but half measure of British blood to temper the foreign gall which corroded his veins that he brought himself to listen to them without indulging the wish he felt to cane the speaker Another thing too somewhat allayed his disgust namely a fellow feeling for the dogged tone with which these opinions were asserted and a respect for the consistency of <PERSON>Moore</PERSON> s crabbed contumacy As the party turned into the <LOCATION>Stilbro</LOCATION> road they met what little wind there was the rain dashed in their faces <PERSON>Moore</PERSON> had been fretting his companion previously and now braced up by the raw breeze and perhaps irritated by the sharp drizzle he began to goad him Does your Peninsular news please you still he asked What do you mean was the surly demand of the rector I mean have you still faith in that <PERSON>Baal</PERSON> of a Lord <LOCATION>Wellington</LOCATION> And what do you mean now Do you still believe that this wooden faced and pebble hearted idol of <LOCATION>England</LOCATION> has power to send fire down from heaven to consume the French holocaust you want to offer up I believe <LOCATION>Wellington</LOCATION> will flog <PERSON>Bonaparte</PERSON> s marshals into the sea the day it pleases him to lift his arm But my dear sir you can t be serious in what you say <PERSON>Bonaparte</PERSON> s marshals are great men who act under the guidance of an omnipotent master spirit Your <LOCATION>Wellington</LOCATION> is the most humdrum of commonplace martinets whose slow mechanical movements are further cramped by an ignorant home government <LOCATION>Wellington</LOCATION> is the soul of <LOCATION>England Wellington</LOCATION> is the right champion of a good cause the fit representative of a powerful a resolute a sensible and an honest nation Your good cause as far as I understand it is simply the restoration of that filthy feeble <PERSON>Ferdinand</PERSON> to a throne which he disgraced Your fit representative of an honest people is a dull witted drover acting for a duller witted farmer and against these are arrayed victorious supremacy and invincible genius Against legitimacy is arrayed usurpation against modest single minded righteous and brave resistance to encroachment is arrayed boastful double tongued selfish and treacherous ambition to possess God defend the right God often defends the powerful What I suppose the handful of Israelites standing dryshod on the <LOCATION>Asiatic</LOCATION> side of the <LOCATION>Red Sea</LOCATION> was more powerful than the host of the Egyptians drawn up on the African side Were they more numerous Were they better appointed Were they more mighty in a word eh <PERSON>Don</PERSON> t speak or you ll tell a lie <PERSON>Moore</PERSON> you know you will They were a poor overwrought band of bondsmen Tyrants had oppressed them through four hundred years a feeble mixture of women and children diluted their thin ranks their masters who roared to follow them through the divided flood were a set of pampered Ethiops about as strong and brutal as the lions of <LOCATION>Libya</LOCATION> They were armed horsed and charioted the poor Hebrew wanderers were afoot Few of them it is likely had better weapons than their shepherds crooks or their masons building tools their meek and mighty leader himself had only his rod But bethink you <PERSON>Robert Moore</PERSON> right was with them the God of battles was on their side Crime and the lost archangel generalled the ranks of Pharaoh and which triumphed We know that well The Lord saved <LOCATION>Israel</LOCATION> that day out of the hand of the Egyptians and <LOCATION>Israel</LOCATION> saw the Egyptians dead upon the sea shore yea the depths covered them they sank to the bottom as a stone The right hand of the Lord became glorious in power the right hand of the Lord dashed in pieces the enemy You are all right only you forget the true parallel <LOCATION>France</LOCATION> is <LOCATION>Israel</LOCATION> and <PERSON>Napoleon</PERSON> is <PERSON>Moses Europe</PERSON> with her old overgorged empires and rotten dynasties is corrupt <LOCATION>Egypt</LOCATION> gallant <LOCATION>France</LOCATION> is the Twelve Tribes and her fresh and vigorous Usurper the Shepherd of Horeb I scorn to answer you <PERSON>Moore</PERSON> accordingly answered himself at least he subjoined to what he had just said an additional observation in a lower voice Oh in <LOCATION>Italy</LOCATION> he was as great as any Moses He was the right thing there fit to head and organize measures for the regeneration of nations It puzzles me to this day how the conqueror of <LOCATION>Lodi</LOCATION> should have condescended to become an emperor a vulgar a stupid humbug and still more how a people who had once called themselves republicans should have sunk again to the grade of mere slaves I despise <LOCATION>France</LOCATION> If <LOCATION>England</LOCATION> had gone as far on the march of civilization as <LOCATION>France</LOCATION> did she would hardly have retreated so shamelessly You don t mean to say that besotted imperial <LOCATION>France</LOCATION> is any worse than bloody republican <LOCATION>France</LOCATION> demanded <PERSON>Helstone</PERSON> fiercely I mean to say nothing but I can think what I please you know Mr <PERSON>Helstone</PERSON> both about <LOCATION>France</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>England</LOCATION> and about revolutions and regicides and restorations in general and about the divine right of kings which you often stickle for in your sermons and the duty of non resistance and the sanity of war and Mr <PERSON>Moore</PERSON> s sentence was here cut short by the rapid rolling up of a gig and its sudden stoppage in the middle of the road Both he and the rector had been too much occupied with their discourse to notice its approach till it was close upon them Nah maister did th wagons hit home demanded a voice from the vehicle Can that be <PERSON>Joe Scott Ay ay</PERSON> returned another voice for the gig contained two persons as was seen by the glimmer of its lamp The men with the lanterns had now fallen into the rear or rather the equestrians of the rescue party had outridden the pedestrians Ay Mr <PERSON>Moore</PERSON> it s <PERSON>Joe Scott</PERSON> I m bringing him back to you in a bonny pickle I fand him on the top of the moor yonder him and three others What will you give me for restoring him to you Why my thanks I believe for I could better have afforded to lose a better man That is you I suppose Mr <PERSON>Yorke</PERSON> by your voice Ay lad it s me I was coming home from <LOCATION>Stilbro</LOCATION> market and just as I got to the middle of the moor and was whipping on as swift as the wind for these they say are not safe times thanks to a bad government I heard a groan I pulled up Some would have whipt on faster but I ve naught to fear that I know of I don t believe there s a lad in these parts would harm me at least I d give them as good as I got if they offered to do it I said Is there aught wrong anywhere Deed is there somebody says speaking out of the ground like What s to do Be sharp and tell me I ordered <PERSON>Nobbut</PERSON> four on us ligging in a ditch says <PERSON>Joe</PERSON> as quiet as could be I telled em more shame to em and bid them get up and move on or I d lend them a lick of the gig whip for my notion was they were all fresh We d ha done that an hour sin but we re teed wi a bit o band says <PERSON>Joe</PERSON> So in a while I got down and loosed em wi my penknife and <PERSON>Scott</PERSON> would ride wi me to tell me all how it happened and t others are coming on as fast as their feet will bring them Well I am greatly obliged to you Mr <PERSON>Yorke</PERSON> Are you my lad You know you re not However here are the rest approaching And here by the Lord is another set with lights in their pitchers like the army of <PERSON>Gideon</PERSON> and as we ve th parson wi us good evening Mr <PERSON>Helstone</PERSON> we se do Mr <PERSON>Helstone</PERSON> returned the salutation of the individual in the gig very stiffly indeed That individual proceeded We re eleven strong men and there s both horses and chariots amang us If we could only fall in wi some of these starved ragamuffins of frame breakers we could win a grand victory We could iv ry one be a <LOCATION>Wellington</LOCATION> that would please ye Mr <PERSON>Helstone</PERSON> and sich paragraphs as we could contrive for t papers Briarfield suld be famous But we se hev a column and a half i th _<ORGANIZATION>Stilbro Courier</ORGANIZATION>_ ower this job as it is I dare say I se expect no less And I ll promise you no less Mr <PERSON>Yorke</PERSON> for I ll write the article myself returned the rector To be sure sartainly And mind ye recommend weel that them at brake t bits o frames and teed <PERSON>Joe Scott</PERSON> s legs wi band suld be hung without benefit o clergy It s a hanging matter or suld be No doubt o that If I judged them I d give them short shrift cried <PERSON>Moore</PERSON> But I mean to let them quite alone this bout to give them rope enough certain that in the end they will hang themselves Let them alone will ye Moore Do you promise that Promise No All I mean to say is I shall give myself no particular trouble to catch them but if one falls in my way You ll snap him up of course Only you would rather they would do something worse than merely stop a wagon before you reckon with them Well we ll say no more on the subject at present Here we are at my door gentlemen and I hope you and the men will step in You will none of you be the worse of a little refreshment <PERSON>Moore</PERSON> and <LOCATION>Helstone</LOCATION> opposed this proposition as unnecessary It was however pressed on them so courteously and the night besides was so inclement and the gleam from the muslin curtained windows of the house before which they had halted looked so inviting that at length they yielded Mr <PERSON>Yorke</PERSON> after having alighted from his gig which he left in charge of a man who issued from an outbuilding on his arrival led the way in It will have been remarked that Mr <PERSON>Yorke</PERSON> varied a little in his phraseology Now he spoke broad <LOCATION>Yorkshire</LOCATION> and anon he expressed himself in very pure English His manner seemed liable to equal alternations He could be polite and affable and he could be blunt and rough His station then you could not easily determine by his speech and demeanour Perhaps the appearance of his residence may decide it The men he recommended to take the kitchen way saying that he would see them served wi summat to taste presently The gentlemen were ushered in at the front entrance They found themselves in a matted hall lined almost to the ceiling with pictures Through this they were conducted to a large parlour with a magnificent fire in the grate the most cheerful of rooms it appeared as a whole and when you came to examine details the enlivening effect was not diminished There was no splendour but there was taste everywhere unusual taste the taste you would have said of a travelled man a scholar and a gentleman A series of Italian views decked the walls Each of these was a specimen of true art A connoisseur had selected them they were genuine and valuable Even by candle light the bright clear skies the soft distances with blue air quivering between the eye and the hills the fresh tints and well massed lights and shadows charmed the view The subjects were all pastoral the scenes were all sunny There was a guitar and some music on a sofa there were cameos beautiful miniatures a set of Grecian looking vases on the mantelpiece there were books well arranged in two elegant bookcases Mr <PERSON>Yorke</PERSON> bade his guests be seated He then rang for wine To the servant who brought it he gave hospitable orders for the refreshment of the men in the kitchen The rector remained standing he seemed not to like his quarters he would not touch the wine his host offered him E en as you will remarked Mr <PERSON>Yorke</PERSON> I reckon you re thinking of Eastern customs Mr <PERSON>Helstone</PERSON> and you ll not eat nor drink under my roof feared we suld be forced to be friends but I am not so particular or superstitious You might sup the contents of that decanter and you might give me a bottle of the best in your own cellar and I d hold myself free to oppose you at every turn still in every vestry meeting and justice meeting where we encountered one another It is just what I should expect of you Mr <PERSON>Yorke</PERSON> Does it agree wi ye now Mr <PERSON>Helstone</PERSON> to be riding out after rioters of a wet night at your age It always agrees with me to be doing my duty and in this case my duty is a thorough pleasure To hunt down vermin is a noble occupation fit for an archbishop Fit for ye at ony rate But where s t curate He s happen gone to visit some poor body in a sick gird or he s happen hunting down vermin in another direction He is doing garrison duty at Hollow s Mill You left him a sup o wine I hope <PERSON>Bob</PERSON> turning to Mr <PERSON>Moore</PERSON> to keep his courage up He did not pause for an answer but continued quickly still addressing <PERSON>Moore</PERSON> who had thrown himself into an old fashioned chair by the fireside Move it <PERSON>Robert Get</PERSON> up my lad That place is mine Take the sofa or three other chairs if you will but not this It belangs to me and nob dy else Why are you so particular to that chair Mr <PERSON>Yorke</PERSON> asked <PERSON>Moore</PERSON> lazily vacating the place in obedience to orders My father war afore me and that s all t answer I sall gie thee and it s as good a reason as Mr <PERSON>Helstone</PERSON> can give for the main feck o his notions <PERSON>Moore</PERSON> are you ready to go inquired the rector <PERSON>Nay Robert</PERSON> s not ready or rather I m not ready to part wi him He s an ill lad and wants correcting Why sir What have I done Made thyself enemies on every hand What do I care for that What difference does it make to me whether your <ORGANIZATION>Yorkshire</ORGANIZATION> louts hate me or like me Ay there it is The lad is a mak of an alien amang us His father would never have talked i that way Go back to <LOCATION>Antwerp</LOCATION> where you were born and bred mauvaise t te Mauvaise t te vous m me je ne fais que mon devoir quant vos lourdauds de paysans je m en moque En ravanche mon gar on nos lourdauds de paysans se moqueront de toi sois en certain replied <PERSON>Yorke</PERSON> speaking with nearly as pure a French accent as G rard <PERSON>Moore</PERSON> C est bon c est bon Et puisque cela m est gal que mes amis ne s en inqui tent pas Tes amis O sont ils tes amis Je fais cho o sont ils et je suis fort aise que l cho seul y r pond Au diable les amis Je me souviens encore du moment o mon p re et mes oncles G rard appell rent autour d eux leurs amis et Dieu sait si les amis se sont empress s d accourir leur secours Tenez M <PERSON>Yorke</PERSON> ce mot ami m irrite trop ne m en parlez plus Comme tu voudras And here Mr <PERSON>Yorke</PERSON> held his peace and while he sits leaning back in his three cornered carved oak chair I will snatch my opportunity to sketch the portrait of this French speaking <LOCATION>Yorkshire</LOCATION> gentleman CHAPTER IV <PERSON>MR YORKE</PERSON> _continued_ A <ORGANIZATION>Yorkshire</ORGANIZATION> gentleman he was _par excellence_ in every point about fifty five years old but looking at first sight still older for his hair was silver white His forehead was broad not high his face fresh and hale the harshness of the north was seen in his features as it was heard in his voice every trait was thoroughly English not a <PERSON>Norman</PERSON> line anywhere it was an inelegant unclassic unaristocratic mould of visage Fine people would perhaps have called it vulgar sensible people would have termed it characteristic shrewd people would have delighted in it for the pith sagacity intelligence the rude yet real originality marked in every lineament latent in every furrow But it was an indocile a scornful and a sarcastic face the face of a man difficult to lead and impossible to drive His stature was rather tall and he was well made and wiry and had a stately integrity of port there was not a suspicion of the clown about him anywhere I did not find it easy to sketch Mr <PERSON>Yorke</PERSON> s person but it is more difficult to indicate his mind If you expect to be treated to a Perfection reader or even to a benevolent philanthropic old gentleman in him you are mistaken He has spoken with some sense and with some good feeling to Mr <PERSON>Moore</PERSON> but you are not thence to conclude that he always spoke and thought justly and kindly Mr <PERSON>Yorke</PERSON> in the first place was without the organ of veneration a great want and which throws a man wrong on every point where veneration is required Secondly he was without the organ of comparison a deficiency which strips a man of sympathy and thirdly he had too little of the organs of benevolence and ideality which took the glory and softness from his nature and for him diminished those divine qualities throughout the universe The want of veneration made him intolerant to those above him kings and nobles and priests dynasties and parliaments and establishments with all their doings most of their enactments their forms their rights their claims were to him an abomination all rubbish he found no use or pleasure in them and believed it would be clear gain and no damage to the world if its high places were razed and their occupants crushed in the fall The want of veneration too made him dead at heart to the electric delight of admiring what is admirable it dried up a thousand pure sources of enjoyment it withered a thousand vivid pleasures He was not irreligious though a member of no sect but his religion could not be that of one who knows how to venerate He believed in God and heaven but his God and heaven were those of a man in whom awe imagination and tenderness lack The weakness of his powers of comparison made him inconsistent while he professed some excellent general doctrines of mutual toleration and forbearance he cherished towards certain classes a bigoted antipathy He spoke of parsons and all who belonged to parsons of lords and the appendages of lords with a harshness sometimes an insolence as unjust as it was insufferable He could not place himself in the position of those he vituperated he could not compare their errors with their temptations their defects with their disadvantages he could not realize the effect of such and such circumstances on himself similarly situated and he would often express the most ferocious and tyrannical wishes regarding those who had acted as he thought ferociously and tyrannically To judge by his threats he would have employed arbitrary even cruel means to advance the cause of freedom and equality Equality yes Mr <PERSON>Yorke</PERSON> talked about equality but at heart he was a proud man very friendly to his workpeople very good to all who were beneath him and submitted quietly to be beneath him but haughty as <PERSON>Beelzebub</PERSON> to whomsoever the world deemed for he deemed no man his superior Revolt was in his blood he could not bear control his father his grandfather before him could not bear it and his children after him never could The want of general benevolence made him very impatient of imbecility and of all faults which grated on his strong shrewd nature it left no check to his cutting sarcasm As he was not merciful he would sometimes wound and wound again without noticing how much he hurt or caring how deep he thrust As to the paucity of ideality in his mind that can scarcely be called a fault a fine ear for music a correct eye for colour and form left him the quality of taste and who cares for imagination Who does not think it a rather dangerous senseless attribute akin to weakness perhaps partaking of frenzy a disease rather than a gift of the mind Probably all think it so but those who possess or fancy they possess it To hear them speak you would believe that their hearts would be cold if that elixir did not flow about them that their eyes would be dim if that flame did not refine their vision that they would be lonely if this strange companion abandoned them You would suppose that it imparted some glad hope to spring some fine charm to summer some tranquil joy to autumn some consolation to winter which you do not feel An illusion of course but the fanatics cling to their dream and would not give it for gold As Mr <PERSON>Yorke</PERSON> did not possess poetic imagination himself he considered it a most superfluous quality in others Painters and musicians he could tolerate and even encourage because he could relish the results of their art he could see the charm of a fine picture and feel the pleasure of good music but a quiet poet whatever force struggled whatever fire glowed in his breast if he could not have played the man in the counting house of the tradesman in the <LOCATION>Piece Hall</LOCATION> might have lived despised and died scorned under the eyes of <PERSON>Hiram Yorke</PERSON> And as there are many <PERSON>Hiram Yorkes</PERSON> in the world it is well that the true poet quiet externally though he may be has often a truculent spirit under his placidity and is full of shrewdness in his meekness and can measure the whole stature of those who look down on him and correctly ascertain the weight and value of the pursuits they disdain him for not having followed It is happy that he can have his own bliss his own society with his great friend and goddess Nature quite independent of those who find little pleasure in him and in whom he finds no pleasure at all It is just that while the world and circumstances often turn a dark cold side to him and properly too because he first turns a dark cold careless side to them he should be able to maintain a festal brightness and cherishing glow in his bosom which makes all bright and genial for him while strangers perhaps deem his existence a Polar winter never gladdened by a sun The true poet is not one whit to be pitied and he is apt to laugh in his sleeve when any misguided sympathizer whines over his wrongs Even when utilitarians sit in judgment on him and pronounce him and his art useless he hears the sentence with such a hard derision such a broad deep comprehensive and merciless contempt of the unhappy Pharisees who pronounce it that he is rather to be chidden than condoled with These however are not Mr <PERSON>Yorke</PERSON> s reflections and it is with Mr <PERSON>Yorke</PERSON> we have at present to do I have told you some of his faults reader as to his good points he was one of the most honourable and capable men in <LOCATION>Yorkshire</LOCATION> even those who disliked him were forced to respect him He was much beloved by the poor because he was thoroughly kind and very fatherly to them To his workmen he was considerate and cordial When he dismissed them from an occupation he would try to set them on to something else or if that was impossible help them to remove with their families to a district where work might possibly be had It must also be remarked that if as sometimes chanced any individual amongst his hands showed signs of insubordination <PERSON>Yorke</PERSON> who like many who abhor being controlled knew how to control with vigour had the secret of crushing rebellion in the germ of eradicating it like a bad weed so that it never spread or developed within the sphere of his authority Such being the happy state of his own affairs he felt himself at liberty to speak with the utmost severity of those who were differently situated to ascribe whatever was unpleasant in their position entirely to their own fault to sever himself from the masters and advocate freely the cause of the operatives Mr <PERSON>Yorke</PERSON> s family was the first and oldest in the district and he though not the wealthiest was one of the most influential men His education had been good In his youth before the French Revolution he had travelled on the Continent He was an adept in the French and Italian languages During a two years sojourn in <LOCATION>Italy</LOCATION> he had collected many good paintings and tasteful rarities with which his residence was now adorned His manners when he liked were those of a finished gentleman of the old school his conversation when he was disposed to please was singularly interesting and original and if he usually expressed himself in the <LOCATION>Yorkshire</LOCATION> dialect it was because he chose to do so preferring his native Doric to a more refined vocabulary A <ORGANIZATION>Yorkshire</ORGANIZATION> burr he affirmed was as much better than a cockney s lisp as a bull s bellow than a raton s squeak Mr <PERSON>Yorke</PERSON> knew every one and was known by every one for miles round yet his intimate acquaintances were very few Himself thoroughly original he had no taste for what was ordinary a racy rough character high or low ever found acceptance with him a refined insipid personage however exalted in station was his aversion He would spend an hour any time in talking freely with a shrewd workman of his own or with some queer sagacious old woman amongst his cottagers when he would have grudged a moment to a commonplace fine gentleman or to the most fashionable and elegant if frivolous lady His preferences on these points he carried to an extreme forgetting that there may be amiable and even admirable characters amongst those who cannot be original Yet he made exceptions to his own rule There was a certain order of mind plain ingenuous neglecting refinement almost devoid of intellectuality and quite incapable of appreciating what was intellectual in him but which at the same time never felt disgust at his rudeness was not easily wounded by his sarcasm did not closely analyze his sayings doings or opinions with which he was peculiarly at ease and consequently which he peculiarly preferred He was lord amongst such characters They while submitting implicitly to his influence never acknowledged because they never reflected on his superiority they were quite tractable therefore without running the smallest danger of being servile and their unthinking easy artless insensibility was as acceptable because as convenient to Mr <PERSON>Yorke</PERSON> as that of the chair he sat on or of the floor he trod It will have been observed that he was not quite uncordial with Mr <PERSON>Moore He</PERSON> had two or three reasons for entertaining a faint partiality to that gentleman It may sound odd but the first of these was that <PERSON>Moore</PERSON> spoke English with a foreign and French with a perfectly pure accent and that his dark thin face with its fine though rather wasted lines had a most anti British and anti <LOCATION>Yorkshire</LOCATION> look These points seem frivolous unlikely to influence a character like <PERSON>Yorke</PERSON> s but the fact is they recalled old perhaps pleasurable associations they brought back his travelling his youthful days He had seen amidst Italian cities and scenes faces like <PERSON>Moore</PERSON> s he had heard in Parisian caf s and theatres voices like his He was young then and when he looked at and listened to the alien he seemed young again Secondly he had known <PERSON>Moore</PERSON> s father and had had dealings with him That was a more substantial though by no means a more agreeable tie for as his firm had been connected with <PERSON>Moore</PERSON> s in business it had also in some measure been implicated in its losses Thirdly he had found <PERSON>Robert</PERSON> himself a sharp man of business He saw reason to anticipate that he would in the end by one means or another make money and he respected both his resolution and acuteness perhaps also his hardness A fourth circumstance which drew them together was that of Mr <PERSON>Yorke</PERSON> being one of the guardians of the minor on whose estate Hollow s Mill was situated consequently <PERSON>Moore</PERSON> in the course of his alterations and improvements had frequent occasion to consult him As to the other guest now present in Mr <PERSON>Yorke</PERSON> s parlour Mr <PERSON>Helstone</PERSON> between him and his host there existed a double antipathy the antipathy of nature and that of circumstances The free thinker hated the formalist the lover of liberty detested the disciplinarian Besides it was said that in former years they had been rival suitors of the same lady Mr <PERSON>Yorke</PERSON> as a general rule was when young noted for his preference of sprightly and dashing women a showy shape and air a lively wit a ready tongue chiefly seemed to attract him He never however proposed to any of these brilliant belles whose society he sought and all at once he seriously fell in love with and eagerly wooed a girl who presented a complete contrast to those he