<ner>image DHQ Logo image Digital Humanities Quarterly Logo homesubmissionsabout dhqdhq peoplecontact Current Issue 2017 11 3 Preview Issue 2017 11 4 Previous Issues 2017 11 2 2017 11 1 2016 10 4 2016 10 3 2016 10 2 2016 10 1 2015 9 4 2015 9 3 2015 9 2 2015 9 1 2014 8 4 2014 8 3 2014 8 2 2014 8 1 2013 7 3 2013 7 2 2013 7 1 2012 6 3 2012 6 2 2012 6 1 2011 5 3 2011 5 2 2011 5 1 2010 4 2 2010 4 1 2009 3 4 2009 3 3 2009 3 2 2009 3 1 2008 2 1 2007 1 2 2007 1 1 Indexes Title Author image sidenavbarimg ISSN 1938 4122 Announcements Call for Reviewers Call for Submissions image button1 addthis gif DHQ Digital Humanities Quarterly 2017 Volume 11 Number 3 2017 11 3 XML Discuss Comments Metaphors in Digital Hermeneutics Zooming through Literary Didactic and Historical Representations of Imaginary and Existing Cities <PERSON>Florentina Armaselu</PERSON> lt florentina_dot_armaselu_at_uni_dot_lu gt <ORGANIZATION>University of Luxembourg</ORGANIZATION> <PERSON>Charles van den Heuvel</PERSON> lt charles_dot_van_dot_den_dot_heuvel_at_huygens_dot_knaw_dot_nl gt <LOCATION>Huygens ING The Hague Netherlands</LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION>University of Amsterdam Abstract The</ORGANIZATION> paper proposes to bridge two areas of inquiry digital hermeneutics and metaphor within a digital environment by the analysis of a less studied phenomenon i e how interpretation is supported and shaped by metaphors embedded in an interface The study is articulated around three use cases for literary didactic and historical representations of imaginary and existing cities based on a model z text and interface Z editor for zoomable texts We will try to demonstrate that the zooming and contextualization features of the tool allow creating layers of meaning that can assist interpretation and critical readings of literature and history 1 <ORGANIZATION>Introduction Digital Hermeneutics</ORGANIZATION> and Metaphor 1 How can interpretations of text and images be supported and shaped by metaphors embedded in an interface This is the central question of our inquiry trying to bridge digital hermeneutics and metaphor within a digital environment Interpretation is understood in terms of reconfiguration reorganization restructuring of content in a sense close to <PERSON>Samuels</PERSON> and <PERSON>McGann</PERSON> s deformance as deformative critical operation <PERSON>Samuels</PERSON> and <PERSON>McGann</PERSON> 1999 36 and <PERSON>Ramsay</PERSON> s transformation or transduction into an alternative vision Ramsay 2008 The aim is to foster insight on metaphor as a cognitive rather than merely linguistic process and its interpretative incentives conveyed by means of a digital tool The model and interface proposed for examination z text and Z editor encompass the metaphor of zooming permitting its users to work across scales and perspectives and eventually encouraging them to make peculiar associations All the presented use cases modeled via the Z editor interface involve cities some imagined some planned and some actually existing as literary historical cultural and theoretical constructs This choice is intended to illustrate how a digital tool creates opportunities for undertaking layered investigations within disciplines but also for engaging in cross disciplinary exploration Considering that scholarship in <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> operates well from both sides using tool making to advance theory and theory to imagine new tools we combine a practical perspective with theoretical reflection An overview of works originating from different fields such as philosophy of science and hermeneutics cognitive linguistics computer science and interface design serves as a starting point for our argument 2 The assumption that digital technologies are shaping our perception and understanding of the world has already been expressed in a variety of studies According to <PERSON>Capurro</PERSON> these technologies have impact on all the levels of our being in the world and it is by the term of digital hermeneutics that he defines the way digital code is being interpreted and implemented or not in today s society Capurro 2010 Going beyond the traditional sense of text centered interpretation <PERSON>Capurro</PERSON> aligns with <PERSON>Ihde</PERSON> s concept of expanding or material hermeneutics that considers technologies as instruments through which things can show themselves Ihde 2003 and which may therefore play an important role in the process of producing knowledge In the context of interactive art <PERSON>Simanowski</PERSON> situates the hermeneutic act at the intersection of formal analysis of a digital artifact structure interface grammar of interaction underpinned by the hidden text the code and interpretation in the sense of how these aspects are perceived by the audience Simanowski 2010 Likewise by their two fold conception of digital hermeneutics as theory of interpretation and context for the development of applications supporting interpretation Akker et al illustrate how the different types of relationships at the level of object event narrative modeled within an interface for online access to historical documents may assist the user in the interpretation of cultural heritage Akker et al 2011 Moreover Rockwell and <PERSON>Sinclair</PERSON> advocate for a digital hermeneutics with the focus on computer assisted text analysis and interpretation intended to the humanities <ORGANIZATION>Rockwell</ORGANIZATION> and Sinclair 2016 Elaborating on <PERSON>Gualeni</PERSON> s philosophical approach to virtual worlds in video games Gualeni 2015 and on <PERSON>Ricoeur</PERSON> s theory of metaphor and narrative as reconfiguring human experience Ricoeur 1990 Ricoeur 2003 Romele draws attention to the reconfiguration power exerted by digital technologies on their users and to the existential and ontological consequences of the production and use of these technologies articulated within the digital hermeneutics framework Romele 2016 5 6 3 Initially considered a purely linguistic and aesthetic phenomenon metaphor is more and more studied in relation with cognitive processes and implicitly interpretation mediated or not via computers Advocating for an experientialist approach within the broader context of a neural theory of language <PERSON>Lakoff</PERSON> and <PERSON>Johnson</PERSON> assume that metaphor is one of the most basic mechanisms we have for understanding our experience <PERSON>Lakoff</PERSON> and <PERSON>Johnson</PERSON> 2003 212 whose primary function is to provide a partial understanding of one kind of experience in terms of another <PERSON>Lakoff</PERSON> and <PERSON>Johnson</PERSON> 2003 155 From an interactionist perspective <PERSON>Indurkhya</PERSON> proposes a cognitive model allowing to see metaphor as an unconventional description of an object or event target by means of a different set of concepts source which may involve the reorganization and restructuring of the cognitive agent s world view Indurkhya 1992 245 In Human Computer Interaction metaphor is often described as providing the user with a model of the system <PERSON>Halskov Masden</PERSON> 1996 or as a device for explaining some system functionality or structure by asserting its similarity to another concept or thing already familiar to the user Barr 2003 9 Other aspects of metaphor as adopted in Computer Science refer for instance to its function in providing a conceptual framework for exploiting both preexisting and emerging similarity and to its pedagogical design oriented and scientific roles <PERSON>Colburn</PERSON> and <PERSON>Shute</PERSON> 2008 528 532 or to the culturally marked nature of computer collocations and metaphors manifested in the process of specialized translation from one language to another Teleoac 2004 4 Within this context evoking different approaches related to digital hermeneutics and metaphor our argumentation will focus on the hermeneutic potential of metaphor as a built in constituent of an interface and especially on its reconfiguring power common both to the interpretative attempt and to the metaphoric expression in a digital setting We assume that such a perspective combined with the presentation of three use cases may encourage insight by going beyond the description of a tool to the discussion and eventually theorization of how knowledge is fashioned by means of that tool In order to support this view the paper is structured in four sections Section 2 provides the description of the z text model and Z editor interface that allows to create and explore zoomable texts Section 3 discusses the three cases of literary didactic and historical interpretations fostered by the metaphor of zooming and the corresponding z texts built via the Z editor interface Section 4 is dedicated to conclusions and future work 2 Z text model Zooming as a Multifaceted Metaphor 5 <PERSON>Steven Johnson</PERSON> claims that after the fixed perspective of Renaissance Art and the collages of Cubism the way of seeing of our era might be called the The Long Zoom It is by any measure a difficult way of thinking in part because our brains did not evolve tools to perceive or intuitively understand the scales of microbes or galaxies You can catch glimpses of the long zoom in special effects sequences but to understand the connections between those different scales to understand our place in the universe of the very large and the very small you have to take another way in <PERSON>Johnson</PERSON> 2006 <PERSON>Johnson</PERSON> s context was the world of computer games but his observations may bring to mind <PERSON>Srinivas</PERSON> s concept of critical hermeneutics an attempt to reconcile interpretation and critical thinking which enables both closeness and distantiation to the object of study Srinivas 2010 43 Representation at different scales together with the possibility for perspective change constitute the main elements of the zooming metaphor implemented in the z text model and Z editor interface as it will be described below While the zooming function supports bridging distant and close reading by scalable reading the combination with contextualization on the various planes to read text and image from various perspectives agrees with notions of deep reading Birkerts 1994 deep maps Bodenhamer 2010 deep texts or topic modeling of hidden texts <PERSON>Blei</PERSON> and <PERSON>Lafferty</PERSON> 2006 and deep networks <PERSON>Heuvel</PERSON> 2015 <PERSON>Heuvel</PERSON> forthcoming This combination allows for the creation of multiple levels of meaning and supports a continuous process of reinterpretation from multiple perspectives contributing this way to recent developments of digital hermeneutic methods 6 Inspired by <PERSON>Stephenson</PERSON> s fictional primer an interactive scalable book that can answer the reader s questions by continuous expansion <PERSON>Stephenson</PERSON> 2003 the z text model Armaselu 2010 incorporates a multifaceted zooming metaphor 7 The first facet alluding to a primer is actually related to the idea of exploration and learning The content accessible at a certain moment via the interface may stimulate the reader s curiosity and his or her desire for further discovery This sort of thing no longer surprised or upset Nell because it had happened hundreds of times during her relationship with the Primer Besides she had known from the very first day <PERSON>Harv</PERSON> had given her the book how the story would come out in the end It was just that the story was anfractuous it developed more ramifications the more closely she read it <PERSON>Stephenson</PERSON> 2003 343 8 A second aspect implied by the anfractuous nature of the primer is the representation at variable scale which can be associated by analogy to the iterative growing of a fractal like in <PERSON>Mandelbrot</PERSON> s measurement of a coastline with smaller and smaller yardsticks Mandelbrot 1983 or to the gradual uncovering of details by zooming on an electronic map In order to function the metaphorical combination of learning or being involved with the text and zooming in the z text model includes a layered structure Armaselu 2014 to each layer corresponding a certain signification or symbolic meaning as compared to the whole 9 Figure 1 presents a z textual layout where units of content called z lexias from <PERSON>Barthes</PERSON> s lexias units of reading Barthes 1974 13 may be expanded on the deeper levels and explored by zoom in and zoom out The z lexias visible at a certain moment on the surface are disposed on different planes along with the Z axis hence the z prefix The process of expanding a z lexia is called z writing for instance zl1 from level 1 is expanded to zl1 1 on level 2 and is conceived as either an addition of details to the selected content or as a broadening in meaning according to a certain logic or argumentation strategy simple to complex concrete to abstract local to global etc or to a particular interpretation as it will be shown in the following section image Figure 1 Z text layout Levels of z lexias center Changing perspective bottom right 10 The traversal of the structure to read the z lexias and made them visible on the screen is called z reading and supposes a back and forth movement through the layers downward for zoom in upward for zoom out Since the conception of layers and their symbolic entailment depend on the author s intentions and imagination the zooming metaphor may be more or less apparent to the reader and its degree of accomplishment is determined by the inner logic driving the transition from one scale to another 11 The ZoomImagine interface Z editor allows both z writing and z reading to each mode expansion zoom in zoom out corresponding a distinct hovering cursor As illustrated in Figure 1 the metaphor of zooming is enriched by an additional facet for perspective change represented by magnifying glasses and planes of different colors right bottom which may turn the representation into a multidimensional conceptual space For example a z lexia on level i can be expanded on level i 1 following multiple perspectives e g attached to a red green or yellow magnifying glass each opening a distinctive succession of layers of meaning The magnifying glass stands therefore for a multifaceted symbol as a tool for curiosity driven exploration discovery and learning by making visible what is at first hidden and as a device providing a kaleidoscopic view on the object of inquiry 12 From a technical point of view Z editor is a Java based editor for documents in XML TEI format To each level corresponds an XML file the ancestor descendants relationships between z lexias being modelled by means of a system of identifiers relating a parent on a certain level to its children on the subsequent one There is no automatic processing for constructing the levels the content and significance of each layer of meaning depend on the author s ingenuity However the XML TEI encoding is completely transparent to the user Although it can be used for annotation and map like exploration compared with editorial platforms for annotation or for connecting maps narratives and timelines such as <PERSON>Pliny</PERSON> and Neatline Z editor is more centered on the concepts of variable scale and perspective change as organizing principles mainly of text that can also include images Therefore it can be used as a tool for reading and interpretation of existing texts and images reconfigured along with a zoomable layout or as an instrument supporting creative scenarios implying for instance the incorporation of details in a gradually expanding piece of writing in a view spotlighting the process rather than the final product The first point reading interpretation and reconfiguration of content makes the object of the present study 3 Use cases Theoretical and <ORGANIZATION>Exploratory Standpoints Imaginary Cities in Literature and History and Historical Analysis of Town Planning</ORGANIZATION> 13 After this introduction to the z text model underlying the ZoomImagine software Z editor we will demonstrate that the zooming and contextualization features of such a tool allow creating layers of meaning that support interpretation and critical readings of literature and history The results of three use cases will be discussed in which the Z editor was used to explore cross overs between text and image and history and literature in descriptions of imaginary cities and imaginary depictions of existing cities in order to establish their potential role in the history of town planning The choice for this topic of imaginary cities in relation to town planning in literature and history makes possible to assess the potential of models like z text for the development of digital hermeneutic methods It also allows to use a wide array of texts and images reading interpretations of various authors and critics from various disciplines and to compare theoretical reflections and practical applications We claim that digital tools should be used to widen the scope of literary and historical analyses by combining multiple perspectives and not only focus on certain patterns in one dimension For instance the historical research of town planning in the digital era is still conditioned by morphological pattern recognition tradition that goes back to 19th century civic art studies such as the international renown and much translated work Der St dtebau nach seinen k nstlerischen Grunds tzen of Camillo Sitte 1889 and <ORGANIZATION>Der St</ORGANIZATION> dtebau 1890 of <PERSON>Josef St bben Bohl</PERSON> and Lejeune 2009 Urban morphology practiced by 20th century in that tradition by urban historians for instance <PERSON>Michael Conzen Saverio Muratori Lewis Mumford</PERSON> and <PERSON>Pierre Lavedan</PERSON> analyzes the spatial structure of towns by focusing on patterns of streets building blocks and lots Some authors such as <PERSON>Gerard Eimer</PERSON> in his Die Stadtplanung in schwedischen Ostseereich 1600 1715 <ORGANIZATION>Mit Beitr gen</ORGANIZATION> zur Geschichte der Idealstadt 1961 or <PERSON>Bruno Fortier</PERSON> La m tropole imaginaire Un atlas de Paris 1989 tried as the titles of their publications reveal to use the morphological approach to link the structure of existing towns with mappings of ideal imaginary cities In this morphological approach images and cartographical resources of imaginary ideal and of existing cities are often translated into grid or radio concentric diagrams for comparative analyses These translations not seldom result in reduction of complexity at the cost of understanding contextual differences between these various images of cities Such morphological readings of images and cartographic sources and their limitations were enhanced by the introduction of GIS in the history of town planning and architecture Koster 2001 However GIS is only partially suitable for mapping literary or historical landscapes For instance The Mapping Lake District Literature pilot of <ORGANIZATION>Lancaster University</ORGANIZATION> makes possible to follow the trails of the authors <PERSON>Thomas Gray</PERSON> and <PERSON>Samuel Taylor Coleridge</PERSON> but the imaginary landscapes depicted in their epistolary journal and letters cannot be plotted by geographical coordinates on the map In his exploration of the potential of spatial humanities <PERSON>David Bodenhamer</PERSON> asks the question how we as humanists make GIS do what is not intended to do namely represent the world as culture and not simply mapped locations <PERSON>Bodenhamer</PERSON> 2010 23 <PERSON>Bodenhamer</PERSON> proposes to create deep maps that contextualize GIS by combining them with multiple layers of multimedia artifacts that can be viewed separately and collectively providing various perspectives Such multilayered multimedia objects would indeed permit to contextualize maps represented by geographical coordinates with non geographical spatial information However they do not allow to start from the other end i e from non Euclidean topical spaces for instance such as the imaginary cities that often inspired urban planners and architects In this context the remarks of the author <PERSON>Italo Calvino</PERSON> 1923 1985 of our first use case <ORGANIZATION>Le Citt Invisibili Invisible Cities</ORGANIZATION> of 1972 are of interest <PERSON>Calvino</PERSON> considered his <ORGANIZATION>Invisible Cities</ORGANIZATION> relevant and actual for contemporary debates on town planning I feel that the idea of the city which the book conjures up is not outside time there is also at times implicit at other explicit a discussion on the city in general I have heard from a number of friends in town planning that the book touches on some of the questions that they are faced with in their work and this is no coincidence as the background from which the book springs is the same as theirs <PERSON>Calvino</PERSON> 1983 40 It is this common background a continuous space with textual and visual representations consisting of imaginary and existing cities that we want to explore and that forms the starting point of our three cases The first literary case concerns readings of the <ORGANIZATION>Invisible Cities</ORGANIZATION> in which <PERSON>Calvino</PERSON> describes <PERSON>Marco Polo</PERSON> s accounts of visits to cities to <PERSON>Kubla Kahn</PERSON> Emperor of the Tartars In this case the z text model allows zooming on imaginary spaces in this framework story and navigating in an associative way between the Invisible Cities related publications and artistic impressions as well as critical readings hereof The zooming metaphor via Z editor in the second didactic case around the Dutch scholar of Flemish origin <PERSON>Simon Stevin</PERSON> 1548 1620 teacher to <PERSON>Maurice Count</PERSON> of <LOCATION>Nassau Prince of Orange</LOCATION> 1567 1625 will demonstrate that the most common purely functional interpretations of his ideal city and houses as planning instrument for the construction of real cities are not convincing but that these should be read in the context of didactic and educational purposes The third historical case discusses how a z text can be used to explore different levels of historical evidence of various imaginary depictions of existing cities To this end drawings of the citadel and the city of <LOCATION>Groningen</LOCATION> in the <LOCATION>Netherlands</LOCATION> in an atlas of the Flemish engineer <PERSON>Pierre Lepoivre</PERSON> 1546 1626 will be analyzed in a comparative way 3 1 Literary Case Invisible Cities a Rhizomatic Layout inside outside <PERSON>Calvino</PERSON> s Text 14 The publication of Le Citt Invisibili in 1972 by <PERSON>Italo Calvino</PERSON> was directly followed by translations and comments by literary critics and by visualizations of artists inspired by the poetical descriptions of the imaginary cities in the imageless book The division into 11 themes associated with the city that return each 5 times in the book City and Memory City and <LOCATION>Desire City</LOCATION> and <ORGANIZATION>Signs Thin Cities Trading Cities Cities</ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION>Eyes Cities and Names Cities</ORGANIZATION> and the Dead Cities and the <ORGANIZATION>Sky Continuous Cities and Hidden Cities</ORGANIZATION> has resulted into various interpretations of these imaginary urban spaces <PERSON>Kerstin Pilz</PERSON> uses <PERSON>Gilles Deleuze</PERSON> and <PERSON>Felix Guattari</PERSON> s concept of rhizomatic space to underpin her argument for a postmodern reading of city descriptions <PERSON>Pilz</PERSON> 2003 while <PERSON>Sambit Panigrahi</PERSON> underlines the importance of cities as strata that are perennially oscillating between deterritorialisation and reterritorialisation Panigrahi 2014 26 based on concepts proposed by the same philosophers Thus Panigrahi compares <PERSON>Calvino</PERSON> s description of the continuous city of <LOCATION>Leonia</LOCATION> that each days breaches through its boundaries of deposited waste at its circumference with <PERSON>Deleuze</PERSON> and <PERSON>Guattari</PERSON> s explanation of a multilayered stratum that deterritorializes from a center to periphery through multiple states epistrata and the creation of new peripheral centres with their peripheries parastrata 15 Starting from these hypotheses the zooming metaphor embedded in the z text model makes possible to interpret through rhizomatic lens <PERSON>Calvino</PERSON> s text itself as strata that can be explored by zoom in and zoom out According to <PERSON>Deleuze</PERSON> and <PERSON>Guattari</PERSON> a rhizome is made of lines of segmentarity and stratification as its dimensions and lines of flight or deterritorialization as the maximum dimension after which the multiplicity undergoes metamorphosis changes in nature <PERSON>Deleuze</PERSON> and <PERSON>Guattari</PERSON> 2014 22 The z text created following this interpretation implied a restructuration articulated along with different lines of stratification and flight or metamorphosis inside and outside <PERSON>Calvino</PERSON> s text 16 Figure 2 illustrates a reorganization of <LOCATION>Leonia</LOCATION> description which appeared to us as oscillating to paraphrase Panigrahi s analysis around the new old divide The first level of the representation left contains fragments z lexias mainly focusing on the concept of new verbalized through expressions like refashion fresh brand new latest up to date new renew The second level right completes the text with elements that highlight the tension between the passion and enjoyment of <LOCATION>Leonia</LOCATION> s inhabitants for incessant renewal and the inevitable accumulation of old produced by it expressed by phrases such as remains yesterday s <LOCATION>Leonia</LOCATION> garbage expel discard yesterday s existence Zooming in or out to surface or hide these elements from deeper strata may draw attention to the new old opposition and dynamics inherent to the text The figure shows the result of a zoom in action manifested by the expansion of the clicked z lexia from the left and the retrieval of <PERSON>Calvino</PERSON> s original fragment on the right image Figure 2 Invisible Cities z text Zoom in level 1 left 2 right Stratification along with the new old line 17 While the new old stratification determined a reconfiguration on levels inside <LOCATION>Leonia</LOCATION> text further interpretation using different lines of flight and changing of perspectives implied ramifications of the z text outside <PERSON>Calvino</PERSON> s text The first extension refers to visual representations not belonging to the original work but imagined by various artists the second moving on the same plane with contextual information enables other readings of <PERSON>Calvino</PERSON> s work both by critics and himself Recently <PERSON>Elio Baldi</PERSON> focused on <PERSON>Calvino</PERSON> s various roles in interactions between authors and critics by occasionally looking through the lens of the writer and in other moments through the eyes of the reader or editor <PERSON>Baldi</PERSON> 2015 Indeed lectures by <PERSON>Calvino</PERSON> and interviews with the author reveal many shifts in perspectives on multiple planes In a published lecture dealing with the writing of Invisible Cities <PERSON>Calvino</PERSON> reacts to almost all critics but also states that the author s view no longer counts and provides interpretations as one reader among others <PERSON>Calvino</PERSON> 1983 41 42 <PERSON>Calvino</PERSON> sometimes directly puts the Invisible Cities into context by referring to works that similarly are inspired by <PERSON>Marco Polo</PERSON> s travels such as the poem <PERSON>Kubla Kahn</PERSON> by <PERSON>Samuel Taylor Coleridge Coleridge</PERSON> 1798 The Message from the Emperor by <PERSON>Franz Kafka</PERSON> of 1919 <PERSON>Kafka</PERSON> 2012 or Il Deserto dei Tartari The Tartar Steppe by <PERSON>Dino Buzzati</PERSON> of 1940 Buzzati 1986 Calvino 1997 On other occasions references are indirect for example when <PERSON>Calvino</PERSON> notes that the atlas of <PERSON>Kubla Kahn</PERSON> contains images of lands visited in thought but not yet discovered or founded New Atlantis Utopia the City of the Sun Calvino 1997 147 On a more detailed level the possibility of sideways movements becomes important when <PERSON>Calvino</PERSON> reacts to all those critics who underlined the importance of the closing sentence by claiming that the <ORGANIZATION>Invisible Cities</ORGANIZATION> is a many facetted book with various possible conclusions <PERSON>Calvino</PERSON> 1983 41 By combining the zooming functionality with the representation of visual and contextual information a z text becomes a multidimensional space as explained below image Figure 3 Invisible Cities z text Zoom in level 2 top left 3 bottom left 3 4 top right 5 6 bottom right Extension along with the lines of flight visual and context <PERSON>Kafka</PERSON> 2012 Coleridge 1798 Calvino 1983 1 18 Figure 3 presents an extension of a level 2 z lexia top left describing <LOCATION>Leonia</LOCATION> s stratified load of refuse by a change of perspective orange VISUAL magnifying glass bottom left that includes an artistic illustration of the city and its mountains of leftovers Brannigan 2006 The same fragment can be expanded by considering a different contextualization angle blue CONTEXT magnifying glass top right adding for instance on levels 3 4 <PERSON>Kafka</PERSON> s depiction of the imperial city piled high with its own refuse <PERSON>Kafka</PERSON> 2012 28 and the walls and towers of <PERSON>Coleridge</PERSON> s Xanadu Coleridge 1798 Further contextualization on levels 5 6 bottom right enriches the representation of <PERSON>Marco Polo</PERSON> s tales of impossible cities narrated to the Kahn by <PERSON>Calvino</PERSON> s own reflections on the crisis of the overgrown city and the destruction of the natural environment as one of the main topics of his book Calvino 1983 39 41 Since these extensions are not part of the original content unlike the first z text they can be interpreted as engendered by different lines of flight determining the metamorphosis of the text that becomes image or paratext 19 The interface may support therefore both the reading and restructuring of the Invisible Cities text according to a stratified interpretation Figure 2 and its expansion by adding layers of related forms of expression and reflection Figure 3 While the latter example hints to potential artistic literary and reflective contextualizations inspired by <PERSON>Calvino</PERSON> s comments we may further imagine this type of gradual extension outside Invisible Cities as developed similarly to <PERSON>Barthes</PERSON> s analysis in S Z in line with different interpretative codes highlighting the writability and plurality of the text As <PERSON>Calvino</PERSON> observes And yet all these pages put together did not make a book for a book I think is something which has a beginning and an end even if it s not a novel in the strict sense of the word It is a space which the reader must enter wander round maybe lose his way in and eventually find an exit or perhaps even several exits or maybe a way of breaking out on his own <PERSON>Calvino</PERSON> 1983 38 If we enter our concentric city of <LOCATION>Leonia</LOCATION> again immediately new associative perspectives pop up As shown in the figure above we recognize for instance <PERSON>Calvino</PERSON> s reference to <PERSON>Kafka</PERSON> s story of the Emperor s messenger wanting to report about the death of <PERSON>Kubla Kahn</PERSON> by trying in vain to break through the walls surrounding the palace <PERSON>Kafka</PERSON> 2012 Nowadays the concentric rings of garbage surrounding <LOCATION>Leonia</LOCATION> has also become symbolic for polluted unlivable cities However another of <PERSON>Calvino</PERSON> s references the one to <PERSON>Campanella</PERSON> s concentric walled City of the Sun allows to link the form of <LOCATION>Leonia</LOCATION> with images of built and not built fortified cities that are relevant to our two next cases focusing on the impact of visualizations of imaginary and existing cities for town planning fortification and architectural design 3 2 Didactic Case <PERSON>Simon Stevin</PERSON> s Multilayered System Based on the <ORGANIZATION>Concept of Mirror Symmetry</ORGANIZATION> 20 In the years 1605 and 1608 the Flemish mathematician <PERSON>Simon Stevin</PERSON> 1548 1620 published five books in two volumes with the title Wisconstighe Ghedachtenissen Mathematical Memoirs that can be seen as a compilation of his private lessons to Prince <PERSON>Maurice</PERSON> of Orange 1567 1625 on mathematics natural sciences and military arts at the court in <LOCATION>The Hague</LOCATION> In the fifth book Van de Ghemengde Stoffen <PERSON>Miscellanea Stevin</PERSON> explained in a note that he had not been able to finish several treatises announced in the table of content on Arithmetic Book keeping Architecture Music Theory Military Arts and other topics in time for the printer and planned therefore to publish these at a later moment Stevin 1605 1608 5 107 By the time <PERSON>Stevin</PERSON> died in 1620 only a few fragments of these announced treatises had appeared in other publications 21 This case discusses interpretations on <PERSON>Stevin</PERSON> s uncompleted treatise on town planning and architecture of which fragments were adapted and published posthumously by his son <PERSON>Hendrik Stevin</PERSON> in his Materiae Politicae Burgherlicke Stoffen Political Matters Civic Affairs 1649 and Wisconstich Filosofisch Bedryf Mathematical Philosophical Act 1667 <PERSON>Charles van den Heuvel</PERSON> made a reconstruction of <PERSON>Stevin</PERSON> s treatise on town planning and architecture <PERSON>De Huysbou</PERSON> on the basis of excerpts in manuscripts of scholars such as <PERSON>Isaac Beeckman Constantijn</PERSON> and <PERSON>Christiaan Huygens</PERSON> and <PERSON>Hendrik Stevin</PERSON> that circulated in the Dutch Republic <PERSON>Heuvel</PERSON> 2005 <PERSON>Stevin</PERSON> s diagrams of ideal buildings and town known via the publication in <PERSON>Hendrik Stevin</PERSON> s Materiae Politicae have been often described in purely morphological and rational terms Eimer 1961 Hoeven and <LOCATION>Louwe</LOCATION> 1985 Oers 2000 However we will try to reveal via the zooming features of the Z editor interface that <PERSON>Stevin</PERSON> s city architecture was not conceived as one rational whole but rather should be read from a didactic perspective to explain a multi layered model of an ideal city and houses all based on the same underlying concept of mirror symmetry Nowadays we are familiar with the concept of mirror symmetry but at the time that <PERSON>Stevin</PERSON> wrote his treatise authors on architecture used the term symmetria in the Vitruvian tradition i e as the harmonious ratio of the parts to the whole For that reason <PERSON>Stevin</PERSON> introduced the neologism lycksijdcheyt literally like sidedness For <PERSON>Stevin</PERSON> this distinction was not trivial But in his view mirror symmetry had its origins in nature unlike the proportional symmetry of <PERSON>Vitruvius</PERSON> and his followers and should therefore serve as the basis for logical architecture a building should be like an animal and if one wishes to make it correctly one should follow nature By which it should be understood that just as nature or the Creator of animals produces like sidedness so the architect should emulate this and design buildings with like sidedness Stevin 1649 13 transl <PERSON>Heuvel</PERSON> 2005 1 22 The zooming and contextualization features of the Z editor Figure 4 allow us to demonstrate why the relationships between <PERSON>Stevin</PERSON> s town and houses should be understood in the context of his didactic explanation of the underlying principle of mirror symmetry rather by the rational arguments based on morphological correspondences between some but not all of the buildings blocks of houses and the town A closer look at <PERSON>Stevin</PERSON> s town plan reveals that most but not all features can be explained rationally The rectangular ground plan with its square buildings blocks enables an efficient distribution of houses and can be therefore read from a civic planning perspective as rational However the bastions with acute pointed faces and the odd double flanks from the bastions adjacent to the corner bastions are compromises from a military point of view <PERSON>Stevin</PERSON> was well aware of that In his treatise on fortification De Sterctenbouwing Stevin 1594 <PERSON>Stevin</PERSON> explained that the optimal form for a large city to defend itself would be a hexagon A comparison on level 1 city shows indeed that the hexagonal perimeter of the fortress city results in bastions with more obtuse points that are less vulnerable for collision after a heavy impact of gunfire Also zooming reveals that <PERSON>Stevin</PERSON> s city cannot be read as one coherent whole Hoeven Louwen represented <PERSON>Stevin</PERSON> s city as a system of building components that could be pieced together <PERSON>Hoeven</PERSON> and Louwe 1985 However if we zoom in to 2nd level that represents buildings blocks containing different numbers of houses it becomes clear that as a result of the variations in their rectangular form they would not all fit into the square buildings blocks represented in the town plan Despite their differences the blocks have in common that they are organized in such a way that all houses receive as much light as possible from the inner courts and that the rules of mirror symmetry are always respected In short <PERSON>Stevin</PERSON> was not interested in forms of towns and dwellings in which contrasting demands of military economic or social orders were planned as one whole Instead <PERSON>Stevin</PERSON> s writings on the layout of houses and towns are characterized by the separation of different levels and the segregation of adjacent functions <PERSON>Stevin</PERSON> s synthesis of houses into blocks blocks into towns and the ordering of urban extensions focused more on the organizational method than on the precise form And this method was governed by a single principle that of mirror symmetry to which all other organizational forms were subordinated The reason why <PERSON>Stevin</PERSON> s city has been read by many authors as one systematic whole might have been enhanced by their use of its representation in print in the work of <PERSON>Hendrik Stevin Hendrik Stevin</PERSON> represented his father s city with all the names of the civic functions palace churches markets university etc engraved in the image itself This way the image of the city could be read independently as one whole However <PERSON>Hendrik Stevin</PERSON> s excerpt in the manuscript version of the Huysbou drawn after the original drawings reveals that his father s representation of the town buildings blocks and separated houses consists of a series of diagrams including letters numbers referred to in the descriptions that can only be understood in combination with the text and other illustrations 23 Figure 4 and 5 present two z texts Figure 4 denotes a transposition of <PERSON>Stevin</PERSON> s drawings and texts allowing the reader to traverse the conceptual space by zooming in and out through the city buildings block and house down to the very definition of like sidedness This traversal corresponds to a change of scale in the representation of the city and its parts correlated with a didactic argumentation lead by the principle of mirror symmetry inspired by <PERSON>Stevin</PERSON> s text itself image Figure 4 <PERSON>Stevin</PERSON> z texts mirror symmetry top right Stevin 1649 2 image Figure 5 <PERSON>Stevin</PERSON> z texts contextualisation Print Manuscript bottom left <PERSON>Heuvel</PERSON> 2017 3 24 The second z text in Figure 5 illustrates zooming with perspective change PRINT MANUSCRIPT in a contextualisation text <PERSON>Heuvel</PERSON> 2017 that explains the differences between the manuscript and the printed version determined by <PERSON>Hendrik</PERSON> s changes in his father s representation of the town 25 Zooming provides therefore a figurative way of unfolding our contextualization and interpretation of <PERSON>Stevin</PERSON> s multi layered model that allowed him in his role of private tutor to explain the principles and natural logic of his architecture and town planning on each level most clearly for educational and pedagogic purposes Logical and lucid models albeit incomplete were for <PERSON>Stevin</PERSON> a more appropriate means of achieving that goal than a complete reproduction of reality that with all its contradictions might obscure the problem or to say it in <PERSON>Simon Stevin</PERSON> s own words in his work on fortification because the teaching should not be complicated by arguments <PERSON>Heuvel</PERSON> 2005 68 3 3 Historical Case Multiple Levels of Historical Evidence in Lepoivre Atlas 26 <PERSON>Stevin</PERSON> was not only the tutor but also a military advisor to Prince <PERSON>Maurice</PERSON> and accompanied him on all his campaigns in the first decades of the Eighty Years War in the Low Countries against <LOCATION>Spain</LOCATION> Although Prince <PERSON>Maurice</PERSON> became Captain General of the <ORGANIZATION>Army</ORGANIZATION> and Admiral of the Fleet after the assassination of his father <PERSON>William the Silent</PERSON> in 1584 when he was 18 years old his inexperience was not the only reason that his uncles insisted on training him in the military arts Training in the military arts made part of the education of noblemen where elementary of warfare and fortification were taught along dancing singing playing music drawing fencing and of course disciplines such as mathematics physics logic rhetoric and languages On the ceiling of the Palazzo dei Cinquecento in <LOCATION>Florence</LOCATION> Archduke <PERSON>Cosimo</PERSON> I dei Medici is depicted drawing a fortress with a compass in his hand and <PERSON>Stevin</PERSON> explained how Prince <PERSON>Maurice</PERSON> developed an instrument in order to learn to draw fortifications in the correct way Knowledge of fortification drawings belonged to the cultural education of noblemen and designs that once played a role in the practice of building defenses for cities ended up in their collections Often they were re used or adapted for decorations of fortified cities on the walls of their palaces or to create beautiful atlases It is in this context that the atlas presented in 1624 by the Flemish engineer <PERSON>Pierre Lepoivre</PERSON> ca 1546 1627 to the archdukes <PERSON>Albert VI</PERSON> and Isabel of <LOCATION>Austria</LOCATION> sovereigns of the <LOCATION>Habsburg Netherlands</LOCATION> must be understood <PERSON>Heuvel</PERSON> 1998 At first sight Les Plans des Villes des Pa s de Hennault d Artois de Breband tr s noblement descripts la plume drawn by <PERSON>Lepoivre</PERSON> between 1615 1622 seem to provide trustworthy depictions of historical battles and sieges that took place in the Eighty Years War in the Low Countries A closer reading of the drawings however reveals that <PERSON>Lepoivre</PERSON> mixed his own mappings of historical events with interpretations of other cartographical depictions of besieged towns and unexecuted designs of cities resulting in different levels of reliability and trustworthiness This becomes clear for instance in four drawings in his atlas based on designs that the Italian engineer <PERSON>Bartolomeo Campi</PERSON> 1573 made for the city and citadel of <LOCATION>Groningen</LOCATION> in the <LOCATION>Netherlands</LOCATION> The detail of the bastion was probably directly copied after <PERSON>Campi</PERSON> s design of 1570 Heuvel 1994 Lepoivre included a drawing after <PERSON>Campi</PERSON> s design for a hexagonal citadel similar to <PERSON>Stevin</PERSON> s fortress city in the form of hexagon but a pentagonal one was executed The third drawing shows <ORGANIZATION>Groningen</ORGANIZATION> with the hexagonal citadel that never existed in that form and the fourth as a part of the <ORGANIZATION>Siege of Groningen</ORGANIZATION> in 1594 when the citadel that existed was already dismantled <PERSON>Heuvel</PERSON> 1998 27 The Z editor not only allows moving along the four different levels of historical evidence but also to position these drawings between more and less imaginary depictions of existing cities image Figure 6 Lepoivre Atlas z text Zoom out level 4 to 1 zoom in level 1 to 4 and perspective change <PERSON>Agustino Campi</PERSON> level 2 <PERSON>Aleotti Campi</PERSON> level 3 Interpretation according to the degree of reliability of the drawings as historical evidence bottom left 4 28 In Figure 6 the explanatory texts and drawings from Lepoivre Atlas are structured on four levels corresponding to different illustrations of the city of <LOCATION>Groningen</LOCATION> bird eye view plan with the hexagonal citadel the hexagonal citadel itself detail of the bastion that can be traversed by zooming in right to left and zooming out left to right Two alternative views outline with pentagonal citadel and pentagonal citadel alone are also provided on level 2 and 3 via perspective change <PERSON>AGUSTINO CAMPI ALEOTTI CAMPI</PERSON> As the symbolic representation bottom left suggests the z text allows the reader not only to explore the projection of the city at different scales but also to understand Lepoivre drawings in a larger context based on the degree of reliability of historical evidence as further explained below 29 <PERSON>Pierre Lepoivre</PERSON> had assisted in the execution of the citadel of <LOCATION>Groningen</LOCATION> and must therefore have known which designs of <PERSON>Campi</PERSON> had been approved for execution <PERSON>Martens</PERSON> 2014 Nowadays we would call <PERSON>Lepoivre</PERSON> s variations on <PERSON>Campi</PERSON> s non executed designs historical falsifications however at the time of Lepoivre the mixing of sources to illuminate historic events that took place apparently was not considered to be problematic Not only <PERSON>Lepoivre</PERSON> knew also the archdukes in their official role of sovereigns of the <LOCATION>Habsburg Netherlands</LOCATION> must have known They had given Lepoivre official commission to make designs for reliable fortification works and given him 500 Flemish pounds for the atlas but seem to have had no objection that the engineer selected or at least included drawings based on non executed designs or adaptations of representations of historical events The re use in Lepoivre s atlas of the designs of <PERSON>Campi</PERSON> originally intended to explain technical details and to support administrators in their decision to approve or disapprove the execution hereof gave them an additional cultural meaning as objects of prestige or study in the private collection of the archdukes 30 Such multiple layers of meaning cannot be grasped in full by GIS or existing spatial digital humanities software but that requires tools such as Z editor for scalable readings and moving through geographical and topical spaces 31 Finally we may picture ourselves navigating in an associative way through imaginary cities whose features might have inspired both <PERSON>Calvino</PERSON> s literary writings as <PERSON>Lepoivre</PERSON> s designs Contemporary artists still inspired by <PERSON>Calvino</PERSON> seem to delve into a collective visual memory of cities in a way Renaissance engineers linked their designs to representations of ideal cities and new fortress towns from <PERSON>Campanella</PERSON> s City of the Sun to <LOCATION>Zamosz</LOCATION> in <LOCATION>Poland</LOCATION> Renaissance ideal fortress cities were radial concentric cities with a polygonal perimeter with angular bastions Therefore circumscribing and inscribing circles played an essential role in designing fortified cities and citadels The design of fortifications was not just functional Training in the <ORGANIZATION>Military Arts</ORGANIZATION> belonged to the education of noblemen who often collected drawings of fortifications Fortification atlases were cultural artifacts amongst other books on architecture such as the many Vitruvius editions of the Renaissance that often contained antique and modern visual interpretations of the city described in the lost original manuscript 32 One of <PERSON>Calvino</PERSON> s references to <PERSON>Campanella</PERSON> s concentric walled City of the Sun allows to link the form of <LOCATION>Leonia</LOCATION> with images of built and not built fortified cities as the designs of citadels in the atlas of Lepoivre This comparison is of interest since <PERSON>Calvino</PERSON> once considered a theme Cities and Form as well but decided to merge it with those of other cities <PERSON>Calvino</PERSON> 1983 38 By extension we can imagine a traversal through the space of city forms following multiple exploration paths and connecting imaginary cities in literature <PERSON>Calvino Campanella</PERSON> and in architectural treatises and theory <PERSON>Vitruvius</PERSON> with imaginary representations of existing cities in design Lepoivre image Figure 7 Imaginary Cities z text Level 1 left 2 top right 3 bottom right Traversal through the space of forms <PERSON>Calvino Campanella Vitruvius Lepoivre</PERSON> 5 33 The examples presented in this section were intended to illustrate how the reconfiguration restructuring reorganization of existing content excerpts from books articles essays etc images may be shaped via metaphoric and digital lens both in the interpretation and the production of knowledge Our assumption was that the interface mediates a two stage process by influencing our perception of a topic as well as the way we represent this perception via the interface In our cases the metaphor of zooming determined a certain predisposition to discern different scales angles associations and layers of meaning in the material of study and at the same time allowed remodeling and ultimately rereading the matter in a digital form consistent with that metaphor A phenomenon worthy of further inquiry 4 Conclusions and Future Work 34 In the introduction we stated that metaphors embedded in the interface may support and shape interpretation It is what we tried to demonstrate navigating through the three use cases for literary didactic and historical representations of imaginary and existing cities and the corresponding z texts built via the Z editor an interface for writing and reading zoomable texts 35 The first case proposed a stratification of textual and visual details made visible or invisible through the change of scale and perspective which allowed a critical projection of <PERSON>Calvino</PERSON> s Invisible Cities onto a rhizomatic interpretative space In the second example we transposed <PERSON>Stevin</PERSON> s conceptual system of town design into a scalable structure from the level of the whole city to that of a house to the abstract layer explaining the concept of mirror symmetry and its role as an organizing principle within the whole system interpreted in this way from a didactic viewpoint An additional z text illustrated the contextualization of <PERSON>Stevin</PERSON> s work by highlighting via the switch of perspective from manuscript to print the differences in the visual textual dynamics in <PERSON>Simon</PERSON> s versus <PERSON>Hendrik</PERSON> s representations of the town plans The third experiment dealt with a symbolic traversal at variable scale of the city of <LOCATION>Groningen</LOCATION> drawings from Lepoivre Atlas which together with views of alternative designs assisted interpretation within the larger context of more or less reliable historical evidence 36 As <PERSON>Eberhardt</PERSON> affirms referring to <LOCATION>Gadamer</LOCATION> s hermeneutics the use of zooming not only provides more detail but also allows horizontal expansion resulting in widening horizons <PERSON>Eberhardt</PERSON> 2004 87 88 The study of the role of zooming in particular and of metaphors in general in digital hermeneutics has in our opinion the potential for widening horizons both in terms of interpretation and of production of knowledge Further experiments and features development should be envisaged e g allowing the users to have an overview reconstruct and annotate the steps they took while navigating in the interpretative space provided by the digital tool and the implied metaphor Moreover further requirements can be explored by interdisciplinary research and training programs like the <ORGANIZATION>Digital History and Hermeneutics Doctoral Training Unit</ORGANIZATION> starting in 2017 at the <ORGANIZATION>University of Luxembourg</ORGANIZATION> intended to create a space of experiment and to encourage critical and self reflexive use of digital tools and technologies Fickers 2016 in order to stimulate creative thinking and to improve the exploitation of these tools and technologies for research and teaching In this context the combined analysis of metaphor and digital hermeneutics may open new paths for experiment and reflection in <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities Notes</ORGANIZATION> 1 <ORGANIZATION>Brannigan Colleen Corradi 2006 Oil</ORGANIZATION> and acrylic paintings <LOCATION>Le Citt Invisibili Leonia</LOCATION> http www cittainvisibili com en portfolio leonia en html with the artist s agreement Accessed May 22 2017 <PERSON>Coleridge Samuel Taylor</PERSON> 1798 <PERSON>Kubla Kahn</PERSON> In The Rime of the Ancient Mariner and <ORGANIZATION>Other Poems New York Dover Publications Inc</ORGANIZATION> Illustration <PERSON>Patten Wilson</PERSON> http www fulltable com vts aoi w wilson 07 jpg Accessed May 22 2017 2 <PERSON>Hendrik Stevin</PERSON> Ideal town plan according to design <PERSON>Simon Stevin</PERSON> drawing in ink <PERSON>Hendrik Stevin Eenighe Stucken</PERSON> der Crychconst Beschreve deur <PERSON>Simon Stevin</PERSON> The <ORGANIZATION>Hague KB National Library</ORGANIZATION> of the Netherlands Manuscript 128 A9 II fol 6 Image c The <ORGANIZATION>Hague KB National Library</ORGANIZATION> of the Netherlands <PERSON>Hendrik Stevin</PERSON> after <PERSON>Simon Stevin</PERSON> s buildings block illustration <PERSON>Hendrik Stevin Materiae Politicae Byvough der Stedenoirdening Leiden Adryaen Rosenboom</PERSON> 1649 <PERSON>Hendrik Stevin</PERSON> after <PERSON>Simon Stevin</PERSON> s house illustration <PERSON>Hendrik Stevin Materiae Politicae Byvough der Stedenoirdening Leiden Adryaen Rosenboom</PERSON> 1649 <PERSON>Hendrik Stevin Ideal</PERSON> town plan according to design <PERSON>Simon Stevin</PERSON> illustration <PERSON>Hendrik Stevin Materiae Politicae Byvough der Stedenoirdening Leiden Adryaen Rosenboom</PERSON> 1649 3 <PERSON>Hendrik Stevin</PERSON> Ideal town plan according to design <PERSON>Simon Stevin</PERSON> drawing in ink <PERSON>Hendrik Stevin Eenighe Stucken</PERSON> der Crychconst Beschreve deur <PERSON>Simon Stevin</PERSON> The <ORGANIZATION>Hague KB National Library</ORGANIZATION> of the Netherlands Manuscript 128 A9 II fol 6 Image c The <ORGANIZATION>Hague KB National Library</ORGANIZATION> of the Netherlands <PERSON>Hendrik Stevin</PERSON> after <PERSON>Simon Stevin</PERSON> s buildings block illustration <PERSON>Hendrik Stevin Materiae Politicae Byvough der Stedenoirdening Leiden Adryaen Rosenboom</PERSON> 1649 <PERSON>Hendrik Stevin</PERSON> after <PERSON>Simon Stevin</PERSON> s house illustration <PERSON>Hendrik Stevin Materiae Politicae Byvough der Stedenoirdening Leiden Adryaen Rosenboom</PERSON> 1649 <PERSON>Hendrik Stevin</PERSON> Ideal town plan according to design <PERSON>Simon Stevin</PERSON> illustration <PERSON>Hendrik Stevin Materiae Politicae Byvough</PERSON> der Stedenoirdening Leiden Adryaen Rosenboom 1649 4 Birds eye view of the <ORGANIZATION>Siege of Groningen</ORGANIZATION> with the hexagonal citadel of <ORGANIZATION>Groningen Brussels Royal Library</ORGANIZATION> manuscript 19611 folio 8 Groninghen Assiegee Plan of the city of <LOCATION>Groningen</LOCATION> and the hexagonal citadel of <ORGANIZATION>Bartolomeo Campi Brussels Royal Library</ORGANIZATION> manuscript 19611 folio 11 Subscription Des trouble du Pais Bas qui sont amines l an 1566 DU PLAN DE GRONINGE ET DU Chasteauquy fut batie par ordre de Sr don <PERSON>Fernande D Alvarez</PERSON> l an 1569 6 March 1618 Design of hexagonal citadel for the City of <ORGANIZATION>Groningen</ORGANIZATION> by <PERSON>Bartolomeo Campi</PERSON> copy by <ORGANIZATION>Pierre Le Poivre Brussels Royal Library</ORGANIZATION> manuscript 19611 folio 10 <ORGANIZATION>LA PLAN DU CHASTEAU DE GRONINGEN</ORGANIZATION> qui fut batit l an 1570 par advis du <PERSON>Duc Alvaqui</PERSON> fut ordon z de l ingenieur Pacciotto fut achev de Bartholomeo Campy P Lepoivre 12 April 1618 Design of Bastion for the <ORGANIZATION>City of Groningen</ORGANIZATION> plan top level and fundaments level by <PERSON>Bartolomeo Campi</PERSON> copy by <PERSON>Pierre LePoivre</PERSON> for his atlas <ORGANIZATION>Brussels Royal Library</ORGANIZATION> manuscript 19611 folio 13 Subscription top <PERSON>Particuliarit</PERSON> s des fondements sic fundaments de l architecture du chasteau de gruningen <ORGANIZATION>Groningen</ORGANIZATION> qui fut comenses sic commenc s de l ingenieur pachote sic <PERSON>Francesco Paciotto</PERSON> et depuis fur achev du Sr <PERSON>Capitano Bertholmeo Campy Bartolomeo Campi Ingenieur de Sa Majest</PERSON> et l autheur de ces oeuvres diondante des dict Ingenieur Ceste scale contient 300 piedz depuis la letter A et B faicte Bruxelle le 19 April 1618 P Lepoivre architecte de Sa Majest Catholique Subscription bottom Particularit s du boulverts y cy dessus remarqu s par la Plan figure de la letter etc Pentagonal citadel of <ORGANIZATION>Groningen</ORGANIZATION> executed after design of <PERSON>Bartolomeo Campi</PERSON> copy by <PERSON>Giambattista Aleotti Ferrara Biblioteca Comunale Aristostea Man Classe</PERSON> I 763 n 138 Outlines for the pentagonal citadel of <ORGANIZATION>Groningen</ORGANIZATION> by <PERSON>Capitano Agustino</PERSON> with the accepted changes proposed by <ORGANIZATION>Bartolomeo Campi Archivo General de Simancas Mapas Planos y Dibujos VII</ORGANIZATION> 48 Dotted lines in red show accepted proposal of <PERSON>Bartolomeo Campi</PERSON> for the measurements of the pentagonal citadel <ORGANIZATION>Groningen</ORGANIZATION> 5 <PERSON>Calvino Italo Les</PERSON> villes invisibles Illustr par <ORGANIZATION>G rard Trignac Edit par Les Amis du Livre Contemporain</ORGANIZATION> 1993 http www trignac gerard com Les villes invisibles Accessed May 22 2017 SADI Space Gallery Continuous city <LOCATION>Leonia</LOCATION> 2009 http www sadi net ge cd 13th lb02 html Accessed May 22 2017 <PERSON>Campanella Tommaso City</PERSON> of the Sun 1602 Latin printed edition <LOCATION>Frankfurt</LOCATION> 1623 <PERSON>Campanella Tommaso City</PERSON> of the Sun http prometey spb su svetochi 0 kampanella html Accessed May 22 2017 Fra Giocondo Vitruvian City 1511 <LOCATION>Caporali Vitruvian City</LOCATION> 1536 Birds eye view of the <ORGANIZATION>Siege of Groningen</ORGANIZATION> with the hexagonal citadel of <ORGANIZATION>Groningen Brussels Royal Library</ORGANIZATION> manuscript 19611 folio 8 Groninghen Assiegee Design of hexagonal citadel for the City of <ORGANIZATION>Groningen</ORGANIZATION> by <PERSON>Bartolomeo Campi</PERSON> copy by <ORGANIZATION>Pierre Le Poivre Brussels Royal Library</ORGANIZATION> manuscript 19611 folio 10 <ORGANIZATION>LA PLAN DU CHASTEAU DE GRONINGEN</ORGANIZATION> qui fut batit l an 1570 par advis du <PERSON>Duc Alvaqui</PERSON> fut ordon z de l ingenieur Pacciotto fut achev de bartholomeo Campy P Lepoivre 12 April 1618 Works Cited Akker et al 2011 <PERSON>Akker Chiel</PERSON> van den et altri 2011 Agora Digital Hermeneutics Online Understanding of Cultural Heritage Proceedings of the 3rd International Conference on Web Science WebSci 11 <ORGANIZATION>Koblenz Germany</ORGANIZATION> 14 17 June 2011 Armaselu 2010 <PERSON>Armaselu Vasilescu Florentina</PERSON> 2010 Ph D thesis Le livre sous la loupe Nouvelles formes d criture lectronique <ORGANIZATION>Papyrus University of Montreal Institutional Repository</ORGANIZATION> https papyrus bib umontreal ca xmlui handle 1866 3964 Accessed May 22 2017 Armaselu 2014 Armaselu Florentina 2014 The Layered Text From <ORGANIZATION>Textual Zoom Text Network Analysis</ORGANIZATION> and Text Summarisation to a Layered Interpretation of Meaning Digital Humanities 2014 Conference Abstract EPFL UNIL <LOCATION>Lausanne Switzerland</LOCATION> 8 12 July 2014 79 82 http dharchive org paper DH2014 Paper 515 xml Accessed May 22 2017 <PERSON>Baldi</PERSON> 2015 <PERSON>Baldi Elio</PERSON> 2015 l ochiochescrive La dinamica dell imagine autoriale di <PERSON>Calvino</PERSON> nellacriticaitaliana Incontri Anno 30 2015 fascicolo 1 p 22 33 www rivista incontri nl Accessed May 22 2017 Barr 2003 Barr Pippin 2003 User Interface Metaphors in Theory and Practice A thesis submitted to <ORGANIZATION>Victoria University of Wellington</ORGANIZATION> in fulfilment of the requirements for the degree of Master of Science in Computer Science http www pippinbarr com academic Pippin_Barr_MSc_Thesis pdf Accessed May 22 2017 Barthes 1974 Barthes Roland 1974 S Z first edition 1970 translated by <PERSON>Richard Miller Hill</PERSON> and <PERSON>Wang</PERSON> <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> Birkerts 1994 Birkerts Sven 1994 The Gutenberg Elegies the Fate of Reading in an <ORGANIZATION>Electronic Age Faber amp Faber Boston MA Blei</ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON>Lafferty</PERSON> 2006 <PERSON>Blei David M Lafferty John</PERSON> D 2006 Dynamic Topic Models In Proceedings of the 23rd international Conference on <ORGANIZATION>Machine Learning ICML</ORGANIZATION> 06 pp 113 120 Bodenhamer 2010 <PERSON>Bodenhamer David</PERSON> 2010 The Potential of Spatial Humanities In The Spatial Humanities GIS and the Future of Humanities Scholarship edited by <PERSON>David J Bodenhamer John Corrigan</PERSON> and <PERSON>Trevor</PERSON> M <ORGANIZATION>Harris Indiana University Press Bloomington</ORGANIZATION> 14 30 <PERSON>Bohl</PERSON> and Lejeune 2009 <PERSON>Bohl Charles Lejeune Jean Francois</PERSON> eds 2009 <PERSON>Sitte Hegemann</PERSON> and the metropolis modern civic art and international exchanges <LOCATION>Routledge London New York Buzzati</LOCATION> 1986 <PERSON>Buzzati Dino</PERSON> 1986 Il Deserto dei Tartari Mondari Milan Org 1940 Calvino 1972 Calvino Italo 1972 Le citt invisibili <PERSON>Einaudi Turin Calvino</PERSON> 1983 Calvino Italo 1983 <PERSON>Italo Calvino</PERSON> on <ORGANIZATION>Invisible Cities Columbia A Journal of Literature</ORGANIZATION> and Art No 8 Spring Summer 1983 7 42 http www jstor org stable 41806854 Accessed May 22 2017 Calvino 1997 Calvino Italo 1997 Invisible Cities Translated from the Italian by <ORGANIZATION>William Weaver Vintage Books London Capurro 2010 Capurro Rafael 2010 Digital Hermeneutics An Outline In AI amp Society</ORGANIZATION> 25 1 35 42 http www capurro de digitalhermeneutics html DOI 10 1007 s00146 009 0255 9 Accessed May 22 2017 <PERSON>Colburn</PERSON> and <PERSON>Shute</PERSON> 2008 <PERSON>Colburn Timothy R Shute Gary</PERSON> M 2008 Metaphor in computer science In Journal of Applied Logic Volume 6 Issue 4 December 2008 Pages 526 533 http www sciencedirect com science article pii S1570868308000463 Accessed May 22 2017 Coleridge 1798 <PERSON>Coleridge Samuel Taylor</PERSON> 1798 <PERSON>Kubla Kahn</PERSON> In The Rime of the Ancient Mariner and <ORGANIZATION>Other Poems Dover Publications Inc New York Deleuze</ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON>Guattari</PERSON> 2014 <PERSON>Deleuze Gilles Guattari</PERSON> F lix 2014 A Thousand Plateaus Capitalism and <ORGANIZATION>Schizophrenia Bloomsbury Academic London New Delhi New York Sydney</ORGANIZATION> paperback 2013 reprinted 2014 <PERSON>Eberhardt</PERSON> 2004 <PERSON>Eberhardt Philippe</PERSON> 2004 The Middle Voice in <LOCATION>Gadamer</LOCATION> s Hermeneutics A basic interpretation with some Theological Implications <PERSON>Mohr Siebeck</PERSON> T bingen <PERSON>Eimer</PERSON> 1961 <PERSON>Eimer Gerhard</PERSON> 1961 Die Stadtplanung in schwedischen Ostseereich 1600 1715 <ORGANIZATION>Mit Beitr</ORGANIZATION> genzur Geschichte der Idealstadt Svenskabokf rlaget Stockholm Fickers 2016 Fickers <PERSON>Andreas</PERSON> e a 2016 PRIDE Doctoral Training Unit DTU on <ORGANIZATION>Digital History amp Hermeneutics</ORGANIZATION> http www dhlab lu digital literacy digital history hermeneutics dtu Accessed May 22 2017 Gualeni 2015 Gualeni Stefano 2015 Virtual Worlds as Philosophical Tools How to Philosophize with a <ORGANIZATION>Digital Hammer Palgrave Macmillan</ORGANIZATION> 194 pp ISBN 978 1137521774 <PERSON>Halskov Masden</PERSON> 1996 <PERSON>Halskov Madsen Kim</PERSON> 1996 A Guide to Metaphorical Design In METAFORERI SPROG OG T NKNING Proceedings fra Metafornetv rketsseminari <ORGANIZATION>Odense</ORGANIZATION> den 8 10 februar 1996 http www sprog asb dk cg metaphor tekst 1 HALSKOV HTM Accessed May 22 2017 Heuvel 1994 <PERSON>Heuvel Charles</PERSON> van den 1994 <PERSON>Bartolomeo Campi</PERSON> successor to <PERSON>Francesco Paciotto</PERSON> A different method of designing citadels <ORGANIZATION>Groningen</ORGANIZATION> and <LOCATION>Flushing</LOCATION> In <LOCATION>Architetti</LOCATION> e ingegneri militari italiani all estero dal XV al XVIII secolo <ORGANIZATION>Sillabe Livorno Roma</ORGANIZATION> 153 167 Heuvel 1998 <PERSON>Heuvel Charles</PERSON> van den 1998 <PERSON>Pierre Le Poivre</PERSON> 1546 1626 Engineer of the King and the Representation of Architecture in W <PERSON>Thomas L Duerloo</PERSON> eds <PERSON>Albrecht</PERSON> amp <PERSON>Isabella</PERSON> Essays Brepols Turnhout 198 202 Heuvel 2005 <PERSON>Heuvel Charles</PERSON> van den 2005 De Huysbou A reconstruction of an unfinished treatise on architecture townplanning and civil engineering by <PERSON>Simon Stevin</PERSON> KNAW <ORGANIZATION>Edita Amsterdam</ORGANIZATION> http www dwc knaw nl wp content HSSN 2005 7 Huysbou 20Stevin pdf Accessed May 22 2017 Heuvel 2015 <PERSON>Heuvel Charles</PERSON> van den 2015 Mapping Knowledge Exchange in Early Modern <ORGANIZATION>Europe Intellectual and Technological Geographies and Network Representations International Journal of Humanities</ORGANIZATION> and Arts Computing 9 1 95 114 DOI 10 3366 ijhac 2015 0140 <PERSON>Heuvel</PERSON> 2017 <PERSON>Heuvel Charles van</PERSON> den 2017 As the Author Intended Transformation of the Unpublished Writings and Drawings of <PERSON>Simon Stevin</PERSON> 1548 1620 Translating Early Modern Science Edited by <PERSON>Sietske Fransen Niall Hodson Karl</PERSON> A E <ORGANIZATION>Enenkel Brill Publishers Leiden Boston</ORGANIZATION> 119 153 <PERSON>Heuvel</PERSON> forthcoming <PERSON>Heuvel Charles van den</PERSON> e a forthcoming Deep Networks as Associative Interfaces to <ORGANIZATION>Historical Research Power of Networks Prospects of Historical Networks Research Edited</ORGANIZATION> by <PERSON>Florian Kerschbaumer Linda von Keyserlingk Martin Stark Marten</PERSON> D ring <ORGANIZATION>Routledge Oxford Hoeven</ORGANIZATION> and Louwe 1985 Hoeven Casper van der <ORGANIZATION>Louwe Jos</ORGANIZATION> 1985 <LOCATION>Amsterdam</LOCATION> als stedelijk bouwwerk Een morfologische analyse <ORGANIZATION>Sun Amsterdam Ihde</ORGANIZATION> 2003 Ihde Don 2003 More Material Hermeneutics Paper presented at the meeting on <ORGANIZATION>Hermeneutics and Science Tihany Hungary</ORGANIZATION> June 7 11 2003 Indurkhya 1992 Indurkhya Bipin 1992 Metaphor and Cognition An <ORGANIZATION>Interactionist Approach Kluwer Academic Publishers Dordrecht Johnson 2006 Johnson Steven</ORGANIZATION> 2006 The Long Zoom The <ORGANIZATION>New York Times</ORGANIZATION> October 8 2006 http www nytimes com 2006 10 08 magazine 08games html _r 0 Accessed May 22 2017 <PERSON>Kafka</PERSON> 2012 <PERSON>Kafka Franz</PERSON> 2012 A Message from the Emperor A Hunger Artist and Other Studies A new translation by <ORGANIZATION>Joyce Crick Oxford Oxford World</ORGANIZATION> Classics 28 0rg 1919 Koster 2001 <PERSON>Koster Elwin</PERSON> 2001 Stadsmorfologie eenproeve van vormgerichtonderzzoek ten behoeve van stedenbouwhistorischonderzoek <ORGANIZATION>Groningen</ORGANIZATION> PhD with an English summary Urban morphology A taste of a form oriented approach to the history of urban development <PERSON>Lakoff</PERSON> and <PERSON>Johnson</PERSON> 2003 <PERSON>Lakoff George Johnson</PERSON> Mark 2003 Metaphors we live by The <ORGANIZATION>University of Chicago</ORGANIZATION> press <ORGANIZATION>Chicago London</ORGANIZATION> Lepoivre 1624 Lepoivre Pierre 1624 Les Plans des <LOCATION>Villes</LOCATION> des Pa s de Hennault d Artois de Breband tr s noblemen descripts a la plume par l architecte <PERSON>Pierre Le Poivre</PERSON> etc Royal Library <PERSON>Albert</PERSON> I <LOCATION>Brussels</LOCATION> Ms 19611 Mandelbrot 1983 <PERSON>Mandelbrot Benoit</PERSON> B 1983 The <ORGANIZATION>Fractal Geometry of Nature W H Freeman and Company New York</ORGANIZATION> 1977 1982 1983 Martens 2014 <PERSON>Martens Pieter</PERSON> 2014 Lepoivre In <ORGANIZATION>Nationaal Biografisch Woordenboek Vol</ORGANIZATION> 21 <ORGANIZATION>Koninklijke Academi</ORGANIZATION> n van <LOCATION>Belgi Brussels</LOCATION> kol 656 670 <ORGANIZATION>Oers 2000 Oers Ron</ORGANIZATION> van 2000 Dutch Town Planning Overseas during VOC and WIC Rule 1600 1800 Walburg Pers Zutphen Panigrahi 2014 Panigrahi Sambit 2014 Cities as Strata in <PERSON>Italo Calvino</PERSON> s Invisible Cities The Explicator 72 1 23 27 DOI 10 1080 00144940 2013 875873 Pilz 2003 <PERSON>Pilz Kerstin</PERSON> 2003 Reconceptualising Thought and Space Labyrinths and Cities in <PERSON>Calvino</PERSON> s Fictions Italica 80 229 242 http www jstor org stable 30038769 Accessed May 22 2017 Ramsay 2008 Ramsay Stephen 2008 Algorithmic Criticism In A Companion to Digital Literary Studies ed <PERSON>Susan Schreibman</PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION>Ray Siemens Blackwell Oxford</ORGANIZATION> http www digitalhumanities org companionDLS Accessed May 22 2017 Ricoeur 1990 Ricoeur Paul 1990 Time and Narrative Volume 1 <ORGANIZATION>The University of Chicago Press Chicago</ORGANIZATION> Ricoeur 2003 <PERSON>Ricoeur Paul</PERSON> 2003 The Rule of <ORGANIZATION>Metaphor Routledge London Rockwell</ORGANIZATION> and Sinclair 2016 Rockwell <PERSON>Geoffrey Sinclair St</PERSON> fan 2016 <ORGANIZATION>Hermeneutica Computer Assisted Interpretation in the Humanities The MIT Press Cambridge London</ORGANIZATION> Romele 2016 Romele Alberto 2016 Toward a <ORGANIZATION>Digital Hermeneutics Techn Research in Philosophy and Technology Philosophy Documentation Center</ORGANIZATION> 20 1 pp 76 83 https hal archives ouvertes fr hal 01298506 document Accessed May 22 2017 <PERSON>Samuels</PERSON> and <PERSON>McGann</PERSON> 1999 <PERSON>Samuels Lisa McGann Jerome</PERSON> 1999 Deformance and Interpretation New Literary History Vol 30 No 1 Poetry amp Poetics Winter 1999 pp 25 56 The <ORGANIZATION>Johns Hopkins University Press Baltimore</ORGANIZATION> http www jstor org stable 20057521 Accessed May 22 2017 Simanowski 2010 Simanowski Roberto 2010 Understanding New Media Art Through Close Reading Four Remarks on <ORGANIZATION>Digital Hermeneutics</ORGANIZATION> www dichtung digital org 2010 simanowski htm Accessed May 22 2017 Srinivas 2010 Srinivas Tulasi 2010 Rethinking Globalization and Religious Pluralism through the <ORGANIZATION>Sathya Sai Movement Columbia University Press New York Stephenson</ORGANIZATION> 2003 <PERSON>Stephenson Neal</PERSON> 2003 The Diamond Age Or a Young Lady s <ORGANIZATION>Illustrated Primer Bantam Books New York</ORGANIZATION> 1995 new editions 1996 2000 2003 Stevin 1594 <PERSON>Stevin Simon</PERSON> 1594 De Sterctenbouwing beschreven door <PERSON>Simon Stevin</PERSON> van <ORGANIZATION>Brugge</ORGANIZATION> Fran oys van <PERSON>Ravelenghien Leiden Stevin</PERSON> 1605 1608 <PERSON>Stevin Simon</PERSON> 1605 1608 Wisconstighe Ghedachtenissen inhoudende t ghene daer hem in gheoeffent heeft den <ORGANIZATION>Doorluchtichsten Hooghgheboren Vorst</ORGANIZATION> ende <PERSON>Heeren Maurits Prince van Oraengien Jan Bouwensz Leiden Stevin</PERSON> 1649 <PERSON>Stevin Hendrik</PERSON> 1649 Materiae Politicae Vervanghende Ghedachtenissen der Oeffeninghen des Doorluchtichsten Prince <PERSON>Maurits van Orangie Adryaan Rosenboom Leiden Teleoac</PERSON> 2004 Teleoac Anca Irinel 2004 Computer Collocations and Computer Metaphors Translation Journal Volume 8 No 3 July 2004 http translationjournal net journal 29colloc htm Accessed May 22 2017 2017 11 3 XML Print Article Please enable JavaScript to view the comments powered by Disqus URL http www digitalhumanities org dhq vol 11 3 000337 000337 html Last updated Comments dhqinfo digitalhumanities org Published by The <ORGANIZATION>Alliance of Digital Humanities Organizations Affiliated</ORGANIZATION> with Literary and Linguistic Computing Copyright 2005 image Creative Commons License This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution NoDerivatives 4 0 International License</ner>
