<ner>image DHQ Logo image Digital Humanities Quarterly Logo homesubmissionsabout dhqdhq peoplecontact Current Issue 2017 11 3 Preview Issue 2017 11 4 Previous Issues 2017 11 2 2017 11 1 2016 10 4 2016 10 3 2016 10 2 2016 10 1 2015 9 4 2015 9 3 2015 9 2 2015 9 1 2014 8 4 2014 8 3 2014 8 2 2014 8 1 2013 7 3 2013 7 2 2013 7 1 2012 6 3 2012 6 2 2012 6 1 2011 5 3 2011 5 2 2011 5 1 2010 4 2 2010 4 1 2009 3 4 2009 3 3 2009 3 2 2009 3 1 2008 2 1 2007 1 2 2007 1 1 Indexes Title Author image sidenavbarimg ISSN 1938 4122 Announcements Call for Reviewers Call for Submissions image button1 addthis gif DHQ Digital Humanities Quarterly 2017 Volume 11 Number 3 2017 11 3 XML Discuss Comments Collaborative Knowledge Creation and Student Led Assignment Design Wikipedia in the University Literature Class <PERSON>Laura Estill</PERSON> lt lestill_at_tamu_dot_edu gt <LOCATION>Texas</LOCATION> A amp M University Abstract This case study outlines how writing for <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> can benefit students in an undergraduate literature class by having them undertake scholarly research read unmediated texts and write for a real life audience In keeping with the collaborative spirit of <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> the rubrics provided here were primarily created by the class as a whole <PERSON>Estill</PERSON> demonstrates how this assignment encouraged students to question received notions of literary canon and to engage critically with <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> itself Perhaps paradoxically writing for <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> gave students ownership of their writing and research Ultimately this assignment facilitated students to become experts on understudied topics and helped them learn about how to do literary research 1 But my other professors told me not to use <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> my class chorused upon hearing that we were going to be writing <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> entries In an unscientific straw poll conducted through a show of hands they all admitted to using the online encyclopedia despite their professors warnings 1 This article explores the benefits of and rationale for having students in a literature class write <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> articles 2 in this case students in a third year Renaissance Drama class analyzed existing <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> articles about early modern plays devised the rubric for how their articles would be evaluated adopted and researched a play presented their work to the class and had the option of publishing their writing on <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia Ultimately</ORGANIZATION> being part of the assignment design process and writing for a public audience led students to undertake primary research to question received ideas of literary canon and to take ownership of their writing This research based writing project relies on the digital humanities principle of having student scholars leverage digital publication in order to participate in social knowledge creation that benefits both the students and the larger often academic community 2 This is not the first article about using <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> as a pedagogical tool For years advocates have touted <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> s usefulness in composition classrooms <PERSON>Haley Brown</PERSON> 2012 Vetter 2014 The <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia Education Program</ORGANIZATION> that encourages educators and students around the world to contribute to <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> in an academic setting <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia Education Program</ORGANIZATION> 2016 3 The <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia Education Program</ORGANIZATION> offers instructors guidelines on How to Use <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> as a teaching tool with sample assignments and case studies by professors who have successfully had students write edit expand or translate <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> articles Professors who ask students to write for <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> agree that having an actual public audience for their writing galvanizes students to research more thoroughly and to write better Kill 2012 Recent academic interventions have focused on the need for clearly theorized and inclusive of race gender sexuality language and more approaches to this digital platform Edwards 2015 Gruwell 2015 <PERSON>Koh</PERSON> and Risam 2013 Indeed as <PERSON>Amanda I Seligman</PERSON> argues writing for encyclopedias is a scholarly and valuable pursuit <PERSON>Seligman</PERSON> 2013 <PERSON>Erin Glass</PERSON> points out that the benefits of integrating NPS Networked Participatory Scholarship in higher and graduate education are clear yet too few undergraduate literature classes take this approach Glass 2015 This case study serves as an example and template of how writing for <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> can be productively incorporated into an undergraduate literature course 3 With over three hundred classes that have used the <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia Education</ORGANIZATION> program and many others classes that were not officially affiliated with the program that also wrote articles why do we need an article about <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> in the university literature classroom Because discipline based <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> editing initiatives have been very successful pedagogically The <ORGANIZATION>American Sociological Association</ORGANIZATION> has had more than 3 300 students write and edit <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> articles with three goals a to develop communication skills for general audiences b to discover the importance of logic strength of argument flow and clarity of writing and the need to cite the appropriate literature and c to experience the significance of accuracy in scientific writing Vandendorpe 2015 As outlined below by writing for <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> literature students can gain general and transferable research and communication skills while also considering the nature of digital texts particularly hypertext and ontologies and literary texts with a focus on canon and textual studies Furthermore the assignment outlined here takes the collaborative nature of <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> s platform one step further students collaboratively created their own learning goals by choosing the rubric on which their <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> articles would be graded 4 Writing for <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> in a literature classroom engages students to question the literary canon to consider the role of editors and editions and to undertake research using primary and secondary sources As is often the case with writing <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> articles this research and writing helped students develop a sense of mastery of the material and provided exigence for real world writing The stakes of defining a literary canon and understanding editorial interventions are always high but especially so when confronting <ORGANIZATION>Renaissance Drama</ORGANIZATION> that literary period and genre dominated by <ORGANIZATION>Shakespeare</ORGANIZATION> 5 Almost ten years ago <PERSON>Michael Best</PERSON> surveyed information about <PERSON>Shakespeare</PERSON> studies on <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> and found that predictably <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> does a good job of dealing with the facts about <PERSON>Shakespeare</PERSON> s life and works and provides some good starting places for further studies in the main articles yet as links take the intrepid explorer into the byways of Early Modern minor writers the quality becomes more uneven Best 2006 109 114 Best concludes by exhorting <ORGANIZATION>Shakespeare Newsletter</ORGANIZATION> readers to take the plunge and wade into <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> waters to update improve and extend the information <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> is making available to our students and to the world Best 2006 114 A decade later <ORGANIZATION>Best</ORGANIZATION> s call to action still holds true minor writers and anonymous works are often entirely overlooked As <PERSON>Matthew Steggle</PERSON> notes <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> s coverage of the Renaissance varies considerably from article to article and even within articles Steggle 2010 In writing <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> articles about these lesser known plays my students responded to a genuine need they were not writing the traditional paper for an audience of one the professor The professor as audience is furthermore someone who presumably already knows the material whereas those reading a <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> article are actively seeking new knowledge Writing for <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> means students have to consider what readers might know before coming to that particular article they learn to consider audience and rhetorical situation in concrete ways that improves their writing 6 Before the digital age scholars attempted to make early modern plays accessible by editing and publishing editions that would not like the original playbooks be safeguarded in rare book rooms Digital projects followed this model making works findable and searchable in even more ways Early digital projects began with canonical texts for instance <ORGANIZATION>Best</ORGANIZATION> founded the Internet Shakespeare Editions ISE in 1996 to meet the demand for scholarly edited online versions of <PERSON>Shakespeare</PERSON> s plays Best 2012 In 2015 <PERSON>Brett D Hirsch</PERSON> launched <ORGANIZATION>Digital Renaissance Editions DRE</ORGANIZATION> a kindred project that moves beyond <PERSON>Shakespeare</PERSON> s plays to publish works by lesser known or anonymous authors including <PERSON>John Redford Walter Mountfort</PERSON> and <PERSON>Richard Edwards Hirsch</PERSON> 2015 Hirsch 2011 4 <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> has traced a similar trajectory the earliest and most detailed entries deal with canonical authors and plays I contend that <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> entries not only reflect the current literary canon but also help to shape it As a first stop for undergraduates graduate students and even at times professors Knight and Pryke 2012 <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> offers at a glance information that can be used as a starting point and without even a stub a short placeholder article that needs to be expanded overlooked works are absent from the literary landscape and commonly and communally held cultural narrative <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> presents 5 Without conscious interventions such as this that seek to expand the canon <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> and other digital projects will only reinscribe our existing canon Earhart 2012 6 7 Many undergraduate literature students have never heard the term canon They have not questioned why there are entire courses listed in the university catalogue about <PERSON>Shakespeare</PERSON> yet none on <PERSON>Ben Jonson</PERSON> or <ORGANIZATION>Mary Sidney Students</ORGANIZATION> instinctively want to begin any written assignment with <PERSON>William Shakespeare</PERSON> is the greatest writer of English literature or words to that effect while instructors help students see the historical reasons the Bard has been positioned over other writers Finding and researching understudied plays for <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> helped students start to question the shape of the English literary canon and consider how anthologies and university course catalogues reify canon 7 8 In the spirit of <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> students collaboratively created the rubric on which their assignment would be graded I determined that a portion of their grade would be established by their presentations and their pre research The bulk of the pre research was a short <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia Analysis</ORGANIZATION> where they analyzed existing articles about Renaissance plays and evaluated what made the articles most useful see Process Elements in the rubric in Appendix A I encouraged students to read the <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> pages about the plays we were reading that semester Some of the questions they considered were What should every <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> page about a Renaissance play have What headings What information and What kind of notes are most useful What sources are cited When prompted to suggest which articles would make good or bad templates the response was almost unanimous lots of plays we read that semester had strong <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> pages such as The Spanish Tragedy and A Chaste Maid in Cheapside but The Tragedy of Mariam the only play we read by a female author had an inadequate page This led students to discuss the treatment of women writers both historically and today 8 Reading the well written write ups furthermore gave students valuable background information that allowed them to engage with the canonical texts we studied in deeper ways Much of the information on a <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> page about a Renaissance play will appear in a modern introduction to that play reading either an introduction or a Wikipedia page can be a passive experience <ORGANIZATION>Analyzing Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> pages however encouraged students to think about the value and reasoning behind the information presented Furthermore as we discussed together in class with its hyperlinking <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> can facilitate deeper research than a print introduction students can be easily drawn into related fields of inquiry as they click through to new pages on literally and figuratively linked topics 9 After handing in their 300 500 word <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia Analysis</ORGANIZATION> students brainstormed in class what makes an effective <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> page on a Renaissance play and what headings and content need to appear in the page We grouped their suggestions into categories and finalized their rubric for the written component see Appendix A This assignment gave students ownership over their material in two ways one they were responsible for a play that nobody else would read and two they decided the desired outcomes for this assignment by collaboratively creating the rubric 9 Students determined that introductions to each play needed to contain some basic key information when available the play s title and alternative titles genre playwright s setting initial performance information date company theatre patron occasion and initial publication information date publisher location This is the kind of information that students take for granted they skim over it when reading a play s introduction they glance at it on <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia Finding</ORGANIZATION> this information when it is not made readily available however gave students the opportunity to undertake true scholarly research Students also start to see the holes or slippages in the narratives we have of Renaissance theatre history often scholars cannot agree on where or when a play was first performed let alone who wrote it 10 Before they could undertake their research however students had to adopt a play I gave students a list of eighty nine plays that had no <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> pages or in some cases stubs 10 As their guidelines read There s no <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> page and you can t read all of these so what should you do see Appendix B I suggested they pick two or three plays based on their title and do a little research on the play I also advised choosing a play they could access in a way they would feel comfortable In order to adopt a play each had to locate an edition some chose plays that can only be found on Early English Books Online EEBO Literature Online LiOn or in facsimile reprints of the first editions whereas others opted to read plays that were recently recuperated by online publication some edited some not in Early Modern Literary Studies or <PERSON>Risa Stephanie Bear</PERSON> s Renascence Editions 11 <ORGANIZATION>EEBO</ORGANIZATION> and LiOn are both subscription resources that we were fortunate to have access to at my institution but they are not required for completing this assignment HathiTrust <ORGANIZATION>Google Books</ORGANIZATION> and the Internet Archive are online repositories that have open access editions of early modern plays sometimes even facsimiles of the original publication 12 11 As the plays my students adopted were generally under studied my students had to learn both new ways of reading and new research methods For many this was the first time facing an unedited early modern text for students used to anthologies of Shakespeare even the non standard orthography could come as a surprise Some students learned that act and scene breaks could be editorial By comparing how plays have been historically treated or ignored my class began asking questions about scholarly editing that is about how the texts we read are mediated in ways we often take for granted 12 Beyond reading the play itself in order to write a summary students had to undertake primary research to write the introductory paragraph about their play As we had established a good <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> entry always gave a play s initial publication and when known details about the first performance such as the company theatre and date I devoted an entire 50 minute class and to how to research their plays Although my students undertook research using primary and secondary materials this assignment did not violate <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> s no original research policy which all material in <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> must be attributable to a reliable published source it did however challenge the standard research undergraduates are asked to undertake 13 I encouraged students to use both print tools such as the Annals of English Drama Harbage et al 1989 and the Records of Early English Drama 14 and online resources like the Database of Early English Playbooks and the English Short Title Catalogue In their assignments students favored digital resources over print none for instance cited The <LOCATION>London</LOCATION> Stage a suggested resource about performance history 15 All however learned to navigate The Database of Early English Playbooks and many turned to The Oxford Dictionary of National Biography and <PERSON>Gale</PERSON> s Dictionary of Literary Biography 13 As a class we looked at <ORGANIZATION>EEBO</ORGANIZATION> to find what the physical play texts looked like Upon finding that we had access to three digital facsimiles of <PERSON>Samuel Daniel</PERSON> s The Tragedie of Cleopatra in quarto my student who adopted this play exclaimed I m going to compare all three The last portion of the research methods class was devoted to finding secondary sources an important skill that would also serve them in good stead for their other university classes Although scholars talk about digital natives 16 in this class period I was reminded that students do not actually have an innate understanding of how to search for things effectively Searching however is not endemic to online sources and students similarly needed guidance with how to search using print sources Showing students how to find the information they seek and discern its value rather than telling them the answers empowers them to come up with even more exciting research questions Furthermore these research skills are foundational to writing a <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> article 14 Equipped with the ability to use new research tools students had two main parts of the assignment to complete write the <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> page and present about their play in class We all know the old adage that you learn something best by teaching In this context student presenters benefited from having an in person audience to speak to as well as their online audience As audience members students learned about a variety of plays and genres that we would not have had time to all read together including domestic tragedy farce roman history and pastoral Taken together these presentations offered an overview of English Renaissance drama that no single anthology could provide Indeed students in this class gained a more realistic view of what was actually available to audiences in <PERSON>Shakespeare</PERSON> s day as well as the key genres that preceded and followed 15 For their presentations I encouraged students not to give a plot synopsis Some however could not resist the temptation as they had put in quite an effort to learn all of the details of in some cases very intricate plots Others however managed to keep to the main points we wanted to hear the themes in the play why this play is interesting or not and why this play has been neglected so far 17 For instance one student who discussed <PERSON>Ben Jonson</PERSON> s The Irish Masque at Court taught the class about masques those performances designed especially for the King or Queen she also explained <LOCATION>Ireland</LOCATION> s political turmoil in the early modern period and most importantly for this text examined the English audience s attitudes towards the Irish and the anticipated reactions to <PERSON>Jonson</PERSON> s harsh portrayal of uneducated ill mannered and ridiculous accented Irish Exploring non canonical plays led to student driven discussions that reflected on an array of primary sources and that truly supported classroom dialogue and critical thinking 16 During these presentations I discovered that my students had taken the adopt a play metaphor seriously Some students felt protective of their plays and wanted to justify their play as worth studying One student wrote about Cupid s Whirligig a city comedy by <PERSON>Edward Sharpham</PERSON> that nobody reads 18 She expressed her shock that Cupid s Whirligig was not regularly taught or anthologized This possessiveness born of truly caring about the texts they read was a recurring theme in the presentations Upper level English majors were some for the first time grappling with ideas of canonicity because they had identified gaps in both in the curriculum and what seems like <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> s universal content 17 Reading non canonical works presenting their adopted play to the class and writing for <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> gave students an incentive to excel specifically writing for <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> increased the exigency of their work as they were addressing an actual lacuna As <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> advertises writing in the classroom can be the end of throwaway assignments and the beginning of real world impact for student editors emphasis in the original These students created <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> articles that in some cases actually contributed to a broader knowledge community 18 I qualified my previous assertion about student contributions because I did not require that students publish their writing on <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia Asking</ORGANIZATION> students to share their work even pseudonymously is an ethical quandary Posting on <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> is different from for instance our course website on a course website I can protect all of the material by requiring a password and even if the site were open access it would not get much traffic As <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> acknowledges it is one of the most popular sites on the internet Ultimately I required students to write a <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> style article but I did not require them to post it to the online encyclopedia for credit 19 Some students creatively formatted their word document submissions such as this entry on The Costlie Whore a title I would not suggest Googling as there is still no <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> article on this anonymous play from 1632 see Figure 1 Even though posting to <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> was optional about a third of my students gave it a try Those students on their own created a <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> username and learned enough about the wiki markup to upload their articles 20 See Figure 2 and Figure 3 for images of the opening of <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> articles my students wrote about <PERSON>Johan Johan the Husband</PERSON> and The Dumb Knight image Figure 1 A <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> article submitted as a word document image Figure 2 The opening part of the <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> page on <PERSON>Johan Johan</PERSON> The Husband February 2017 image Figure 3 The opening part of the <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> page on The Dumb Knight February 2017 19 Initially some of the write ups my students created and uploaded to <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> were marked as orphans that is to say no other pages linked to them Even though students were not required to upload their work to <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> we talked about how they should categorize their plays and where their articles should both link to and be linked from They had to indicate what links they would include even if they handed in their paper in a word document While most students were able to include appropriate links many did not understand the categories of articles on <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> nor what the benefit of linking to your page versus from the page might be Uploading new pages to <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> and writing as if your work were to be uploaded leads students to consider how to classify information Exploring ontologies and taxonomies those categories that we apply 1631 plays or sometimes choose not to apply plays published in quarto when creating a <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> page helps students approach disciplinary knowledge systems <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> s categories makes assumptions about how users will navigate the pages and what might interest them <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> s explicit organization can prompt students to interrogate implicit ontologies in literary studies 20 Adding new <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> pages about early modern plays includes other people beyond the classroom in the learning experience and can lead students to continue to learn beyond the short time they are in class As the revision history of a page created by a student on <PERSON>Thomas Heywood</PERSON> s The Fayre Mayde of the Exchange demonstrates a dozen Wikipedians read and edited the page see Figure 5 most of the post assignment edits involved normalizing the spelling to American and yes sometimes adding or changing the categories Beyond those Wikipedians who actively edited the text there are the users who simply read this page and made no changes which we cannot track Perhaps most impressively the most recent update to the page 15 November 2014 Renaissancefan is from the same person who created it in 2012 no longer a student this person is still engaging with the texts and ideas from their class Although it might seem counterintuitive writing for <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> that is putting your work on the internet for all to use and change can allow students to feel intellectual ownership Renaissancefan is not just a consumer of knowledge shared by a professor but an expert contributing to broader discussions image Figure 4 The opening part of the <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> page on The Fayre Mayde of the Exchange February 2017 image Figure 5 The complete revision history of the <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> page on The Fayre Mayde of the Exchange November 2015 21 With her <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> page on The Fayre Maid of the Exchange Renaissancefan is participating in collaborative authorship <PERSON>Steggle</PERSON> suggests that we can perhaps better understand models of early modern writing by engaging with <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> It is one thing to know that in principle Renaissance drama is at home with co authored repatched plays with plays that plagiarize pieces of earlier plays and with plays that change radically from version to version But to realize that we happily use <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> articles whose status is comparable helps us to see how well that might work in practice Steggle 2010 We might tell students about the highly collaborative practice of writing early plays for a public audience this assignment helps students engage with the largest collaborative writing project ever undertaken Of course all collaborative modes of writing are not the same an early modern playwright revising an older work is not the same as a student contributing to <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia That</ORGANIZATION> said writing for <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> can help students think of authorship models beyond the often fallacious idea of the single author genius 22 Admittedly writing about Renaissance plays on <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> is a finite project At some point in the future all the plays listed in the Database of Early English Playbooks could have complete entries If and when that halcyon day comes class projects in this field can move to new related topics that are not yet covered adequately such as royal progresses and processions acting companies and actors and even manuscript sources for early modern drama The future of digital pedagogy projects that promote editing <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> is at its heart one that both defines and reflects future avenues for scholarship 23 This article has demonstrated the concrete benefits of having students write pages for <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> including self motivated learning improved communication skills writing for a real life audience and undertaking scholarly research Some of the benefits to writing articles discussed here are field specific such as reading unedited plays considering notions of literary canon and exploring how and what we study as literary scholars Beyond the values that <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> itself touts and those discipline specific skills that students gained this assignment fosters critical thinking about <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> itself what s in what s out and what these bounds suggest about our cultural values Learning about <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> prompts students to question how other sometimes seemingly monolithic sites are conceptualized and created as manifested in our class discussions <ORGANIZATION>Analyzing Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> also promotes what might be called digital civic engagement this kind of action can help make digital spaces more inclusive and representative although this is currently an uphill battle 24 Even after writing their own <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> pages my class agreed that for final papers <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> was best used in the pre research phase and not cited in the bibliography As I overheard one of my students comment to a classmate on the way out of class this is more work than a research paper Yes doing scholarly research reading unmediated texts and writing for a real life audience is work it is the work we undertake as literary scholars As the students in my Renaissance Drama proved students are eager to learn to undertake real literary scholarship when we offer them the chance to gain and share their expertise by writing for <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia Appendix A Rubric</ORGANIZATION> 25 This appendix presents the Rubric used I assigned the process elements and presentation elements values CourseRoster was about joining our class wiki and learning to participate in discussion My students developed the WikiProject Written Component section of the rubric as well as the explanatory information 26 Rubric see below for clarification 27 Process Elements Total 15 CourseRoster 3 Adopt a Play 2 <ORGANIZATION>WikipediaAnalysis</ORGANIZATION> 10 28 Presentation Elements Total 45 Handout 15 Presentation 15 Discussion Questions and Leadership 10 Participation 5 29 <ORGANIZATION>WikiProject Written Component Total</ORGANIZATION> 40 Intro Blurb 5 Synopsis including Character List 12 Themes Motifs 5 Other 8 References 5 Linking 2 5 <ORGANIZATION>Organization</ORGANIZATION> 2 5 30 The Handout is the handout you give on the day of presentations Please make enough for the whole class 21 including the instructor This handout should include key points about the play including a brief one paragraph summary Other key points include authorship performance venue and when the play was written performed and published Elements from your handout can be taken from your WikiProject You can also include other useful information like character charts timelines plot graphs etc 31 Please include at least one image on the handout at minimum please include an image of the play s title page which you can get from Early English Books Online EEBO available through the UVic library page 32 Remember to add a bibliography of the play are there multiple editions Is there an edition that is most useful as well as secondary sources including online that were most useful to your presentation 33 The handout should include a glossary of unfamiliar terms both relating to and used in the play 34 If you would like you can also include some of your more salient discussion questions 35 You can choose to do an online handout by creating a wiki page prezi powerpoint for your presentation and including all of the above You can also choose a mixed handout that presents some material online and some material on paper If you choose to include a digital component you will need to send the link to me which I will circulate to the whole class 36 Presentation 37 Length 4 5 minutes 3 4 minutes of discussion Total Length 7 10 minutes 38 Key points to mention what genre is your play when was it written performed and published does it connect with any interesting historical moments where was it performed who wrote it what are the themes of the play why is this play interesting or important conversely why not why has this play been neglected so far what information is presented and what information is omitted on the title page 39 Possibly relevant points to consider was it performed for a particular occasion was it dedicated to a particular patron does your play connect to any particular literary movements is there anything special about the way your play was published Is there for instance a woodcut on the title page 40 The presentation grade will account for your stage presence the clarity of your discussion the way you present yourself as well as the content of the presentation Part of your presentation grade will also include the interest factor is your presentation interesting 41 If you would like to show youtube videos in class you can set up a webpage on the wiki with the videos or do whatever you d like 42 Part of your presentation grade will reflect the research effort and preparation that you undertook The content of your presentation should introduce the class to a new play and hit the salient points above 43 Discussion Questions and Leadership 44 You will hand in a page with your discussion questions at the end of your presentation You will need to come up with at least 3 questions about your play author period etc You might consider giving a short piece of text 14 lines or less even a couplet would be strong and asking a question about a particular textual moment 45 Class discussions however often go to places you don t expect so part of your grade will be based on how well you navigate hard to charter waters 46 Remember to ask the group if we have questions for you part of your grade depends on your answers to our questions 47 Participation 48 Your participation grade depends on your participation during other people s presentations Do you listen carefully Do you have interesting questions to ask them at the end of their presentations Do you thoughtfully answer the discussion questions the presenter asks 49 Intro Blurb 50 Includes if appropriate and if known remember to organize your information a one to two sentence synopsis title and alternate titles dates performance publication if known who published setting of play period place a mention of the play s genre author if known patron occasion for performance company amp theatre of initial performance 51 Synopsis including Character List Use subheadings 52 Themes Motifs 53 This seems pretty evident 54 Other 55 This might include but is not limited to Important Adaptations Films Performances A broader discussion of the play s genre Sources Influences Intertexts Allusions 56 References 57 These should follow <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> s house style follow other articles as a template 58 This should include both the primary source editions of the play bibliographic sources like the Annals or <PERSON>Greg</PERSON> s Bibliography or the Database of Early English Playbooks as well as any secondary sources that is literary criticism 59 Linking Please note this has been updated This includes the links you would want to have to other articles What connections comparisons are you drawing This also includes how you suggest bookmarking your own page and the categories you would like to include on your page Please also include a list of places you would add links to your page This can be in a note to me at the end of your essay Remember you might want to include target links to pages on <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> that do not exist This is tantamount to suggesting a page be created You can indicate this to me in a note in your word document or simply create the links which will appear red on your <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> page 60 Organization 61 What sections you choose to include the order you put the sections and the general presentation of your information Appendix B Adopting a Play 62 Below are the instructions my students used to find a play 63 How to Choose a Play 64 There s no Wikipedia page and you can t read all of these so what should you do See if any titles interest you <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> them and make a shortlist of 4 8 plays that interest you See if there s a modern edition of the play This will make your life easier Narrow your choice to just one and claim it for your own See below on claiming your play 65 You can choose any of the plays below You can also propose to write about a play that isn t on this list If you choose to write about a play that is not on this list please send me an email with the title date and author if known of the play you d like to adopt Then include a short explanation of why the wikipedia article needs expanding or why this play should be considered 66 How to find a Modern Edition Check SEEDIE but be careful because this site is in beta so is not complete doesn t have a lot of say anonymous plays or even some by canonical authors Do a google book search Search the internet archive for edited versions Remember some of these plays will be in the collected works Some key editions include The <ORGANIZATION>Oxford Middleton G B Evans</ORGANIZATION> s collection of works by <PERSON>William Cartwright</PERSON> etc An edition from the 19th century might be a good one so long as it has notes Grosart for instance has a good edition of the <PERSON>Samuel Daniel</PERSON> plays There might be an edition online especially at EMLS Renascence Editions Early Modern Literary Studies Consider what will help you most Do you need modernized spelling Do you want a print play to read rather than an online one Do you feel comfortable reading a play without notes And sadly there might not be a modern edition of some of the plays below If you re up for it you can get the play from <ORGANIZATION>EEBO</ORGANIZATION> and LiOn via the library and use that copy 67 Getting Your Play First try the library If we don t have it use inter library loan If you want to buy a copy make sure that you re not buying an <ORGANIZATION>OCR</ORGANIZATION> d version of the play be sure you re buying an edited version If you want an OCR d play you can get that for free from Literature Online via the library Consider do you need a physical copy Can you work with Literature Online and Early English Books Online You will be able to find a facsimile of your play likely the first edition which could be difficult to read via <ORGANIZATION>EEBO</ORGANIZATION> 68 Plays that need reading and writing about in no particular order <PERSON>John Heywood</PERSON> The Four PP <PERSON>John Heywood Johan Johan</PERSON> The Husband <PERSON>John Marston Antonio</PERSON> and <PERSON>Mellida Ben Jonson</PERSON> The Irish Masque at Court <PERSON>Ben Jonson</PERSON> The Newcastle Entertainment The Entertainment at Blackfriars Thomas Goffe The Raging Turk or Bajazet the Second Thomas Goffe The Courageous Turk Thomas Killigrew The Pilgrim <PERSON>Dekker Chettle</PERSON> and <PERSON>Haughton</PERSON> Patient <PERSON>Grissel William Davenant</PERSON> The Just Italian <PERSON>William Davenant</PERSON> The Cruel Brother <PERSON>William Davenant</PERSON> News from <PERSON>Plymouth John Denham</PERSON> The <PERSON>Sophy John Suckling Brennoralt Richard Edwards Damon</PERSON> and Pythias <PERSON>Thomas Middleton</PERSON> The Masque of Heroes <PERSON>Thomas Middleton</PERSON> The Triumphs of Love and Antiquity Anon The Tragedy of <PERSON>Nero</PERSON> not <PERSON>Chapman</PERSON> s play <PERSON>George Wilkins</PERSON> The Miseries of Enforced Marriage <PERSON>Thomas Drue Drewe</PERSON> The Duchess of <LOCATION>Suffolk</LOCATION> <PERSON>Robert Greene Selimus Emperor</PERSON> of the Turks <PERSON>Robert Greene</PERSON> Alphonsus John Day Law Tricks John Day The Blind Beggar of Bethnal Green John Day Humour out of Breath <PERSON>Samuel Daniel Philotas Samuel Daniel Cleopatra Thomas Dekker</PERSON> The Whore of <PERSON>Babylon Thomas Dekker</PERSON> If This Be Not a Good Play The Devil is in it Anon Look About You <PERSON>Thomas Dekker</PERSON> and <PERSON>John Ford</PERSON> The Bristow Merchant Collaborative The Mountebanks Masque <PERSON>Mary Sidney The Tragedie</PERSON> of <PERSON>Antonie Nathaniel Richards</PERSON> The Tragedy of Messalina the Roman Empress Anon A Warning for Fair Women Anon Wiley Beguiled Anon The Wit of a Woman Anon Captain <PERSON>Thomas Stukeley Jasper Mayne</PERSON> The City Match Jasper Mayne The Amorous War <PERSON>William Peaps Love</PERSON> in Its Ecstasy <PERSON>William Cavendish</PERSON> The Variety <PERSON>William Davenant Love</PERSON> and <PERSON>Honour Francis Quarles</PERSON> The Virgin Widow Anon The Valiant <PERSON>Scot William Cartwright</PERSON> The Royal Slave <PERSON>William Cartwright</PERSON> The Lady Errant <PERSON>William Cartwright</PERSON> The Siege or Love s Convert <PERSON>William Cartwright</PERSON> The Ordinary <PERSON>Henry Porter</PERSON> The Two Angry Women of <PERSON>Abington Thomas Kyd Soliman</PERSON> and <PERSON>Perseda George Peele</PERSON> The Arraignment of <LOCATION>Paris</LOCATION> <PERSON>George Peele</PERSON> The Love of King <PERSON>David</PERSON> and <PERSON>Fair Bethsabe Edward Sharpham</PERSON> The Fleir Edward Sharpham Cupid s Whirligig Anon Heywood Fair Maid of the Exchange Lording <PERSON>Barry Ram Alley Thomas Tomkis Work</PERSON> for Cutlers <PERSON>Fulke Greville Mustapha Fulke Greville Alaham Robert Armin</PERSON> The Italian Tailor and his Boy Anon Every Woman in her <PERSON>Humour Gervase Markham</PERSON> and <PERSON>Lewis Machin</PERSON> The Dumb Knight <PERSON>Gervase Markham</PERSON> and <PERSON>William Sampson Herod</PERSON> and <PERSON>Antipater Thomas May The Heir Thomas May Julia Agrippina Thomas May Cleopatra John Mason</PERSON> The Turk Nathan Field A Woman is a Weathercock Nathan Field Amends for Ladies Anon Two Wise Men and the Rest all Fools <PERSON>Anon Heteroclitanomalonomia Robert Taylor</PERSON> The Hog Hath Lost His Pearl <PERSON>Phineas Fletcher Sicelides Peter Hausted</PERSON> The Rival Friends <PERSON>Thomas Randolph</PERSON> The Jealous Lovers <PERSON>Richard Zouch</PERSON> The Sophister Anon The Costly Whore <PERSON>Thomas Heywood</PERSON> A Maidenhead Well Lost <PERSON>Thomas Heywood</PERSON> The Tragedy of the Rape of Lucrece <PERSON>Thomas Heywood</PERSON> A Challenge For Beauty <PERSON>Thomas Heywood The Wise Woman of Hogsdon Thomas Nabbes Tottenham Court Thomas Nabbes Covent Garden Thomas Nabbes</PERSON> The Bride <PERSON>John Tatham</PERSON> Love Crowns the End <PERSON>John Tatham</PERSON> The Distracted State <PERSON>John Tatham</PERSON> The Scots Figgaries or a Knot of Knaves <PERSON>John Tatham</PERSON> The Rump 69 Maybe Plays 70 These plays have short <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> articles If you want to write about one of these send me a short email that explains why the <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> article is lacking and how you plan to improve it Some of these especially the <PERSON>Jonson</PERSON> plays have a lot of secondary criticism and so would be very challenging choices <PERSON>Thomas Goffe</PERSON> The Tragedy of Orestes <PERSON>John Marston Jack</PERSON> Drum s Entertainment <PERSON>Jonson Sejanus Jonson Catiline Marston</PERSON> The Dutch Courtesan <PERSON>Marston Sophonisba</PERSON> The Wonder of Women <PERSON>Marston Histriomastix Marston</PERSON> What you Will Notes 1 I would like to thank <PERSON>Diane Jakacki Sarah Potvin Kailin Wright Emily Murphy</PERSON> and <PERSON>Shannon Smith</PERSON> for their insightful advice that helped make this a better paper In 2010 <PERSON>Alison J Head</PERSON> and <PERSON>Michael B Eisenberg</PERSON> demonstrated that 52 of university students used <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> always or frequently when undertaking research related to their courses This figure rises to 75 when we include students who occasionally use <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia Head</ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON>Eisenberg</PERSON> 2010 2 This paper builds on the extensive scholarship by scholars on the value of writing for <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> in the composition class See especially Cummings 2009 3 As their site explains the WEP is run by Wikimedia chapters affiliate organizations and dedicated volunteers worldwide <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia Education Program</ORGANIZATION> 2016 4 As <LOCATION>Steggle</LOCATION> has argued it is not just editions but also bibliographical data that lead to canon development Steggle 2008 Some of the strongest digital resources for researching Renaissance drama have begun to challenge notions of canonicity by offering inclusive if bounded content such as the Database of Early English Playbooks DEEP and the forthcoming Compendium of Renaissance Drama CORD Lesser and Farmer 2007 <PERSON>Corrigan</PERSON> 2015 5 Although <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> might lack write ups about Renaissance playwrights and their works these are often listed without links in the List of Years in Literature page which links to specific pages such as 1607 in literature See https en wikipedia org wiki List_of_years_in_literature 6 For more on the often lost potential of digital projects to expand canon see <PERSON>Mandell</PERSON> and Gamer 1998 Ezell 2010 7 On the value of teaching canonicity see Bacon 1993 Graff 1990 and Hentschell 2002 On the canon of early modern drama in particular see <PERSON>Bevington</PERSON> 2012 and <PERSON>Lopez</PERSON> 2014 8 Positioning women s writing in relation to the changing early modern literary canon is an ongoing scholarly concern Consider collections such as Woods and Hannay 2000 and <PERSON>Ostovich</PERSON> and <PERSON>Sauer</PERSON> 2004 9 Having students behave as experts in both the genre of writing and the topic they wrote on draws on <PERSON>Dorothy Heathcote</PERSON> s drama in education technique <PERSON>Mantle</PERSON> of the Expert Although students are not experts when they embark on this assignment in a university classroom they can truly become experts whereas <PERSON>Heathcote</PERSON> anticipated an audience of younger students See O <PERSON>Neill</PERSON> 2015 10 For my list of plays and instructions on how to choose a play see Appendix B I generated this list using DEEP As of this writing some of these plays now have write ups including those by my students 11 As of this writing both Renascence Editions and Early Modern Literary Studies sites have not been maintained in years and so have broken links that the students needed to navigate in order to find their plays or in some cases turn to another resource 12 HathiTrust has some of its material freely available but some books are accessible only by users at subscribing institutions 13 See https en wikipedia org wiki <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia No_original_research</ORGANIZATION> and https en wikipedia org wiki <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia Verifiability</ORGANIZATION> 14 Records of Early English Drama is a series published by the university of <LOCATION>Toronto</LOCATION> Many of their volumes are available as pdfs from the Internet Archive http archive org search php query records of early english drama AND collection 3Atoronto 15 At the time this course was taught The London Stage had not yet been digitized It is now available via HathiTrust http catalog hathitrust org Record 000200105 <PERSON>Van Lennep</PERSON> et al 1965 68 16 For a discussion of the problematic understanding of digital natives that proposes a more nuanced view of undergraduate knowledge and preparation see <PERSON>Erika E Smith</PERSON> s The Digital Native Debate in Higher Education Smith 2012 17 Each presentation was short only 4 5 minutes but it was followed by 3 4 minutes of discussion The presenters prepared three questions for discussion and also solicited questions from the class When I teach this assignment again I will give a sample presentation on a play that we have not read together in order to offer students some models for how to initiate a discussion about a work that their audience has not read Some of the best techniques students used include linking their play to plays we read as a class aligning the play to historical events or giving a short passage or paratext such as the title page to discuss 18 As I was writing this article I could not remember who wrote this obscure play so I did what everyone does I googled it The <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> page my student wrote was the first result 19 Personally I have had students request to have their written assignments removed from publicly facing websites when they went on the job market allowing students the choice to publish their work rather than requiring it is respectful of their privacy and ability to make decisions <ORGANIZATION>HASTAC Humanities Arts Science and Technology Alliance</ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION>Collaboratory</ORGANIZATION> suggests that students be encouraged to write under a pseudonym and not be required to publish their work online because of legal ramifications including <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> s FERPA Family Education Rights and Privacy Act HASTAC 2015 <PERSON>Erin Glass</PERSON> acknlowledges that privacy control and ownership are not yet adequately addressed in relation to online student writing Glass 2015 Neither Glass nor this HASTAC post focuses on <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> which allows students to publish pseudonymously This assignment does however participate in what Glass terms Networked Participatory Scholarship by being open peer centric user friendly comparatively and enabl ing users to engage with exponentially larger networks Glass 2015 20 Of those who chose to post to <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> not a single student emailed me for technical help On the course website I provided <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> s help documents for writing articles and creating a user account The students who wanted to learn the <ORGANIZATION>Wikimedia</ORGANIZATION> markup system had not used it before but were self selecting and self taught Works Cited Bacon 1993 Bacon J Impasse or Tension Pedagogy and the <ORGANIZATION>Canon Controversy College</ORGANIZATION> English 55 5 1993 501 14 Best 2006 Best M Electronic Shakespeares On <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia Shakespeare Newsletter</ORGANIZATION> 56 3 2006 109 114 Best 2012 Best M The Internet Shakespeare Editions History and Vision Internet Shakespeare Editions http internetshakespeare uvic ca Foyer ISEoverview html Bevington 2012 <PERSON>Bevington</PERSON> D Recent Trends in Editing of Renaissance Drama Anthologies Renaissance Drama 40 2012 91 100 Corrigan 2015 <PERSON>Corrigan</PERSON> B Compendium of Renaissance Drama Forthcoming online <ORGANIZATION>University of Georgia Library Cummings</ORGANIZATION> 2009 Cummings R E Lazy Virtues Teaching Writing in the Age of <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia Nashville Vanderbilt University Press</ORGANIZATION> 2009 Earhart 2012 Earhart A Can Information Be Unfettered Race and the <ORGANIZATION>New Digital Humanities Canon In M K Gold ed Debates</ORGANIZATION> in the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities Minneapolis University of Minnesota Press</ORGANIZATION> 2012 309 18 Expanded version http dhdebates gc cuny edu Edwards 2015 <PERSON>Edwards</PERSON> J C Wiki Women Bringing Women Into <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> through Activism and Pedagogy The History Teacher 48 3 2015 409 36 Ezell 2010 <PERSON>Ezell</PERSON> M J M Editing Early Modern Women s Manuscripts Theory Electronic Editions and the Accidental Copy Text Literature Compass 7 2 2010 102 9 Glass 2015 Glass E Social Paper Retooling Student Consciousness Scholarly and <ORGANIZATION>Research Communication</ORGANIZATION> 6 4 2015 http src online ca index php src article view 221 444 Graff 1990 <PERSON>Graff</PERSON> G Teach the Conflicts The <LOCATION>South Atlantic</LOCATION> Quarterly 89 1990 51 67 Gruwell 2015 <PERSON>Leigh Gruwell</PERSON> L <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> s Politics of Exclusion Gender Epistemology and Feminist Rhetorical In action Computers and Composition 37 2015 117 31 HASTAC 2015 HASTAC Admin Guidelines for Public Student Class Blogs Ethics Legalities FERPA and More 30 November 2012 https www hastac org blogs superadmin 2012 11 30 guidelines public student class blogs ethics legalities ferpa and more <PERSON>Haley Brown</PERSON> 2012 <PERSON>Haley Brown</PERSON> J Risky Writing in Unsafe Spaces <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> as a FYC First Year Composition Venue Kairos A Journal of Rhetoric Technology and Pedagogy 16 3 2012 http kairos technorhetoric net 16 3 praxis hea et al haley brown index html Harbage et al 1989 Harbage A revised by <PERSON>Schoenbaum</PERSON> S and <PERSON>Stoler</PERSON> S Annals of English Drama 975 1700 An Analytical Record of All Plays Extant or Lost Chronologically Arranged and Indexed by Author Title Dramatic Companies amp c 3rd edition <LOCATION>London</LOCATION> and <ORGANIZATION>New York Routledge</ORGANIZATION> 1989 Head and <PERSON>Eisenberg</PERSON> 2010 Head A J and <PERSON>Eisenberg</PERSON> M B How Today s College Students Use <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia for Course Related Research First</ORGANIZATION> Monday 15 3 2010 http www firstmonday org ojs index php fm article view 2830 2476 Hentschell 2002 Hentschell R Teaching in Context Reading on the Margins Renaissance Non canonical Literature on the Undergraduate Syllabus Working Papers on the Web 4 2002 http extra shu ac uk wpw renaissance hentschell htm <PERSON>Hirsch</PERSON> 2011 <PERSON>Hirsch</PERSON> B D The Kingdom Has Been Digitized Electronic Editions of <ORGANIZATION>Renaissance Drama</ORGANIZATION> and the Shadows of <PERSON>Shakespeare</PERSON> and Print Literature Compass 8 9 2011 568 91 Hirsch 2015 <PERSON>Hirsch</PERSON> B D Historical Overview Digital Renaissance Editions http digitalrenaissance uvic ca Foyer DREoverview Kill 2012 Kill M <ORGANIZATION>Teaching Digital Rhetoric Wikipedia Collaboration</ORGANIZATION> and the Politics of Free Knowledge In B <PERSON>Hirsch</PERSON> ed <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities Pedagogy Practices Principles and Politics United Kingdom</ORGANIZATION> and United States Open Book 2012 389 405 http www openbookpublishers com product 161 digital humanities pedagogy practices principles and politics Knight and <PERSON>Pryke</PERSON> 2012 Knight C and <ORGANIZATION>Pryke S Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> and the University A Case Study Teaching in Higher Education 17 6 2012 649 59 <PERSON>Koh</PERSON> and Risam 2013 Koh A and Risam R The <ORGANIZATION>Rewriting Wikipedia Project Postcolonial Digital Humanities Working Group</ORGANIZATION> http dhpoco org rewriting wikipedia Lesser and Farmer 2007 Lesser Z and Farmer A B Database of Early English Playbooks deep sas upenn edu <PERSON>Lopez</PERSON> 2014 <PERSON>Lopez</PERSON> J Constructing the <ORGANIZATION>Canon of Early Modern Drama Cambridge Cambridge University Press</ORGANIZATION> 2014 <PERSON>Mandell</PERSON> and Gamer 1998 <PERSON>Mandell</PERSON> L and Gamer M On Romanticism the <ORGANIZATION>Canon</ORGANIZATION> and the Web Special Issue of Romanticism on the Net 10 1998 http www erudit org revue ron 1998 v n10 index html O Neill 2015 O <PERSON>Neill</PERSON> C ed <PERSON>Dorothy Heathcote</PERSON> on <ORGANIZATION>Education and Drama Essential Writings New York Routledge 2015 Ostovich</ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON>Sauer</PERSON> 2004 Ostovich H and <PERSON>Sauer</PERSON> E with <PERSON>Smith</PERSON> M eds Reading Early Modern Women An Anthology of Texts in Manuscript and Print 1550 1700 <LOCATION>New York Routledge</LOCATION> 2004 <PERSON>Seligman</PERSON> 2013 <PERSON>Seligman</PERSON> A I Urban History Encyclopedias Public Digital Scholarly Projects The Public Historian 35 2 2013 24 35 <ORGANIZATION>Smith 2012 Smith E E The Digital Native Debate in Higher Education A Comparative Analysis of Recent Literature Canadian Journal of Learning and Technology</ORGANIZATION> 38 3 2012 1 18 http www cjlt ca index php cjlt article view 649 347 Steggle 2008 Steggle M Knowledge will be multiplied <ORGANIZATION>Digital Literary Studies</ORGANIZATION> and Early Modern Literature In S Schriebman and R <ORGANIZATION>Siemens</ORGANIZATION> eds A Companion to <ORGANIZATION>Digital Literary Studies Oxford Blackwell</ORGANIZATION> 2008 http www digitalhumanities org companionDLS Steggle 2010 Steggle M <ORGANIZATION>Prospero</ORGANIZATION> and Plagiarism Early Modern Studies and the Rise of <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia Digital Studies</ORGANIZATION> Le champ num rique 2 1 2010 http www digitalstudies org ojs index php digital_studies article view 205 241 <PERSON>Van Lennep</PERSON> et al 1965 68 <PERSON>Van Lennep</PERSON> W <PERSON>Avery E L Scouten</PERSON> A H <PERSON>Winchester Stone Jr G Beecher Hogan</PERSON> C The London Stage 1660 1800 5 parts 11 vols <ORGANIZATION>Carbondale Southern Illinois University Press</ORGANIZATION> 1965 1968 http catalog hathitrust org Record 000200105 Vandendorpe 2015 Vandendorpe C <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> and the Ecosystem of <ORGANIZATION>Knowledge Scholarly and Research Communication</ORGANIZATION> 6 3 2015 http src online ca index php src article view 201 424 Vetter 2014 <PERSON>Vetter</PERSON> M A Archive 2 0 What Composition Students and Academic Libraries Can Gain from <ORGANIZATION>Digital Collaborative Pedagogies Composition Studies</ORGANIZATION> 42 1 2014 35 53 <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia Education Program 2016 Wikipedia Education Program</ORGANIZATION> https outreach wikimedia org wiki Education Woods and Hannay 2000 Woods S and <PERSON>Hannay</PERSON> M P eds Teaching <PERSON>Tudor</PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION>Stuart Women Writers New York Modern Language Association</ORGANIZATION> 2000 2017 11 3 XML Print Article Please enable JavaScript to view the comments powered by Disqus URL http www digitalhumanities org dhq vol 11 3 000320 000320 html Last updated Comments dhqinfo digitalhumanities org Published by The <ORGANIZATION>Alliance of Digital Humanities Organizations Affiliated</ORGANIZATION> with Literary and Linguistic Computing Copyright 2005 image Creative Commons License This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution NoDerivatives 4 0 International License</ner>
