<ner>Skip to main content bookmark image Main menu Home About SIGs Publications Conference Awards Committees News Resources ADHO About The <ORGANIZATION>Alliance of Digital Humanities Organizations ADHO</ORGANIZATION> is an umbrella organisation whose goals are to promote and support digital research and teaching across arts and humanities disciplines drawing together humanists engaged in digital and computer assisted research teaching creation dissemination and beyond in all areas reflected by its diverse membership ADHO supports initiatives for publication presentation collaboration and training recognises and supports excellence in these endeavours and acts as an community based consultative and advisory force In doing so ADHO embraces and coordinates activity across its constituent organisations the <ORGANIZATION>European Association for Digital Humanities EADH</ORGANIZATION> founded in 1973 as the <ORGANIZATION>Association for Literary and Linguistic Computing the Association for Computers and the Humanities ACH</ORGANIZATION> founded in 1978 the <ORGANIZATION>Canadian Society for Digital Humanities Soci</ORGANIZATION> t canadienne des humanit s num riques CSDH SCHN founded in 1986 as the <ORGANIZATION>Consortium for Computers in the Humanities Consortium</ORGANIZATION> pour ordinateurs en sciences humaines centerNet the <ORGANIZATION>Australasian Association for Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> aaDH the <ORGANIZATION>Japanese Association for Digital Humanites JADH</ORGANIZATION> and Humanistica L association francophone des humanit s num riques digitales Members in ADHO societies are those at the forefront of areas such as textual analysis electronic publication document encoding textual studies and theory new media studies and multimedia digital libraries applied augmented reality interactive gaming and beyond We are researchers and lecturers in humanities computing and in academic departments such as English History French Modern Languages Philosophy Theatre Music Computer Science and Visual Arts We are resource specialists working in libraries archival centres and with humanities computing groups We are academic administrators and members of the private and public sectors We are independent scholars students graduate students and research assistants We are from countries in every hemisphere ADHO organizations offer several membership options including standard membership which includes a print subscription to Digital Scholarship in the Humanities formerly LLC membership only society fee which does not include the <ORGANIZATION>DSH LLC</ORGANIZATION> subscription senior rate student rate and developing country rate You may also select joint membership in all of the ADHO organizations Frequently Asked Questions about ADHO membership are answered here ADHO Constituent Organizations The following organizations are current members of <ORGANIZATION>ADHO Australasian Association for Digital Humanities aaDH Association for Computers and the Humanities ACH Canadian Society for Digital Humanities Soci</ORGANIZATION> t canadienne des humanit s num riques CSDH SCHN centerNet The <ORGANIZATION>European Association for Digital Humanities EADH Japanese Association for Digital Humanites JADH Humanistica L association</ORGANIZATION> francophone des humanit s num riques digitales Humanistica ADHO Governance Structure The <ORGANIZATION>Alliance for Digital Humanities Organizations</ORGANIZATION> is led by a steering committee which handles general strategy and administration of the organization Its voting members come from each of the seven constituent regional members of ADHO Non voting members are elected officers chairs from <ORGANIZATION>ADHO</ORGANIZATION> s other committees the ADHO affiliated journal editors and chairs of the <ORGANIZATION>Special Interest Groups ADHO</ORGANIZATION> also uses committees to support its primary activities These include the <ORGANIZATION>Admissions Committee the Awards Committee the Conference Coordinating Committee the Communications Committee the Infrastructure Committee the Multilingualism Multiculturalism Committee the Program Committee</ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION>Publications Committee</ORGANIZATION> ADHO s Governance Protocol is available here History of ADHO The effort to establish ADHO began in <LOCATION>Tuebingen</LOCATION> at the ALLC ACH conference in 2002 a <ORGANIZATION>Steering Committee</ORGANIZATION> was appointed at the ALLC ACH meeting in 2004 in <LOCATION>Gothenburg Sweden</LOCATION> At the 2005 meeting in <LOCATION>Victoria</LOCATION> the executive committees of the <ORGANIZATION>ACH</ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION>ALLC</ORGANIZATION> approved the governance and conference protocols and nominated their first representatives to the official <ORGANIZATION>ADHO Steering Committee</ORGANIZATION> and various ADHO standing committees The 2006 conference was the first <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> conference In 2007 the <ORGANIZATION>ADHO Steering Committee</ORGANIZATION> voted to enfranchise The <ORGANIZATION>Society for Digital Humanities Soci</ORGANIZATION> t pour l tude des m dias interactifs SDH SEMI now <ORGANIZATION>CSDH SCHN</ORGANIZATION> founded in 1986 as the <ORGANIZATION>Consortium for Computers in the Humanities Consortium</ORGANIZATION> pour ordinateurs en sciences humaines In 2012 centerNet and the <ORGANIZATION>Australasian Association for Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> aaDH became full constituent organizations in ADHO followed in January 2013 by the <ORGANIZATION>Japanese Association for Digital Humanites JADH</ORGANIZATION> and Humanistica L association francophone des humanit s num riques digitales <PERSON>Humanistica</PERSON> in 2016 The <ORGANIZATION>Stichting ADHO Foundation</ORGANIZATION> established in the <LOCATION>Netherlands</LOCATION> in 2013 serves as the legal entity for ADHO Logo The ADHO logo is available here as an EPS vector image Search form Search Current Issue of DHCommons Journal From Documents to Structured Data First Milestones of the <PERSON>Garzoni</PERSON> GO DH Translation Toolkit Creating a <ORGANIZATION>Digital Community Radio Station</ORGANIZATION> in an informal <LOCATION>Refugee Camp</LOCATION> in <ORGANIZATION>Calais France Advance Issue of Digital Scholarship</ORGANIZATION> in the Humanities formerly LLC Attesting similarity Supporting the organization and study of art image collections with computer vision Rho grams and rho sets Significant links in the web of words <PERSON>Christopher Marlowe</PERSON> Hype and <ORGANIZATION>Hoax Advance Issue of Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> Quarterly DHQ Introducci n de los editoresEditors Introduction <PERSON>Cartograf</PERSON> as de la sociedad redCartographies of the <ORGANIZATION>Network Society Laboratorios</ORGANIZATION> ciudadanos y humanidades digitalesCitizen Laboratories and <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities Geograf</ORGANIZATION> as digitales Iluminando las relaciones espaciales en una colecci n de blogs literariosDigital Geographies Illuminating Spatial Relationships in a Collection of Literary Blogs Retorno a trazos de mil historiasA Return to the Traces of a Thousand Stories image ADHO logo ADHO Constituent Organizations The <ORGANIZATION>European Association for Digital Humanities EADH Association for Computers and the Humanities ACH Canadian Society for Digital Humanities Soci</ORGANIZATION> t canadienne des humanit s num riques <ORGANIZATION>CSDH SCHN centerNet Australasian Association for Digital Humanities aaDH Japanese Association for Digital Humanities JADH Humanistica L association</ORGANIZATION> francophone des humanit s num riques digitales <ORGANIZATION>Humanistica Contact Contact</ORGANIZATION> form Email web digitalhumanities org <ORGANIZATION>Google Facebook Twitter YouTube</ORGANIZATION> Events Calendar image Creative Commons Attribution License This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3 0 Unported License</ner>
