<ner>Skip to main content Home Calendar and News Calendar and News Faculty News Alumni News Interdisciplinary Activities Undergraduate Undergraduate Why Major in History Alumni Speak Major and Minor Law History and Society Fall 2018 Courses Spring 2019 Courses Summer 2018 Courses Gertrude Casebier Grant Honors Program 4 1 Combined BA MA Dewey <PERSON>Grantham</PERSON> and Prize Awards <ORGANIZATION>Phi Alpha Theta Vanderbilt Historical Review Special Programs History Majors</ORGANIZATION> in the Job Market Graduate Program Overview Application Financial Aid Graduate Catalog Fall 2018 Courses Spring 2019 Courses Graduate Student News <ORGANIZATION>Graduate History Association GHA Career Services Resources and Related Pages Funding</ORGANIZATION> for Travel People Faculty Faculty Specialty List Graduate Students Visiting Scholars and Lecturers Emeritus Faculty Recent PhDs in History Vanderbilt History Seminar Vanderbilt History Seminar Main Page 2017 2018 2016 2017 2015 2016 2014 2015 2013 2014 2012 2013 2011 2012 2010 2011 2009 2010 2008 2009 Byrn Lecture Legal History Colloquium Legal History Colloquium 2016 2017 Contact Us Department of History image <ORGANIZATION>Department of History Jane Landers Gertrude Conaway Vanderbilt</ORGANIZATION> Professor of History <PERSON>Jane Landers</PERSON> is an historian of Colonial <LOCATION>Latin America</LOCATION> and the <LOCATION>Atlantic World</LOCATION> specializing in the history of Africans and their descendants in those worlds She is the author of Atlantic Creoles in the Age of Revolutions Cambridge Mass 2010 which was awarded the Rembert Patrick Book Award and honorary mention for the Conference on Latin American History s 2011 <PERSON>Bolton Johnson</PERSON> Prize Her first monograph <ORGANIZATION>Black Society</ORGANIZATION> in Spanish <LOCATION>Florida Urbana</LOCATION> 1999 2001 2002 2005 was awarded the Frances B Simkins Prize for Distinguished First Book in Southern History and was a CHOICE Outstanding Academic Title Landers co authored the college textbook The <LOCATION>Atlantic World</LOCATION> A History 1400 1888 <PERSON>Harlan Davidson</PERSON> 2007 and edited Slavery and Abolition in the <LOCATION>Atlantic</LOCATION> World New Sources and New Findings <LOCATION>Oxfordshire England</LOCATION> 2017 Colonial Plantations and Economy in <LOCATION>Florida Gainesville</LOCATION> 2000 2001 and <ORGANIZATION>Against the Odds Free Blacks</ORGANIZATION> in the Slave Societies of the <LOCATION>Americas London</LOCATION> 1996 She also co edited Slaves Subjects and <ORGANIZATION>Subversives Blacks</ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION>Colonial Latin America Albuquerque</LOCATION> 2006 and The African American <ORGANIZATION>Heritage of Florida Gainesville</ORGANIZATION> 1995 which won the Rembert Patrick Book Award and a commendation from the <ORGANIZATION>American Society for State</ORGANIZATION> and Local History Landers 2015 <PERSON>Nathan</PERSON> I Huggins Lectures A View from the Other Side The Saint Domingue Revolution through Spanish Sources delivered at the <ORGANIZATION>Hutchins Center for African amp African American Research Harvard University</ORGANIZATION> will be her next publication Link to first lecture here Link to second lecture here Link to third lecture here She has published essays in The <ORGANIZATION>American Historical Review Slavery</ORGANIZATION> and Abolition The New West Indian Guide The Americas Colonial Latin American Historical Review The Journal of African American History and a variety of anthologies and edited volumes <PERSON>Landers</PERSON> was awarded fellowships from the <ORGANIZATION>John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation</ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION>American Council for Learned Societies</ORGANIZATION> for another project in progress African Kingdoms Black Republics and Free Black Towns across the <LOCATION>Iberian Atlantic</LOCATION> Her research has also been supported by grants from the <ORGANIZATION>National Endowment for the Humanities the Andrew W Mellon Foundation the Conference on Latin American History Vanderbilt University the Gilder Lehrman Center for the Study of Slavery Resistance and Abolition the Historic St Augustine Research Institute</ORGANIZATION> and the Program for Cultural Cooperation between <LOCATION>Spain</LOCATION> s <ORGANIZATION>Ministry of Culture and United States Universities Landers</ORGANIZATION> is past president of the <ORGANIZATION>Conference on Latin American History</ORGANIZATION> past president of the <ORGANIZATION>Forum on European Expansion and Global Interaction</ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION>Latin American and Caribbean Section of the Southern Historical Association</ORGANIZATION> and an Associate of the <ORGANIZATION>Harriet Tubman Institute for Research</ORGANIZATION> on the <ORGANIZATION>Global Migrations of African Peoples York University She</ORGANIZATION> serves on the editorial boards for several historical journals including <ORGANIZATION>Slavery amp Abolition Colonial Latin American Historical Review Oxford</ORGANIZATION> Bibliography On line <LOCATION>Atlantic World</LOCATION> and History Compass She has also consulted on a variety of archaeological projects documentary films web sites and museum exhibits related to the African Diaspora including <ORGANIZATION>Gracia Real de Santa Teresa de Mose</ORGANIZATION> the first free black town in what is today the <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> http www flmnh ufl edu histarch mose htm <PERSON>Landers</PERSON> directs the Ecclesiastical and <ORGANIZATION>Secular Sources for Slave Societies Digital Archive ESSSS</ORGANIZATION> hosted by the Jean and <ORGANIZATION>Alexander Heard Library</ORGANIZATION> at <ORGANIZATION>Vanderbilt</ORGANIZATION> which is preserving endangered ecclesiastical and secular documents related to slavery in the Americas With grants from the <ORGANIZATION>National Endowment for the Humanities the American Council for Learned Societies the British Library Endangered Archives Programme the Historic St Augustine Research Institute</ORGANIZATION> and the Diocese of <ORGANIZATION>St Augustine</ORGANIZATION> and with the help of her graduate students <PERSON>Landers</PERSON> and her international teams have preserved records in <LOCATION>Cuba Brazil Colombia Florida</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Cape Verde</LOCATION> the oldest dating from the 16th century http www vanderbilt edu esss index php Courses taught Undergraduate Rise of the Iberian Atlantic Empires Decline of the <ORGANIZATION>Iberian Atlantic Empires Africans</ORGANIZATION> in the Americas Comparative Slavery Destruction of the <ORGANIZATION>Indies Pirates</ORGANIZATION> of the <ORGANIZATION>Caribbean Graduate Seminars Atlantic World History Readings in Colonial Latin American History Comparative Slavery Latin American Studies Interdisciplinary Research Specializations History</ORGANIZATION> of colonial <LOCATION>Latin America</LOCATION> the <LOCATION>Atlantic World</LOCATION> the <ORGANIZATION>Circum Caribbean</ORGANIZATION> borderlands comparative slave systems women and gender in colonial <LOCATION>Latin America</LOCATION> image <ORGANIZATION>Contact Information Email Phone 615 322 3403 114 Benson Hall Office Hours</ORGANIZATION> Tuesday 10 00 12 00 <ORGANIZATION>Education PhD University of Florida 1988 Curriculum Vitae People Faculty Faculty</ORGANIZATION> by specialty Graduate Students Visiting Scholars and <ORGANIZATION>Lecturers Emeritus Faculty Administration Connect</ORGANIZATION> with <ORGANIZATION>History Twitter Facebook Instagram Department of History Vanderbilt University 2301 Vanderbilt Place PMB</ORGANIZATION> 351802 <LOCATION>Nashville</LOCATION> TN 37235 For UPS and FedEx deliveries <PERSON>Benson Hall</PERSON> room 227 Phone 615 322 2575 Fax 615 343 6002 Office hours M F 8 a m 4 30 p m <ORGANIZATION>CST Vanderbilt University</ORGANIZATION> All rights reserved <ORGANIZATION>Site Development University Web Communications Vanderbilt University</ORGANIZATION> is committed to principles of equal opportunity and affirmative action <ORGANIZATION>Vanderbilt Vanderbilt University V Oak Leaf Design Star V Design</ORGANIZATION> and Anchor Down are trademarks of The <ORGANIZATION>Vanderbilt University</ORGANIZATION></ner>
