<ner><ORGANIZATION>Help Category Digital Humanities From Wikimedia Commons</ORGANIZATION> the free media repository Jump to navigation search <ORGANIZATION>Digital</ORGANIZATION> humanities projects pictures graphics etc Subcategories This category has the following 10 subcategories out of 10 total C Conference Digital Humanities 19 F D Digital Humanists 5 F <ORGANIZATION>Digital</ORGANIZATION> humanities conference in <LOCATION>Tartu</LOCATION> 2017 50 F Digital Humanities Consultation 13July2013 8 F <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities Seminar and Wikipedia Workshop</ORGANIZATION> at <ORGANIZATION>UIC</ORGANIZATION> in <ORGANIZATION>Barcelona</ORGANIZATION> 8 F E Emmabunt s 19 C 1 P 2 F F Frontiers in <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> 1 F K Konferencija Digitalna humanistika 1 F M Mainzed 8 F R <PERSON>Roy Rosenzweig</PERSON> Center for History and New Media 8 F Pages in category Digital Humanities This category contains only the following page M User Mainzed Media in category Digital Humanities The following 42 files are in this category out of 42 total image Around DH in 80 Days png Around DH in 80 Days png 863 795 134 KB image <ORGANIZATION>Bandeau Manifeste des Digital Humanities FR png Bandeau Manifeste des Digital Humanities FR png</ORGANIZATION> 3 181 1 393 24 KB image <PERSON>Dan Cohen</PERSON> academic JPG <PERSON>Dan Cohen</PERSON> academic JPG 1 935 2 136 2 31 MB image <ORGANIZATION>Digital</ORGANIZATION> humanities chart jpg <ORGANIZATION>Digital</ORGANIZATION> humanities chart jpg 792 4 263 1 87 MB image <ORGANIZATION>Digital</ORGANIZATION> humanities graph from ngram png <ORGANIZATION>Digital</ORGANIZATION> humanities graph from ngram png 1 272 506 34 KB image <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities on Twitter png Digital Humanities on Twitter</ORGANIZATION> png 1 000 824 1 09 MB image <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities Oxford</ORGANIZATION> 2017 Masterclass on <ORGANIZATION>Wikimedia pdf Digital Humanities Oxford</ORGANIZATION> 2017 Masterclass on Wikimedia pdf 4 000 2 250 35 pages 2 78 MB image <ORGANIZATION>Digital</ORGANIZATION> humanities pdf <ORGANIZATION>Digital</ORGANIZATION> humanities pdf 1 500 843 10 pages 1 25 MB image <ORGANIZATION>Digital</ORGANIZATION> literacy disciplines png Digital literacy disciplines png 960 720 57 KB image <PERSON>Dominique Vinck</PERSON> in <LOCATION>Mexico</LOCATION> 3 JPG <PERSON>Dominique Vinck</PERSON> in <LOCATION>Mexico</LOCATION> 3 JPG 6 016 4 000 5 78 MB image DRAPIer logo 2010 png DRAPIer logo 2010 png 377 110 8 KB image EHDEG1 jpg EHDEG1 jpg 1 024 768 175 KB image EHDEG2 jpg EHDEG2 jpg 1 024 768 160 KB image EHDEG3 jpg EHDEG3 jpg 1 024 768 119 KB image EHDEG4 jpg EHDEG4 jpg 1 024 768 179 KB image <ORGANIZATION>Gephi</ORGANIZATION> 0 9 1 <ORGANIZATION>Network Analysis and Visualization Software png Gephi</ORGANIZATION> 0 9 1 <ORGANIZATION>Network Analysis and Visualization Software</ORGANIZATION> png 1 397 871 566 KB image <ORGANIZATION>Historia</ORGANIZATION> 2 0 pdf <ORGANIZATION>Historia</ORGANIZATION> 2 0 pdf 1 239 1 754 150 pages 1 4 MB image <PERSON>Huma</PERSON> 16 42 jpg Huma 16 42 jpg 2 048 1 365 478 KB image Humanit s Num riques JPG Humanit s Num riques JPG 3 264 2 448 2 29 MB image <ORGANIZATION>King s College London Digital Humanities png King s College London Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> png 500 480 23 KB image <ORGANIZATION>Manifeste des Digital Humanities FR png Manifeste des Digital Humanities FR</ORGANIZATION> png 3 150 4 725 339 KB image <PERSON>Martin Grandjean</PERSON> 3 jpg <PERSON>Martin Grandjean</PERSON> 3 jpg 3 302 4 953 10 66 MB image <PERSON>Moreno Sociogram</PERSON> 2nd Grade png <PERSON>Moreno Sociogram</PERSON> 2nd Grade png 525 525 75 KB image Poemage png Poemage png 1 600 934 1 02 MB image Pride and Prejudice in Voyant Tools png Pride and Prejudice in <ORGANIZATION>Voyant Tools</ORGANIZATION> png 1 452 917 160 KB image <ORGANIZATION>RobertDarnton Digital Library</ORGANIZATION> 1 jpg <ORGANIZATION>RobertDarnton Digital Library</ORGANIZATION> 1 jpg 3 264 2 176 869 KB image <ORGANIZATION>RobertDarnton Digital Library</ORGANIZATION> 2 jpg <ORGANIZATION>RobertDarnton Digital Library</ORGANIZATION> 2 jpg 3 264 2 176 523 KB image <ORGANIZATION>RobertDarnton Digital Library</ORGANIZATION> 3 jpg <ORGANIZATION>RobertDarnton Digital Library</ORGANIZATION> 3 jpg 3 264 2 176 665 KB image <ORGANIZATION>RobertDarnton Digital Library</ORGANIZATION> 4 jpg <ORGANIZATION>RobertDarnton Digital Library</ORGANIZATION> 4 jpg 3 264 2 176 829 KB image <ORGANIZATION>Roy Rosenzweig Center for History and New Media C Stierch</ORGANIZATION> jpg <ORGANIZATION>Roy Rosenzweig Center for History and New Media C Stierch</ORGANIZATION> jpg 3 648 2 736 2 12 MB image <PERSON>Shakespeare</PERSON> s Hamlet in Voyant Tools png <PERSON>Shakespeare</PERSON> s Hamlet in <ORGANIZATION>Voyant Tools</ORGANIZATION> png 1 377 900 190 KB image <ORGANIZATION>Social Network Analysis Visualization png Social Network Analysis Visualization png</ORGANIZATION> 1 185 883 1 21 MB image <ORGANIZATION>Social Network Visualization png Social Network Visualization png</ORGANIZATION> 1 600 1 200 1 57 MB image SocialNetworkAnalysis png SocialNetworkAnalysis png 5 459 3 529 11 75 MB image T SNE visualisation of word embeddings generated using 19th century literature pdf T SNE visualisation of word embeddings generated using 19th century literature pdf 1 658 1 125 963 KB image T SNE visualisation of word embeddings generated using 19th century literature png T SNE visualisation of word embeddings generated using 19th century literature png 1 592 1 080 913 KB image The Humanities Matter infographic banner jpg The Humanities Matter infographic banner jpg 2 756 25 310 4 22 MB image Tripletsnew2012 png Tripletsnew2012 png 538 574 387 KB image <ORGANIZATION>University of Delaware Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> Edit A Thon 2014 jpg <ORGANIZATION>University of Delaware Wikipedia Edit A Thon</ORGANIZATION> 2014 jpg 1 500 1 000 280 KB image Voyant Tools Reveal Your Texts png Voyant Tools Reveal Your Texts png 3 142 2 118 1 02 MB image Wikidata for Humanists a slide Workshop by <PERSON>Asaf Bartov</PERSON> jpg Wikidata for Humanists a slide Workshop by <PERSON>Asaf Bartov</PERSON> jpg 1 979 2 638 560 KB image Wikidata for Humanists A Gentle Introduction to <ORGANIZATION>Wikimedia</ORGANIZATION> s linked data project pdf Wikidata for Humanists A Gentle Introduction to <ORGANIZATION>Wikimedia</ORGANIZATION> s linked data project pdf 1 500 843 12 pages 1 14 MB image Retrieved from https commons wikimedia org w index php title Category Digital_Humanities amp oldid 296310610 <ORGANIZATION>Categories Humanities Digital</ORGANIZATION> technology Computing and society Non topical index Interwiki from wikidata Navigation menu Personal tools English Not logged in Talk Contributions Create account Log in Namespaces Category Discussion Variants Views View Edit History More Search Navigate Main page Welcome Community portal Village pump Help center Participate Upload file Recent changes Latest files Random file Contact us Print export Create a book Download as PDF Printable version In other projects Wikipedia Tools What links here Related changes Special pages Permanent link Page information Wikidata item In <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> Catal Cymraeg Deutsch English Espa ol Euskara Suomi Fran ais <LOCATION>Magyar Italiano Latina Polski Srpskohrvatski Sloven ina</LOCATION> <PERSON>Svenska Ti ng Vi</PERSON> t Edit links This page was last edited on 9 April 2018 at 11 41 Text is available under the Creative Commons Attribution ShareAlike License additional terms may apply By using this site you agree to the Terms of Use and Privacy Policy Privacy policy About Wikimedia Commons Disclaimers Developers Cookie statement Mobile view image <ORGANIZATION>Wikimedia Foundation</ORGANIZATION> image Powered by <PERSON>MediaWiki</PERSON></ner>
