<ner>Help Search results Jump to navigation search Search Results 1 20 of 6 581 Content pages Multimedia Translations Everything Advanced Search categories View other tools Help Phrases in double quotes For example holly dolly returns very few results as opposed to holly dolly Exclusion Terms can be excluded with for example windows system note there is no space between and the excluded term Wildcard search Wildcards symbols representing unknown text can be prefixed and suffixed for example the search stan will produce results like <LOCATION>Kazakhstan</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Afghanistan</LOCATION> For more details including fuzzy search Boolean operators and keywords intitle incategory and prefix see Search Help on English Wikipedia Browse Category overview Root Category tree Browse by topic <ORGANIZATION>Nature Society Science Browse</ORGANIZATION> by type Images Sound Video Indices Galleries Categories New files Search Google image search all Wikimedia Wikiwix Random File Gallery Category Create the page <ORGANIZATION>Digital</ORGANIZATION> humanities on this wiki image File Digital humanities pdf DescriptionDigital humanities pdf digital humanities project Date 12 October 1 500 843 1 25 MB 18 54 12 October 2017 image File Interview of <PERSON>Amlan Das Gupta</PERSON> at <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> Consultation 2013 webm Play media File Interview of <PERSON>Amlan Das Gupta</PERSON> at <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> Consultation 2013 webm DescriptionInterview of <PERSON>Amlan Das Gupta</PERSON> at <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> Consultation 2013 webm English Interview of <PERSON>Amlan Das Gupta</PERSON> at <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities Consultation</ORGANIZATION> organized at WebM VP8 Vorbis video file 4 min 58 s 19 48 11 January 2017 image <ORGANIZATION>File Digital Humanities Oxford</ORGANIZATION> 2017 Masterclass on <ORGANIZATION>Wikimedia pdf University of Oxford Digital Humanities Summer School</ORGANIZATION> DHOxSS The title was <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> s sister projects as platforms for the digital humanities and the time 4 000 2 250 2 78 MB 22 48 15 February 2018 image <ORGANIZATION>File Digital Humanities on Twitter png DescriptionDigital Humanities on Twitter png English Graph of Digital Humanities Twitter</ORGANIZATION> users with 1 434 nodes and 137 061 directed edges that each 1 000 824 1 09 MB 12 47 28 December 2016 image File Digital humanities chart jpg DescriptionDigital humanities chart jpg English A chart with multiple types of statistics about progress in the digital humanities Date 20 January 792 4 263 1 87 MB 18 01 15 February 2018 image File <ORGANIZATION>Conference Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> 16 <ORGANIZATION>JPG DescriptionConference Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> 16 JPG English Conference <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> at the <ORGANIZATION>Faculty of Philology University of Belgrade</ORGANIZATION> 22 26 September 2 560 1 536 1 55 MB 15 22 24 November 2016 image File Conference Digital Humanities 007 JPG DescriptionConference Digital Humanities 007 JPG English Conference <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> at the <ORGANIZATION>Faculty of Philology University of Belgrade</ORGANIZATION> 22 26 2 560 1 536 1 31 MB 15 22 24 November 2016 image File <ORGANIZATION>Conference Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> 14 <ORGANIZATION>JPG DescriptionConference Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> 14 JPG English Conference <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> at the <ORGANIZATION>Faculty of Philology University of Belgrade</ORGANIZATION> 22 26 September 2 560 1 536 1 52 MB 15 22 24 November 2016 image File <ORGANIZATION>Conference Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> 13 <ORGANIZATION>JPG DescriptionConference Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> 13 JPG English Conference <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> at the <ORGANIZATION>Faculty of Philology University of Belgrade</ORGANIZATION> 22 26 September 2 560 1 536 1 6 MB 15 22 24 November 2016 image File Conference Digital Humanities 010 JPG DescriptionConference Digital Humanities 010 JPG English Conference <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> at the <ORGANIZATION>Faculty of Philology University of Belgrade</ORGANIZATION> 22 26 2 560 1 536 1 34 MB 15 22 24 November 2016 image File <ORGANIZATION>Conference Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> 03 <ORGANIZATION>JPG DescriptionConference Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> 03 JPG English Conference <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> at the <ORGANIZATION>Faculty of Philology University of Belgrade</ORGANIZATION> 22 26 September 1 280 768 450 KB 15 22 24 November 2016 image File Conference Digital Humanities 011 JPG DescriptionConference Digital Humanities 011 JPG English Conference <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> at the <ORGANIZATION>Faculty of Philology University of Belgrade</ORGANIZATION> 22 26 2 560 1 536 1 45 MB 15 22 24 November 2016 image File Conference Digital Humanities 006 JPG DescriptionConference Digital Humanities 006 JPG English Conference <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> at the <ORGANIZATION>Faculty of Philology University of Belgrade</ORGANIZATION> 22 26 2 560 1 536 274 KB 15 22 24 November 2016 image File <ORGANIZATION>Conference Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> 06 <ORGANIZATION>JPG DescriptionConference Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> 06 JPG English Conference <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> at the <ORGANIZATION>Faculty of Philology University of Belgrade</ORGANIZATION> 22 26 September 1 725 880 643 KB 15 22 24 November 2016 image File <ORGANIZATION>Conference Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> 02 <ORGANIZATION>JPG DescriptionConference Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> 02 JPG English Conference <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> at the <ORGANIZATION>Faculty of Philology University of Belgrade</ORGANIZATION> 22 26 September 1 536 1 139 810 KB 15 22 24 November 2016 image File <ORGANIZATION>Conference Digital Humanities 04 JPG DescriptionConference Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> 04 JPG English Conference <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> at the <ORGANIZATION>Faculty of Philology University of Belgrade</ORGANIZATION> 22 26 September 1 725 880 630 KB 15 22 24 November 2016 image File Conference Digital Humanities 008 JPG DescriptionConference Digital Humanities 008 JPG English Conference <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> at the <ORGANIZATION>Faculty of Philology University of Belgrade</ORGANIZATION> 22 26 2 560 1 536 1 31 MB 15 22 24 November 2016 image File <ORGANIZATION>Conference Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> 18 <ORGANIZATION>JPG DescriptionConference Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> 18 <ORGANIZATION>JPG English Conference Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> at the <ORGANIZATION>Faculty of Philology University of Belgrade</ORGANIZATION> 22 26 September 2 560 1 536 1 56 MB 15 22 24 November 2016 image File Conference Digital Humanities 009 JPG DescriptionConference Digital Humanities 009 JPG English Conference <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> at the <ORGANIZATION>Faculty of Philology University of Belgrade</ORGANIZATION> 22 26 2 560 1 536 285 KB 15 22 24 November 2016 image File <ORGANIZATION>Conference Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> 17 <ORGANIZATION>JPG DescriptionConference Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> 17 JPG English Conference <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> at the <ORGANIZATION>Faculty of Philology University of Belgrade</ORGANIZATION> 22 26 September 2 560 1 536 1 56 MB 15 22 24 November 2016 View previous 20 next 20 20 50 100 250 500 image Retrieved from https commons wikimedia org wiki Special Search Navigation menu Personal tools English Not logged in Talk Contributions Create account Log in Namespaces Special page Variants Views More Search Navigate Main page Welcome Community portal Village pump Help center Participate Upload file Recent changes Latest files Random file Contact us Tools Special pages Printable version Privacy policy About Wikimedia Commons Disclaimers Developers Cookie statement Mobile view image <ORGANIZATION>Wikimedia Foundation</ORGANIZATION> image Powered by <PERSON>MediaWiki</PERSON></ner>
