<ner>Skip to main content centerNet An international network of digital humanities centers Menu Main menu Home About Centers Contact Initiatives Join centerNet News About centerNet centerNet is an international network of digital humanities centers formed for cooperative and collaborative action to benefit digital humanities and allied fields in general and centers as humanities cyberinfrastructure in particular Anchored by its new publication DHCommons centerNet enables individual <ORGANIZATION>DH Centers</ORGANIZATION> to network internationally sharing and building on projects tools staff and expertise Through initiatives such as Day s of DH and Resources for Starting and Sustaining DH Centers centerNet provides a virtual DH center for isolated DH projects and platform for educating the broader scholarly community about <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities Read</ORGANIZATION> more centerNet News CFP Calling for Proposals to Host Day of DH in 2017 and 2018 Submitted by kdalziel2 unl edu on Mon 05 23 2016 10 47 A Day in the Life of the Digital Humanities Day of DH is an open community initiative sponsored by centerNet that each year brings together scholars interested in the digital humanities from around the world to document what they do on one day The goal is to create a website that weaves together a picture of the participants activities on the day and which answers the question Just what do digital humanists really do Participants document their day through photographs and text all of which is published on a community online platform forming a record of the day Read more about CFP Calling for Proposals to Host Day of DH in 2017 and 2018 News from centerNet Centers DARIAH DE Grand Tour Reproduzierbare Forschung und Erweitertes Publizieren mit Jupyter Notebooks Posted Tuesday April 10 2018 05 21 by <ORGANIZATION>Textgrid Digitale Methoden</ORGANIZATION> entwickeln sich zunehmend zur allt glichen Praxis in den <PERSON>Geisteswissenschaften Von der Erstellung</PERSON> einer <PERSON>Sammlung</PERSON> ber Bildanalysen Text Annotierung bis hin zu <PERSON>Netzwerk Analysen</PERSON> f r die Ideengeschichte keiner dieser Bereiche wird heutzutage noch ohne Computer angegangen <PERSON>Durch</PERSON> diese wachsende Bedeutung treten Themen die urspr nglich in der Software Entwicklung angesiedelt Read full post external link When Pigs Fly Improbable Perspectives on Mediated Realism Part II Posted Monday April 9 2018 15 54 by Media Arts Pr Opening Reception April 30 5 7pmGallery Hours May 1 4 10am 5pm closes at 2pm on May 4 Location SCA Gallery Room 120 and <ORGANIZATION>SCA</ORGANIZATION> Stage 4 <ORGANIZATION>USC School of Cinematic</ORGANIZATION> Arts900 West 34th Street Los Angeles CA 90089 2211 Facebook Event The post When Pigs Fly Improbable Perspectives on Mediated Realism Part II appeared Read full post external link Erster internationaler Modellathon 3D Rekonstruktion Ergebnisse Posted Monday April 9 2018 12 37 by <ORGANIZATION>Textgrid Die Arbeitsgruppe Digitale Rekonstruktion AGDR</ORGANIZATION> des <ORGANIZATION>Verbands Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> im deutschsprachigen Raum DHd hat im Rahmen des Kongresses Kritik der Digitalen Vernunft im M rz 2018 in K ln den ersten internationalen Modellathon veranstaltet In dieser Spielart des Hackathons haben sich Studierende eine Woche lang mit der digitale <PERSON>Rekonstruktionsaufgabe Vermitteln Sie den Teilnehmern</PERSON> der Read full post external link Web Programmierung UX UI Design und Usability <LOCATION>Berlin</LOCATION> E 13 TV L 50 Posted Monday April 9 2018 09 04 by Textgrid Die BBAW sucht f r ihr Projekt Kulturerbe als Linked Open Data Pilotprojekt f r den Census zum fr hestm glichen Zeitpunkt eine <PERSON>einen Wissenschaftliche</PERSON> n <PERSON>Mitarbeiter</PERSON> in in <LOCATION>Teilzeit</LOCATION> 50 mit <LOCATION>Erfahrungen</LOCATION> mit Web Programmierung UX UI Design und Usability befristet bis zum 31 12 2020 <ORGANIZATION>Der Census of Antique Works</ORGANIZATION> of Art and Architecture Known in the Renaissance enth lt ca 250 Read full post external link Ank ndigung PARTHENOS Workshop ESU 2018 und Freie Pl tze PARTHENOS Webinar zur <ORGANIZATION>Entwicklung von Forschungsfragen</ORGANIZATION> Posted Monday April 9 2018 08 24 by <ORGANIZATION>Textgrid Lost</ORGANIZATION> in Isolation <PERSON>Dann</PERSON> bewerben Sie sich bis zum 01 05 2018 f r den <ORGANIZATION>PARTHENOS Workshop How Research Infrastructures</ORGANIZATION> empower eHumanities and eHeritage Research ers und lernen Sie wie Sie mit <ORGANIZATION>Hilfe</ORGANIZATION> von <PERSON>Forschungsinfrastrukturen Wissen Daten Methoden</PERSON> und Tools geisteswissenschaftlicher Forschungsgemeinschaften f r Ihre Forschungsprojekte nutzbar machen k nnen Read full post external link <ORGANIZATION>Digitalisierungsexperten</ORGANIZATION> m w <ORGANIZATION>Entgeltgruppe</ORGANIZATION> 13 TV L Vollzeit Posted Monday April 9 2018 06 50 by <ORGANIZATION>Textgrid Die Zentralkustodie der Friedrich Alexander Universit</ORGANIZATION> t <LOCATION>Erlangen</LOCATION> N rnberg sucht zum n chstm glichen Zeitpunkt befristet bis 29 02 2020 f r die <PERSON>Abteilung H Haushalt</PERSON> und <ORGANIZATION>Liegenschaften Digitalisierungsexperten</ORGANIZATION> m w <ORGANIZATION>Entgeltgruppe</ORGANIZATION> 13 TV L <PERSON>Vollzeit</PERSON> f r den <ORGANIZATION>Aufbau</ORGANIZATION> und die <LOCATION>Weiterentwicklung</LOCATION> einer digitalen Infrastruktur zur <PERSON>Erfassung</PERSON> und Vernetzung universit rer <LOCATION>Sammlungen</LOCATION> in Read full post external link Fristverl ngerung Stellenausschreibung IT Leiter IT <ORGANIZATION>Leiterin Philipps Universit</ORGANIZATION> t <ORGANIZATION>Marburg Deutsches Dokumentationszentrum</ORGANIZATION> f r <ORGANIZATION>Kunstgeschichte Bildarchiv Foto Marburg</ORGANIZATION> bis E 14 Posted Friday April 6 2018 03 00 by <PERSON>Textgrid Die Bewerbungsfrist</PERSON> f r folgende Ausschreibung ist bis zum 20 04 2018 verl ngert worden Am <PERSON>Deutschen Dokumentationszentrum</PERSON> f r <ORGANIZATION>Kunstgeschichte Bildarchiv Foto Marburg Philipps Universit</ORGANIZATION> t <ORGANIZATION>Marburg</ORGANIZATION> suchen wir zum n chstm glichen Zeitpunkt eine einen IT Leiter IT Leiterin bis E 14 TV L Vollzeit unbefristet Zu den Aufgaben geh ren die verantwortliche Read full post external link The Four Horsemen of the Free Speech Apocalypse Emerging Conceptual Challenges for Civil Libertarians Posted Wednesday April 4 2018 22 05 by MIT Center for Last April I blogged about a talk on trigger warnings I gave as a representative of the <ORGANIZATION>Board of the National Coalition Against Censorship NCAC</ORGANIZATION> a nonprofit whose mission is to promote freedom of thought inquiry and expression and oppose censorship in all its forms Earlier today at the request of Executive Director <PERSON>Chris Finan</PERSON> I presented to the rest of the Board some early thoughts Read full post external link <ORGANIZATION>Global Epistemics</ORGANIZATION> 6 Questions to <PERSON>Inanna Hamati Ataya</PERSON> Posted Wednesday April 4 2018 11 09 by Centre for Rese blog_description Entwicklerin Entwickler Web Applikation Angular 5 Posted Wednesday April 4 2018 04 05 by <PERSON>Textgrid</PERSON> via <ORGANIZATION>Vera Chiquet Universit</ORGANIZATION> t <ORGANIZATION>Basel Vollzeit auf Wunsch</ORGANIZATION> 80 Anfangsdatum so bald wie m glich <PERSON>Dauer Ein Jahr Eine Verl</PERSON> ngerung ist nicht ausgeschlossen <ORGANIZATION>Das Digital Humanities Lab</ORGANIZATION> ist eine technologisch ausgerichtete Institution an der Philosophisch Historischen Fakult t der Universit t <LOCATION>Basel</LOCATION> mit mehr als 20 <PERSON>Jahren Praxiserfahrung</PERSON> in der interdisziplin ren Forschung Ihre AufgabenKnora Read full post external link Pages 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 next last <ORGANIZATION>Featured Centers Centre for Digital Humanities Ryerson University Toronto ON Canada</ORGANIZATION> http www ryerson ca cdh <ORGANIZATION>Oxford e Research Centre</ORGANIZATION> 7 <ORGANIZATION>Keble Road Oxford United Kingdom</ORGANIZATION> OX1 3QG http www oerc ox ac uk <ORGANIZATION>Digitales</ORGANIZATION> <LOCATION>Madrid Spain</LOCATION> http linhd uned es en <ORGANIZATION>Digital Scholarship Lab Richmond VA United States</ORGANIZATION> http dsl richmond edu Laboratoire de recherche historique <ORGANIZATION>Lyon Cedex</ORGANIZATION> 07 <LOCATION>France</LOCATION> http larhra ish lyon cnrs fr <ORGANIZATION>Douglas College Digital Cultures Lab Vancouver BC Canada</ORGANIZATION> http digitalcultureslab ca Initiatives DHCommons centerNet s new publication DHCommons is merging with <ORGANIZATION>Arts Humanities</ORGANIZATION> net to create one large scale discovery and review publication for digital humanities projects Resources for Starting and Sustaining DH Centers The Resources page lists talks articles sample DH proposals and other sources of information about ways to start and sustain DH centers Day s of DH A Day of the Life of the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> an event where digital humanists from around the world document what they do Read more Becoming a Member If you think your center is a digital humanities center in whole or in part then we d be glad to have you join centerNet We leave the definition of digital humanities up to you but we intend to be inclusive and we know that there will be cross over into the social sciences media studies digital arts and other related areas This might include humanities centers with a strong interest in or focus on digital platforms One caveat a center should be larger than a single project and it should have some history or promise of persistence To see a list our Founding Centers from around the world click here Read more Search Search</ner>
