<ner>Skip to main content This service is more advanced with JavaScript available learn more at http activatejavascript org SpringerLink Search Home Contact us Log in image Computers and the <ORGANIZATION>Humanities Computers</ORGANIZATION> and the Humanities September 1976 Volume 10 Issue 5 pp 265 274 Cite as Computational linguistics and the humanist Authors Authors and affiliations <PERSON>William Benzon David G Hays</PERSON> Article 1 Shares 52 Downloads 2 Citations Keywords Computational Linguistic These keywords were added by machine and not by the authors This process is experimental and the keywords may be updated as the learning algorithm improves This is a preview of subscription content log in to check access Preview Unable to display preview Download preview PDF Unable to display preview Download preview PDF Bibliography <PERSON>Anderson John</PERSON> R Computer simulation of language acquisition A first report In <LOCATION>Solso</LOCATION> ed <ORGANIZATION>Information Processing and Cognition The Loyola Symposium New York</ORGANIZATION> <PERSON>John Wiley</PERSON> and Sons 1975 pp 295 349 <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> Scholar <PERSON>Arbib Michael</PERSON> A Artificial intelligence and brain theory Unities and diversities <ORGANIZATION>Computer and Information Science Department University of Massachusetts Technical Report 75C</ORGANIZATION> 8 September 1975 Google Scholar Bates Madeleine The use of syntax in a speech understanding system <ORGANIZATION>IEEE Transactions on Acoustics Speech and Signal Processing</ORGANIZATION> 23 1 February 1975 112 117 CrossRefGoogle Scholar Bates Madeleine Syntax in automatic speech understanding <ORGANIZATION>AJCL</ORGANIZATION> 45 1976 <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> Scholar <PERSON>Bechtel Robert</PERSON> and <PERSON>Stuart C Shapiro</PERSON> A logic for semantic networks <ORGANIZATION>Computer Science Department Indiana University</ORGANIZATION> Technical Report No 47 March 1976 <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> Scholar <PERSON>Becker Richard W</PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION>Fausto Poza Acoustic</ORGANIZATION> research in speech understanding <ORGANIZATION>IEEE Transactions on Acoustics Speech and Signal Processing</ORGANIZATION> 23 1975 416 426 CrossRefGoogle Scholar <PERSON>Benzon William Cognitive</PERSON> networks and literary semantics Modern Language Notes The Centennial Issue Summer 1976 Google Scholar <PERSON>Collins Allan</PERSON> M and <PERSON>Elizabeth F Loftus</PERSON> A spreading activation theory of semantic processing Psychological Review 82 1975 407 428 CrossRefGoogle Scholar Cullingford R E The application of script based world knowledge in an integrated story understanding system Abstract inAJCL 48 1976 31 Preprints of <ORGANIZATION>ICCL</ORGANIZATION> 1976 <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> Scholar <PERSON>Erman Lee</PERSON> D <PERSON>Richard D Fennell Victor R Lesser</PERSON> and D <PERSON>Raj Reddy</PERSON> System organization for speech understanding Implications of network and multiprocessor computer architecture IEEE Transactions on Computers 25 April 1976 414 421 <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> Scholar <PERSON>Frederiksen Carl</PERSON> H Representing logical and semantic structure of knowledge acquired from discourse Cognitive Psychology 7 1975 371 485 CrossRefGoogle Scholar <PERSON>Friedman Joyce</PERSON> with <PERSON>Thomas H Bredt Robert W Doran Bary W Pollack</PERSON> and <PERSON>Theodore S Martner</PERSON> A <ORGANIZATION>Computer Model of Transformational Grammar New York American Elsevier 1971 Google Scholar Goldman Neil M Sentence</ORGANIZATION> paraphrasing from a conceptual base Communications of the ACM 18 1975 96 <ORGANIZATION>CrossRefGoogle Scholar Gregg Lee W Knowledge and Cognition Potomac MD Lawrence Erlbaum Associates</ORGANIZATION> 1974 <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> Scholar <PERSON>Grishman Ralph</PERSON> A survey of syntactic analysis procedures for natural languages <ORGANIZATION>AJCL</ORGANIZATION> 47 1976 Google Scholar <PERSON>Hays David</PERSON> G Cognitive Structures Manuscript 1975 <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> Scholar <PERSON>Hays David</PERSON> G On alienation An essay in the psycholinguistics of science InAlienation ed <PERSON>Felix Geyer</PERSON> in press Leiden H E Stenfert Kroese B V 1976 Google Scholar <PERSON>Hendrix Gary G Semantic</PERSON> processing for speech understanding <ORGANIZATION>AJCL</ORGANIZATION> 34 1975 34 48 <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> Scholar <PERSON>Hockett Charles</PERSON> F The State of the Art The Hague Mouton 1968 <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> Scholar <PERSON>Joshi Aravind K</PERSON> and <PERSON>Stanley J Rosenschein</PERSON> Problems of inferencing and its relation to decomposition Abstract inAJCL 48 1976 38 41 To appear inSMIL <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> Scholar <PERSON>Kaplan Ronald</PERSON> M A general syntactic processor In <PERSON>Randall Rustin</PERSON> ed <ORGANIZATION>Natural Language Processing New York Algorithmics Press</ORGANIZATION> 1973 pp 193 241 <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> Scholar <PERSON>Klein Sheldon</PERSON> et al Modelling <PERSON>Propp</PERSON> and <PERSON>Levi Strauss</PERSON> in meta symbolic simulation system <ORGANIZATION>Computer Sciences Department University of Wisconsin</ORGANIZATION> Technical Report No 226 October 1974 <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> Scholar <PERSON>Kintsch Walter</PERSON> The Representation of Meaning in <ORGANIZATION>Memory Hillsdale NJ Lawrence Erlbaum Associates</ORGANIZATION> 1974 <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> Scholar <PERSON>Lehnert Wendy</PERSON> Question answering in a story understanding system <ORGANIZATION>Department of Computer Science Yale University Research Report No</ORGANIZATION> 57 December 1975 Google Scholar <PERSON>Lipovski G Jack</PERSON> and Stanley Y W Su On non numeric architecture SIGIR Forum 10 1 Summer 1975 5 20 <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> Scholar <PERSON>Macksey Richard</PERSON> and <PERSON>Eugenio Donato</PERSON> The Languages of Criticism and the Sciences of Man The Structuralist Controversy Baltimore Johns Hopkins 1970 Google Scholar <PERSON>McFarland Thomas</PERSON> Tragic Meanings in <ORGANIZATION>Shakespeare New York Random House</ORGANIZATION> 1966 <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> Scholar <PERSON>Meehan James</PERSON> R Using planning structures to generate stories <ORGANIZATION>AJCL</ORGANIZATION> 33 1975 78 94 <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> Scholar <PERSON>Miller George</PERSON> A Toward a third metaphor for psycholinguistics In <PERSON>Weimer</PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION>Palermo</ORGANIZATION> eds Cognition and the Symbolic Processes <ORGANIZATION>Hillsdale NJ Lawrence Erlbaum Associates</ORGANIZATION> 1974 pp 397 413 <ORGANIZATION>Google Scholar Minsky Marvin Semantic Information Processing Cambridge The MIT</ORGANIZATION> Press 1968 Google Scholar <PERSON>Minsky Marvin</PERSON> A framework for representing knowledge In P H Winston ed The <ORGANIZATION>Psychology of Computer Vision New York McGraw Hill</ORGANIZATION> 1975 pp 211 277 <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> Scholar <PERSON>Nash Webber Bonnie Semantic</PERSON> support for a speech understanding system <ORGANIZATION>IEEE Transactions on Acoustics Speech and Signal Processing</ORGANIZATION> 23 1 February 1975 124 129 CrossRefGoogle Scholar <PERSON>Norman Donald A David E Rumelhart</PERSON> and the <ORGANIZATION>LNR Research Group Explorations in Cognition San Francisco W H Freeman 1975 Google</ORGANIZATION> Scholar <PERSON>Paxton William</PERSON> H A best first parser <ORGANIZATION>IEEE Transactions on Acoustics Speech and Signal Processing</ORGANIZATION> 23 1975 426 432 CrossRefGoogle Scholar <PERSON>Reddy</PERSON> D Raj Speech Recognition Invited Papers of the <ORGANIZATION>IEEE Symposium New York Academic Press</ORGANIZATION> 1975 Google Scholar <PERSON>Reddy</PERSON> D <PERSON>Raj Speech</PERSON> recognition by machine A review Proceedings of the IEEE 64 April 1976 501 531 CrossRefGoogle Scholar <PERSON>Reddy D Raj Lee D Erman Richard D Fennell</PERSON> and <PERSON>Richard B Neely</PERSON> The Hearsay I speech understanding system An example of the recognition process IEEE Transactions on Computers 25 April 1976 422 431 <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> Scholar <PERSON>Reddy D Raj</PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION>Allen Newell Knowledge</ORGANIZATION> and its representation in a speech understanding system In <PERSON>Lee W Gregg</PERSON> ed Knowledge and <ORGANIZATION>Cognition Lawrence Erlbaum Associates</ORGANIZATION> 1974 pp 253 285 <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> Scholar Rieger Chuck Understanding by conceptual inference <ORGANIZATION>AJCL</ORGANIZATION> 13 1974 <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> Scholar <PERSON>Rovner Paul Bonnie Nash Webber</PERSON> and <PERSON>William A Woods</PERSON> Control concepts in a speech understanding system <ORGANIZATION>IEEE Transactions on Acoustics Speech and Signal Processing</ORGANIZATION> 23 February 1975 136 140 CrossRefGoogle Scholar <PERSON>Schank Roger</PERSON> C and C J <PERSON>Rieger</PERSON> III Inference and the computer understanding of natural language Artificial Intelligence 5 1974 373 412 CrossRefGoogle Scholar <PERSON>Schank Roger</PERSON> C et al <ORGANIZATION>Conceptual Information Processing New York American Elsevier 1975a Google</ORGANIZATION> Scholar <PERSON>Schank Roger C</PERSON> and the <ORGANIZATION>Yale AI Project SAM</ORGANIZATION> A story understander <ORGANIZATION>Department of Computer Science Yale University Research Report</ORGANIZATION> 43 August 1975b <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> Scholar <PERSON>Scragg Greg</PERSON> W Frames planes and nets A synthesis Working papers of the <ORGANIZATION>Institute for Semantic</ORGANIZATION> and Cognitive Studies No 19 1975 Google Scholar <PERSON>Shapiro Stuart</PERSON> C and <ORGANIZATION>Mitchell Wand</ORGANIZATION> The relevance of relevance <ORGANIZATION>Computer Science Department Indiana University Bloomington Technical</ORGANIZATION> Report No 46 March 1976 Google Scholar Sheil B A On context free parsing Abstract inAJCL 48 1976 58 63 To appear inSMIL <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> Scholar <PERSON>Silva Georgette</PERSON> On automatic speech understanding systems Computers and the Humanities 9 September 1975 237 244 CrossRefGoogle Scholar <PERSON>Solso Robert</PERSON> L ed Contemporary Issues in <ORGANIZATION>Cognitive Psychology Washington DC V H Winston amp Sons 1973 Google Scholar Solso Robert L ed Information Processing and Cognition Hillsdale NJ Lawrence Erlbaum Associates</ORGANIZATION> 1975 <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> Scholar <PERSON>Tulving Endel</PERSON> and <PERSON>Wayne Donaldson</PERSON> eds <ORGANIZATION>Organization of Memory New York Academic Press</ORGANIZATION> 1972 Google Scholar <PERSON>Walker Donald</PERSON> E The SRI speech understanding system <ORGANIZATION>IEEE Transactions on Acoustics Speech and Signal Processing 23 1975 397 416 CrossRefGoogle Scholar White Mary J Cognitive networks</ORGANIZATION> and world view The metaphysical terminology of a millenarian community Dissertation <ORGANIZATION>SUNY Buffalo 1975 Google</ORGANIZATION> Scholar Wilks Yorick An intelligent analyzer and understander of English Communications of the ACM 18 1975a 264 274 CrossRefGoogle Scholar <PERSON>Wilks Yorick Putnam</PERSON> and <PERSON>Clarke</PERSON> and mind and body <ORGANIZATION>British Journal</ORGANIZATION> for the Philosophy of Science 26 1975b 213 225 <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> Scholar <PERSON>Wilks Yorick</PERSON> A preferential pattern seeking semantics for natural language inference Artificial Intelligence 6 1975c 53 74 <ORGANIZATION>CrossRefGoogle Scholar Wilks Yorick Seven</ORGANIZATION> theses on artificial intelligence and natural language <ORGANIZATION>Institute for Semantic</ORGANIZATION> and Cognitive Studies Working Paper 17 1975d Google Scholar Wilks Yorick Natural language understanding systems within the A I paradigm A survey and some comparisons <ORGANIZATION>AJCL</ORGANIZATION> 40 1976a <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> Scholar Wilks Yorick Frames stories scripts and fantasies Abstract inAJCL 48 1976b 21 Preprints of <ORGANIZATION>ICCL</ORGANIZATION> 1976 <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> Scholar <PERSON>Winston Patrick H</PERSON> ed The <ORGANIZATION>Psychology of Computer Vision New York McGraw Hill 1975 Google</ORGANIZATION> Scholar Woods William A Motivation and overview of SPEECHLIS An experimental prototype for speech understanding research <ORGANIZATION>IEEE Transactions on Acoustics Speech and Signal Processing</ORGANIZATION> 23 1 February 1975 2 11 CrossRefGoogle Scholar Woods William A and J Makhoul Mechanical inference problems in continuous speech understanding Artificial Intelligence 5 1 1974 73 91 CrossRefGoogle Scholar Copyright information <ORGANIZATION>Pergamon Press</ORGANIZATION> 1976 Authors and Affiliations <PERSON>William Benzon</PERSON> 1 <PERSON>David G Hays</PERSON> 1 1 <ORGANIZATION>State University of New YorkBuffalo About</ORGANIZATION> this article Cite this article as <PERSON>Benzon</PERSON> W amp <PERSON>Hays</PERSON> D G Comput Hum 1976 10 265 https doi org 10 1007 BF02420060 DOI https doi org 10 1007 BF02420060 Publisher Name Kluwer Academic Publishers Print ISSN 0010 4817 Online ISSN 1572 8412 About this journal Reprints and Permissions Personalised recommendations Cite article How to cite RIS Papers Reference Manager RefWorks Zotero ENW EndNote BIB BibTeX JabRef Mendeley Buy options Actions Log in to check access Buy PDF USD 39 95 Unlimited access to the full article Instant download Include local sales tax if applicable Subscribe to Journal Get Access to Computers and the Humanities for the whole of 2018 Rent this article via <ORGANIZATION>DeepDyve Learn</ORGANIZATION> about institutional subscriptions Cite article How to cite RIS Papers Reference Manager RefWorks Zotero ENW EndNote BIB BibTeX JabRef Mendeley Cookies We use cookies to improve your experience with our site More information Accept Over 10 million scientific documents at your fingertips Switch Edition Academic Edition Corporate Edition Home Impressum Legal information Accessibility Contact us <ORGANIZATION>Springer Nature 2017 Springer International Publishing AG</ORGANIZATION> Part of Springer Nature Not logged in Not affiliated 99 65 190 47</ner>
