<ner>Skip to main content This service is more advanced with JavaScript available learn more at http activatejavascript org SpringerLink Search Home Contact us Log in image Proceedings of the <ORGANIZATION>International Workshop on Computational Intelligence in Security for Information Systems CISIS</ORGANIZATION> 08 Proceedings of the <ORGANIZATION>International Workshop on Computational Intelligence in Security for Information Systems CISIS</ORGANIZATION> 08 pp 53 60 Cite as Virtual Weapons for Real Wars Text Mining for <ORGANIZATION>National Security Authors Authors</ORGANIZATION> and affiliations <PERSON>Alessandro Zanasi</PERSON> Conference paper 2 Citations 1 Mentions 13 Readers 440 Downloads Part of the Advances in Soft Computing book series AINSC volume 53 Abstract Since the end of the Cold War the threat of large scale wars has been substituted by new threats terrorism organized crime trafficking smuggling proliferation of weapons of mass destruction The new criminals especially the so called jihadist terrorists are using the new technologies as those enhanced by Web2 0 to fight their war Text mining is the most advanced knowledge management technology which allow intelligence analysts to automatically analyze the content of information rich online data banks suspected web sites blogs emails chat lines instant messages and all other digital media detecting links between people and organizations trends of social and economic actions topics of interest also if they are sunk among terabytes of information Keywords National security information sharing text mining This is a preview of subscription content log in to check access Preview Unable to display preview Download preview PDF Unable to display preview Download preview PDF References 1 <ORGANIZATION>Lisse W The Economics of Information</ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION>Internet Competitive Intelligence Review</ORGANIZATION> 9 4 1998 Google Scholar 2 <ORGANIZATION>Treverton G F Reshaping National Intelligence</ORGANIZATION> in an Age of <ORGANIZATION>Information Cambridge University Press Cambridge 2001 Google</ORGANIZATION> Scholar 3 <PERSON>Ronfeldt</PERSON> D <PERSON>Arquilla</PERSON> J The Advent of Netwar Rand Corporation 1996 <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> Scholar 4 Goldfinger C Travail et hors Travail vers une societe fluide In Jacob O ed 1998 Google Scholar 5 <PERSON>Kohlmann</PERSON> E The Real Online Terrorist Threat Foreign Affairs September October 2006 Google Scholar 6 Mueller J Is There Still a Terrorist Threat Foreign Affairs September October 2006 Google Scholar 7 Riedel B Al Qaeda Strikes Back Foreign Affairs May June 2007 Google Scholar 8 Zanasi A ed Text Mining and its Applications to <ORGANIZATION>Intelligence CRM</ORGANIZATION> and Knowledge Management WIT Press Southampton 2007 Google Scholar 9 <PERSON>Bobbitt</PERSON> P The Shield of Achilles War Peace and the Course of History Knopf 2002 <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> Scholar 10 Zanasi A New forms of war new forms of Intelligence Text Mining In ITNS Conference Riyadh 2007 <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> Scholar 11 <PERSON>Steinberg</PERSON> J In Protecting the Homeland 2006 2007 The Brookings Institution 2006 <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> Scholar 12 Rheingold H The <ORGANIZATION>Virtual Community MIT Press Cambridge 2000 Google</ORGANIZATION> Scholar 13 Feldman S Insider Trading and More IDC Report Doc 28651 December 2002 Google Scholar 14 de Laat M Network and content analysis in an online community discourse <ORGANIZATION>University of Nijmegen 2002 Google</ORGANIZATION> Scholar 15 Benedetti A Il linguaggio delle nuove Brigate Rosse Erga Edizioni 2002 <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> Scholar 16 Zanasi A <ORGANIZATION>Competitive Intelligence Thru Data Mining Public Sources Competitive Intelligence Review</ORGANIZATION> vol 9 1 <PERSON>John Wiley</PERSON> amp <ORGANIZATION>Sons Inc</ORGANIZATION> Chichester 1998 Google Scholar 17 The Other War The Economist March 26 2003 <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> Scholar 18 <ORGANIZATION>Campbell D World</ORGANIZATION> under <ORGANIZATION>Watch Interception Capabilities</ORGANIZATION> in the 21st Century ZDNet co 2001 updated version of Interception Capabilities 2000 A report to European Parlement 1999 <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> Scholar 19 Zanasi A Email chatlines newsgroups a continuous opinion surveys source thanks to text mining In Excellence in Int l Research 2003 ESOMAR Nl 2003 <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> Scholar 20 <ORGANIZATION>Jones C W Online Impression Management University of California</ORGANIZATION> paper July 2005 <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> Scholar 21 Degenne A <ORGANIZATION>Forse M Introducing Social Networks Sage Publications</ORGANIZATION> <LOCATION>London</LOCATION> 1999 MATHGoogle Scholar Copyright information Springer Verlag <LOCATION>Berlin Heidelberg</LOCATION> 2009 Authors and Affiliations <PERSON>Alessandro Zanasi</PERSON> 1 1 <ORGANIZATION>ESRIF European Security Research and Innovation ForumUniversity of Bologna</ORGANIZATION> Professor <PERSON>Temis</PERSON> SA Cofounder About this paper Cite this paper as Zanasi A 2009 Virtual Weapons for Real Wars Text Mining for National Security In <PERSON>Corchado</PERSON> E <PERSON>Zunino</PERSON> R Gastaldo P <PERSON>Herrero</PERSON> eds Proceedings of the <ORGANIZATION>International Workshop on Computational Intelligence in Security for Information Systems CISIS</ORGANIZATION> 08 Advances in Soft Computing vol 53 <ORGANIZATION>Springer Berlin Heidelberg DOI</ORGANIZATION> https doi org 10 1007 978 3 540 88181 0_7 Publisher Name Springer <LOCATION>Berlin Heidelberg</LOCATION> Print ISBN 978 3 540 88180 3 Online ISBN 978 3 540 88181 0 eBook Packages Engineering About this book Reprints and Permissions Personalised recommendations Cite paper How to cite RIS Papers Reference Manager RefWorks Zotero ENW EndNote BIB BibTeX JabRef Mendeley Buy options Actions Log in to check access Buy eBook USD 249 00 Buy paper PDF USD 29 95 Instant download Readable on all devices Own it forever Local sales tax included if applicable Learn about institutional subscriptions Cite paper How to cite RIS Papers Reference Manager RefWorks Zotero ENW EndNote BIB BibTeX JabRef Mendeley Cookies We use cookies to improve your experience with our site More information Accept Over 10 million scientific documents at your fingertips Switch Edition Academic Edition Corporate Edition Home Impressum Legal information Accessibility Contact us <ORGANIZATION>Springer Nature 2017 Springer International Publishing AG</ORGANIZATION> Part of Springer Nature Not logged in Not affiliated 99 65 190 47</ner>
