<ner>Skip to main content We use cookies to improve your experience with our site Accept and close More info image Advertisement Thank you for visiting nature com You are using a browser version with limited support for CSS To obtain the best experience we recommend you use a more up to date browser or turn off compatibility mode in Internet Explorer In the meantime to ensure continued support we are displaying the site without styles and JavaScript nature com nature genetics news amp views article A Nature Research Journal Menu image Nature Genetics image Search E alert Submit My Account Login image Altmetric 3 Citations 22 More detail News amp Views Linking microarray data to the literature <PERSON>Daniel</PERSON> R Masys1 The availability in computerized form of the published literature on genes is a potentially rich source of information for the interpretation of microarray data Automated text processing confronts substantial challenges due to variability in the language used by authors but even incomplete linking of gene clusters to the literature can reveal functional information that is useful in explaining gene expression patterns Subscribe to <ORGANIZATION>Nature Genetics</ORGANIZATION> for full access 59 Subscribe Additional access options Already a subscriber Log in now or Register for online access Login via <ORGANIZATION>Athens Login</ORGANIZATION> via Shibboleth Use a document delivery service Purchase a site license References 1 <PERSON>Jenssen</PERSON> T K Laegrid A Komoroski J amp Hovig E Nature <PERSON>Genet</PERSON> 28 21 28 2001 <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> Scholar 2 Johnson S Preface to Dictionary of the English Language London 1775 <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> Scholar 3 <ORGANIZATION>Funk M E Reid C A amp McGoogar L S Bull Med Library Assoc</ORGANIZATION> 71 176 183 1983 <ORGANIZATION>CAS Google</ORGANIZATION> Scholar 4 Masys D R et al Bioinformatics 7 319 326 2001 Article Google Scholar Download references Author information <ORGANIZATION>Affiliations Uiversity of California San Diego School of Medicine La Jolla California USA dmasys ucsd edu Daniel R Masys Authors Search</ORGANIZATION> for <PERSON>Daniel R Masys</PERSON> in Nature Research journals PubMed <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> Scholar Rights and permissions To obtain permission to re use content from this article visit RightsLink Article Tools Tools Tools Print Share Twitter Facebook Article Information Journal Nature Genetics 28 9 10 2001 DOI doi 10 1038 ng0501 9 Citation Download Citation Published 01 May 2001 image Advertisement Menu Nature Genetics Current Issue Browse Issues News amp Comment Research Browse Articles Browse collections Focuses amp Supplements About the Journal For Authors For Referees Web Feeds Journals A Z Journals A Z <ORGANIZATION>Nature Nature Communications Nature Protocols Review</ORGANIZATION> journals Scientific Reports View all journals All Subjects All Subjects <ORGANIZATION>Biological Sciences Earth amp Environmental Sciences Health Sciences Physical Sciences Scientific Community amp Society View</ORGANIZATION> all subjects nature com nature com <ORGANIZATION>Subscriptions Authors amp Referees Librarians Advertisers Press</ORGANIZATION> About Search Search Nature com advanced Search Nature Genetics ISSN 1546 1718 online Issue Cover Image Ree Treweek Cover Design Ree Treweek and <PERSON>Erin Dewalt</PERSON> nature com sitemap For authors and referees Guide to Authors Guide to Referees Editorial policies Scientific editing Reprints amp permissions For readers Journals A Z Subject Pages Protocol Exchange Blogs Podcasts Webcasts Subscriptions Mobile apps RSS For librarians Account administration Site licenses Catalogs Print subscriptions Pay per view Open access Promotion tools Public interfaces User guides Library relations Publisher collaborations Careers and events Nature conferences Nature events Nature jobs com Regional websites Nature asia <ORGANIZATION>Nature China Nature India Nature Japan Nature Korea Nature Middle East Nature Research About us Work</ORGANIZATION> for us Help Contact us Privacy Policy Use of cookies Legal notice Accessibility statement <ORGANIZATION>Terms amp Conditions Partners For</ORGANIZATION> advertisers Advertising options <ORGANIZATION>Journal</ORGANIZATION> audience Event advertising Job posts Contact representative For press <ORGANIZATION>Press</ORGANIZATION> site Press room Contact press office image Springer Nature 2018 <ORGANIZATION>Macmillan Publishers Limited</ORGANIZATION> part of Springer Nature All rights reserved image image image</ner>
