<ner>Skip to main content We use cookies to improve your experience with our site Accept and close More info image Advertisement Thank you for visiting nature com You are using a browser version with limited support for CSS To obtain the best experience we recommend you use a more up to date browser or turn off compatibility mode in Internet Explorer In the meantime to ensure continued support we are displaying the site without styles and JavaScript nature com nature genetics articles article A Nature Research Journal Menu image Nature Genetics image Search E alert Submit My Account Login image Altmetric 6 Citations 515 More detail Article A literature network of human genes for high throughput analysis of gene expression Tor Kristian Jenssen1 Astrid L greid2 Jan Komorowski1 4 amp <ORGANIZATION>Eivind Hovig3 Nature Genetics</ORGANIZATION> volume 28 pages 21 28 2001 doi 10 1038 ng0501 21 <ORGANIZATION>Download Citation Received</ORGANIZATION> 05 July 2000 Accepted 26 March 2001 Published 01 May 2001 Abstract We have carried out automated extraction of explicit and implicit biomedical knowledge from publicly available gene and text databases to create a gene to gene co citation network for 13 712 named human genes by automated analysis of titles and abstracts in over 10 million <ORGANIZATION>MEDLINE</ORGANIZATION> records The associations between genes have been annotated by linking genes to terms from the medical subject heading MeSH index and terms from the gene ontology GO database The extracted database and accompanying web tools for gene expression analysis have collectively been named PubGene We validated the extracted networks by three large scale experiments showing that co occurrence reflects biologically meaningful relationships thus providing an approach to extract and structure known biology We validated the applicability of the tools by analyzing two publicly available microarray data sets Subscribe to Nature Genetics for full access 59 Subscribe Additional access options Already a subscriber Log in now or Register for online access Login via <ORGANIZATION>Athens Login</ORGANIZATION> via Shibboleth Use a document delivery service Purchase a site license References 1 Adams M D et al The genome sequence of Drosophila melanogaster Science 287 2185 2195 2000 PubMed Article Google Scholar 2 The C elegans Sequencing Consortium Genome sequence of the nematode C elegans a platform for investigating biology Science 282 2012 2018 1998 errata 283 35 1999 283 2103 1999 285 1493 1999 <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> Scholar 3 Goffeau A et al Life with 6000 genes Science 274 546 563 567 1996 Article Google Scholar 4 Ashburner M et al Gene ontology tool for the unification of biology The <ORGANIZATION>Gene Ontology Consortium Nature Genet</ORGANIZATION> 25 25 29 2000 <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> Scholar 5 <PERSON>Schena M Shalon D Davis R W amp Brown</PERSON> P O Quantitative monitoring of gene expression patterns with a complementary DNA microarray Science 270 467 470 1995 CAS PubMed Article Google Scholar 6 <PERSON>Eisen</PERSON> M B Spellman P T Brown P O amp <PERSON>Botstein</PERSON> D Cluster analysis and display of genome wide expression patterns <ORGANIZATION>Proc Natl Acad Sci USA</ORGANIZATION> 95 14863 14868 1998 CAS PubMed Article Google Scholar 7 Andrade M A amp <PERSON>Bork</PERSON> P Automated extraction of information in molecular biology FEBS Lett 476 12 17 2000 CAS PubMed Article Google Scholar 8 <PERSON>Blaschke</PERSON> C Andrade M A Ouzounis C amp Valencia A Automatic extraction of biological information from scientific text protein protein interactions in <ORGANIZATION>Intelligent Systems for Molecular Biology</ORGANIZATION> 60 67 <ORGANIZATION>AAAI Press Heidelberg</ORGANIZATION> 1999 Google Scholar 9 <PERSON>Thomas J Milward</PERSON> D Ouzounis C <PERSON>Pulman</PERSON> S amp <PERSON>Carroll</PERSON> M Automatic extraction of protein interactions from scientific abstracts Pac Symp Biocomput 5 541 552 2000 <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> Scholar 10 <PERSON>Humphreys K Demetriou</PERSON> G amp Gaizauskas R Two applications of information extraction to biological science journal articles enzyme interactions and protein structures Pac Symp Biocomput 5 505 516 2000 <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> Scholar 11 <ORGANIZATION>Sekimizu T Park H S</ORGANIZATION> amp Tsujii J Identifying the interaction between genes and gene products based on frequently seen verbs in <ORGANIZATION>Medline</ORGANIZATION> abstracts in <ORGANIZATION>Genome Informatics Workshop</ORGANIZATION> 62 71 <ORGANIZATION>Universal Academy Press</ORGANIZATION> Tokyo 1998 Google Scholar 12 Craven M amp Kumlien J Constructing biological knowledge bases by extracting information from text sources in Intelligent Systems for Molecular Biology 77 86 AAAI Press Heidelberg 1999 <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> Scholar 13 Rindflesch T C <PERSON>Rayan</PERSON> J V amp Hunter L Extracting molecular binding relationships from biomedical text in Applied Natural Language Processing and the <ORGANIZATION>North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics 188 195 Association for Computational Linguistics Seattle 2000 Google</ORGANIZATION> Scholar 14 <ORGANIZATION>Rindflesch T C Tanabe</ORGANIZATION> L <PERSON>Weinstein</PERSON> J N amp Hunter L EDGAR extraction of drugs genes and relations from the biomedical literature Pac Symp Biocomput 5 517 528 2000 <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> Scholar 15 Proux D Rechenmann F Julliard L <PERSON>Pillet</PERSON> V amp Jacq B Detecting gene symbols and names in biological texts A first step toward pertinent information extraction in <ORGANIZATION>Genome Informatics Workshop</ORGANIZATION> 72 80 <ORGANIZATION>Universal Academy Press</ORGANIZATION> Tokyo 1998 Google Scholar 16 <PERSON>Fukuda K Tsunoda T Tamura</PERSON> A amp <PERSON>Takagi</PERSON> T Toward information extraction identifying protein names from biological papers Pac Symp Biocomput 3 705 716 1998 <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> Scholar 17 Andrade M A amp <LOCATION>Valencia</LOCATION> A Automatic annotation for biological sequences by extraction of keywords from <ORGANIZATION>MEDLINE</ORGANIZATION> abstracts Development of a prototype system in <ORGANIZATION>Intelligent Systems for Molecular Biology</ORGANIZATION> 25 32 AAAI Press Halkidiki 1997 Google Scholar 18 <PERSON>Jenssen T K Komorowski</PERSON> J L greid A amp Hovig E Pubgen Discovering and visualising gene gene relations in Currents in <ORGANIZATION>Computational Molecular Biology</ORGANIZATION> eds Miyano S <PERSON>Shamir</PERSON> R amp <PERSON>Takagi</PERSON> T 48 49 <ORGANIZATION>Universal Academy Press Tokyo 2000 Google</ORGANIZATION> Scholar 19 Stapley B J amp <PERSON>Benoit G Biobibliometrics</PERSON> information retrieval and visualization from co occurrences of gene names in <ORGANIZATION>Medline</ORGANIZATION> abstracts Pac Symp Biocomput 5 529 540 2000 <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> Scholar 20 Shatkay H <PERSON>Edwards</PERSON> S <PERSON>Wilbur</PERSON> W amp <PERSON>Boguski</PERSON> M Genes themes and microarrays using information retrieval for large scale gene analysis in Intelligent Systems for Molecular Biology 317 328 <ORGANIZATION>AAAI Press San Diego 2000 Google</ORGANIZATION> Scholar 21 Alizadeh A A et al Distinct types of diffuse large B cell lymphoma identified by gene expression profiling Nature 403 503 511 2000 CAS PubMed Article Google Scholar 22 Iyer V R et al The transcriptional program in the response of human fibroblasts to serum Science 283 83 87 1999 <ORGANIZATION>CAS PubMed Article Google</ORGANIZATION> Scholar 23 Gu Y Shen Y Gibbs R A amp <PERSON>Nelson</PERSON> D L Identification of FMR2 a novel gene associated with the FRAXE <ORGANIZATION>CCG</ORGANIZATION> repeat and CpG island Nature Genet 13 109 113 1996 <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> Scholar 24 <ORGANIZATION>Jager U et al Follicular</ORGANIZATION> lymphomas BCL 2 IgH junctions contain templated nucleotide insertions novel insights into the mechanism of t 14 18 translocation Blood 95 3520 3529 2000 CAS PubMed <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> Scholar 25 <PERSON>Stamatopoulos</PERSON> K et al Molecular insights into the immunopathogenesis of follicular lymphoma Immunol Today 21 298 305 2000 CAS PubMed Article Google Scholar 26 Lossos I S et al Ongoing immunoglobulin somatic mutation in germinal center B cell like but not in activated B cell like diffuse large cell lymphomas <ORGANIZATION>Proc Natl Acad Sci USA</ORGANIZATION> 97 10209 10213 2000 CAS PubMed Article Google Scholar 27 Bravo R Growth factor responsive genes in fibroblasts Cell Growth Differ 1 305 309 1990 CAS PubMed <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> Scholar 28 <PERSON>Parsons Wingerter</PERSON> P <PERSON>Elliott K E Clark</PERSON> J I amp Farr A G Fibroblast growth factor 2 selectively stimulates angiogenesis of small vessels in arterial tree Arterioscler Thromb Vasc Biol 20 1250 1256 2000 CAS PubMed <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> Scholar 29 <PERSON>Aronson</PERSON> A R Rindflesch T C amp <PERSON>Browne</PERSON> A C Exploiting a large thesaurus for information retrieval in Proceedings of the 6th Applied Natural Language Processing Conference <ORGANIZATION>Rockefellar University Press New York</ORGANIZATION> 1994 Google Scholar 30 White J A et al Guidelines for human gene nomenclature Genomics 45 468 471 1997 CAS PubMed Article Google Scholar 31 <ORGANIZATION>Cormen T H Leiserson C E amp Rivest R L Introduction</ORGANIZATION> to Algorithms 1028 <ORGANIZATION>MIT Press Cambridge</ORGANIZATION> Massachusetts 1990 Google Scholar Download references Acknowledgements We thank the <ORGANIZATION>National Library of Medicine</ORGANIZATION> for access to <ORGANIZATION>MEDLINE</ORGANIZATION> D Tjeldvoll for help with installation and use of the Graphviz software and contributions to programming on early versions of the web interface H C <PERSON>Aasheim</PERSON> and <PERSON>Fodstad</PERSON> for discussions and S Bade W P <PERSON>Kuo S Vinterbo</PERSON> and D <PERSON>Warren</PERSON> for comments on the manuscript This work was supported in part by grants from the <ORGANIZATION>Norwegian Cancer Society T K J</ORGANIZATION> was supported by grant 134422 410 from the <ORGANIZATION>Norwegian Research Council</ORGANIZATION> Author information <ORGANIZATION>Affiliations Department of Computer and Information Science Norwegian University of Science and Technology Trondheim Norway</ORGANIZATION> <PERSON>Tor Kristian Jenssen</PERSON> amp <ORGANIZATION>Jan Komorowski Department of Physiology and Biomedical Engineering Norwegian University of Science and Technology Trondheim Norway Astrid L greid Department of Tumour Biology Institute for Cancer Research The Norwegian Radium Hospital Oslo Norway Eivind Hovig Department of Computer and Information Science Link ping University Sweden Jan Komorowski Authors Search</ORGANIZATION> for <PERSON>Tor Kristian Jenssen</PERSON> in <ORGANIZATION>Nature Research</ORGANIZATION> journals PubMed <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> Scholar Search for Astrid L greid in <ORGANIZATION>Nature Research</ORGANIZATION> journals PubMed <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> Scholar Search for <PERSON>Jan Komorowski</PERSON> in <ORGANIZATION>Nature Research</ORGANIZATION> journals PubMed <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> Scholar Search for <PERSON>Eivind Hovig</PERSON> in <ORGANIZATION>Nature Research</ORGANIZATION> journals PubMed <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> Scholar Corresponding author Correspondence to <PERSON>Eivind Hovig</PERSON> Supplementary information HTML files 1 Web Table A 2 Web Table B Videos 1 Web Movie A 2 Web Movie B 3 Web Movie C 4 Web Movie D Rights and permissions To obtain permission to re use content from this article visit RightsLink Article Tools Tools Tools Print Share Twitter Facebook image Advertisement Menu Nature Genetics Current Issue Browse Issues News amp Comment Research Browse Articles Browse collections Focuses amp Supplements About the Journal For Authors For Referees Web Feeds Journals A Z Journals A Z <ORGANIZATION>Nature Nature Communications Nature Protocols Review</ORGANIZATION> journals Scientific Reports View all journals All Subjects All Subjects <ORGANIZATION>Biological Sciences Earth amp Environmental Sciences Health Sciences Physical Sciences Scientific Community amp Society View</ORGANIZATION> all subjects nature com nature com <ORGANIZATION>Subscriptions Authors amp Referees Librarians Advertisers Press</ORGANIZATION> About Search Search Nature com advanced Search Nature Genetics ISSN 1546 1718 online Issue Cover Image Ree Treweek Cover Design Ree Treweek and <PERSON>Erin Dewalt</PERSON> nature com sitemap For authors and referees Guide to Authors Guide to Referees Editorial policies Scientific editing Reprints amp permissions For readers Journals A Z Subject Pages Protocol Exchange Blogs Podcasts Webcasts Subscriptions Mobile apps RSS For librarians Account administration Site licenses Catalogs Print subscriptions Pay per view Open access Promotion tools Public interfaces User guides Library relations Publisher collaborations Careers and events Nature conferences Nature events Nature jobs com Regional websites Nature asia <ORGANIZATION>Nature China Nature India Nature Japan Nature Korea Nature Middle East Nature Research About us Work</ORGANIZATION> for us Help Contact us Privacy Policy Use of cookies Legal notice Accessibility statement <ORGANIZATION>Terms amp Conditions Partners For</ORGANIZATION> advertisers Advertising options <ORGANIZATION>Journal</ORGANIZATION> audience Event advertising Job posts Contact representative For press <ORGANIZATION>Press</ORGANIZATION> site Press room Contact press office image Springer Nature 2018 <ORGANIZATION>Macmillan Publishers Limited</ORGANIZATION> part of Springer Nature All rights reserved image image image</ner>
