<ner>Skip to main content image <ORGANIZATION>European Commission</ORGANIZATION> logo image This site has been archived on 2015 01 01 01 01 15 Licences for <LOCATION>Europe</LOCATION> Structured stakeholder dialogue 2013 About this site Legal notice Navigation path <ORGANIZATION>European Commission Licences for Europe Home</ORGANIZATION> Working Groups Main working groups page <ORGANIZATION>Cross</ORGANIZATION> border Working group <ORGANIZATION>WG1 User Generated Content Working Group WG2 Audiovisual Heritage Working Group WG3 Text and Data Mining Working Group</ORGANIZATION> WG4 Participants 1st Plenary Mid term review Final Plenary Meeting image <ORGANIZATION>European Commission</ORGANIZATION> logo Licences for <LOCATION>Europe</LOCATION> Home Working Groups Main working groups page <ORGANIZATION>Cross</ORGANIZATION> border Working group <ORGANIZATION>WG1 User Generated Content Working Group WG2 Audiovisual Heritage Working Group WG3 Text and Data Mining Working Group</ORGANIZATION> WG4 Participants 1st Plenary Mid term review Final Plenary Meeting Latest Content 13 12 2013 gt Participants You will find below the lists of the organisations invited to participate in the work of the four Working Groups List of participants in workging 07 01 2014 gt Final Plenary Meeting The Communication on Content in the Digital Single Market 18 December 2012 announced a final plenary meeting to conclude the <ORGANIZATION>Licences for Europe</ORGANIZATION> 06 11 2013 gt WG2 Presentations 6th meeting 25 October OLA_general_forL4EWG2 pdfOS_IFRRO_IndustryInitiatives pdfPresentationGRust pdf 23 10 2013 gt WG4 Presentations 6th meeting 14 October Customer Industrial Chemist Perspective pdfPublishers Perspective Initiatives pdf 13 09 2014 gt WG1 Presentations 6th meeting 15 October Content Map pptFindAnyFilm ppt 08 07 2015 gt WG3 Presentations 6th meeting 20 September ACE discussion document pdfAGICOA pdfCopyswede pdfEBLIDA pdfIDA pdfSVT pdf About this site image image Online there are new ways of providing creating and distributing content and new ways to generate value The emergence of new business models that use the internet to deliver content represents both a challenge and an opportunity for the creative industries authors and artists The digital economy has been a major driver of growth in the past two decades and is expected to grow seven times faster than overall <ORGANIZATION>EU</ORGANIZATION> GDP in coming years The aim of the <ORGANIZATION>European Commission</ORGANIZATION> is to ensure that copyright and licensing stay fit for purpose in this new digital context As announced in the Communication on Content in the Digital Single Market 18 December 2012 Licences for <LOCATION>Europe</LOCATION> is an initiative jointly led by <ORGANIZATION>Commissioners Michel Barnier Internal Market and Services Neelie Kroes Digital Agenda</ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION>Androulla Vassiliou Education Culture Multilingualism</ORGANIZATION> and Youth Its main purpose is to seek to deliver rapid progress in bringing content online through practical industry led solutions Tags copyright stakeholder dialogue Contribute and debate Cross border access and portability of services User generated content and licensing Audiovisual sector and cultural heritage Text and data minig Check the participants in the working groups Last update 21 07 2015 Top</ner>
