<ner>Skip to main content Toggle navigation <PERSON>Miriam Posner</PERSON> s Blog About <ORGANIZATION>Miriam CV Projects Workshops</ORGANIZATION> and Speaking How did they make that August 29 2013February 1 2014 <ORGANIZATION>Miriam Digital Humanities Cross</ORGANIZATION> posted on <ORGANIZATION>UCLA</ORGANIZATION> s DH Bootcamp blog Edit Dot <PERSON>Porter</PERSON> made a <LOCATION>Zotero</LOCATION> collection for this post Thanks Dot Many students tell me that in order to get started with digital humanities they d like to have some idea of what they might do and what technical skills they might need in order to do it Here s a set of digital humanities projects that might help you to get a handle on the kinds of tools and technologies available for you to use I ve tried to include a few different types of projects but it s hard to provide a really representative list If you d like to see more digital humanities projects you can find directories at art humanities net and DHCommons Here I discuss a gallery of primary sources a digital scholarly edition a mapping project a network visualization computer aided text analysis a historical 3D model a longform media rich narrative bookmark gallery A Gallery of Primary Sources Making the History of 1989 image Screen Shot 2014 01 04 at 8 38 55 PM What it is A collection of primary sources related to the fall of Communism in <LOCATION>Eastern Europe</LOCATION> accompanied by teaching materials and interpretive essays What you d need to know Omeka org which forms the basis of the site or you could use Omeka net if you aren t so picky about the way the site looks and acts HTML and <ORGANIZATION>CSS</ORGANIZATION> optional to customize the way the site looks <ORGANIZATION>PHP</ORGANIZATION> optional to customize certain site functions like the way items display Get started Up and Running with <ORGANIZATION>Omeka</ORGANIZATION> net Up and Running with HTML Introducing <ORGANIZATION>PHP</ORGANIZATION> bookmark edition A Digital Scholarly Edition The Willa Cather Archive image Screen Shot 2014 01 04 at 8 41 10 PM What it is A carefully edited digital archive of the writings of <PERSON>Willa Cather</PERSON> along with extensive scholarly essays analysis and multimedia galleries What you d need to know TEI the markup language designed for scholarly editing XSLT or an XML publication system Get started TEI by Example bookmark map A Mapping Project The Negro Travelers Green Book image Screen Shot 2014 01 04 at 8 42 35 PM What it is A searchable map of the addresses contained in the 1956 Negro Travelers Green Book which the user can filter by state or establishment type What you d need to know Google Fusion Tables Google Maps Some JavaScript to get the map to display properly Alternatives There are almost too many mapping technologies to list but some popular tools include Neatline which you d use together with <PERSON>Omeka GeoCommons</PERSON> a relatively simple mapping application and ArcGIS used for complex or large scale mapping projects If you re serious about learning to build dynamic web based maps you d be wise to learn the client side language JavaScript to control the way things show up on browsers a server side language like <ORGANIZATION>PHP</ORGANIZATION> to interact with data and the database language SQL to manage your geospatial data More mapping tools Get started Learn how to clean and map data using <ORGANIZATION>Google Maps</ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION>Google Fusion Tables</ORGANIZATION> bookmark network A <ORGANIZATION>Network Visualization A Co Citation Network</ORGANIZATION> for Philosophy image philcites static What it is A visualization of the authors referenced together in a corpus of philosophy journals What you d need to know D3 js a JavaScript library for producing visualizations on the web The programming language Python for manipulating your data A dataset This one came from the Web of Science which allows you to download citation data for academic articles Alternatives You can make network visualizations without necessarily coding by using the web based ManyEyes or the free Gephi or Cytoscape Other tools for data visualization Get started Use Cytoscape to make a simple network visualization Learn to use Python Demystifying networks bookmark text <ORGANIZATION>Computer Aided Text Analysis Topic Modeling Martha Ballard</ORGANIZATION> s Diary image coldweatherbymonth What it is An analysis of a historical document that uses a statistical method called topic modeling to group together the topics found in a large set of texts What you d need to know MALLET a Java based software package for text analysis including topic modeling R a programming language for statistical analysis and graphics Alternatives The Topic Modeling Tool provides a simpler to use graphical user interface for topic modeling as does Paper Machines which produces topic models from your Zotero library But topic modeling is just one kind of textual analysis Find a rundown of different kinds of text analysis here Often people who are new to text analysis enjoy starting with the web based <ORGANIZATION>Voyant Tools</ORGANIZATION> I also like the Lexos suite More tools for text analysis Get started Very basic strategies for interpreting results from the Topic Modeling Tool Special issue of the <ORGANIZATION>Journal of Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> on topic modeling bookmark 3d A Historical 3D Model Digital Magnesia image tumblr_majyquyyAN1rtd5e2 What it is A painstakingly researched re creation of the Hellenistic city of Magnesia What you d need to know This particular model is created using the procedural modeler CityEngine Alternatives The easiest way to create 3D models is probably with SketchUp Serious 3D modelers often use Maya or Rhino Get started Intro to 3D modeling bookmark narrative A Longform Media Rich Narrative The Nicest Kids in Town image Screen Shot 2014 01 04 at 8 47 23 PM What it is An essay accompanied by photographs video and sound that can be reconfigured by the viewer to be read in multiple ways What you d have to know <PERSON>Scalar</PERSON> a multimedia authoring platform <ORGANIZATION>CSS</ORGANIZATION> optional to add custom styling to Scalar Get started Scalar webinars August 30 <ORGANIZATION>Post</ORGANIZATION> edited to reflect that you don t need Python to download Web of Science data Thanks for the correction <PERSON>Scott Weingart</PERSON> 3D computer graphics 3D computer graphics software Cytoscape digital humanities Geographic information system getting started Topic model topic modeling 75 thoughts to How did they make that Comment navigation Older Comments Pingback 3D Mapping UMass Honors 391 <ORGANIZATION>Pingback A Digital N Ethnographic Journey</ORGANIZATION> through the Roots and Routes of <ORGANIZATION>Boylesque Digital Methods Pingback A Digital N Ethnographic Journey</ORGANIZATION> through the Roots and Routes of Boylesque The Roots and Routes of <PERSON>Boylesque Pingback How</PERSON> did you make that digital literary geography <PERSON>David Joseph Wrisley Pingback Lab</PERSON> 5 <PERSON>Jane Wagar Pingback</PERSON> HST251 PROJECT REVIEW II laurensiyulu Pingback CFP How Did They Make That dh lib <PERSON>Pingback</PERSON> recent beginners resources for dh The Linked Librarian Pingback Week 3 Feb 22 Let s all get it done together <ORGANIZATION>ITP Core</ORGANIZATION> 2 Spring 2016 Pingback A Real DH Project Example and a few extra thoughts on the matter Hype from <LOCATION>Abby Pingback</LOCATION> September 3 Freaks On the Fringe Pingback Digital Projects An Intro to the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities Pingback</ORGANIZATION> C mo lo hicieron <PERSON>Silvia Guti</PERSON> rrez Pingback Syllabus The Humanist in the <ORGANIZATION>Computer Digital Humanities and Social Justice</ORGANIZATION> COLT 18 02 Dr <ORGANIZATION>Kirstyn Leuner Postdoctoral Fellow Dartmouth College Pingback Project Profile Mean Green Mapped Digital Humanities Pingback Project Profile Organs of the Soul Digital Humanities Pingback Project Profile 3DHOTBED Digital Humanities Pingback Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> A Starting Point ArLiSNAP Pingback Project Profile The <ORGANIZATION>Queer Zine Archive Project Digital Humanities Pingback Mighty Mitch Pingback Tip How</ORGANIZATION> did they make that Pingback How Did They Make That Pingback How Did They Make That image 3dpraxisstudio com says January 26 2018 at 2 46 am Very nice article Yeah I will try to make my websites to run good on mobile devices Thanks for the share image BuckChief says April 20 2018 at 10 03 am I have checked your site and i ve found some duplicate content that s why you don t rank high in google but there is a tool that can help you to create 100 unique articles search for boorfe s tips unlimited content Comment navigation Older Comments Leave a Reply Cancel reply Your email address will not be published Comment Name Email Website Post navigation Using Mozilla Popcorn Maker to Create an Interactive Video A dead simple weekly email A little workflow for bringing people together About me My name is <PERSON>Miriam Posner</PERSON> and I m an assistant professor of information studies and digital humanities at the <ORGANIZATION>University of California Los Angeles</ORGANIZATION> You can read more about me here Meet with me <ORGANIZATION>UCLA</ORGANIZATION> people are welcome to book a meeting with me by grabbing a time here Search for Course Sites DH101 Introduction to <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities DH150 Digital Labor</ORGANIZATION> and Materiality DH150 Selfies Snapchat and Cyberbullies Coming of Age Online IS270 Systems and Infrastructures IS289 Museums in the Digital Age Workshops amp Tutorials Getting Started with <ORGANIZATION>Palladio Google</ORGANIZATION> Fusion Table Basics Download journals in bulk with wget Working with <ORGANIZATION>Medical Images Network Analysis</ORGANIZATION> with Cytoscape My highly opinionated guide to DH tools amp tutorials Travel amp Talks May 9 10 Archivists and Librarians in the History of the <ORGANIZATION>Health Sciences Los Angeles</ORGANIZATION> May 14 15 <ORGANIZATION>University of Wisconsin Green Bay</ORGANIZATION> June 26 29 <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities 2018 Mexico City Archives</ORGANIZATION> April 2018 December 2017 November 2017 July 2017 July 2016 June 2016 April 2016 March 2016 December 2015 October 2015 September 2015 August 2015 July 2015 June 2015 May 2015 April 2015 January 2015 December 2014 November 2014 October 2014 September 2014 April 2014 March 2014 January 2014 December 2013 November 2013 August 2013 April 2013 March 2013 February 2013 January 2013 November 2012 October 2012 September 2012 August 2012 July 2012 May 2012 March 2012 February 2012 January 2012 December 2011 November 2011 October 2011 September 2011 August 2011 July 2011 May 2011 April 2011 March 2011 February 2011 January 2011 November 2010 August 2010 July 2010 May 2010 February 2010 January 2010 December 2009 November 2009 September 2009 July 2009 June 2009 May 2009 April 2009 March 2009 Subscribe to this blog via <ORGANIZATION>RSS Reading Lists Capitalism and American Culture Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION>Library Early American Silent Film Labor</ORGANIZATION> and Materiality in the Digital Age Major Theories of <ORGANIZATION>Spectatorship Medicine and Visual Culture Psychiatry Photography</ORGANIZATION> and Lobotomy A Bibliography Workshops and Speaking sparkling Theme by Colorlib Powered by WordPress</ner>
