<ner>The following is the full text of an essay published in differences 25 1 2014 as part of a special issue entitled In the Shadows of the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> edited by <PERSON>Ellen Rooney</PERSON> and <PERSON>Elizabeth Weed Duke</PERSON> UP s publishing agreements allow authors to post the final version of their own work but not using the publisher s PDF The essay as you see it here is thus a PDF that I created and formatted myself from the copy edited file I received from the press subscribers of course can also read it in the press s published form direct from the Duke UP site Other than accidentals of formatting and pagination this text should not differ from the published one in any way If there are discrepancies they are likely the result of final copy edits just before printing I d appreciate having them pointed out These and other comments can be sent to mgk umd edu This article is copyright 2014 Duke University Press What Is <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> and Why Are They Saying Such Terrible Things about It <ORGANIZATION>Matthew Kirschenbaum University of Maryland</ORGANIZATION> I In the midst of the 2009 MLA Convention Chronicle of Higher Education blogger <PERSON>William Pannapacker</PERSON> wrote Amid all the doom and gloom one field seems to be alive and well the digital humanities More than that Among all the contending subfields the digital humanities seem like the first next big thing in a long time because the implications of digital technology affect every field Two years later <PERSON>Pannapacker</PERSON> titled his <ORGANIZATION>MLA Chronicle</ORGANIZATION> column with the seemingly unnecessary interrogative Digital Humanities Triumphant But would that more in life were so predictable as an academic dialectic in 2013 Pannapacker s by now anticipated convention <ORGANIZATION>Kirschenbaum What is Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> and Why Are They Saying Such Terrible Things about It differences 25 1 2014 46 63 Copyright 2014 <ORGANIZATION>Duke University Press</ORGANIZATION> 2 coverage centered on The Dark Side of the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> the special session event from which this journal issue is derived I was not a participant on the panel but I was in the crowded ballroom at the <ORGANIZATION>Boston Sheraton</ORGANIZATION> The mood beforehand was festive not contentious Everyone was expecting a good show from the A list speakers assembled From somewhere up front the strains of the Star Wars Imperial March made tinny by a laptop speaker were accompanied by scattered laughter Nonetheless the issues raised and the charges leveled were of the most serious order <PERSON>Richard Grusin</PERSON> who had convened the session built toward an arresting summation I would assert that it is no coincidence that the digital humanities has emerged as the next big thing at the same moment that the neoliberalization and corporatization of higher education has intensified in the first decades of the twenty first century This short essay is not intended as a defense of digital humanities not least because I don t think I disagree with <PERSON>Grusin</PERSON> at least insofar as his articulation of the institutional environment that surrounds digital humanities is concerned I work in a university too I have eyes I have ears Yet next big thing or no when it comes to digital humanities we are still only ever talking about someone s or several someones work the errors and limitations of which whatever they may be in their particulars should require no special forum or occasion for airing So let me say it at the outset everything produced by digital humanities and I do mean every thing every written scripted coded or fabricated thing in whatever its guise or form medium or format may be subject to criticism and critique on the basis of its methods assumptions expressions and outcomes All of that is completely normative and part of the routine conduct of academic disciplines Yet in the last couple of years events that are not normative or routine have occurred and it is those events that we are addressing with this special journal issue and that were addressed at the <ORGANIZATION>MLA</ORGANIZATION> special session These events I would maintain concern not the papers projects and other material pursuits of digital humanities not the things of the digital humanities but rather the advent of a construct of a digital humanities Lest anyone think I am beginning with a semantic slip slide what I have just asserted is not only uncontroversial it is also unoriginal echoing as it does statements by the <ORGANIZATION>MLA</ORGANIZATION> session s invited participants <PERSON>Wendy Chun</PERSON> for example insisted But let me be clear my critique is not directed at DH per se DH projects have extended and renewed the humanities and revealed that the kinds of critical thinking close textual analysis that the humanities have <PERSON>Kirschenbaum</PERSON> What is <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> and Why Are They Saying Such Terrible Things about It differences 25 1 2014 46 63 Copyright 2014 <ORGANIZATION>Duke University Press</ORGANIZATION> 3 always been engaged in is and has always been central to crafting technology and society emphasis in original By this account then DH projects have extended and renewed the humanities and have also helped historicize its activities in ways <PERSON>Chun</PERSON> finds salutary <PERSON>Rita Raley</PERSON> meanwhile commenting afterward on the response to the session which unfolded in real time on Twitter is even more direct noting T hough our roundtable referred in passing to actually existing projects collectives and games that we take to be affirmative and inspiring the digital humanities under analysis was a discursive construction and I should add clearly noted as such throughout my emphasis Whatever else we are talking about in this special issue then whatever else the <ORGANIZATION>MLA</ORGANIZATION> session was addressing itself to and whatever else I am engaging in my contribution here it is not the material conduct of digital humanities or if you prefer actually existing projects an especially clarifying phrase to keep in mind It is instead and still in <PERSON>Raley</PERSON> s terms a discursive construction I have written about the existence of such a construct before in two previous essays to which this I suppose contributes a third and final entry in an unanticipated trilogy The first and most widely circulated of these What Is <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> and What s It Doing in English Departments began as an assignment for a 2010 <ORGANIZATION>Association of Departments</ORGANIZATION> of English meeting hence the specificity of its address I opened it by enjoining anyone truly interested in the first half of the titular question to <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> it or perhaps consult <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> At the time I was merely acting out my impatience since whatever else one could say about digital humanities there had been no shortage of writing seeking to define it and so as I put it then Whoever asks the question has not gone looking very hard for an answer But my real point wasn t that <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> or <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> were the de facto authorities but rather that they offered convenient portals to layers of consensus that are shaped over time by a community of interested persons In other words digital humanities was a construct and the state of the construct could be more or less effectively monitored by checking in on its self representations in aggregate The remainder of the piece did some historical spadework excavating the actual origin of the term digital humanities and explaining why I thought English departments had again historically been especially hospitable to its emergence But while the essay historicizes and characterizes DH at no time does it actively define it instead in retrospect here is what I see as its most clearly spoken moment <ORGANIZATION>Digital</ORGANIZATION> humanities has also I would propose lately been galvanized by a group of younger or not so young graduate students faculty members both tenure line and <PERSON>Kirschenbaum</PERSON> What is <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> and Why Are They Saying Such Terrible Things about It differences 25 1 2014 46 63 Copyright 2014 <ORGANIZATION>Duke University Press</ORGANIZATION> 4 contingent and other academic professionals who now wield the label digital humanities instrumentally amid an increasingly monstrous institutional terrain defined by declining public support for higher education rising tuitions shrinking endowments the proliferation of distance education and the for profit university and underlying it all the conversion of full time tenure track academic labor to a part time adjunct workforce I don t see this description of what I term a monstrous institutional terrain differing substantially from <PERSON>Grusin</PERSON> s view of where we are in the academy today For several years thereafter whenever asked to define digital humanities my response was thus to say a term of tactical convenience The contention that DH was usefully understood as a tactical term then became the subject of the second of these two essays a contention necessary in order to as I next wrote insist on the reality of circumstances in which it digital humanities is unabashedly deployed to get things done things that might include getting a faculty line or funding a staff position establishing a curriculum revamping a lab or launching a center Digital 415 That second piece does some further historical work examining in detail one such tactical deployment of DH at one specific institution and also in a separate section attempting to delineate how DH as a signifier was increasingly operationalized algorithmically on the network actively mobilized via hashtags and metadata This essay has been criticized by <PERSON>Brian Lennon</PERSON> on the grounds that tactical if read to follow de Certeau s usage invokes an outsider position that DH can no longer or indeed ever claim the luxury of inhabiting that DH is rather a strategic formation complicit with the state or at the very least complicit with the aims of conniving deans and administrators and foundation officers who are actively seeking to dismantle the bare ruined choirs of the professoriate As I previously responded F or those of us who have built centers programs curricula what have you one proposal one hire one lecture series one grant one server one basement room at a time the institutional interiority and strategic complicity of digital humanities seems perhaps equally unpersuasive Comment Be that as it may Why write a third piece on the topic While questions about digital humanities did not originate with the 2013 MLA that moment does seem to me to mark the onset of an increasingly aggressive challenge that deserves recognition and response Some elements of that challenge like the <ORGANIZATION>MLA</ORGANIZATION> session or this journal issue assume <ORGANIZATION>Kirschenbaum What is Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> and Why Are They Saying Such Terrible Things about It differences 25 1 2014 46 63 Copyright 2014 <ORGANIZATION>Duke University Press</ORGANIZATION> 5 conventional shapes and forms that will be familiar to the uninitiated and easily processed Others like blog entries perhaps with comments appended are also increasingly accepted as part of the space of our conversations a grey literature that requires only a link passed in an email or on <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> to access and assimilate Yet other maneuvers have unfolded in more hermetic environments largely inaccessible to outsiders defined especially by Twitter but more specifically by the interaction between Twitter and other online services including <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> and blogs the result being a complex always evolving ecology that rewards the 24 7 attention cycle This particular discourse network is characterized by subtle layers of indirection and innuendo sometimes called subtweets for subliminal tweets i e oblique commentaries in which particular individuals may or may not recognize themselves a kind of social steganography danah boyd s term whose stratifications render individual agendas transparent to the initiated and opaque to the neophyte While no one can be plugged in all the time for a number of the contributors to this issue these discussions form a normative part of their routines an extension or facet of their critical engagement over the course of a day as the feed refreshes and the notifications chime I pause for these details because online speech denaturalizes the register of the discourse here and I lay emphasis on them to break down the dualism between the landscape of social media and traditional venues of professional record like a <ORGANIZATION>Duke University Press</ORGANIZATION> journal If you follow the right Twitter accounts then if you read the right blogs if you re on the right lists and if you re included in the right backchannels if you do these things you ll be within your rights to wonder all over again what digital humanities is anyway and why on earth anyone would want it in their English or any other department Herewith then are some of the terrible things of my title hardly any of which are exaggerated for effect <ORGANIZATION>Digital</ORGANIZATION> humanities is a nest of big data ideologues <ORGANIZATION>Digital</ORGANIZATION> humanities digs <ORGANIZATION>MOOCs Digital</ORGANIZATION> humanities is an artifact of the post 9 11 security and surveillance state the <ORGANIZATION>NSA</ORGANIZATION> of the MLA Like <PERSON>Johnny</PERSON> digital humanities can t read <ORGANIZATION>Digital</ORGANIZATION> humanities doesn t do theory <ORGANIZATION>Digital</ORGANIZATION> humanities never historicizes <ORGANIZATION>Digital</ORGANIZATION> humanities is complicit <ORGANIZATION>Digital</ORGANIZATION> humanities is naive <ORGANIZATION>Digital</ORGANIZATION> humanities is hollow huckster boosterism <ORGANIZATION>Digital</ORGANIZATION> humanities is managerial <ORGANIZATION>Digital</ORGANIZATION> humanities is the academic import of <LOCATION>Silicon Valley</LOCATION> solutionism the term that is the shibboleth of bad boy tech critic <PERSON>Evgeny Morozov</PERSON> <ORGANIZATION>Digital</ORGANIZATION> humanities cannot abide critique <ORGANIZATION>Digital</ORGANIZATION> humanities appeals to those in search of an oasis from the concerns of race <PERSON>Kirschenbaum</PERSON> What is <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> and Why Are They Saying Such Terrible Things about It differences 25 1 2014 46 63 Copyright 2014 <ORGANIZATION>Duke University Press</ORGANIZATION> 6 class gender and sexuality <ORGANIZATION>Digital</ORGANIZATION> humanities does not inhale easily the best line of the bunch <ORGANIZATION>Digital</ORGANIZATION> humanities wears <ORGANIZATION>Google Glass Digital</ORGANIZATION> humanities wears thick thick glasses guilty Perhaps most damning of all digital humanities is something separate from the rest of the humanities and this is the real secret digital humanities wants it that way 1 Terrible things indeed these are But while terrible can mean repugnant the etymology of the word Greek tre in to tremble also encompasses that which is terrific by which we can mean possessed of great intensity see also contemporary French usage It is not then so inappropriate to be saying terrible things about digital humanities at this particular moment a moment when the institutions we inhabit are indeed at the epicenter of seismic shifts in attitude means and mission But we should be clear about exactly what it is we are addressing with these terrible allegations we are almost always addressing and investing a construct a construct that is variously journalistic note the straight line from <PERSON>Grusin</PERSON> s <ORGANIZATION>MLA</ORGANIZATION> comments to Pannapacker administrative algorithmic and opportunistic for which one might read yes tactical Collectively and above all else it is discursive as <PERSON>Raley</PERSON> so astutely noted The very orthographic contours of digital humanities have been subject to unprecedented scrutiny not long ago <PERSON>William Germano</PERSON> now <ORGANIZATION>Dean of Humanities and Social Sciences</ORGANIZATION> at <ORGANIZATION>Cooper Union</ORGANIZATION> pronounced upon t he spectacular rise of DH as the most powerful digraph in the non STEM academy It is appropriate that <PERSON>Germano</PERSON> editor in chief for twenty years at <ORGANIZATION>Columbia University Press</ORGANIZATION> prior to his <ORGANIZATION>Cooper Union</ORGANIZATION> appointment selects exactly the right term of art here The digraph DH variously also dh DH D_H dh as well as transformdh and dhpoco is especially conspicuous on Twitter where it functions not only as economical shorthand but also as I have noted previously as a hashtag metadata to be operationalized through search engines aggregators and notification services The orthographic and very often orthogonal tensions around digital humanities is it the digital humanities or just digital humanities is it capitalized or not capitalized are further emblematic in this regard The agon par excellence of the construct is of course the question of definition what is digital humanities The insistence on the question is what allows the construct to do its work to function as a space of contest for competing agendas But more importantly and this is precisely where the logic of the construct most readily reveals itself there is no actual shortage of definitions of digital humanities They are by contrast always latent and very often explicit in every curriculum and program proposal every search Kirschenbaum What is <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> and Why Are They Saying Such Terrible Things about It differences 25 1 2014 46 63 Copyright 2014 <ORGANIZATION>Duke University Press</ORGANIZATION> 7 committee charge and hiring brief every grant application and book project that sees fit to invoke the term The definitions may not align indeed they may at times prove inimical to one another But variegation is not the same as absence or ineffability and so we may conclude that the continued insistence on definition is precisely what allows the construct to function as a self evident given perpetuating itself through brute repetition and the proliferation of localized sometimes media specific digraphic focalizers You may recall that the Construct was also the name given to the self contained emulation of the Matrix in the <ORGANIZATION>Wachowskis</ORGANIZATION> films the dojo where Neo spars with Morpheus to hone his <LOCATION>Kung Fu</LOCATION> technique The construct in this sense is overtly a place of ritualized and dematerialized contest This is not incidental to the sense in which I use it here literalizing the meaning of the term beyond I am sure <PERSON>Raley</PERSON> s intentions In the construct the habitus of social media disrupts the traditional comity of academic exchange Just as Neo learns to bend hack the physics of his programmed reality here one bends collegial niceties in competition for hits retweets likes and replies the very stuff the Fu in Internet parlance of such odious reputation trackers as Klout Indeed we know that when this journal issue is published its availability will be widely tweeted Brief excerpts from the essays 140 characters remember will circulate on Twitter Blog posts characterizing or responding to the essays at greater length will appear the essays themselves may be uploaded to personal sites or institutional repositories by their authors The authors and others will engage one another in the tweets and blog comments All of this will happen over a course of days weeks and months While the records of those responses will linger thereafter on the Web they will be mute remainders mere husks of the frisson the serotonin and caffeine fueled jags that propel real time online exchange Only much more slowly will these essays pass into the collected professional literature where they will be indexed quoted and referenced in the usual way This issue on the dark side of the digital humanities is itself an artifact an issue of the construct and will serve to sustain it not least through again the cascade of agonistic reductionism that will inevitably characterize those engaging it through channels of metrical that is reputation based circulation on social media Metrical and often brutal Brutalism or what some have dubbed the rhetoric of contempt like ex cathedra pronouncement and aphorism is a recognized online interactive mode and the take down is its consummate expression as genre and form Such is in fact the signature style of <PERSON>Evgeny Morozov</PERSON> the caustic technology critic whose first book was titled The Net Kirschenbaum What is <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> and Why Are They Saying Such Terrible Things about It differences 25 1 2014 46 63 Copyright 2014 <ORGANIZATION>Duke University Press</ORGANIZATION> 8 Delusion The Dark Side of Internet Freedom 2011 <PERSON>Morozov</PERSON> as much as the dark sides of Star Wars or <PERSON>Pink Floyd</PERSON> furnishes the referential framing for the current debate He enters the scene as one of the most visible and vociferous critics of <LOCATION>Silicon Valley</LOCATION> and indeed the Internet a macroconstruct whose artifice he emphasizes by insisting on its embrace with quotation marks The critique honed on the whetstone of personal contact and up close immersion in the day to day doings of the technoratti see for example his 15 000 words on <PERSON>Tim O Reilly</PERSON> in The Baffler is aimed at technological essentialism and technological determinism and above all idealism what <PERSON>Morozov</PERSON> brands solutionism which his second book To Save Everything Click Here effectively demolishes As a break out public intellectual <PERSON>Morozov</PERSON> is in his element online cultivating an uncompromising acerbic persona his Twitter bio reads simply There are idiots Look around The transposition to digital humanities by some of his followers was predictable DHers are themselves solutionists pretenders who arrive to fix the ills of the present day academy with tools apps and the rhetorical equivalent of TED talks all driven by a naive and duplicitous agenda that has its roots if not yet in an IPO then in the academic currency of jobs funding and tenure But this is poor critique and worse history suggesting as it does that the differences between venture capital and public institutions are quite literally immaterial <ORGANIZATION>Digital</ORGANIZATION> humanities in the <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> at least has its beginnings not in <LOCATION>California</LOCATION> and not for the most part on the Ivy campuses but instead in mostly eastern land grant institutions When a full documentary and archivally sound history of digital humanities is written it will have to take into account the idiosyncrasies of this particular class of institution and these will I think reveal a very different set of contexts than <LOCATION>Silicon Valley</LOCATION> s orchards lofts and technology parks Charges of brutalism and lack of civility are de facto subject to infinite regress for the very charges become the object of brutal ridicule and the cycle perpetuates But at some level it should be uncontroversial to observe that many of the terrible things uttered about digital humanities as a construct simply lack an elemental generosity as if there were no critical let alone ethical distinctions obtainable between data mining a corpus of nineteenth century fiction and data mining your telephone calling records as if those who do DH haven t been educated in the same critical traditions indeed sometimes in the same graduate programs as their opponents as if those who do DH aren t also politically committed and politically engaged and as if they don t as a result typically find <PERSON>Morozov</PERSON> himself both amusing and smart and profoundly uncontroversial And you will not convince me otherwise here I unapologetically rely on my own stores of anecdote and <PERSON>Kirschenbaum</PERSON> What is <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> and Why Are They Saying Such Terrible Things about It differences 25 1 2014 46 63 Copyright 2014 <ORGANIZATION>Duke University Press</ORGANIZATION> 9 personal interaction on conversations and relationships that go back in some cases decades to make these determinations To indulge digital humanities only ever as a construct and a site of contest is also thus to give in to a world view that seems to me precisely neoliberal precisely zero sum and agonistic disembodied desocialized and evacuated of materiality or material history II I am finishing this essay in the weeks immediately following the conclusion of the Digital Humanities 2013 conference held in <LOCATION>Lincoln Nebraska</LOCATION> DH13 was this year s conference of record for the <ORGANIZATION>Alliance of Digital Humanities Organizations ADHO</ORGANIZATION> first formed in 2005 as an administrative entity shared by two scholarly associations the predominantly <ORGANIZATION>North American Association for Computing and the Humanities</ORGANIZATION> and the predominantly <ORGANIZATION>European Association for Literary and Linguistic Computing</ORGANIZATION> which have themselves been holding joint conferences since 1989 and individually since the early 1970s Today ADHO encompasses six constituent organizations also including the <ORGANIZATION>Canadian Society for Digital Humanities Soci</ORGANIZATION> t pour l tude des m dias interactifs SDH SEMI now SDH SCHN the <ORGANIZATION>Australasian Association for Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> aaDH centerNet An <ORGANIZATION>International Network of Digital Humanities Centers</ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION>Japanese Association for Digital Humanities JADH</ORGANIZATION> I mention these particulars to place two sets of facts before us one that digital humanities even in its current configuration what <PERSON>Steve Ramsay</PERSON> has dubbed DH Type 2 has a history going back nearly a decade and as humanities computing much longer than that and two that digital humanities has become thoroughly internationalized Indeed an attendee at the 2013 conference might have heard papers such as Uncovering the <ORGANIZATION>Hidden Histories of Computing</ORGANIZATION> in the Humanities 1949 1980 Findings and Reflections on the Pilot Project or Authorship Problem s of Japanese Early Modern Literatures in Seventeenth Century Or else papers like Are <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> s Linguistic Prosthesis Biased toward Commercially More Interesting Expressions A Preliminary Study on the Linguistic Effects of Autocompletion Algorithms or The Digitized Divide Mapping Access to Subscription Based Digitized Resources or Against the Binary of Gender A Case for Considering the Many Dimensions of Gender in DH Teaching and Research While the conference is heavily attended by humanities faculty and graduate students it also includes significant representation from information studies <ORGANIZATION>Kirschenbaum What is Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> and Why Are They Saying Such Terrible Things about It differences 25 1 2014 46 63 Copyright 2014 <ORGANIZATION>Duke University Press</ORGANIZATION> 10 computer science and library and archives professionals as well as the so called alt ac space Consequently critical methods assumptions and discourse networks do not always align even within the same panel for every scrupulously written and carefully read paper citing <PERSON>Judith Butler</PERSON> or <PERSON>Bruno Latour</PERSON> there were slide decks with data sets graphs and bullet points If definition is the first great agon of the construct inclusion and extent who s in who s out is the second The stakes are obvious when a federal funding agency flies the flag of the digital humanities one is incentivized to brand their work as digital humanities When an R1 does a cluster hire in digital humanities one is incentivized to be on the market as a digital humanist When a digital humanities center has institutional resources one is incentivized to seek to claim them by doing DH None of this is disingenuous or cynical nor can anyone who has looked in detail at the history of academic disciplines think digital humanities is in any way exceptional with regard to dependencies between its intellectual currency and bottom line ways and means Yet we frequently ignore these institutionalized realities in favor of an appeal to the digital humanities construct as though the construct and not the institution were the desired locus of our agency and efficacy In fact digital humanists are recognized in the same way as individuals working in other fields by doing work that is recognizable as digital humanities My publishing in differences does not make me a scholar of feminist cultural studies were I to wish to have myself considered as such though I would seek to publish in differences and kindred venues and I would develop my work within a network of citations recognizable to the already active participants who are publishing and speaking and teaching in that area with the goal of being listened to by them In time if my contributions had merit they might be taken up and cited by others and thus assimilated into an ongoing conversation So it is with digital humanities you are a digital humanist if you are listened to by those who are already listened to as digital humanists and they themselves got to be digital humanists by being listened to by others Jobs grant funding fellowships publishing contracts speaking invitations these things do not make one a digital humanist though they clearly have a material impact on the circumstances of the work one does to get listened to Put more plainly if my university hires me as a digital humanist and if I receive a federal grant say to do such and such a thing that is described as digital humanities and if I am then rewarded by my department with promotion for having done it not least because outside evaluators whom my department is enlisting to listen to as digital humanists have attested to its value to the digital humanities then well yes I am a Kirschenbaum What is <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> and Why Are They Saying Such Terrible Things about It differences 25 1 2014 46 63 Copyright 2014 <ORGANIZATION>Duke University Press</ORGANIZATION> 11 digital humanist Can you be a digital humanist without doing those things Yes if you want to be though you may find yourself being listened to less unless and until you do some thing that is sufficiently noteworthy that reasonable people who themselves do similar things must account for your work your thing as part of the progression of a shared field of interest That is what being a digital humanist is it is almost all of what being a digital humanist is And while the material particulars of the work may vary in certain respects including some very consequential respects it is different not at all from being a Victorianist or a feminist cultural studies scholar or a scholar of Victorian feminist cultural studies <ORGANIZATION>Digital</ORGANIZATION> humanists don t want to extinguish reading and theory and interpretation and cultural criticism <ORGANIZATION>Digital</ORGANIZATION> humanists want to do their work They want jobs and if the job includes the opportunity for it they want tenure and promotion They often want to teach They often want to publish They want to be heard They want professional recognition and stability whether as contingent labor ladder faculty graduate students or in alt ac settings In short they want pretty much the same things that every working academic wants and the terrible truth is that they go about it in more or less familiar ways that include teaching publishing and administration Take for example <PERSON>Matthew Jockers</PERSON> a collaborator and past colleague of <PERSON>Franco Moretti</PERSON> he who gave us the term distant reading now <PERSON>Jockers</PERSON> is on the English faculty at the <ORGANIZATION>University of Nebraska Lincoln</ORGANIZATION> an institution that has developed an exceptionally strong capacity in digital humanities hence its hosting the recent conference If anybody is in DH surely it is Jockers He has recently published a book titled Macroanalysis Digital Methods and Literary History as part of the <ORGANIZATION>University of Illinois Press</ORGANIZATION> s Topics in the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> series In one early chapter over the span of about a page <PERSON>Jockers</PERSON> deploys a sequence of metaphors gleaned from strip mining to articulate his work s relation to the literary history of his subtitle W hat is needed now is the equivalent of open pit mining or hydraulicking Close reading traditional searching will continue to reveal nuggets while the deeper veins lie buried beneath the mass of gravel layered above What are required are the methods for aggregating and making sense out of both the nuggets and the tailings to exploit the trammel of computation to process condense deform and analyze the deeper strata from which these nuggets were born to unearth for the first time what these corpora really contain 9 10 I am quoting selectively and elsewhere <PERSON>Jockers</PERSON> develops his argument along paths more subtle perhaps more comfortable than mountaintop removal Kirschenbaum What is <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> and Why Are They Saying Such Terrible Things about It differences 25 1 2014 46 63 Copyright 2014 <ORGANIZATION>Duke University Press</ORGANIZATION> 12 But that s secondary to my point which is that to receive even such passages as these with the agonistic zero sum view that the author seeks to somehow eradicate traditional close reading and interpretation makes sense only in the construct The facts after all are these <PERSON>Jockers</PERSON> s book was published in late 2012 with a print run of such and such It will be bought by university libraries and some number of individuals Some fewer number of those who bought it will read it It will be reviewed in some number of venues though the reviews will fall off after the first few years as they always do Eventually we do not know when it will go out of print It will be cited by how many we do not yet know It will be assigned to how many classes we do not yet know It will inspire some number of students some fraction of whom may perhaps go to <LOCATION>Nebraska</LOCATION> to work with <PERSON>Jockers</PERSON> At some point the approaches in the book may pass out of fashion and it may thus appear dated or naive At some point the approaches may become more widespread in which case the book will appear prescient and wise Regardless the book will do what almost all serious books do albeit to greater or lesser extents contribute to a conversation Right now there is an especially lively such conversation around how we read My colleague <PERSON>Lee Konstantinou</PERSON> has been collecting the different modalities besides close and distant his list includes also uncritical reading <PERSON>Michael Warner</PERSON> reparative reading <PERSON>Eve Sedgwick</PERSON> generous reading <PERSON>Timothy Bewes</PERSON> disintegrated reading <PERSON>Rita Raley</PERSON> surface reading <ORGANIZATION>Sharon Best</ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON>Stephen Marcus</PERSON> also <PERSON>Heather Love</PERSON> and the hermeneutics of situation <PERSON>Chris Nealon</PERSON> and <PERSON>Jeffrey Nealon Jockers</PERSON> s interventions in <LOCATION>Macroanalysis</LOCATION> have precisely no chance of displacing or discouraging any of these other modes of reading even if such were his intent which it manifestly is not <PERSON>Jockers</PERSON> does not wish for us all to become text miners and for none of us to read symptomatically or generously or reparatively he likely wishes for more of us to mine texts surely that is a motive in writing the book and then talk to those who read reparatively and generously and closely surely that is the motive in doing the mining None of this differs in any substantial way from the publication of a special journal issue collecting papers from a group of scholars around an intervention such as surface reading for example Let me offer an example from another quarter <PERSON>Peter Robinson</PERSON> who has had a long and distinguished career as an editorial theorist and textual scholar has lately been giving papers in which he purports to explain w hy digital humanists should get out of textual scholarship And if they don t <PERSON>Kirschenbaum</PERSON> What is <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> and Why Are They Saying Such Terrible Things about It differences 25 1 2014 46 63 Copyright 2014 <ORGANIZATION>Duke University Press</ORGANIZATION> 13 why we textual scholars should throw them out <PERSON>Robinson</PERSON> s argument is predicated on the belief that digital humanists build tools and that textual studies now more or less has all the tools it needs to go about its work which is that of making critical editions electronic or otherwise He ends with this We may use digital humanities to be better textual scholars but we do not pretend to be digital humanists In return digital humanists might also declare we do digital humanities and we try to help textual scholars to be better textual scholars through digital humanities but we do not pretend to be textual scholars There are many ways in which one might seek to answer <PERSON>Robinson</PERSON> starting with the assumption that digital humanities is confined to the activity of tool building But we can also say this <PERSON>Robinson</PERSON> s concluding statement is a catechism that makes sense only in the construct that virtual discursive space where Morpheus and Neo who are both really on the same side remember can battle without regard for bodies history or physics Outside of the construct <PERSON>Robinson</PERSON> s statement has no sense indeed no context It speaks to no body Why Because it presumes the existence of entities called digital humanities or for that matter textual scholarship that exist apart from the practices of the people who identify with them To be sure there are exemplars of digital humanists who have no great interest in textual scholarship just as there are textual scholars who have no investments in the digital humanities but these individual cases merely reflect the reality of individual choices and careers not the fractal coastlines of some metadisciplinary geography exposed at low tide <PERSON>Robinson</PERSON> is thus making a purely discursive move in a purely discursive space Put more plainly it is not as if one could sit in the audience and hear his talk and say Yes <PERSON>Robinson</PERSON> has this right and so I will return to my campus and dissociate digital humanities from textual scholarship forthwith Indeed <PERSON>Robinson</PERSON> himself clearly knows this since the most tangible action items in his paper refer to the material circumstances of scholarly production copyrights costs the quality of markup and metadata and the interoperability of tools In any case <PERSON>Robinson</PERSON> s positions would have been unimaginable just a few years ago before the first large scale deployments of the digital humanities construct Not because there are no intellectual distinctions to be drawn between what digital humanities does and what textual scholarship does but rather because the number of actual people outside the construct who would wish to concern themselves with the things <PERSON>Robinson</PERSON> concerns himself with who do not also have a history and identity in the digital humanities is nowadays vanishingly small Kirschenbaum What is <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> and Why Are They Saying Such Terrible Things about It differences 25 1 2014 46 63 Copyright 2014 <ORGANIZATION>Duke University Press</ORGANIZATION> 14 I have written as I have to suggest neither that all dark side critiques are disingenuous nor that any questioning of digital humanities is universally reducible to a construct Of course one should ask questions about any set of disciplinary practices that have been as visible and prodigious as digital humanities in recent years And the construct serves its purpose too reductionism is often nothing more and nothing less than a concession to the limitations of the human capacity for attention Indeed the formation of discursive constructs around areas of critical engagement is itself entirely normative see for example New Historicism or Romanticism <PERSON>Brian McHale</PERSON> once chose exactly that phrase discursive construct to characterize postmodernism 4 5 Thus it is also not surprising that DHers themselves have written innumerable statements which contribute to the construct s formation and perpetuation But it is also necessary and appropriate to draw attention to what seems to me to be a recent and particular and peculiarly conspicuous set of moves those suggested by the serial repetition of qualifying language seeking to establish discursive distance between critiques of digital humanities as such and those addressed to individual projects and productions Drawing attention to that move I have sought to do this typographically through my own use of quotation marks around digital humanities much as <PERSON>Morozov</PERSON> insists on the Internet ought to remind us of the limits of critique when critique is exercised according to recognizable and repeatable and procedural stances So called dark side critiques could therefore productively probe the digital humanities construct in relation to what we know of prior academic discursive formations an inquiry remarkably absent from those critiques to date despite their own charges that digital humanities is not sufficiently invested in its histories Moreover critiques of digital humanities can ameliorate the construct as opposed to indulging its brutal and metric perpetuation by acknowledging historically materially that digital humanities is in fact a diversified set of practices one whose details and methodologies responsible critique has a responsibility to understand and engage Such I would dearly like to see for it is needed not just by digital humanities but by the constituencies of the humanities Recent revelations notwithstanding we cannot proceed as though such suddenly public phenomena as metadata or data mining are simply the calling cards of the state I know of at least one exemplar already at hand I am thinking of <PERSON>Alan Liu</PERSON> s essay The Meaning of the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> in the March 2013 issue of PMLA Given the title one could be forgiven for expecting the usual bout with definitions and measures of inclusion But the essay offers Kirschenbaum What is <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> and Why Are They Saying Such Terrible Things about It differences 25 1 2014 46 63 Copyright 2014 <ORGANIZATION>Duke University Press</ORGANIZATION> 15 little in that regard It makes a remarkably novel move instead a close reading if you will of one particular digital humanities project specifically a paper published out of <ORGANIZATION>Stanford University</ORGANIZATION> s Literary Lab based on experiments with computational analysis of a data corpus In focusing his address on the research reported in this one paper <PERSON>Liu</PERSON> hews very close to the science and technology studies STS approach that I believe offers the best basis for relevant critique of and in the digital humanities a critique focused around the illumination of the antecedents assumptions and material dependencies of particular tools methods parentages of mentoring and institutional settings <ORGANIZATION>Digital</ORGANIZATION> humanities after all is sometimes said to suffer from physics envy Let us then take that as it may be and avail ourselves of a singularly powerful intellectual precedent for examining in close yes microscopic detail the material conditions of knowledge production in scientific settings or configurations Let us read citation networks and publication venues Let us examine the usage patterns around particular tools Let us treat the recensio of data sets <PERSON>Liu</PERSON> gives us a more than passing glimpse of what all this may look like he undertakes to correspond for example with the managing editor of the Historical Thesaurus of the Oxford English Dictionary HTOED a reference whose data furnishes the main ingredient in what <PERSON>Liu</PERSON> terms an essential adjustment step in the authors methodology <PERSON>Liu</PERSON> a master reader rightly recognizes this as the crux of the narrative he is unspooling and so he follows the thread to the source in order to expose the implications of the dependencies to the <PERSON>HTOED Liu</PERSON> further notes that the HTOED though historically precomputational is not pretechnological and has in fact been implemented and transposed through a series of online databases since its origins in the 1960s it thus now manifests a rich range of media archaeological layers The essay succeeds not only because it offers up a critique with which we may better see the contributions and limits of a particular project but also because it is actively interested in I would go so far as to say fascinated by digital humanities <PERSON>Liu</PERSON> in short seeks to give us the digital humanities in action and so he sites critique amid the evidentiary details of data sets and databases and algorithms as well literary historical interpretation and disciplinary knowledge 2 In previous essays I ve described digital humanities as both a methodological outlook What is and as a tactical term DH As is In closing I will be as plain as I can be we will never know what digital humanities is because we don t want to know nor is it useful for us to know <PERSON>John Unsworth</PERSON> who may well have written the foundational naming <PERSON>Kirschenbaum</PERSON> What is <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> and Why Are They Saying Such Terrible Things about It differences 25 1 2014 46 63 Copyright 2014 <ORGANIZATION>Duke University Press</ORGANIZATION> 16 document for digital humanities given as a talk on May 25 2001 introduced digital humanities as a concession arrived at for want of other different terms From that very day we were already in the construct a concession that exists to consolidate and propagate vectors of ambiguity affirmation and dissent 3 Regardless there is one thing that digital humanities ineluctably is digital humanities is work somebody s work somewhere some thing always We know how to talk about work So let s talk about this work in action this actually existing work 4 Notes 1 This paragraph consolidates and paraphrases but exaggerates hardly at all a number of ongoing discourses around digital humanities principally online Those wishing to reconstruct the particular sources that inspired me which are by no means coextensive with the totality of the dark side critique are advised to consult the following For digital humanities as big data ideology and antitheoretical historical hermeneutical critical see the 2012 13 Twitter feeds of <PERSON>David Golumbia</PERSON> and <PERSON>Brian Lennon See</PERSON> also the various entries in the digital humanities category on <PERSON>Golumbia</PERSON> s Uncomputing blog For digital humanities and MOOCs see if only as a starting point <PERSON>Grusin</PERSON> For digital humanities and the post 9 11 surveillance state see esp <PERSON>Lennon</PERSON> on Twitter For digital humanities as managerial see Allington For <PERSON>Morozov</PERSON> worship see again <PERSON>Golumbia</PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION>Lennon Twitter Digital</ORGANIZATION> humanities never once inhaled is from <PERSON>Alan Liu</PERSON> s trenchant essay Where Is Cultural Criticism in the Digital Humanities For an extensive discussion around race class gender sexuality and disability and the extent to which DH is or is not a refuge from them all see <PERSON>Smith</PERSON> and <PERSON>Koh</PERSON> and <LOCATION>Risam</LOCATION> including comments Though this accounting is not exhaustive a reader who spends any length of time with these sources including also comments replies and the other dialogic features of online expression will I think see voiced most if not all of the terrible things I seek here to address 2 <PERSON>Fred Gibbs</PERSON> reacting to an earlier essay of <PERSON>Liu</PERSON> s has also delineated the need for such a situated critique He asserts digital humanities criticism needs to go beyond typical peer review and inhabit a genre of its own a critical discourse a kind of scholarship in its own right 3 That mere definitions of digital humanities are commonplace and easy to come by <PERSON>Ashgate</PERSON> has now devoted a reader to collecting them only accentuates the point See Terras <PERSON>Nyhan</PERSON> and Vanhouette 4 A number of wise friends commented on an initial draft of this essay I am grateful to them Works Cited <PERSON>Allington Daniel</PERSON> The Managerial Humanities or Why the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities Don</ORGANIZATION> t Exist Weblog entry <PERSON>Daniel Allington</PERSON> 31 Mar 2013 http www danielallington net 2013 03 the managerial humanities or why the digital humanities dont exist Kirschenbaum What is <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> and Why Are They Saying Such Terrible Things about It differences 25 1 2014 46 63 Copyright 2014 <ORGANIZATION>Duke University Press</ORGANIZATION> 17 <PERSON>Chun Wendy Hui Kyong</PERSON> The <ORGANIZATION>Dark Side of Digital Humanities Part</ORGANIZATION> 1 Center for 21st Century Studies 9 Jan 2013 http www c21uwm com 2013 01 09 the dark side of the digital humanities part 1 <PERSON>Germano William WmGermano</PERSON> The spectacular rise of DH as the most powerful digraph in the non STEM academy 19 Jan 2013 9 35 a m Tweet Gibbs Fred Critical Discourse in <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities Journal of Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> 1 1 2011 http journalofdigitalhumanities org 1 1 critical discourse in digital humanities by fred gibbs accessed 10 October 2013 Gold Matthew ed Debates in the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities Minneapolis U of Minnesota</ORGANIZATION> P 2011 <PERSON>Golumbia David Uncomputing Weblog</PERSON> http www uncomputing org cat 235 accessed 1 October 2013 dgolumbia Twitter Grusin Richard The <ORGANIZATION>Dark Side of Digital Humanities Part</ORGANIZATION> 2 Center for 21st Century Studies 9 Jan 2013 http www c21uwm com 2013 01 09 the dark side of the digital humanities part 2 <ORGANIZATION>Jockers Matthew L Macroanalysis Digital Methods and Literary History Urbana U of Illinois P 2013 Kirschenbaum Matthew Comment on Digital Humanities Two Definitions Uncomputing</ORGANIZATION> 21 Jan 2013 http www uncomputing org p 203 amp cpage 1 comment 2135 <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> as Is a Tactical Term Gold 415 28 What Is <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> and What s It Doing in English Departments ADE Bulletin 150 2010 http mkirschenbaum files wordpress com 2011 03 ade final pdf accessed Aug 5 2013 <PERSON>Koh Adeline</PERSON> and Roopika Risam Open Thread The <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> as a Historical Refuge from Race Class Gender Sexuality Disability Weblog entry <ORGANIZATION>Postcolonial Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> 10 May 2013 http dhpoco org blog 2013 05 10 open thread the digital humanities as a historical refuge from raceclassgendersexualitydisability <PERSON>Konstantinou Lee</PERSON> Personal communication 20 Jul 2013 8 46 p m <ORGANIZATION>Lennon Brian Comment on Digital Humanities Two Definitions Uncomputing</ORGANIZATION> 21 Jan 2013 http www uncomputing org p 203 amp cpage 1 comment 2129 cesgnal <ORGANIZATION>Twitter Liu Alan</ORGANIZATION> The Meaning of the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities PMLA</ORGANIZATION> 128 2 March 2013 409 23 http journalofdigitalhumanities org 1 1 critical discourse in digital humanities by fred gibbs http journalofdigitalhumanities org 1 1 critical discourse in digital humanities by fred gibbs <ORGANIZATION>Kirschenbaum What is Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> and Why Are They Saying Such Terrible Things about It differences 25 1 2014 46 63 Copyright 2014 <ORGANIZATION>Duke University Press</ORGANIZATION> 18 Where Is Cultural Criticism in the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities Gold 2011 McHale Brian Postmodernist Fiction New York</ORGANIZATION> and <LOCATION>London</LOCATION> Routledge 1987 <PERSON>Morozov Evgeny</PERSON> The Net Delusion The Dark Side of Internet Freedom <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> PublicAffairs 2011 Pannapacker William The <ORGANIZATION>MLA</ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities Chronicle</ORGANIZATION> of Higher Education 28 Dec 2009 http chronicle com blogPost The <ORGANIZATION>MLAthe Digital</ORGANIZATION> 19468 Raley Rita The <ORGANIZATION>Dark Side of Digital Humanities Part</ORGANIZATION> 4 Center for 21st Century Studies 9 Jan 2013 http www c21uwm com 2013 01 09 the dark side of the digital humanities part 4 Ramsay <PERSON>Stephen</PERSON> DH Types One and Two Weblog entry <PERSON>Stephen Ramsay</PERSON> 5 May 2013 Robinson Peter Why Digital Humanists Should Get Out of Textual Scholarship And If They Don t Why We Textual Scholars Should Throw Them Out Scholarly Digital Editions 29 Jul 2013 http scholarlydigitaleditions blogspot com 2013 07 why digital humanists should get out of html <ORGANIZATION>Smith Martha Nell</ORGANIZATION> The Human Touch Software of the Highest Order Revisiting Editing as Interpretation Textual Cultures Texts Contexts Interpretation 2 1 2007 1 15 Terras <PERSON>Melissa Julianne Nyhan</PERSON> and <PERSON>Edward Vanhoutte</PERSON> eds <ORGANIZATION>Defining Digital Humanities A Reader Farnham Surrey</ORGANIZATION> Ashgate 2013 Unsworth John A Master s Degree in Digital Humanities Part of the Media Studies Program at the <ORGANIZATION>University of Virginia 2001 Congress of the Social Sciences and Humanities Universit Laval Qu bec Canada Lecture</ORGANIZATION> 25 May 2001 http people lis illinois edu unsworth laval html</ner>
