<ner>Burns Documents ADE 150 2010 File Kirschenbaum_ade150 indd Job 320 30 1 5 11 <ORGANIZATION>LG</ORGANIZATION> DC LG ADE BullEtin numBEr 150 2010 1 The author is associ ate professor of English and associate director of the <ORGANIZATION>Maryland Institute for Technology in the Humanities</ORGANIZATION> at the Uni versity of <LOCATION>Maryland</LOCATION> A version of this article was presented at the 2010 ADE Summer Seminar East in <LOCATION>College Park Maryland</LOCATION> People who say that the last battles of the computer revolution in En glish departments have been fought and won don t know what they re talking about If our current use of computers in En glish studies is marked by any common theme at all it is experimentation at the most basic level As a pro fession we are just learning how to live with computers just beginning to integrate these machines effectively into writing and reading intensive courses just starting to consider the implications of the multilayered literacy associated with computers <PERSON>Cynthia Selfe</PERSON> What is or are the digital humanities aka humanities computing It s tempt ing to say that whoever asks the question has not gone looking very hard for an answer What is digital humanities essays like this one are already genre pieces <PERSON>Willard McCarty</PERSON> has been contributing papers on the subject for years a mono graph too Under the earlier appellation <PERSON>John Unsworth</PERSON> has advised us what is humanities computing and what is it not Most recently <PERSON>Patrik Svensson</PERSON> has been publishing a series of well documented articles on multiple aspects of the topic including the lexical shift from humanities computing to digital humanities More over as <PERSON>Cynthia Selfe</PERSON> in an ADE Bulletin from 1988 reminds us computers have been part of our disciplinary lives for well over two decades now During this time digital humanities has accumulated a robust professional apparatus that is probably more rooted in En glish than any other departmental home The contours of this professional apparatus are easily discoverable an organiza tion called the alliance of <ORGANIZATION>Digital humanities Organizations</ORGANIZATION> hosts a well attended annual international conference called <ORGANIZATION>Digital</ORGANIZATION> humanities it grew out of an earlier annual series of conferences hosted jointly by the association for Computers and the humanities and the association for Literary and Linguistic Computing since 1989 There is <ORGANIZATION>Blackwell s Companion to Digital Humanities There</ORGANIZATION> is a book series yes a book series topics in the <ORGANIZATION>Digital</ORGANIZATION> humanities from the <ORGANIZATION>University of Illinois Press There</ORGANIZATION> is a refereed journal called <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities Quarterly</ORGANIZATION> one of several that serve the field including a newer publication Digital Studies Le champ num rique sponsored by the <ORGANIZATION>Canadian Society for Digital humanities Soci</ORGANIZATION> t pour L tude des M dias <ORGANIZATION>Interactifs The University of Victoria</ORGANIZATION> hosts the annual <ORGANIZATION>Digital</ORGANIZATION> humani ties Summer Institute to train new scholars Crucially there are digital humanities centers and institutes probably at least one hundred worldwide some of them estab lished for a decade or more with staffs numbering in the dozens these are served by an organization known as centerNet There have been digital humanities manifestos I know of at least two and FaQs colloquia and symposia workshops and special sessions Not to mention of course that a gloss or explanation of digital humani ties is implicit in every mission statement every call for papers and proposals every What Is <ORGANIZATION>Digital</ORGANIZATION> humanities and What s It Doing in English Departments <PERSON>Matthew G Kirschenbaum</PERSON> ADE and the <ORGANIZATION>Association of Departments of En</ORGANIZATION> glish are trademarks owned by the <ORGANIZATION>Modern Language Association</ORGANIZATION> by the <ORGANIZATION>Association of Departments of En</ORGANIZATION> glish CrossRef DOI 10 1632 ade 150 XXX ISSN 0001 0898 Burns Documents ADE 150 2010 File Kirschenbaum_ade150 indd Job 320 30 1 5 11 <ORGANIZATION>LG</ORGANIZATION> DC LG ADE BullEtin numBEr 150 2010 2 What Is <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> and What s It Doing in En glish Departments <PERSON>Matthew G Kirschenbaum</PERSON> strategic plan and curriculum development document every hiring request and so forth that invokes the term Or the countless times the question has been visited on electronic discussion lists blogs <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> walls and Twitter feeds contributing all the flames and exhortations celebrations and screeds one could wish to read We could also of course simply <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> the question <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> takes us to <ORGANIZATION>Wikipe</ORGANIZATION> dia and what we find there is not bad The digital humanities also known as humanities computing is a field of study research teaching and invention concerned with the intersection of computing and the disciplines of the humanities It is methodological by nature and interdisciplinary in scope It involves investigation analysis synthesis and presentation of information in electronic form It studies how these media affect the disciplines in which they are used and what these disciplines have to contribute to our knowledge of computing as a working definition this serves as well as any I ve seen which is not surprising since a glance at the page s View history tab reveals individuals closely associated with the digital humanities as contributors at its core then digital humanities is more akin to a common methodological outlook than an investment in any one specific set of texts or even technologies We could attempt to refine this outlook quantitatively using some of the very tools and techniques digital humanities has pioneered For example we might use a text analysis tool named Voyeur developed by <ORGANIZATION>St</ORGANIZATION> fan <PERSON>Sinclair</PERSON> to mine the proceedings from the annual <ORGANIZATION>Digital</ORGANIZATION> humanities con ference and develop lists of topic frequencies or collocate key terms or visualize the papers citation networks We could also choose to explore the question qualitatively by examining sets of projects from self identified digital humanities centers at the <ORGANIZATION>University of Maryland</ORGANIZATION> where I serve as an associate director at the <LOCATION>Maryland</LOCATION> In stitute for technology in the humanities we support work from <PERSON>Shakespeare</PERSON> to Second Life as we re fond of saying the Shakespeare Quartos archive funded by a joint grant program administered by the <LOCATION>United Kingdom</LOCATION> s JISC and the <ORGANIZATION>NEh</ORGANIZATION> makes a searchable digital facsimile of each of the thirty two extant quarto copies of Hamlet available online while the Preserving Virtual Worlds project supported by the <ORGANIZATION>Library of Congress</ORGANIZATION> has developed and tested standards and best practices for archiving and ensuring future access to computer games interactive fiction and virtual communities Yet digital humanities is also a social undertaking It harbors networks of people who have been working together sharing research arguing competing and col laborating for many years Key achievements from this community like the text Encoding Initiative or the <LOCATION>Orlando</LOCATION> Project were mostly finished before the current wave of interest in digital humanities began Nonetheless the rapid and remark able rise of digital humanities as a term can be traced to a set of surprisingly specific circumstances <PERSON>John Unsworth</PERSON> who was the founding director of the <ORGANIZATION>Institute</ORGANIZATION> for advanced technology in the humanities at the <ORGANIZATION>University of Virginia</ORGANIZATION> for a decade and is currently dean of the <ORGANIZATION>Graduate School of Library</ORGANIZATION> and Information Science at the <ORGANIZATION>University of Illinois</ORGANIZATION> has this to relate The real origin of that term digital humanities was in conversation with andrew <PERSON>McNeillie</PERSON> the original acquiring editor for the <ORGANIZATION>Blackwell Companion to Digital Hu</ORGANIZATION> manities We started talking with him about that book project in 2001 in april and Burns Documents ADE 150 2010 File Kirschenbaum_ade150 indd Job 320 30 1 5 11 <ORGANIZATION>LG</ORGANIZATION> DC LG ADE BullEtin numBEr 150 2010 3 What Is <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> and What s It Doing in En glish Departments <PERSON>Matthew G Kirschenbaum</PERSON> by the end of November we d lined up contributors and were discussing the title for the contract <ORGANIZATION>Ray Siemens</ORGANIZATION> wanted a Companion to humanities Computing as that was the term commonly used at that point the editorial and marketing folks at <ORGANIZATION>Blackwell</ORGANIZATION> wanted <ORGANIZATION>Companion to Digitized humanities</ORGANIZATION> I suggested Companion to <ORGANIZATION>Digital</ORGANIZATION> humanities to shift the emphasis away from simple digitization Message at about the same time the <PERSON>Blackwell</PERSON> s volume was being put together the leader ship of two scholarly organizations opened discussions about creating an umbrella entity for themselves and eventually other organizations and associations with like interests as anyone who has ever tried to run a scholarly organization will know economies of scale are difficult to come by with only a few hundred members and so the thought was to consolidate and share infrastructure and services The two or ganizations were the aforementioned association for Computers in the humanities and the association for Literary and Linguistic Computing The umbrella structure that resulted was called aDhO or the alliance of <ORGANIZATION>Digital</ORGANIZATION> humanities Organiza tions here is <PERSON>Unsworth</PERSON> again from the same communication Conversations about merging aCh and aLLC began at tuebingen in a bar in a conversation between harold Short and me in July 2002 a couple of months later I had set a list called adhoc allied digital humanities organizations committee first message dated august 16 2002 We finally got things off the dime in Swe den at the 2004 aLLC aCh and after waffling some more about names IChIO OhCO and others we voted in april of 2005 to go with aDhO changing a from allied to alliance By 2005 then the <PERSON>Blackwell</PERSON> s Companion had been published and the alliance for <ORGANIZATION>Digital humanities Organizations</ORGANIZATION> had been established There s one more key event to relate and that s the launch in 2006 of the <ORGANIZATION>Digital</ORGANIZATION> humanities Initiative by the NEh then under the chairmanship of <PERSON>Bruce Cole</PERSON> and with leadership provided by <PERSON>Brett Bobley</PERSON> a charismatic and imaginative individual who doubles as the agency s CIO In an e mail to me <PERSON>Bobley</PERSON> describes a January 2006 lunch with another <ORGANIZATION>NEh</ORGANIZATION> staffer at which they were brainstorming ideas for what would become the <ORGANIZATION>Digital</ORGANIZATION> humanities Initiative at the lunch I jotted down a bunch of names including humanities computing ehumanities and digital humanities When I got back to the office I Googled all three of them and digital humanities seemed to be the winner I liked it for a few reasons due to aDhO and their annual <ORGANIZATION>Digital</ORGANIZATION> humanities conference the name brought up a lot of relevant hits I believe I d also heard from <PERSON>Julia Flanders</PERSON> about the forthcoming <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities Quarterly</ORGANIZATION> journal I also appreciated the fact that it seemed to cast a wider net than humanities computing which seemed to imply a form of computing whereas digital humanities implied a form of human ism I also thought it would be an easier sell to the humanities community to have the emphasis on humanities In 2008 the <ORGANIZATION>Digital</ORGANIZATION> humanities Initiative became the <ORGANIZATION>Office of Digital</ORGANIZATION> humani ties the designation of office assigning the program and its budget line a perma nent place within the agency That the major federal granting agency for scholarship in the humanities taking its cues directly from a small but active and influential group of scholars had devoted scarce resources to launching a number of new grant <PERSON>Burns</PERSON> Documents ADE 150 2010 File Kirschenbaum_ade150 indd Job 320 30 1 5 11 <ORGANIZATION>LG</ORGANIZATION> DC LG ADE BullEtin numBEr 150 2010 4 What Is <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> and What s It Doing in En glish Departments <PERSON>Matthew G Kirschenbaum</PERSON> opportunities many of them programmatically innovative in and of themselves around an endeavor termed digital humanities was doubtless the tipping point for the branding of Dh at least in the <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> These events will I think earn a place in histories of the profession alongside other major critical movements like the <LOCATION>Birmingham</LOCATION> school or <ORGANIZATION>Yale</ORGANIZATION> deconstruction In the space of a little more than five years digital humanities had gone from being a term of convenience used by a group of researchers who had already been working together for years to something like a movement Individual scholars routinely now self identify as digital humanists or Dhers There is an unusually strong sense of community and common purpose manifested for example in events such as the Day of <ORGANIZATION>Digital</ORGANIZATION> humanities organized by a team at the <ORGANIZATION>University of alberta</ORGANIZATION> Its second annual iteration featured over 150 participants up from around one hun dred the first year who blogged on a shared site about the details of their workday posted photographs of their offices and screens and reflected on the nature of their enterprise <ORGANIZATION>Digital</ORGANIZATION> humanities has even been the recipient of its own Downfall re mix the Internet meme whereby the climactic scene from the hBO film depicting hitler s final days in the bunker is closed captioned with in this instance a tirade about the pernicious influence of online scholarship <ORGANIZATION>Digital</ORGANIZATION> humanities was also you may have heard big news at the 2009 MLa an nual Convention in <LOCATION>Philadelphia</LOCATION> On 28 December midway through the conven tion <PERSON>William Pannapacker</PERSON> one of the Chronicle of Higher Education s officially appointed bloggers wrote the following for the online Brainstorm section amid all the doom and gloom of the 2009 MLa Convention one field seems to be alive and well the digital humanities More than that among all the contending sub fields the digital humanities seem like the first next big thing in a long time It seems fair to say that <PERSON>Pannapacker</PERSON> who is the author of Graduate School in the humanities Just Don t Go under the pseudonym <PERSON>Thomas Benton</PERSON> is not a man easily impressed <PERSON>Jennifer</PERSON> howard meanwhile a veteran <ORGANIZATION>Chronicle</ORGANIZATION> reporter who has covered the convention before noted the vitality of digital humanities with its overflow crowds to too small conference rooms There were several dozen panels devoted to the digital humanities at the MLa convention and one could and did easily navigate the three day convention by moving among them Crucially digital humanities was visible in another way at the conference the social networking service <ORGANIZATION>Twitter Twitter</ORGANIZATION> is the love it or hate it Web 2 0 application often maligned as the final triumph of the attention deficit generation because it lim its postings to a mere 140 characters not 140 words 140 characters The reason has less to do with attention spans than <ORGANIZATION>Twitter</ORGANIZATION> s origins in the messaging protocols of mobile devices but the format encourages brief conversational posts tweets that also tend to contain a fair measure of flair and wit Unlike <ORGANIZATION>Facebook Twitter</ORGANIZATION> allows for asymmetrical relationships you can follow someone or they can follow you without the relationship s being reciprocated tweeting has rapidly become an inte gral part of the conference scene with a subset of attendees on Twitter providing real time running commentary through a common tag mla09 for example which allows everyone who follows it to tune in to the conversation This phenomenon has Burns Documents ADE 150 2010 File Kirschenbaum_ade150 indd Job 320 30 1 5 11 <ORGANIZATION>LG</ORGANIZATION> DC LG ADE BullEtin numBEr 150 2010 5 What Is <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> and What s It Doing in En glish Departments <PERSON>Matthew G Kirschenbaum</PERSON> some very specific ramifications amanda French ran the numbers and concluded that nearly half 48 of attendees at the <ORGANIZATION>Digital</ORGANIZATION> humanities 2009 conference were tweeting the sessions By contrast only 3 of MLa convention attendees tweeted according to French s data out of about 7 800 attendees at the MLa convention only 256 tweeted Of these the vast majority were people already associated with digital humanities through their existing networks of followers <PERSON>Jennifer</PERSON> howard again writing for the <ORGANIZATION>Chronicle</ORGANIZATION> noted the centrality of Twitter to the Dh crowd and its im pact on scholarly communication going so far as to include people s <ORGANIZATION>Twitter</ORGANIZATION> identities in her roundup of major stories from the convention Inside Higher Ed also devoted coverage to Twitter at the MLa convention noting that <PERSON>Rosemary G Feal</PERSON> was using it to connect with individual members of the organization not surprisingly many of them <ORGANIZATION>Dhers Feal</ORGANIZATION> in fact kept up a lively stream of tweets throughout the confer ence gamely mixing it up with the sometimes irreverent back channel conversation and in a scene out of Small World had it only been written twenty years later issued an impromptu invite for her tweeps to join the association s elite for nightcaps in the penthouse of one of the convention hotels While it s not hard to see why the academic press devoured the story there s more going on than mere shenanigans <ORGANIZATION>Twitter</ORGANIZATION> along with blogs and other online outlets has inscribed the digital humanities as a network topology that is to say lines drawn by aggregates of affinities formally and functionally manifest in who follows whom who friends whom who tweets whom and who links to what <ORGANIZATION>Digital</ORGANIZATION> humanities has also I would propose lately been galvanized by a group of younger or not so young graduate students faculty members both tenure line and contingent and other academic professionals who now wield the label digital humanities instru mentally amid an increasingly monstrous institutional terrain defined by declin ing public support for higher education rising tuitions shrinking endowments the proliferation of distance education and the for profit university and underlying it all the conversion of full time tenure track academic labor to a part time adjunct workforce One example is the remarkable tale of <PERSON>Brian Croxall</PERSON> the recent <ORGANIZATION>Emory</ORGANIZATION> PhD who went viral online for a period of several weeks during and after the <PERSON>MLa Croxall</PERSON> had his paper The absent Presence today s Faculty read at the con vention in absentia while he simultaneously published it on his blog after finding himself unable to afford to travel to <LOCATION>Philadelphia</LOCATION> because he hadn t landed any con vention interviews as numerous observers pointed out <PERSON>Croxall</PERSON> s paper which was heavily blogged and tweeted and received coverage in both the Chronicle and Inside Higher Ed was undoubtedly and by many orders of magnitude the most widely seen and read paper from the 2009 MLa convention These events were subsequently dis cussed in a series of cross postings and conversations that spilled across Twitter and the blogosphere for several weeks after the convention ended Many seemed to feel that the connection to wider academic issues was not incidental or accidental and that digital humanities with a culture that values collaboration openness nonhier archical relations and agility might be an instrument for real resistance or reform So what is digital humanities and what is it doing in En glish departments The answer to the latter portion of the question is easier I can think of some half a dozen reasons why En glish departments have historically been hospitable settings for this Burns Documents ADE 150 2010 File Kirschenbaum_ade150 indd Job 320 30 1 5 11 <ORGANIZATION>LG</ORGANIZATION> DC LG ADE BullEtin numBEr 150 2010 6 What Is <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> and What s It Doing in En glish Departments <PERSON>Matthew G Kirschenbaum</PERSON> kind of work First after numeric input text has been by far the most tractable data type for computers to manipulate Unlike images audio video and so on there is a long tradition of text based data processing that was within the capabilities of even some of the earliest computer systems and that has for decades fed research in fields like stylistics linguistics and author attribution studies all heavily associated with En glish departments Second of course there is the long association between computers and composition almost as long and just as rich in its lineage Third is the pitch perfect convergence between the intense conversations around editorial theory and method in the 1980s and the widespread means to implement electronic archives and editions very soon after <PERSON>Jerome McGann</PERSON> is a key figure here with his work on the <PERSON>Rossetti</PERSON> Archive which he has repeatedly described as a vehicle for applied theory standing as paradigmatic Fourth and at roughly the same time is a modest but much promoted belle lettristic project around hypertext and other forms of electronic literature that continues to this day and is increasingly vibrant and diverse Fifth is the openness of En glish departments to cultural studies where computers and other objects of digital material culture become the centerpiece of analysis I m thinking here for example of the reader <PERSON>Stuart</PERSON> hall and others put together around the <ORGANIZATION>Sony Walkman</ORGANIZATION> that hipster iPod of old Finally today we see the simultaneous explosion of interest in e reading and e book devices like the Kindle iPad and Nook and the advent of large scale text digitization projects the most significant of course being <ORGANIZATION>Google Books</ORGANIZATION> with scholars like <PERSON>Franco Moretti</PERSON> tak ing up data mining and visualization to perform distance readings of hundreds thousands or even millions of books at a time <ORGANIZATION>Digital</ORGANIZATION> humanities which began as a term of consensus among a relatively small group of researchers is now backed on a growing number of campuses by a level of funding infrastructure and administrative commitments that would have been unthinkable even a decade ago Even more recently I would argue the network ef fects of blogs and Twitter at a moment when the academy itself is facing massive and often wrenching changes linked both to new technologies and the changing political and economic landscape has led to the construction of digital humanities as a free floating signifier one that increasingly serves to focus the anxiety and even outrage of individual scholars over their own lack of agency amid the turmoil in their insti tutions and profession This is manifested in the intensity of debates around open access publishing where faculty members increasingly demand the right to retain ownership of their own scholarship meaning their own labor and disseminate it freely to an audience apart from or parallel with more traditional structures of aca demic publishing which in turn are perceived as outgrowths of dysfunctional and outmoded practices surrounding peer review tenure and promotion see <PERSON>Fitzpatrick</PERSON> on planned obsolescence in this issue Whatever else it might be then the digital humanities today is about a scholarship and a pedagogy that is publicly visible in ways to which we are generally unaccus tomed a scholarship and pedagogy that are bound up with infrastructure in ways that are deeper and more explicit than we are generally accustomed to a scholarship and pedagogy that are collaborative and depend on networks of people and that live an active 24 7 life online Isn t that something you want in your En glish department Burns Documents ADE 150 2010 File Kirschenbaum_ade150 indd Job 320 30 1 5 11 <ORGANIZATION>LG</ORGANIZATION> DC LG ADE BullEtin numBEr 150 2010 7 What Is <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> and What s It Doing in En glish Departments <PERSON>Matthew G Kirschenbaum</PERSON> Works Cited Bobley Brett What s in a Name NEh and <ORGANIZATION>Digital</ORGANIZATION> humanities Message to the author 12 apr 2010 E mail <ORGANIZATION>Digital</ORGANIZATION> humanities <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia Wikimedia</ORGANIZATION> 2 Nov 2010 Web 2 aug 2010 French amanda Make 10 Louder or The amplification of Scholarly Communication Amandafrench net French 30 Dec 2009 Web 2 aug 2010 howard <PERSON>Jennifer</PERSON> The MLa Convention in translation <ORGANIZATION>Chronicle of Higher Education Chronicle</ORGANIZATION> of higher <ORGANIZATION>Educ</ORGANIZATION> 31 Dec 2009 Web 2 aug 2010 <ORGANIZATION>McCarty Willard Humanities Computing New York Palgrave</ORGANIZATION> 2005 Print Pannapacker William The MLa and the <ORGANIZATION>Digital humanities Chronicle of Higher Education Chron</ORGANIZATION> icle of higher <ORGANIZATION>Educ</ORGANIZATION> 28 Dec 2009 Web 2 aug 2010 Selfe Cynthia Computers in En glish Departments The Rhetoric of technopower ADE Bulletin 90 1988 63 67 Web 2 aug 2010 <ORGANIZATION>Svensson Patrik humanities Computing as Digital humanities Digital Humanities Quarterly</ORGANIZATION> 3 3 2009 n pag Web 2 aug 2010 The Landscape of <ORGANIZATION>Digital humanities Digital Humanities Quarterly</ORGANIZATION> 4 1 2010 n pag Web 2 aug 2010 Unsworth <PERSON>John Message</PERSON> to the author 5 apr 2010 E mail What Is humanities Computing and What Is It Not Unsworth 8 Nov 2002 Web 2 aug 2010</ner>
