<ner>Untangling Text Data Mining Marti A <ORGANIZATION>Hearst School of Information Management amp Systems University of California Berkeley 102 South Hall Berkeley CA</ORGANIZATION> 94720 4600 http www sims berkeley edu hearst This paper appears in the Proceedings of ACL 99 the 37th Annual Meeting of the <ORGANIZATION>Association for Computational Linguistics University of Maryland June</ORGANIZATION> 20 26 1999 invited paper Abstract The possibilities for data mining from large text collections are virtually untapped Text expresses a vast rich range of information but encodes this information in a form that is difficult to decipher automatically Perhaps for this reason there has been little work in text data mining to date and most people who have talked about it have either conflated it with information access or have not made use of text directly to discover heretofore unknown information In this paper I will first define data mining information access and corpus based computational linguistics and then discuss the relationship of these to text data mining The intent behind these contrasts is to draw attention to exciting new kinds of problems for computational linguists I describe examples of what I consider to be real text data mining efforts and briefly outline our recent ideas about how to pursue exploratory data analysis over text bookmark SECTION00010000000000000000 Introduction The nascent field of text data mining TDM has the peculiar distinction of having a name and a fair amount of hype but as yet almost no practitioners I suspect this has happened because people assume TDM is a natural extension of the slightly less nascent field of data mining DM also known as knowledge discovery in databases <PERSON>Fayyad</PERSON> and Uthurusamy1999 and information archeology <PERSON>Brachman</PERSON> et al 1993 Additionally there are some disagreements about what actually constitutes data mining It turns out that mining is not a very good metaphor for what people in the field actually do Mining implies extracting precious nuggets of ore from otherwise worthless rock If data mining really followed this metaphor it would mean that people were discovering new factoids within their inventory databases However in practice this is not really the case Instead data mining applications tend to be semi automated discovery of trends and patterns across very large datasets usually for the purposes of decision making <PERSON>Fayyad</PERSON> and Uthurusamy1999 Fayyad1997 Part of what I wish to argue here is that in the case of text it can be interesting to take the mining for nuggets metaphor seriously bookmark SECTION00020000000000000000 TDM vs Information Access It is important to differentiate between text data mining and information access or information retrieval as it is more widely known The goal of information access is to help users find documents that satisfy their information needs <PERSON>Baeza Yates</PERSON> and <PERSON>Ribeiro</PERSON> Neto1999 The standard procedure is akin to looking for needles in a needlestack the problem isn t so much that the desired information is not known but rather that the desired information coexists with many other valid pieces of information Just because a user is currently interested in <ORGANIZATION>NAFTA</ORGANIZATION> and not Furbies does not mean that all descriptions of Furbies are worthless The problem is one of homing in on what is currently of interest to the user As noted above the goal of data mining is to discover or derive new information from data finding patterns across datasets and or separating signal from noise The fact that an information retrieval system can return a document that contains the information a user requested does not imply that a new discovery has been made the information had to have already been known to the author of the text otherwise the author could not have written it down I have observed that many people when asked about text data mining assume it should have something to do with making things easier to find on the web For example the description of the <ORGANIZATION>KDD</ORGANIZATION> 97 panel on Data Mining and the Web stated Two challenges are predominant for data mining on the Web The first goal is to help users in finding useful information on the Web and in discovering knowledge about a domain that is represented by a collection of Web documents The second goal is to analyse the transactions run in a Web based system be it to optimize the system or to find information about the clients using the system bookmark tex2html1 1 This search centric view misses the point that we might actually want to treat the information in the web as a large knowledge base from which we can extract new never before encountered information <PERSON>Craven</PERSON> et al 1998 On the other hand the results of certain types of text processing can yield tools that indirectly aid in the information access process Examples include text clustering to create thematic overviews of text collections Cutting et al 1992 <PERSON>Chalmers</PERSON> and Chitson1992 Rennison1994 Wise et al 1995 Lin et al 1991 <PERSON>Chen</PERSON> et al 1998 automatically generating term associations to aid in query expansion Peat and Willett1991 Voorhees1994 Xu and Croft1996 and using co citation analysis to find general topics within a collection or identify central web pages White and McCain1989 Larson1996 Kleinberg1998 Aside from providing tools to aid in the standard information access process I think text data mining can contribute along another dimension In future I hope to see information access systems supplemented with tools for exploratory data analysis Our efforts in this direction are embodied in the LINDI project described in Section 5 below bookmark SECTION00030000000000000000 TDM and Computational Linguistics If we extrapolate from data mining as practiced on numerical data to data mining from text collections we discover that there already exists a field engaged in text data mining corpus based computational linguistics Empirical computational linguistics computes statistics over large text collections in order to discover useful patterns These patterns are used to inform algorithms for various subproblems within natural language processing such as part of speech tagging word sense disambiguation and bilingual dictionary creation Armstrong1994 It is certainly of interest to a computational linguist that the words prices prescription and patent are highly likely to co occur with the medical sense of drug while abuse paraphernalia and illicit are likely to co occur with the illegal drug sense of this word Church and Liberman1991 However the kinds of patterns found and used in computational linguistics are not likely to be what the general business community hopes for when they use the term text data mining Within the computational linguistics framework efforts in automatic augmentation of existing lexical structures seem to fit the data mining as ore extraction metaphor Examples include automatic augmentation of WordNet relations Fellbaum1998 by identifying lexico syntactic patterns that unambiguously indicate those relations Hearst1998 and automatic acquisition of subcategorization data from large text corpora Manning1993 However these serve the specific needs of computational linguistics and are not applicable to a broader audience bookmark SECTION00040000000000000000 TDM and Category Metadata Some researchers have claimed that text categorization should be considered text data mining Although analogies can be found in the data mining literature e g referring to classification of astronomical phenomena as data mining <PERSON>Fayyad</PERSON> and Uthurusamy1999 I believe when applied to text categorization this is a misnomer Text categorization is a boiling down of the specific content of a document into one or more of a set of pre defined labels This does not lead to discovery of new information presumably the person who wrote the document knew what it was about Rather it produces a compact summary of something that is already known However there are two recent areas of inquiry that make use of text categorization and do seem to fit within the conceptual framework of discovery of trends and patterns within textual data for more general purpose usage One body of work uses text category labels associated with <ORGANIZATION>Reuters</ORGANIZATION> newswire to find unexpected patterns among text articles <PERSON>Feldman</PERSON> and Dagan1995 Dagan et al 1996 <PERSON>Feldman</PERSON> et al 1997 The main approach is to compare distributions of category assignments within subsets of the document collection For instance distributions of commodities in country C1 are compared against those of country C2 to see if interesting or unexpected trends can be found Extending this idea one country s export trends might be compared against those of a set of countries that are seen as an economic unit such as the G 7 Another effort is that of the <ORGANIZATION>DARPA Topic Detection</ORGANIZATION> and Tracking initiative <PERSON>Allan</PERSON> et al 1998 While several of the tasks within this initiative are standard text analysis problems such as categorization and segmentation there is an interesting task called On line New Event Detection whose input is a stream of news stories in chronological order and whose output is a yes no decision for each story made at the time the story arrives indicating whether the story is the first reference to a newly occurring event In other words the system must detect the first instance of what will become a series of reports on some important topic Although this can be viewed as a standard classification task where the class is a binary assignment to the new event class it is more in the spirit of data mining in that the focus is on discovery of the beginning of a new theme or trend The reason I consider this examples using multiple occurrences of text categories to detect trends or patterns to be real data mining is that they use text metadata to tell us something about the world outside of the text collection itself However since these applications use metadata associated with text documents rather than the text directly it is unclear if it should be considered text data mining or standard data mining The computational linguistics applications tell us about how to improve language analysis but they do not discover more widely usable information The various contrasts made above are summarized in Table 1 bookmark table Table 1 A classification of data mining and text data mining applications Finding Patterns F inding Nuggets Novel Non Novel Non textual data standard data mining database queries Textual data computational linguistics real TDM information retrieval bookmark SECTION00050000000000000000 bookmark eda <ORGANIZATION>Text Data Mining as Exploratory Data Analysis Another</ORGANIZATION> way to view text data mining is as a process of exploratory data analysis Tukey1977 <PERSON>Hoaglin</PERSON> et al 1983 that leads to the discovery of heretofore unknown information or to answers to questions for which the answer is not currently known Of course it can be argued that the standard practice of reading textbooks journal articles and other documents helps researchers in the discovery of new information since this is an integral part of the research process However the idea here is to use text for discovery in a more direct manner Two examples are described below bookmark SECTION00051000000000000000 Using Text to Form Hypotheses about Disease For more than a decade <PERSON>Don Swanson</PERSON> has eloquently argued why it is plausible to expect new information to be derivable from text collections experts can only read a small subset of what is published in their fields and are often unaware of developments in related fields Thus it should be possible to find useful linkages between information in related literatures if the authors of those literatures rarely refer to one another s work <PERSON>Swanson</PERSON> has shown how chains of causal implication within the medical literature can lead to hypotheses for causes of rare diseases some of which have received supporting experimental evidence Swanson1987 Swanson1991 <PERSON>Swanson</PERSON> and Smalheiser1994 <PERSON>Swanson</PERSON> and Smalheiser1997 For example when investigating causes of migraine headaches he extracted various pieces of evidence from titles of articles in the biomedical literature Some of these clues can be paraphrased as follows stress is associated with migraines stress can lead to loss of magnesium calcium channel blockers prevent some migraines magnesium is a natural calcium channel blocker spreading cortical depression SCD is implicated in some migraines high leveles of magnesium inhibit SCD migraine patients have high platelet aggregability magnesium can suppress platelet aggregability These clues suggest that magnesium deficiency may play a role in some kinds of migraine headache a hypothesis which did not exist in the literature at the time <PERSON>Swanson</PERSON> found these links The hypothesis has to be tested via non textual means but the important point is that a new potentially plausible medical hypothesis was derived from a combination of text fragments and the explorer s medical expertise According to swanson91 subsequent study found support for the magnesium migraine hypothesis Ramadan et al 1989 This approach has been only partially automated There is of course a potential for combinatorial explosion of potentially valid links beeferman98 has developed a flexible interface and analysis tool for exploring certain kinds of chains of links among lexical relations within WordNet bookmark tex2html3 2 However sophisticated new algorithms are needed for helping in the pruning process since a good pruning algorithm will want to take into account various kinds of semantic constraints This may be an interesting area of investigation for computational linguists bookmark SECTION00052000000000000000 Using Text to Uncover Social Impact Switching to an entirely different domain consider a recent effort to determine the effects of publicly financed research on industrial advances <PERSON>Narin</PERSON> et al 1997 After years of preliminary studies and building special purpose tools the authors found that the technology industry relies more heavily than ever on government sponsored research results The authors explored relationships among patent text and the published research literature using a procedure which was reported as follows in broad97 The <ORGANIZATION>CHI Research</ORGANIZATION> team examined the science references on the front pages of American patents in two recent periods 1987 and 1988 as well as 1993 and 1994 looking at all the 397 660 patents issued It found 242 000 identifiable science references and zeroed in on those published in the preceding 11 years which turned out to be 80 percent of them Searches of computer databases allowed the linking of 109 000 of these references to known journals and authors addresses After eliminating redundant citations to the same paper as well as articles with no known American author the study had a core collection of 45 000 papers Armies of aides then fanned out to libraries to look up the papers and examine their closing lines which often say who financed the research That detective work revealed an extensive reliance on publicly financed science Further narrowing its focus the study set aside patents given to schools and governments and zeroed in on those awarded to industry For 2 841 patents issued in 1993 and 1994 it examined the peak year of literature references 1988 and found 5 217 citations to science papers Of these it found that 73 3 percent had been written at public institutions universities government labs and other public agencies both in the <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> and abroad Thus a heterogeneous mix of operations was required to conduct a complex analyses over large text collections These operations included 1 Retrieval of articles from a particular collection patents within a particular date range 2 Identification of the citation pool articles cited by the patents 3 Bracketing of this pool by date creating a new subset of articles 4 Computation of the percentage of articles that remain after bracketing 5 Joining these results with those of other collections to identify the publishers of articles in the pool 6 Elimination of redundant articles 7 Elimination of articles based on an attribute type author nationality 8 Location of full text versions of the articles 9 Extraction of a special attribute from the full text the acknowledgement of funding 10 Classification of this attribute by institution type 11 Narrowing the set of articles to consider by an attribute institution type 12 Computation of statistics over one of the attributes peak year 13 Computation of the percentage of articles for which one attribute has been assigned another attribute type whose citation attribute has a particular institution attribute Because all the data was not available online much of the work had to be done by hand and special purpose tools were required to perform the operations bookmark SECTION00053000000000000000 The LINDI Project The objectives of the LINDI project bookmark tex2html5 3 are to investigate how researchers can use large text collections in the discovery of new important information and to build software systems to help support this process The main tools for discovering new information are of two types support for issuing sequences of queries and related operations across text collections and tightly coupled statistical and visualization tools for the examination of associations among concepts that co occur within the retrieved documents Both sets of tools make use of attributes associated specifically with text collections and their metadata Thus the broadening narrowing and linking of relations seen in the patent example should be tightly integrated with analysis and interpretation tools as needed in the biomedical example Following amant96 the interaction paradigm is that of a mixed initiative balance of control between user and system The interaction is a cycle in which the system suggests hypotheses and strategies for investigating these hypotheses and the user either uses or ignores these suggestions and decides on the next move We are interested in an important problem in molecular biology that of automating the discovery of the function of newly sequenced genes <PERSON>Walker</PERSON> et al 1998 Human genome researchers perform experiments in which they analyze co expression of tens of thousands of novel and known genes simultaneously bookmark tex2html6 4 Given this huge collection of genetic information the goal is to determine which of the novel genes are medically interesting meaning that they are co expressed with already understood genes which are known to be involved in disease Our strategy is to explore the biomedical literature trying to formulate plausible hypotheses about which genes are of interest Most information access systems require the user to execute and keep track of tactical moves often distracting from the thought intensive aspects of the problem Bates1990 The <ORGANIZATION>LINDI</ORGANIZATION> interface provides a facility for users to build and so reuse sequences of query operations via a drag and drop interface These allow the user to repeat the same sequence of actions for different queries In the gene example this allows the user to specify a sequence of operations to apply to one co expressed gene and then iterate this sequence over a list of other co expressed genes that can be dragged onto the template The Visage interface Derthick et al 1997 implements this kind of functionality within its information centric framework These include the following operations see Figure 1 Iteration of an operation over the items within a set This allows each item retrieved in a previous query to be use as a search terms for a new query Transformation i e applying an operation to an item and returning a transformed item such as extracting a feature Ranking i e applying an operation to a set of items and returning a possibly reordered set of items with the same cardinality Selection i e applying an operation to a set of items and returning a possibly reordered set of items with the same or smaller cardinality Reduction i e applying an operation to one or more sets of items to yield a singleton result e g to compute percentages and averages This system will allow maintenance of several different types of history including history of commands issued history of strategies employed and history of hypotheses tested For the history view we plan to use a spreadsheet layout <PERSON>Hendry</PERSON> and Harper1997 as well as a variation on a slide sorter view which Visage uses for presentation creation but not for history retention Roth et al 1997 Since gene function discovery is a new area there is not yet a known set of exploration strategies So initially the system must help an expert user generate and record good exploration strategies The user interface provides a mechanism for recording and modifying sequences of actions These include facilities that refer to metadata structure allowing for example query terms to be expanded by terms one level above or below them in a subject hierarchy Once a successful set of strategies has been devised they can be re used by other researchers and with luck by an automated version of the system The intent is to build up enough strategies that the system will begin to be used as an assistant or advisor Amant1996 ranking hypotheses according to projected importance and plausibility Thus the emphasis of this system is to help automate the tedious parts of the text manipulation process and to integrate underlying computationally driven text analysis with human guided decision making within exploratory data analysis over text bookmark fig image Figure 1 A hypothetical sequence of operations for the exploration of gene function within a biomedical text collection where the functions of genes A B and C are known and commonalities are sought to hypothesize the function of the unknown gene The mapping operation imposes a rank ordering on the selected keywords The final operation is a selection of only those documents that contain at least one of the top ranked keywords and that contain mentions of all three known genes bookmark SECTION00060000000000000000 Summary For almost a decade the computational linguistics community has viewed large text collections as a resource to be tapped in order to produce better text analysis algorithms In this paper I have attempted to suggest a new emphasis the use of large online text collections to discover new facts and trends about the world itself I suggest that to make progress we do not need fully artificial intelligent text analysis rather a mixture of computationally driven and user guided analysis may open the door to exciting new results Acknowledgements <PERSON>Hao Chen Ketan Mayer Patel</PERSON> and <PERSON>Vijayshankar Raman</PERSON> contributed to the design and did all the implementation of the first LINDI prototype bookmark SECTIONREF Footnotes bookmark foot16 system bookmark foot16 1 http www aaai org Conferences KDD 1997 kdd97 schedule html bookmark foot58 WordNet bookmark foot58 2 See http www link cs cmu edu lexfn bookmark foot67 project bookmark foot67 3 LINDI Linking Information for Novel Discovery and Insight bookmark foot70 simultaneously bookmark foot70 4 A gene g co expresses with gene g when both are found to be activated in the same cells at the same time with much more likelihood than chance bookmark SECTIONREF Bibliography bookmark allan98 Allan et al 1998 J <PERSON>Allan J Carbonell G Doddington J Yamron</PERSON> and Y Yang 1998 Topic detection and tracking pilot study Final report In Proceedings of the <ORGANIZATION>DARPA Broadcast News Transcription and Understanding Workshop</ORGANIZATION> pages 194 218 bookmark amant96 Amant1996 <PERSON>Robert</PERSON> St Amant 1996 A Mixed Initiative Planning Approach to Exploratory Data Analysis Ph D thesis Univeristy of <LOCATION>Massachusetts Amherst</LOCATION> bookmark armstrong94 Armstrong1994 <PERSON>Susan Armstrong</PERSON> editor 1994 Using Large Corpora <ORGANIZATION>MIT Press</ORGANIZATION> bookmark baeza99 <PERSON>Baeza Yates</PERSON> and <PERSON>Ribeiro Neto1999 Ricardo Baeza Yates</PERSON> and <PERSON>Berthier Ribeiro Neto</PERSON> 1999 <ORGANIZATION>Modern Information Retrieval Addison Wesley Longman Publishing Company</ORGANIZATION> bookmark bates90 Bates1990 <PERSON>Marcia J Bates</PERSON> 1990 The berry picking search User interface design In Harold Thimbleby editor User Interface Design <PERSON>Addison Wesley</PERSON> bookmark beeferman98 Beeferman1998 <PERSON>Douglas Beeferman</PERSON> 1998 Lexical discovery with an enriched semantic network In Proceedings of the ACL COLING Workshop on Applications of WordNet in <ORGANIZATION>Natural Language Processing Systems</ORGANIZATION> pages 358 364 bookmark brachman93 <PERSON>Brachman</PERSON> et al 1993 R J <PERSON>Brachman</PERSON> P G Selfridge L G Terveen B Altman A Borgida F <PERSON>Halper</PERSON> T <PERSON>Kirk A Lazar D L McGuinness</PERSON> and L A Resnick 1993 Integrated support for data archaeology <ORGANIZATION>International Journal</ORGANIZATION> of Intelligent and <ORGANIZATION>Cooperative Information Systems</ORGANIZATION> 2 2 159 185 bookmark broad97 Broad1997 <PERSON>William J Broad</PERSON> 1997 Study finds public science is pillar of industry In The <ORGANIZATION>New York Times</ORGANIZATION> May 13 bookmark chalmers92 <PERSON>Chalmers</PERSON> and Chitson1992 <PERSON>Matthew Chalmers</PERSON> and <PERSON>Paul Chitson</PERSON> 1992 Bead Exploration in information visualization In Proceedings of the 15th Annual International ACM SIGIR Conference pages 330 337 <LOCATION>Copenhagen Denmark</LOCATION> bookmark hchen98 Chen et al 1998 <PERSON>Hsinchen Chen Andrea L Houston Robin R Sewell</PERSON> and <PERSON>Bruce R Schatz</PERSON> 1998 Internet browsing and searching User evaluations of category map and concept space techniques Journal of the <ORGANIZATION>American Society for Information Sciences JASIS</ORGANIZATION> 49 7 bookmark church91c Church and <ORGANIZATION>Liberman1991 Kenneth W Church</ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON>Mark Y Liberman</PERSON> 1991 A status report on the ACL DCI In The Proceedings of the 7th Annual Conference of the <LOCATION>UW Centre</LOCATION> for the New OED and <ORGANIZATION>Text Research Using Corpora</ORGANIZATION> pages 84 91 <ORGANIZATION>Oxford</ORGANIZATION> bookmark craven98 Craven et al 1998 M <PERSON>Craven</PERSON> D DiPasquo D Freitag A <ORGANIZATION>McCallum T Mitchell K Nigam</ORGANIZATION> and S Slattery 1998 Learning to extract symbolic knowledge from the world wide web In Proceedings of AAAI bookmark cutting92 Cutting et al 1992 <PERSON>Douglass</PERSON> R Cutting Jan O <PERSON>Pedersen David Karger</PERSON> and <PERSON>John W Tukey</PERSON> 1992 Scatter Gather A cluster based approach to browsing large document collections In Proceedings of the 15th Annual International ACM SIGIR Conference pages 318 329 <LOCATION>Copenhagen Denmark</LOCATION> bookmark dagan96 Dagan et al 1996 <PERSON>Ido Dagan Ronen Feldman</PERSON> and <PERSON>Haym Hirsh</PERSON> 1996 Keyword based browsing and analysis of large document sets In Proceedings of the <ORGANIZATION>Fifth Annual Symposium on Document Analysis and Information Retrieval SDAIR Las Vegas NV</ORGANIZATION> bookmark derthick97 Derthick et al 1997 <PERSON>Mark Derthick John Kolojejchick</PERSON> and <PERSON>Steven</PERSON> F Roth 1997 An interactive visualization environment for data exploration In Proceedings of the Third Annual Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining <ORGANIZATION>KDD Newport Beach</ORGANIZATION> bookmark fayyad96b <PERSON>Fayyad</PERSON> and Uthurusamy1999 <PERSON>Usama Fayyad</PERSON> and Ramasamy Uthurusamy 1999 Data mining and knowledge discovery in databases Introduction to the special issue Communications of the ACM 39 11 November bookmark fayyad97 Fayyad1997 Usama Fayyad 1997 Editorial Data Mining and Knowledge Discovery 1 1 bookmark feldman95 <PERSON>Feldman</PERSON> and Dagan1995 <PERSON>Ronen Feldman</PERSON> and <PERSON>Ido Dagan</PERSON> 1995 KDT knowledge discovery in texts In Proceedings of the First Annual Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining <ORGANIZATION>KDD</ORGANIZATION> Montreal bookmark feldman97a <PERSON>Feldman</PERSON> et al 1997 <PERSON>Ronen Feldman Will Klosgen</PERSON> and <PERSON>Amir Zilberstein</PERSON> 1997 Visualization techniques to explore data mining results for document collections In Proceedings of the Third Annual Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining <ORGANIZATION>KDD Newport Beach</ORGANIZATION> bookmark fellbaum98 Fellbaum1998 Christiane Fellbaum editor 1998 <ORGANIZATION>WordNet An Electronic Lexical Database MIT Press</ORGANIZATION> bookmark hearst98b Hearst1998 Marti A Hearst 1998 Automated discovery of wordnet relations In <PERSON>Christiane Fellbaum</PERSON> editor <ORGANIZATION>WordNet An Electronic Lexical Database MIT Press Cambridge MA</ORGANIZATION> bookmark hendry97 <PERSON>Hendry</PERSON> and Harper1997 <PERSON>David G Hendry</PERSON> and <PERSON>David J Harper</PERSON> 1997 An informal information seeking environment Journal of the <ORGANIZATION>American Society for Information Science</ORGANIZATION> 48 11 1036 1048 bookmark hoaglin83 <PERSON>Hoaglin</PERSON> et al 1983 <PERSON>David C Hoaglin Frederick Mosteller</PERSON> and <PERSON>John W Tukey</PERSON> 1983 Understanding Robust and <ORGANIZATION>Exploratory Data Analysis John Wiley amp Sons Inc</ORGANIZATION> bookmark kleinberg98 Kleinberg1998 Jon Kleinberg 1998 Authoritative sources in a hyperlinked environment In Proceedings of the 9th ACM SIAM Symposium on Discrete Algorithms bookmark larson96b Larson1996 <PERSON>Ray R Larson</PERSON> 1996 Bibliometrics of the world wide web An exploratory analysis of the intellectual structure of cyberspace In ASIS 96 Proceedings of the 1996 Annual ASIS Meeting bookmark lin91 Lin et al 1991 <PERSON>Xia Lin Dagobert Soergel</PERSON> and <PERSON>Gary Marchionini</PERSON> 1991 A self organizing semantic map for information retrieval In Proceedings of the 14th Annual International ACM SIGIR Conference pages 262 269 <LOCATION>Chicago</LOCATION> bookmark manning93 Manning1993 Christopher D Manning 1993 Automatic acquisition of a large subcategorization dictionary from corpora In Proceedings of the <ORGANIZATION>31st Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Lingusitics</ORGANIZATION> pages 235 242 <ORGANIZATION>Columbus</ORGANIZATION> OH bookmark narin97 Narin et al 1997 <PERSON>Francis Narin Kimberly S Hamilton</PERSON> and <PERSON>Dominic Olivastro</PERSON> 1997 The increasing linkage between us technology and public science Research Policy 26 3 317 330 bookmark peat91 Peat and Willett1991 <PERSON>Helen J Peat</PERSON> and <PERSON>Peter Willett</PERSON> 1991 The limitations of term co occurence data for query expansion in document retrieval systems <ORGANIZATION>JASIS</ORGANIZATION> 42 5 378 383 bookmark ramadan89 Ramadan et al 1989 N M Ramadan H <PERSON>Halvorson</PERSON> A Vandelinde and S R Levine 1989 Low brain magnesium in migraine Headache 29 7 416 419 bookmark rennison94 Rennison1994 Earl Rennison 1994 Galaxy of news An approach to visualizing and understanding expansive news landscapes In Proceedings of UIST 94 ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology pages 3 12 New York bookmark roth97 Roth et al 1997 <PERSON>Steven F Roth Mei C Chuah Stephan Kerpedjiev John A Kolojejchick</PERSON> and <PERSON>Peter Lucas</PERSON> 1997 Towards an information visualization workspace Combining multiple means of expression <ORGANIZATION>Human Computer Interaction</ORGANIZATION> 12 1 2 131 185 bookmark swanson94 <PERSON>Swanson</PERSON> and Smalheiser1994 <PERSON>Don R Swanson</PERSON> and N R Smalheiser 1994 Assessing a gap in the biomedical literature Magnesium deficiency and neurologic disease <ORGANIZATION>Neuroscience Research Communications</ORGANIZATION> 15 1 9 bookmark swanson97 <PERSON>Swanson</PERSON> and Smalheiser1997 <PERSON>Don R Swanson</PERSON> and N R Smalheiser 1997 An interactive system for finding complementary literatures a stimulus to scientific discovery Artificial Intelligence 91 183 203 bookmark swanson87 Swanson1987 Don R Swanson 1987 Two medical literatures that are logically but not bibliographically connected JASIS 38 4 228 233 bookmark swanson91 Swanson1991 Don R Swanson 1991 Complementary structures in disjoint science literatures In Proceedings of the 14th Annual International ACM SIGIR Conference pages 280 289 bookmark tukey77 Tukey1977 <PERSON>John W Tukey</PERSON> 1977 <ORGANIZATION>Exploratory Data Analysis Addison Wesley Publishing Company</ORGANIZATION> bookmark voorhees94 Voorhees1994 <PERSON>Ellen M Voorhees</PERSON> 1994 Query expansion using lexical semantic relations In Proceedings of the 17th Annual International ACM SIGIR Conference pages 61 69 <LOCATION>Dublin Ireland</LOCATION> bookmark mikewalker98 Walker et al 1998 <PERSON>Michael G Walker Walter Volkmuth Einat Sprinzak David Hodgson</PERSON> and <PERSON>Tod Klingler</PERSON> 1998 Prostate cancer genes identified by genome scale expression analysis Technical Report unnumbered Incyte Pharmaceuticals July bookmark white89 White and McCain1989 H D White and K W <PERSON>McCain</PERSON> 1989 <ORGANIZATION>Bibliometrics Annual Review of Information Science and Technology</ORGANIZATION> 24 119 186 bookmark wise95 Wise et al 1995 <PERSON>James A Wise James J Thomas Kelly Pennock David Lantrip Marc Pottier</PERSON> and <PERSON>Anne Schur</PERSON> 1995 Visualizing the non visual Spatial analysis and interaction with information from text documents In Proceedings of the <ORGANIZATION>Information Visualization Symposium 95</ORGANIZATION> pages 51 58 <ORGANIZATION>IEEE Computer Society Press</ORGANIZATION> bookmark xu96 <PERSON>Xu</PERSON> and <PERSON>Croft1996 J Xu</PERSON> and W B Croft 1996 Query expansion using local and global document analysis In SIGIR 96 Proceedings of the 19th Annual International ACM SIGIR Conference on <ORGANIZATION>Research and Development in Information Retrieval</ORGANIZATION> pages 4 11 <LOCATION>Zurich</LOCATION> bookmark SECTION00080000000000000000 About this document Untangling Text Data Mining This document was generated using the LaTeX2HTML translator Version 98 1p1 release March 2nd 1998 Copyright 1993 1994 1995 1996 1997 <ORGANIZATION>Nikos Drakos Computer Based Learning Unit University of Leeds Marti Hearst</ORGANIZATION> 1999 05 12</ner>
