<ner>Text mining From Wikipedia the free encyclopedia Jump to navigation search Text mining also referred to as text data mining roughly equivalent to text analytics is the process of deriving high quality information from text High quality information is typically derived through the devising of patterns and trends through means such as statistical pattern learning Text mining usually involves the process of structuring the input text usually parsing along with the addition of some derived linguistic features and the removal of others and subsequent insertion into a database deriving patterns within the structured data and finally evaluation and interpretation of the output High quality in text mining usually refers to some combination of relevance novelty and interestingness Typical text mining tasks include text categorization text clustering concept entity extraction production of granular taxonomies sentiment analysis document summarization and entity relation modeling i e learning relations between named entities Text analysis involves information retrieval lexical analysis to study word frequency distributions pattern recognition tagging annotation information extraction data mining techniques including link and association analysis visualization and predictive analytics The overarching goal is essentially to turn text into data for analysis via application of natural language processing <ORGANIZATION>NLP</ORGANIZATION> and analytical methods A typical application is to scan a set of documents written in a natural language and either model the document set for predictive classification purposes or populate a database or search index with the information extracted Contents 1 Text analytics 2 Future 3 Text analysis processes 4 Applications 4 1 Security applications 4 2 Biomedical applications 4 3 Software applications 4 4 Online media applications 4 5 Business and marketing applications 4 6 Sentiment analysis 4 7 Academic applications 4 8 <ORGANIZATION>Digital</ORGANIZATION> humanities and computational sociology 5 Software 6 Intellectual property law 6 1 Situation in <LOCATION>Europe</LOCATION> 6 2 Situation in the <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> 7 Implications 8 See also 9 References 9 1 Citations 9 2 Sources 10 External links Text analytics edit The term text analytics describes a set of linguistic statistical and machine learning techniques that model and structure the information content of textual sources for business intelligence exploratory data analysis research or investigation 1 The term is roughly synonymous with text mining indeed <PERSON>Ronen Feldman</PERSON> modified a 2000 description of text mining 2 in 2004 to describe text analytics 3 The latter term is now used more frequently in business settings while text mining is used in some of the earliest application areas dating to the 1980s 4 notably life sciences research and government intelligence The term text analytics also describes that application of text analytics to respond to business problems whether independently or in conjunction with query and analysis of fielded numerical data It is a truism that 80 percent of business relevant information originates in unstructured form primarily text 5 These techniques and processes discover and present knowledge facts business rules and relationships that is otherwise locked in textual form impenetrable to automated processing Future edit Increasing interest is being paid to multilingual data mining the ability to gain information across languages and cluster similar items from different linguistic sources according to their meaning The challenge of exploiting the large proportion of enterprise information that originates in unstructured form has been recognized for decades 6 It is recognized in the earliest definition of business intelligence BI in an October 1958 <ORGANIZATION>IBM Journal</ORGANIZATION> article by H P Luhn A Business Intelligence System which describes a system that will utilize data processing machines for auto abstracting and auto encoding of documents and for creating interest profiles for each of the action points in an organization Both incoming and internally generated documents are automatically abstracted characterized by a word pattern and sent automatically to appropriate action points Yet as management information systems developed starting in the 1960s and as BI emerged in the 80s and 90s as a software category and field of practice the emphasis was on numerical data stored in relational databases This is not surprising text in unstructured documents is hard to process The emergence of text analytics in its current form stems from a refocusing of research in the late 1990s from algorithm development to application as described by Prof <PERSON>Marti</PERSON> A <ORGANIZATION>Hearst</ORGANIZATION> in the paper Untangling Text Data Mining 7 For almost a decade the computational linguistics community has viewed large text collections as a resource to be tapped in order to produce better text analysis algorithms In this paper I have attempted to suggest a new emphasis the use of large online text collections to discover new facts and trends about the world itself I suggest that to make progress we do not need fully artificial intelligent text analysis rather a mixture of computationally driven and user guided analysis may open the door to exciting new results <ORGANIZATION>Hearst</ORGANIZATION> s 1999 statement of need fairly well describes the state of text analytics technology and practice a decade later Text analysis processes edit Subtasks components of a larger text analytics effort typically include Information retrieval or identification of a corpus is a preparatory step collecting or identifying a set of textual materials on the Web or held in a file system database or content corpus manager for analysis Although some text analytics systems apply exclusively advanced statistical methods many others apply more extensive natural language processing such as part of speech tagging syntactic parsing and other types of linguistic analysis citation needed Named entity recognition is the use of gazetteers or statistical techniques to identify named text features people organizations place names stock ticker symbols certain abbreviations and so on Disambiguation the use of contextual clues may be required to decide where for instance <ORGANIZATION>Ford</ORGANIZATION> can refer to a former U S president a vehicle manufacturer a movie star a river crossing or some other entity Recognition of Pattern Identified Entities Features such as telephone numbers e mail addresses quantities with units can be discerned via regular expression or other pattern matches Coreference identification of noun phrases and other terms that refer to the same object Relationship fact and event Extraction identification of associations among entities and other information in text Sentiment analysis involves discerning subjective as opposed to factual material and extracting various forms of attitudinal information sentiment opinion mood and emotion Text analytics techniques are helpful in analyzing sentiment at the entity concept or topic level and in distinguishing opinion holder and opinion object 8 Quantitative text analysis is a set of techniques stemming from the social sciences where either a human judge or a computer extracts semantic or grammatical relationships between words in order to find out the meaning or stylistic patterns of usually a casual personal text for the purpose of psychological profiling etc 9 Applications edit The technology is now broadly applied for a wide variety of government research and business needs Applications can be sorted into a number of categories by analysis type or by business function Using this approach to classifying solutions application categories include <ORGANIZATION>Enterprise Business Intelligence Data Mining Competitive Intelligence E Discovery Records Management National Security Intelligence Scientific</ORGANIZATION> discovery especially <ORGANIZATION>Life Sciences Sentiment Analysis Tools Listening Platforms Natural Language Semantic Toolkit</ORGANIZATION> or Service Publishing Automated ad placement Search Information Access Social media monitoring Security applications edit Many text mining software packages are marketed for security applications especially monitoring and analysis of online plain text sources such as Internet news blogs etc for national security purposes 10 It is also involved in the study of text encryption decryption Biomedical applications edit Main article Biomedical text mining A range of text mining applications in the biomedical literature has been described 11 One online text mining application in the biomedical literature is PubGene that combines biomedical text mining with network visualization as an Internet service 12 13 GoPubMed is a knowledge based search engine for biomedical texts Software applications edit Text mining methods and software is also being researched and developed by major firms including <ORGANIZATION>IBM</ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION>Microsoft</ORGANIZATION> to further automate the mining and analysis processes and by different firms working in the area of search and indexing in general as a way to improve their results Within public sector much effort has been concentrated on creating software for tracking and monitoring terrorist activities 14 Online media applications edit Text mining is being used by large media companies such as the <ORGANIZATION>Tribune Company</ORGANIZATION> to clarify information and to provide readers with greater search experiences which in turn increases site stickiness and revenue Additionally on the back end editors are benefiting by being able to share associate and package news across properties significantly increasing opportunities to monetize content Business and marketing applications edit Text mining is starting to be used in marketing as well more specifically in analytical customer relationship management 15 Coussement and <PERSON>Van</PERSON> den Poel 2008 16 17 apply it to improve predictive analytics models for customer churn customer attrition 16 Text mining is also being applied in stock returns prediction 18 Sentiment analysis edit Sentiment analysis may involve analysis of movie reviews for estimating how favorable a review is for a movie 19 Such an analysis may need a labeled data set or labeling of the affectivity of words Resources for affectivity of words and concepts have been made for WordNet 20 and <ORGANIZATION>ConceptNet</ORGANIZATION> 21 respectively Text has been used to detect emotions in the related area of affective computing 22 Text based approaches to affective computing have been used on multiple corpora such as students evaluations children stories and news stories Academic applications edit The issue of text mining is of importance to publishers who hold large databases of information needing indexing for retrieval This is especially true in scientific disciplines in which highly specific information is often contained within written text Therefore initiatives have been taken such as Nature s proposal for an Open Text Mining Interface OTMI and the <ORGANIZATION>National Institutes of Health</ORGANIZATION> s common Journal Publishing Document Type Definition DTD that would provide semantic cues to machines to answer specific queries contained within text without removing publisher barriers to public access Academic institutions have also become involved in the text mining initiative The National Centre for Text Mining NaCTeM is the first publicly funded text mining centre in the world NaCTeM is operated by the <ORGANIZATION>University of Manchester</ORGANIZATION> 23 in close collaboration with the Tsujii Lab 24 <ORGANIZATION>University of Tokyo</ORGANIZATION> 25 NaCTeM provides customised tools research facilities and offers advice to the academic community They are funded by the <ORGANIZATION>Joint Information Systems Committee JISC</ORGANIZATION> and two of the <LOCATION>UK</LOCATION> Research Councils EPSRC amp BBSRC With an initial focus on text mining in the biological and biomedical sciences research has since expanded into the areas of social sciences In the <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> the <ORGANIZATION>School of Information at University of California Berkeley</ORGANIZATION> is developing a program called BioText to assist biology researchers in text mining and analysis The <ORGANIZATION>Text Analysis Portal for Research TAPoR</ORGANIZATION> currently housed at the <ORGANIZATION>University of Alberta</ORGANIZATION> is a scholarly project to catalogue text analysis applications and create a gateway for researchers new to the practice <ORGANIZATION>Digital</ORGANIZATION> humanities and computational sociology edit The automatic analysis of vast textual corpora has created the possibility for scholars to analyse millions of documents in multiple languages with very limited manual intervention Key enabling technologies have been parsing machine translation topic categorization and machine learning image Narrative network of <LOCATION>US</LOCATION> Elections 2012 26 The automatic parsing of textual corpora has enabled the extraction of actors and their relational networks on a vast scale turning textual data into network data The resulting networks which can contain thousands of nodes are then analysed by using tools from network theory to identify the key actors the key communities or parties and general properties such as robustness or structural stability of the overall network or centrality of certain nodes 27 This automates the approach introduced by quantitative narrative analysis 28 whereby subject verb object triplets are identified with pairs of actors linked by an action or pairs formed by actor object 26 Content analysis has been a traditional part of social sciences and media studies for a long time The automation of content analysis has allowed a big data revolution to take place in that field with studies in social media and newspaper content that include millions of news items Gender bias readability content similarity reader preferences and even mood have been analyzed based on text mining methods over millions of documents 29 30 31 32 33 The analysis of readability gender bias and topic bias was demonstrated in <LOCATION>Flaounas</LOCATION> et al 34 showing how different topics have different gender biases and levels of readability the possibility to detect mood patterns in a vast population by analysing Twitter content was demonstrated as well 35 36 Software edit Text mining computer programs are available from many commercial and open source companies and sources See List of text mining software Intellectual property law edit Situation in <LOCATION>Europe</LOCATION> edit image File FixCopyright Copyright amp Research Text amp Data Mining TDM Explained webm Play media Video by Fix Copyright campaign explaining TDM and its copyright issues in the <ORGANIZATION>EU</ORGANIZATION> 2016 3 52 Because of a lack of flexibilities in European copyright and database law the mining of in copyright works such as web mining without the permission of the copyright owner is illegal In the <LOCATION>UK</LOCATION> in 2014 on the recommendation of the <PERSON>Hargreaves</PERSON> review the government amended copyright law 37 to allow text mining as a limitation and exception It was only the second country in the world to do so following <LOCATION>Japan</LOCATION> which introduced a mining specific exception in 2009 However owing to the restriction of the Copyright Directive the <LOCATION>UK</LOCATION> exception only allows content mining for non commercial purposes <LOCATION>UK</LOCATION> copyright law does not allow this provision to be overridden by contractual terms and conditions The European Commission facilitated stakeholder discussion on text and data mining in 2013 under the title of Licences for <ORGANIZATION>Europe</ORGANIZATION> 38 The fact that the focus on the solution to this legal issue was licences and not limitations and exceptions to copyright law led representatives of universities researchers libraries civil society groups and open access publishers to leave the stakeholder dialogue in May 2013 39 Situation in the <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> edit By contrast to <LOCATION>Europe</LOCATION> the flexible nature of <LOCATION>US</LOCATION> copyright law and in particular fair use means that text mining in <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> as well as other fair use countries such as <LOCATION>Israel Taiwan</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>South Korea</LOCATION> is viewed as being legal As text mining is transformative meaning that it does not supplant the original work it is viewed as being lawful under fair use For example as part of the <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> Book settlement the presiding judge on the case ruled that <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> s digitisation project of in copyright books was lawful in part because of the transformative uses that the digitisation project displayed one such use being text and data mining 40 Implications edit Until recently websites most often used text based searches which only found documents containing specific user defined words or phrases Now through use of a semantic web text mining can find content based on meaning and context rather than just by a specific word Additionally text mining software can be used to build large dossiers of information about specific people and events For example large datasets based on data extracted from news reports can be built to facilitate social networks analysis or counter intelligence In effect the text mining software may act in a capacity similar to an intelligence analyst or research librarian albeit with a more limited scope of analysis Text mining is also used in some email spam filters as a way of determining the characteristics of messages that are likely to be advertisements or other unwanted material Text mining plays an important role in determining financial market sentiment See also edit Concept mining Document processing Full text search List of text mining software Market sentiment Name resolution semantics and text extraction Named entity recognition News analytics Record linkage Sequential pattern mining string and sequence mining w shingling Web mining a task that may involve text mining e g first find appropriate web pages by classifying crawled web pages then extract the desired information from the text content of these pages considered relevant References edit Citations edit 1 Archived November 29 2009 at the Wayback Machine KDD 2000 Workshop on Text Mining Call for Papers Cs cmu edu Retrieved 2015 02 23 2 Archived March 3 2012 at the Wayback Machine <PERSON>Hobbs Jerry R Walker Donald E Amsler Robert</PERSON> A 1982 Proceedings of the 9th conference on Computational linguistics 1 127 32 doi 10 3115 991813 991833 Unstructured Data and the 80 Percent Rule Breakthrough Analysis Retrieved 2015 02 23 A Brief History of Text Analytics by <PERSON>Seth Grimes Beyenetwork</PERSON> 2007 10 30 Retrieved 2015 02 23 <ORGANIZATION>Hearst Marti</ORGANIZATION> A 1999 Proceedings of the 37th annual meeting of the <ORGANIZATION>Association for Computational Linguistics on Computational Linguistics</ORGANIZATION> 3 10 doi 10 3115 1034678 1034679 ISBN 1 55860 609 2 <ORGANIZATION>Full Circle Sentiment Analysis Breakthrough Analysis</ORGANIZATION> Retrieved 2015 02 23 <PERSON>Mehl Matthias</PERSON> R 2006 Handbook of multimethod measurement in psychology 141 doi 10 1037 11383 011 ISBN 1 59147 318 7 <PERSON>Zanasi Alessandro</PERSON> 2009 Proceedings of the <ORGANIZATION>International Workshop on Computational Intelligence in Security for Information Systems CISIS</ORGANIZATION> 08 Advances in Soft Computing 53 53 doi 10 1007 978 3 540 88181 0_7 ISBN 978 3 540 88180 3 <PERSON>Cohen</PERSON> K Bretonnel Hunter Lawrence 2008 Getting Started in Text Mining PLoS Computational Biology 4 1 e20 doi 10 1371 journal pcbi 0040020 PMC 2217579 image Freely accessible PMID 18225946 image open access publication free to read <PERSON>Jenssen Tor Kristian</PERSON> L greid <PERSON>Astrid Komorowski Jan Hovig Eivind</PERSON> 2001 A literature network of human genes for high throughput analysis of gene expression <ORGANIZATION>Nature Genetics</ORGANIZATION> 28 1 21 8 doi 10 1038 ng0501 21 PMID 11326270 Masys Daniel R 2001 Linking microarray data to the literature <ORGANIZATION>Nature Genetics</ORGANIZATION> 28 1 9 10 doi 10 1038 ng0501 9 PMID 11326264 3 Archived October 4 2013 at the <ORGANIZATION>Wayback Machine Text Analytics Medallia</ORGANIZATION> Retrieved 2015 02 23 a b <PERSON>Coussement Kristof Van Den Poel Dirk</PERSON> 2008 Integrating the voice of customers through call center emails into a decision support system for churn prediction <ORGANIZATION>Information amp Management</ORGANIZATION> 45 3 164 74 doi 10 1016 j im 2008 01 005 <ORGANIZATION>Coussement Kristof Van Den Poel Dirk</ORGANIZATION> 2008 Improving customer complaint management by automatic email classification using linguistic style features as predictors Decision Support Systems 44 4 870 82 doi 10 1016 j dss 2007 10 010 <PERSON>Ramiro H G lvez Agust</PERSON> n <PERSON>Gravano</PERSON> 2017 Assessing the usefulness of online message board mining in automatic stock prediction systems Journal of Computational Science 19 1877 7503 doi 10 1016 j jocs 2017 01 001 <PERSON>Pang Bo Lee Lillian Vaithyanathan Shivakumar</PERSON> 2002 Proceedings of the ACL 02 conference on Empirical methods in natural language processing 10 79 86 doi 10 3115 1118693 1118704 <PERSON>Alessandro Valitutti Carlo Strapparava Oliviero</PERSON> Stock 2005 Developing Affective Lexical Resources <ORGANIZATION>PDF Psychology Journal</ORGANIZATION> 2 1 61 83 <PERSON>Erik Cambria Robert Speer Catherine Havasi Amir Hussain</PERSON> 2010 SenticNet a Publicly Available Semantic Resource for Opinion Mining PDF Proceedings of AAAI <ORGANIZATION>CSK</ORGANIZATION> pp 14 18 <PERSON>Calvo Rafael</PERSON> A d <ORGANIZATION>Mello Sidney 2010 Affect Detection An Interdisciplinary Review of Models Methods</ORGANIZATION> and Their Applications IEEE Transactions on Affective Computing 1 1 18 37 doi 10 1109 T <ORGANIZATION>AFFC</ORGANIZATION> 2010 1 <ORGANIZATION>The University of Manchester Manchester</ORGANIZATION> ac uk Retrieved 2015 02 23 Tsujii Laboratory Tsujii is s u tokyo ac jp Retrieved 2015 02 23 The <ORGANIZATION>University of Tokyo</ORGANIZATION> UTokyo Retrieved 2015 02 23 a b Automated analysis of the <LOCATION>US</LOCATION> presidential elections using <ORGANIZATION>Big Data</ORGANIZATION> and network analysis S <ORGANIZATION>Sudhahar GA Veltri N Cristianini Big Data amp Society</ORGANIZATION> 2 1 1 28 2015 Network analysis of narrative content in large corpora S <ORGANIZATION>Sudhahar G De Fazio R Franzosi N Cristianini Natural Language Engineering</ORGANIZATION> 1 32 2013 Quantitative Narrative Analysis <PERSON>Roberto Franzosi</PERSON> <ORGANIZATION>Emory University 2010 Lansdall Welfare</ORGANIZATION> <PERSON>Thomas Sudhahar Saatviga Thompson James Lewis Justin Team</PERSON> FindMyPast Newspaper Cristianini Nello 2017 01 09 Content analysis of 150 years of British periodicals Proceedings of the <ORGANIZATION>National Academy of Sciences</ORGANIZATION> 201606380 doi 10 1073 pnas 1606380114 ISSN 0027 8424 PMID 28069962 I Flaounas M <PERSON>Turchi O Ali N Fyson T De Bie N Mosdell J Lewis</PERSON> N Cristianini The Structure of <ORGANIZATION>EU Mediasphere PLoS ONE Vol</ORGANIZATION> 5 12 pp e14243 2010 Nowcasting Events from the Social Web with Statistical Learning V Lampos N Cristianini ACM Transactions on <ORGANIZATION>Intelligent Systems and Technology TIST</ORGANIZATION> 3 4 72 NOAM news outlets analysis and monitoring system I Flaounas O <PERSON>Ali M Turchi</PERSON> T <PERSON>Snowsill</PERSON> F <ORGANIZATION>Nicart T De Bie N Cristianini Proc</ORGANIZATION> of the 2011 ACM SIGMOD international conference on Management of data Automatic discovery of patterns in media content N Cristianini Combinatorial Pattern Matching 2 13 2011 I <ORGANIZATION>Flaounas O Ali T Lansdall Welfare</ORGANIZATION> T <PERSON>De Bie N Mosdell J Lewis</PERSON> N Cristianini RESEARCH METHODS IN THE AGE OF DIGITAL JOURNALISM Digital Journalism Routledge 2012 Circadian Mood Variations in <ORGANIZATION>Twitter Content Fabon Dzogang Stafford Lightman Nello Cristianini Brain and Neuroscience Advances</ORGANIZATION> 1 2398212817744501 Effects of the Recession on <ORGANIZATION>Public Mood</ORGANIZATION> in the <LOCATION>UK</LOCATION> T <ORGANIZATION>Lansdall Welfare V Lampos N Cristianini Mining Social Network Dynamics</ORGANIZATION> MSND session on Social Media Applications 4 Archived June 9 2014 at the <ORGANIZATION>Wayback Machine Licences for Europe Structured Stakeholder Dialogue 2013 European Commission</ORGANIZATION> Retrieved 14 November 2014 Text and Data Mining Its importance and the need for change in <ORGANIZATION>Europe Association of European Research Libraries Retrieved</ORGANIZATION> 14 November 2014 Judge grants summary judgment in favor of <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> Books a fair use victory Lexology com <ORGANIZATION>Antonelli Law Ltd</ORGANIZATION> Retrieved 14 November 2014 Sources edit Ananiadou S and <PERSON>McNaught</PERSON> J Editors 2006 Text Mining for Biology and <ORGANIZATION>Biomedicine Artech House</ORGANIZATION> Books ISBN 978 1 58053 984 5 Bilisoly R 2008 Practical Text Mining with <PERSON>Perl New York John Wiley</PERSON> amp Sons ISBN 978 0 470 17643 6 <ORGANIZATION>Feldman R</ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON>Sanger</PERSON> J 2006 The <ORGANIZATION>Text Mining Handbook New York Cambridge University Press ISBN</ORGANIZATION> 978 0 521 83657 9 Indurkhya N and Damerau F 2010 Handbook Of Natural Language Processing 2nd Edition Boca Raton FL CRC Press ISBN 978 1 4200 8592 1 Kao A and <ORGANIZATION>Poteet S Editors Natural Language Processing</ORGANIZATION> and Text Mining Springer ISBN 1 84628 175 X Konchady M Text Mining Application Programming Programming Series Charles River Media ISBN 1 58450 460 9 Manning C and <PERSON>Schutze</PERSON> H 1999 Foundations of <ORGANIZATION>Statistical Natural Language Processing Cambridge MA MIT Press</ORGANIZATION> ISBN 978 0 262 13360 9 <ORGANIZATION>Miner G Elder J Hill</ORGANIZATION> T <PERSON>Nisbet R Delen</PERSON> D and Fast A 2012 Practical Text Mining and <ORGANIZATION>Statistical Analysis for Non</ORGANIZATION> structured <ORGANIZATION>Text Data Applications Elsevier Academic Press ISBN</ORGANIZATION> 978 0 12 386979 1 McKnight W 2005 Building business intelligence Text data mining in business intelligence DM Review 21 22 Srivastava A and Sahami M 2009 Text Mining Classification Clustering and <ORGANIZATION>Applications Boca Raton FL CRC Press</ORGANIZATION> ISBN 978 1 4200 5940 3 Zanasi A Editor 2007 Text Mining and its Applications to <ORGANIZATION>Intelligence CRM</ORGANIZATION> and Knowledge Management WIT Press ISBN 978 1 84564 131 3 External links edit Marti Hearst What Is Text Mining October 2003 Automatic Content Extraction Linguistic Data Consortium Automatic Content Extraction <ORGANIZATION>NIST Research</ORGANIZATION> work and applications of Text Mining for instance AgroNLP Text Mining Free Tools <PERSON>Wui Lee Chang Kai Meng Tay</PERSON> and <PERSON>Chee Peng Lim</PERSON> A New Evolving Tree Based Model with Local Re learning for Document Clustering and Visualization Neural Processing Letters DOI 10 1007 s11063 017 9597 3 https link springer com article 10 1007 s11063 017 9597 3 <ORGANIZATION>Authority</ORGANIZATION> control NDL 01119322 image Retrieved from https en wikipedia org w index php title Text_mining amp oldid 829722012 Categories Text mining Artificial intelligence applications Applied data mining Computational linguistics Natural language processing Statistical natural language processing Text Hidden categories Webarchive template wayback links All articles with unsourced statements Articles with unsourced statements from February 2012 Navigation menu Personal tools Not logged in Talk Contributions Create account Log in Namespaces Article Talk Variants Views Read Edit View history More Search Navigation Main page Contents Featured content Current events Random article Donate to <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> store Interaction Help About Wikipedia Community portal Recent changes Contact page Tools What links here Related changes Upload file Special pages Permanent link Page information Wikidata item Cite this page Print export Create a book Download as PDF Printable version In other projects Wikimedia Commons Languages e tina <ORGANIZATION>Deutsch Espa</ORGANIZATION> ol Euskara Fran ais <LOCATION>Bahasa Indonesia Magyar Nederlands Polski Portugu</LOCATION> s <ORGANIZATION>Sloven ina Svenska T</ORGANIZATION> rk e <PERSON>Ti ng Vi</PERSON> t Edit links This page was last edited on 10 March 2018 at 11 24 Text is available under the Creative Commons Attribution ShareAlike License additional terms may apply By using this site you agree to the Terms of Use and <ORGANIZATION>Privacy Policy Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> is a registered trademark of the <ORGANIZATION>Wikimedia Foundation Inc</ORGANIZATION> a non profit organization Privacy policy <ORGANIZATION>About Wikipedia Disclaimers Contact Wikipedia Developers Cookie</ORGANIZATION> statement Mobile view image <ORGANIZATION>Wikimedia Foundation</ORGANIZATION> image Powered by <PERSON>MediaWiki</PERSON></ner>
