<ner>Skip to main content image SSRN logo Advanced Browse Subscriptions Rankings Top Papers Top Authors Top Organizations Submit a paper My Library Blog Register now REGISTER SIGN IN Email This field is required Password This field is required Sign in Remember me Forgot ID or Password Register now Public User Public User Your Account User Home Personal Info Affiliations Subscriptions My Papers My Library Sign out Advanced Search Download This Paper Open PDF in Browser Add Paper to My Library Share Permalink Using the URL or DOI link below will ensure access to this page indefinitely Copy URL Copy URL Fashionable Functions A <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> Ngram View of Trends in Functional Differentiation 1800 2000 International Journal of Technology and Human Interaction Vol 10 No 2 pp 34 58 2014 28 Pages Posted 4 Sep 2014 Last revised 28 Aug 2016 <ORGANIZATION>Steffen Roth La Rochelle Business School Yerevan State University</ORGANIZATION> Date Written 2014 Abstract Computer communication is revolutionizing modern society to the same extend as the invention of writing or the printing press have unsettled the archaic or the ancient society respectively In the present article this idea will be exemplified by a demonstration of how the <ORGANIZATION>Google Ngram</ORGANIZATION> viewer an online graphing tool which charts annual counts of words or sentences as found in the largest available corpus of digitalized books allows for checks and challenges of familiar self definitions of modern society As functional differentiation is considered the central unique feature of modern societies the hypotheses focus on the testing of prominent modern trend statements and predictions such as the secularization politicization economization and mediatization of society All hypotheses are tested through a comparative analysis of word frequency time series plots produced by means of the <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> Ngram Viewer The results show that the importance of individual function systems to society features signifcant change in time and considerable regional differences Furthermore the findings suggest adopting a skeptical position on some of the most frequent common senses of trends in functional differentiation and corresponding self defnitions of society Keywords Culturomics Economization Function Systems Functional Differentiation Google Ngram Mediatization Politicization Secularization Social Systems JEL Classification Z1 Z10 Suggested Citation Suggested Citation Roth Steffen Fashionable Functions A <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> Ngram View of Trends in Functional Differentiation 1800 2000 2014 International Journal of Technology and Human Interaction Vol 10 No 2 pp 34 58 2014 Available at SSRN https ssrn com abstract 2491422 <ORGANIZATION>Steffen Roth Contact Author Yerevan State University</ORGANIZATION> email <PERSON>Alex Manoogian</PERSON> 1 <LOCATION>Yerevan</LOCATION> 0025 <LOCATION>Armenia</LOCATION> La <ORGANIZATION>Rochelle Business School</ORGANIZATION> email 102 <LOCATION>rue de Coureilles Les Minimes La Rochelle</LOCATION> 17024 <LOCATION>France</LOCATION> Download This Paper Open PDF in Browser Register to support our free research Register Paper statistics Downloads 1 220 rank 13 839 Abstract Views 5 233 PlumX Related eJournals Writing Technologies eJournal Follow Writing Technologies eJournal Subscribe to this free journal for more curated articles on this topic FOLLOWERS 832 PAPERS 1 091 This Journal is curated by <PERSON>David C Logan</PERSON> at <ORGANIZATION>University of Southern California Marshall School of Business Cultural Anthropology eJournal Follow Cultural Anthropology eJournal Subscribe</ORGANIZATION> to this fee journal for more curated articles on this topic FOLLOWERS 653 PAPERS 28 467 <ORGANIZATION>Econometrics Computer Programs amp Software eJournal Follow Econometrics Computer Programs amp Software eJournal Subscribe</ORGANIZATION> to this fee journal for more curated articles on this topic FOLLOWERS 475 PAPERS 383 Economic History eJournal Follow Economic History eJournal Subscribe to this fee journal for more curated articles on this topic FOLLOWERS 403 PAPERS 6 312 This Journal is curated by <PERSON>Chris Minns</PERSON> at <ORGANIZATION>London School of Economics amp Political Science LSE Department of Economic History Jeffrey G Williamson</ORGANIZATION> at <ORGANIZATION>Harvard University Department of Economics Laird Bell Professor of Economics Emeritus European Economics Political Economy amp Public Economics eJournal Follow European Economics Political Economy amp Public Economics eJournal Subscribe</ORGANIZATION> to this fee journal for more curated articles on this topic FOLLOWERS 394 PAPERS 8 973 This Journal is curated by <PERSON>Marco Da Rin</PERSON> at <ORGANIZATION>Tilburg University Department of Finance</ORGANIZATION> <PERSON>Francesco Giavazzi</PERSON> at <ORGANIZATION>University of Bocconi Innocenzo Gasparini Institute for Economic Research IGIER Linguistic Anthropology eJournal Follow Linguistic Anthropology eJournal Subscribe</ORGANIZATION> to this fee journal for more curated articles on this topic FOLLOWERS 279 PAPERS 1 807 Philosophy of Language eJournal Follow Philosophy of Language eJournal Subscribe to this free journal for more curated articles on this topic FOLLOWERS 253 PAPERS 771 <ORGANIZATION>Econometrics Econometric</ORGANIZATION> amp Statistical Methods Special Topics eJournal Follow <ORGANIZATION>Econometrics Econometric</ORGANIZATION> amp Statistical Methods Special Topics eJournal Subscribe to this fee journal for more curated articles on this topic FOLLOWERS 170 PAPERS 6 282 Comparative Political Economy Comparative Capitalism eJournal Follow Comparative Political Economy Comparative Capitalism eJournal Subscribe to this fee journal for more curated articles on this topic FOLLOWERS 46 PAPERS 5 443 This Journal is curated by <PERSON>Frances McCall Rosenbluth</PERSON> at <ORGANIZATION>Yale University Department of Political Science Political Methods Computational</ORGANIZATION> eJournal Follow Political Methods Computational eJournal Subscribe to this fee journal for more curated articles on this topic FOLLOWERS 32 PAPERS 143 Recommended Papers Common Values Fifty Two Cases of Value Semantics Copying on Corporate Websites By <ORGANIZATION>Steffen Roth Coining Societies An Inter Functional Comparative Analysis</ORGANIZATION> of the Euro By <PERSON>Steffen Roth</PERSON> The <ORGANIZATION>Multifunctional Organization Two Cases for a Critical Update for Research Programs</ORGANIZATION> in Management and Organization By <ORGANIZATION>Steffen Roth Booties Bounties Business Models</ORGANIZATION> A Map to the Next Red Oceans By <PERSON>Steffen Roth</PERSON> Smart Regions Two Cases of Crowdsourcing for Regional Development By <PERSON>Steffen Roth Jari Kaivo</PERSON> oja The Things that Go Without Saying On Performative Differences between <ORGANIZATION>Business Value Communication</ORGANIZATION> and Communication on Business Values By <PERSON>Steffen Roth</PERSON> Leaving Commonplaces on the Common Place Cornerstones of a Polyphonic Market Theory By <PERSON>Steffen Roth</PERSON> Ten Systems Toward a Canon of Function Systems By <PERSON>Steffen Roth</PERSON> and <PERSON>Anton Sch</PERSON> tz Future Industrial Platforms and Radical Technology Foresight The Case of 3D Printing in <LOCATION>Finland</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Europe</LOCATION> By <PERSON>Jari Kaivo</PERSON> oja <ORGANIZATION>Toni Ahlqvist Les Deux Angleterres Et Le Continent Anglophone Sociology</ORGANIZATION> as the Guardian of Old European Semantics By <PERSON>Steffen Roth</PERSON> Feedback Feedback to SSRN Feedback required Email required Submit If you need immediate assistance call 877 SSRNHelp 877 777 6435 in the <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> or 1 585 442 8170 outside of the <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> 8 30AM to 6 00PM U S Eastern Monday Friday image Submit a Paper Section 508 Text Only Pages SSRN Quick Links SSRN Solutions Research Paper Series Conference Papers Partners in <ORGANIZATION>Publishing Jobs amp Announcements Newsletter</ORGANIZATION> Sign Up SSRN Rankings Top Papers Top Authors Top Organizations About SSRN SSRN Objectives Network Directors Presidential Letter Announcements Contact us FAQs image Elsevier logo Copyright Terms and Conditions Privacy Policy Cookies are used by this site To decline or learn more visit our Cookies page This page was processed by apollobot1 in 0 188 seconds image <ORGANIZATION>Relx Group</ORGANIZATION> logo image</ner>
