<ner>bookmark top image resources guide banner home about ask online publications online resources related projects events order a copy now published by <ORGANIZATION>West Virginia University Press</ORGANIZATION> 2001 revised Contents Preface Introduction <PERSON>Marilyn Deegan</PERSON> Starting points on the Internet Frances Condron Classics and ancient history <PERSON>Frances Condron Language</PERSON> and linguistics <PERSON>Frances Condron</PERSON> Literature in English and other languages <ORGANIZATION>Stuart Sutherland Frances Condron Media</ORGANIZATION> and film <ORGANIZATION>Stuart Sutherland Philosophy Frances Condron Religion</ORGANIZATION> and theology <PERSON>Michael Fraser</PERSON> Text creation and analysis <PERSON>Michael Fraser Frances Condron</PERSON> Fonts and special characters <ORGANIZATION>Frances Condron Bibliographic</ORGANIZATION> resources <PERSON>Stuart Sutherland</PERSON> Teaching learning and assessment resources Frances Condron Index Bibliography Acknowledgements Glossary of Terms image black line Photo from the Guide launch event Friday 18 February 2000 <ORGANIZATION>Ashmolean Museum Oxford</ORGANIZATION> image back to contents guide contents top of this page image back to contents image black line HTML admin <PERSON>Michael Fraser</PERSON> Document created Feb Mar 2000 Document last modified October 2002 The URL of this document is http info ox ac uk ctitext resguide2000 contents shtml</ner>
