<ner>image Digging Into Data Web Site Search Wednesday May 16 2012 Home Award Recipients 2009 Site Navigation image image Home image image image Repositories image image image DiD Logos image image image Award Recipients 2009 image image image Digging into Image Data image image image Digging into the Enlightenment image image image Mining a Year of Speech image image image Structural Analysis of Large Amounts of Music image image image Harvesting Speech Datasets for Linguistic Research image image image Using Zotero and TAPoR on the Old <PERSON>Bailey</PERSON> image image image Towards Dynamic Variorum Editions image image image Railroads and the Making of Modern <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> image image image Conference for 2009 Awardees image image image Award Recipients 2011 bookmark 610 Awardees of 2009 Digging into Data Challenge image Minimize Congratulations to the 2009 Digging into Data Challenge Awardees and a big thank you to all the teams that competed and the many libraries and archives that made their collections available to the researchers Important note Each DiD project is composed of an international team of scholars and scientists Each team had to select one institution to be the awardee of record for each granting agency However many other institutions played critical roles in each project Below we will list both the awardees of record as well as other key team members Digging into <ORGANIZATION>Image Data to Answer Authorship Related Questions Awardees Dean Rehberger Michigan State University NEH Peter Bajcsy University of Illinois at Urbana Champaign NSF Peter Ainsworth University of Sheffield JISC</ORGANIZATION> more gt Digging into the Enlightenment Mapping the Republic of Letters Awardees <PERSON>Dan Edelstein</PERSON> <ORGANIZATION>Stanford University NEH Chris Weaver University of Oklahoma NSF Robert McNamee University of Oxford</ORGANIZATION> JISC more gt Mining a Year of <ORGANIZATION>Speech Awardees Mark Liberman University of Pennsylvania NSF John Coleman University of Oxford</ORGANIZATION> JISC Additional Key Participants The British Library more gt <ORGANIZATION>Structural Analysis of Large Amounts of Musical Information Awardees Stephen Downie University of Illinois</ORGANIZATION> at <ORGANIZATION>Urbana Champaign NSF David De Roure University of Southhampton JISC Ichiro Fujinaga McGill University</ORGANIZATION> SSHRC more gt Harvesting Speech Datasets for Linguistic Research on the Web Awardees <ORGANIZATION>Mats Rooth Cornell University NSF Michael Wagner McGill University</ORGANIZATION> SSHRC Description This project will harvest audio and transcribed data more gt Using Zotero and TAPOR on the <ORGANIZATION>Old Bailey Proceedings Data Mining</ORGANIZATION> with <ORGANIZATION>Criminal Intent Awardees Dan Cohen George Mason University NEH Tim Hitchcock University of Hertfordshire JISC Geoffrey Rockwell University of Alberta</ORGANIZATION> SSHRC more gt Towards Dynamic Variorum Editions Awardees Gregory Crane <ORGANIZATION>Tufts University NEH John Darlington Imperial College London JISC Bruce Robertson Mount Allison University</ORGANIZATION> SSHRC more gt Railroads and the making of <ORGANIZATION>Modern America Tools for Spatio Temporal Correlation Analysis and Visualization Awardees William Thomas University of Nebraska Lincoln NEH Richard Healey University of Portsmouth</ORGANIZATION> JISC Additional Key Participants The <ORGANIZATION>University of Victoria</ORGANIZATION> more gt image Print image bookmark 620 Announcement of 2009 Competition image Minimize The Digging into Data Challenge is an international grant competition sponsored by four leading research agencies the <ORGANIZATION>Joint Information Systems Committee JISC</ORGANIZATION> from the <ORGANIZATION>United Kingdom the National Endowment for the Humanities NEH</ORGANIZATION> from the <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> the <ORGANIZATION>National Science Foundation NSF</ORGANIZATION> from the <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> and the <ORGANIZATION>Social Sciences and Humanities Research Council</ORGANIZATION> SSHRC from <LOCATION>Canada</LOCATION> What is the challenge we speak of The idea behind the Digging into Data Challenge is to answer the question what do you do with a million books Or a million pages of newspaper Or a million photographs of artwork That is how does the notion of scale affect humanities and social science research Now that scholars have access to huge repositories of digitized data far more than they could read in a lifetime what does that mean for research Applicants will form international teams from at least two of the participating countries Winning teams will receive grants from two or more of the funding agencies and one year later will be invited to show off their work at a special conference Our hope is that these projects will serve as exemplars to the field The advent of what has been called data driven inquiry or cyberscholarship has changed the nature of inquiry across many disciplines including the sciences and humanities revealing new opportunities for interdisciplinary collaboration on problems of common interest The creation of vast quantities of Internet accessible digital data and the development of techniques for large scale data analysis and visualization have led to remarkable new discoveries in genetics astronomy and other fields and importantly connections between academic disciplinary areas New techniques of large scale data analysis allow researchers to discover relationships detect discrepancies and perform computations on data sets that are so large that they can be processed only using computing resources and computational methods developed and made economically affordable within the past few years With books newspapers journals films artworks and sound recordings being digitized on a massive scale it is possible to apply data analysis techniques to large collections of diverse cultural heritage resources as well as scientific data How might these techniques help scholars use these materials to ask new questions about and gain new insights into our world To encourage innovative approaches to this question four international research organizations are organizing a joint grant competition to focus the attention of the social science and humanities research communities on large scale data analysis and its potential application to a wide range of scholarly resources The goals of the initiative are to promote the development and deployment of innovative research techniques in large scale data analysis to foster interdisciplinary collaboration among scholars in the humanities social sciences computer sciences information sciences and other fields around questions of text and data analysis to promote international collaboration and to work with data repositories that hold large digital collections to ensure efficient access to these materials for research If you are interested in taking up this challenge please read the <ORGANIZATION>RFP</ORGANIZATION> and addenda available on this page image Print image bookmark 622 2009 Sponsors image Minimize image Agency Logos image Print image bookmark 619 Press image Minimize Press Releases About the Launch off Digging into Data Challenge January 2009 JISC NEH NSF SSHRC Press Releases about Awardees December 2009 JISC NEH NSF SSHRC Speech by <ORGANIZATION>NEH</ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON>Jim Leach</PERSON> at DiD awards ceremony Articles about the Winning Projects PhysOrg com December 4 2009 Digging into Data Challenge grant awarded The Tufts Daily December 4 2009 Classics department researchers earn grant The <ORGANIZATION>Chronicle</ORGANIZATION> of Higher Education December 4 2009 A New Digital Class Digs Into Data Inside HPC December 7 2009 What would you do with one million books HPCWire December 11 2009 Grant Supports Computational Analysis Of Manuscripts Maps and Quilts The Chronicle of Higher Education December 13 2009 How to Prepare Your College for an Uncertain Digital Future The Mason Gazette December 15 2009 Digging through the History of Crime Wins Center a <ORGANIZATION>Federal Grant McGill</ORGANIZATION> Reporter December 17 2009 Two <ORGANIZATION>McGill</ORGANIZATION> researchers among winners of new international competition The <ORGANIZATION>New York Times</ORGANIZATION> November 16 2010 <ORGANIZATION>Digital Keys</ORGANIZATION> for Unlocking the Humanities Riches image Print image bookmark 621 Related Reading image Minimize Below are some related readings Please feel free to send us further suggestions <PERSON>Anderson Chris</PERSON> The End of Theory The Data Deluge Makes the Scientific Method Obsolete Wired 16 07 2008 Arms <PERSON>William</PERSON> and <PERSON>Ronald Larsen</PERSON> editors The Future of Scholarly Communication Building the Infrastructure for Cyberscholarship NSF JISC workshop <ORGANIZATION>Phoenix Arizona</ORGANIZATION> April 17 to 19 2007 Clement <PERSON>Tanya Sara Steger John Unsworth</PERSON> and <PERSON>Kirsten Uszkalo</PERSON> How Not to Read a Million Books Presentation at <ORGANIZATION>Harvard University 2008 Cohen Daniel From Babel</ORGANIZATION> to <ORGANIZATION>Knowledge Data Mining Large Digital Collections D Lib Magazine</ORGANIZATION> 12 3 2006 Cohen KB Hunter L Getting Started in Text Mining PLoS Computational Biology 4 1 e20 doi 10 1371 journal pcbi 0040020 <PERSON>Crane Greg</PERSON> What Do You Do with a <ORGANIZATION>Million Books D Lib Magazine</ORGANIZATION> 12 3 2006 <ORGANIZATION>Friedlander Amy</ORGANIZATION> editor <ORGANIZATION>Promoting Digital Scholarship Formulating Research Challenges</ORGANIZATION> in the <ORGANIZATION>Humanities Social Sciences and Computation Council on Library</ORGANIZATION> and Information Resources 2008 <PERSON>Halevy Alon Peter Norvig</PERSON> and <PERSON>Fernando Pereira</PERSON> The Unreasonable Effectiveness of Data IEEE Intelligent Systems vol 24 no 2 pp 8 12 Mar Apr 2009 doi 10 1109 MIS 2009 36 Venter Craig Bigger Faster Better Seed November 20 2008 image Print image bookmark 623 Contact image Minimize image ODH Logo The Digging into Data Challenge is being administered by the <ORGANIZATION>Office of Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> at the <ORGANIZATION>National Endowment for the Humanities</ORGANIZATION> To contact ODH with any kinds of questions please send us an e mail If you have funder specific questions please see the specific contact information found in each RFP Addendum image Twitter Icon Follow us on Twitter image Print image image image Privacy Terms of Use</ner>
