<ner>Welcome Guest Log In Register Membership Benefits image Intelligent Enterprise Better Insight for Business Decisions image Intelligent Enterprise Better Insight for Business Decisions image search Intelligent Enterprise image RSS Webcasts Digital Library Subscribe Home BUSINESS INTELLIGENCE ENTERPRISE APPLICATIONS INFORMATION MANAGEMENT PERFORMANCE MANAGEMENT PROCESS MANAGEMENT BLOGS EXPERTS image Breakthrough Analysis by <PERSON>Seth Grimes Seth Grimes</PERSON> is an analytics strategist with <LOCATION>Washington DC</LOCATION> based <ORGANIZATION>Alta Plana Corporation</ORGANIZATION> He consults on data management and analysis systems See More by <PERSON>Seth Grimes</PERSON> E MAIL image Follow Us on Twitter FOLLOW <LOCATION>US</LOCATION> image Share Defining Text Analytics image Posted by <PERSON>Seth Grimes</PERSON> Thursday February 8 2007 10 37 AM I ve been writing and speaking and consulting on text analytics for years This work led to a recent call from <PERSON>Philip Russom</PERSON> an analyst at the <ORGANIZATION>Data Warehousing Institute</ORGANIZATION> late of <PERSON>Forrester Giga Hurwitz</PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION>Intelligent Enterprise Philip</ORGANIZATION> invited me to contribute an expert comment my take on text analytics in six sentences or fewer for a forthcoming <ORGANIZATION>TDWI</ORGANIZATION> report on BI search and text analytics I failed I took eight sentences we ll see if <PERSON>Philip</PERSON> cuts them down and I thought I d share the lot with you bookmark more Text analytics is technology and process both a mechanism for knowledge discovery applied to documents a means of finding value in text Solutions mine documents and other forms of unstructured data They analyze linguistic structure and apply statistical and machine learning techniques to discern entities names dates places terms and their attributes as well as relationships concepts and even sentiments They extract these features to databases for further analysis and automate classification and processing of source documents They exploit visualization for exploratory analysis of discovered information Text analytics goes beyond search to turn documents into data It extends <ORGANIZATION>Business Intelligence BI</ORGANIZATION> and data mining and brings analytical power to content management Together these complementary technologies have the potential to turn knowledge management into knowledge analytics Does this capture the matter I fear my definition is a bit grandiose That would reflect my enthusiasm for text analytics The technology broadly or narrowly defined and still in an early adoption phase has demonstrated potential to add value to many diverse applications Let me know your take And if you re a text analytics researcher or vendor or practitioner send me your predictions of what s next for text for a white paper I m writing for the 2007 instance of the Text Analytics Summit that I chair Top of my list is Question Answering which I wrote about in a Breakthrough Analysis column last year Text analytics is about making human communications comprehensible to computers However the field does develop I know it will remain intriguing a rewarding IT discipline to be involved in <LOCATION>Technorati Profile</LOCATION> image E MAIL image Follow Us on Twitter FOLLOW <LOCATION>US</LOCATION> image Share bookmark comments image This is a public forum <ORGANIZATION>United Business Media</ORGANIZATION> and its affiliates are not responsible for and do not control what is posted herein <ORGANIZATION>United Business Media</ORGANIZATION> makes no warranties or guarantees concerning any advice dispensed by its staff members or readers image Community standards in this comment area do not permit hate language excessive profanity or other patently offensive language Please be aware that all information posted to this comment area becomes the property of <ORGANIZATION>United Business Media LLC</ORGANIZATION> and may be edited and republished in print or electronic format as outlined in <ORGANIZATION>United Business Media</ORGANIZATION> s Terms of Service image Important Note This comment area is NOT intended for commercial messages or solicitations of business image image Blog Channels image <PERSON>Cindi Howson</PERSON> on Business Intelligence image <PERSON>Tony Byrne</PERSON> on Content Management image Rajan Chandras on IT amp Information Management image <PERSON>Seth Grimes</PERSON> on Analytics image In Context by <PERSON>Doug Henschen</PERSON> image <PERSON>Phil Kemelor</PERSON> on Web Analytics image <PERSON>Sandy Kemsley</PERSON> s Column Two image Nelson King on Enterprise App Development image <PERSON>David Linthicum</PERSON> on Changing the Enterprise image SharePoint TrendWatch by <PERSON>Shawn Shell</PERSON> image Data Frontiers by <PERSON>Curt Monash</PERSON> image Enterprise Architecture TrendWatch by <PERSON>Kas Thomas</PERSON> image <PERSON>Alan Pelz Sharpe</PERSON> on Content Management image <PERSON>Neil Raden</PERSON> on Business Intelligence image Bruce Silver on Business Process Management image STRATEGIC KNOWLEDGE BY DAVE STODDER image Subscribe to RSS feed of all blogs Archives November 2009 October 2009 September 2009 August 2009 July 2009 June 2009 May 2009 April 2009 March 2009 February 2009 January 2009 December 2008 November 2008 October 2008 September 2008 August 2008 July 2008 June 2008 May 2008 April 2008 March 2008 February 2008 January 2008 December 2007 November 2007 October 2007 September 2007 August 2007 July 2007 June 2007 May 2007 April 2007 March 2007 February 2007 January 2007 December 2006 November 2006 October 2006 August 2006 July 2006 June 2006 May 2006 April 2006 March 2006 February 2006 January 2006 December 2005 November 2005 October 2005 September 2005 August 2005 July 2005 June 2005 April 2005 March 2005 image image TechWeb image The Global Leader In Technology Media <ORGANIZATION>InformationWeek Business Technology Network Advanced Trading Bank Systems amp Technology Bank Systems amp Technology</ORGANIZATION> Executive Summit bMighty com Contentinople Dark Reading Dr Dobbs <ORGANIZATION>InformationWeek</ORGANIZATION> InformationWeek 500 <ORGANIZATION>InformationWeek</ORGANIZATION> 500 Conference <ORGANIZATION>InformationWeek Analytics InformationWeek Events InformationWeek Financial Services InformationWeek Global CIO InformationWeek</ORGANIZATION> Government <ORGANIZATION>InformationWeek Healthcare InformationWeek India InformationWeek Magazine Insurance amp Technology Insurance amp Technology</ORGANIZATION> Executive Summit Intelligent Enterprise Internet Evolution Network Computing No Jitter Plug into the Cloud Wall Street amp Technology image Light Reading Communications Network Heavy Reading Light Reading Light Reading Asia Light Reading Insider Light Reading Live Light Reading s Digital Cable News Light Reading s Ethernet Expo Pyramid Research TelcoTV Tower Technology Summit Unstrung image <ORGANIZATION>TechWeb Events Network Black Hat Cloud Connect Enterprise</ORGANIZATION> 2 0 Gov 2 0 Expo Gov 2 0 Summit <ORGANIZATION>GTEC Interop VoiceCon</ORGANIZATION> Web 2 0 Expo Web 2 0 Summit image Most Popular ANTenna <PERSON>Bob Evan</PERSON> s Global CIO Cable Catchup <PERSON>David Berlind</PERSON> s <ORGANIZATION>Tech Radar Digital Life Enterprise</ORGANIZATION> 2 0 Blog Evil Bytes <ORGANIZATION>InformationWeek Analytics Interop Blog</ORGANIZATION> <PERSON>Jon Erickson</PERSON> s Blog Microsoft Windows Blog Monkey Bidness Over the Air The <ORGANIZATION>Philter Valley Wonk</ORGANIZATION> Web 2 0 Blog <PERSON>Wolfe</PERSON> s <ORGANIZATION>Den About TechWeb Advertising Contacts Become</ORGANIZATION> a Member Membership Benefits Contact Us Feedback Reprints Technology Marketing Solutions TechWeb Digital Library White Papers TechWeb com <ORGANIZATION>News Business Intelligence Enterprise Applications Information Management</ORGANIZATION> Performance Management Process Management White Papers About Us Advertising Contacts Technology Marketing Solutions Blogosphere Intelligent Enterprise Print Archive Newsletters Contact Us Events Awards PR Info Authors TechWebCasts Database Magazine Print Archive Site Map Privacy Terms of Service Copyright 2009 <ORGANIZATION>United Business Media LLC</ORGANIZATION></ner>
