<ner>Skip to content CUNY Academic Commons Wiki Archive Menu Home Contents From CUNY Academic Commons image Here are just a few examples of <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> work to give a sense of its range What other projects would you want to show to a beginning DHer bookmark Advocacy Advocacy 4Humanities a site created by the international community of DH scholars and educators to assist in advocating for the humanities Provides a communication platform tools and resources The humanities are in trouble today and digital methods have an important role to play in effectively showing the public why the humanities need to be part of any vision of a future society bookmark The_Archive 2C_Digital_Preservation_of_Analog_ 26_Born Digital_Materials The <ORGANIZATION>Archive Digital Preservation of Analog amp Born Digital Materials Transcribe Bentham</ORGANIZATION> based at <ORGANIZATION>University College London</ORGANIZATION> has been crowdsourcing the transcription of thousands of manuscripts written by <PERSON>Jeremy Bentham</PERSON> 1748 1832 Anyone can sign up to participate viewing the original documents and transcribing and encoding them online in a wiki instructions and a discussion forum are provided See also What s On the Menu which invites users to transcribe the <ORGANIZATION>New York Public Library</ORGANIZATION> s collection of 40 000 menus a project of NYPL Labs The <ORGANIZATION>Rossetti Archive</ORGANIZATION> sponsored by the <ORGANIZATION>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities University of Virginia</ORGANIZATION> under the direction of <PERSON>Jerome McGann</PERSON> provides access to <PERSON>Dante Gabriel Rossetti</PERSON> s complete works including high quality images detailed descriptions and commentary Related works contemporary and antecedents are also included along with a bibliography The <ORGANIZATION>Walt Whitman Archive</ORGANIZATION> an electronic research and teaching tool that sets out to make <PERSON>Whitman</PERSON> s vast work easily and conveniently accessible to scholars students and general readers drawing on the resources of libraries and collections from around the <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> and around the world Directed by <PERSON>Kenneth</PERSON> M <ORGANIZATION>Price University of Nebraska Lincoln</ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION>Ed Folsom University of Iowa Preserving Virtual Worlds</ORGANIZATION> 2 exploring methods for preserving digital game environments A collaboration between the <ORGANIZATION>University of Illinois at Urbana Champaign Maryland Institute for Technology in the Humanities MITH Stanford University Libraries</ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION>Rochester Institute of Technology</ORGANIZATION> The work of institutions such as the <ORGANIZATION>Ransom Center</ORGANIZATION> at the <ORGANIZATION>University of Texas</ORGANIZATION> in preserving born digital textual materials Omeka a free open source web publishing platform for the display of library museum archives and scholarly collections and exhibitions developed by the team at <ORGANIZATION>Roy Rosenzweig Center for History and New Media CHNM</ORGANIZATION> at <ORGANIZATION>George Mason University</ORGANIZATION> with non IT specialists in mind allowing users to focus on content and interpretation rather than programming bookmark Digital_Fabrication 2FMaking_Things Digital Fabrication Making Things See <PERSON>William J Turkel</PERSON> s work on humanistic fabrication also his post A Few Arguments for Humanistic Fabrication bookmark Networked_Pedagogy Networked Pedagogy Looking for <PERSON>Whitman</PERSON> an experiment in multi campus digital pedagogy funded by the <ORGANIZATION>NEH s Office of Digital Humanities LFW</ORGANIZATION> used open source tools to connect classrooms in multiple institutions creating a dynamic social collaborative learning environment students at <ORGANIZATION>New York City College of Technology CUNY New York University University of Mary Washington</ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION>Rutgers University Camden</ORGANIZATION> shared their intellectual experiences of exploring <PERSON>Whitman</PERSON> s work in relationship to specific places in which <PERSON>Whitman</PERSON> lived with students from Novi Sad in <LOCATION>Serbia</LOCATION> adding a global perspective Not specific to DH but an important related movement in Educational Technology are projects that provide open platforms for teaching learning and collaboration such as <ORGANIZATION>University of Mary Washington Blogs CUNY</ORGANIZATION> is a leader in this space with the ePortfolio Gateway and <ORGANIZATION>Macaulay Social Network</ORGANIZATION> at <ORGANIZATION>CUNY</ORGANIZATION> s <ORGANIZATION>Macaulay Honors College Blogs Baruch</ORGANIZATION> at <ORGANIZATION>CUNY</ORGANIZATION> s <ORGANIZATION>Baruch College</ORGANIZATION> and now the OpenLab at <ORGANIZATION>City Tech</ORGANIZATION> bookmark Scholarly_Communication_ 26_Publishing Scholarly Communication amp Publishing The CUNY Academic Commons you re on it A network designed to support faculty initiatives and build community through the use s of technology in teaching and learning Members are graduate students and faculty across the CUNY campuses See also <ORGANIZATION>UMW Blogs Macaulay Social Network and Blogs Baruch</ORGANIZATION> above Commons in a Box in which the <ORGANIZATION>CUNY Commons</ORGANIZATION> team has partnered with the <ORGANIZATION>Alfred P Sloan Foundation</ORGANIZATION> to create an easily implementable installation of the <ORGANIZATION>CUNY Academic Commons The Modern Language Association</ORGANIZATION> has used the platform to create an MLA Commons for its 30 000 members PressForward a <ORGANIZATION>Sloan Foundation</ORGANIZATION> funded initiative of the CHNM Bringing together the best scholarship from across the web producing vital open publications scholarly communities can gather around Publications include the DHNow the <ORGANIZATION>Journal of Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> with others such as THATCamp proceedings to come <PERSON>Zotero</PERSON> a <ORGANIZATION>Mellon</ORGANIZATION> funded free open source extension to the <ORGANIZATION>Firefox</ORGANIZATION> browser developed by the team at the CHNM It enables users to collect manage cite and share research sources See also Online Communities Discussion Forums Anthologize another initiative of the CHNM this is a plug in for <ORGANIZATION>WordPress</ORGANIZATION> 3 0 that transforms online content into an electronic book See also Training Professional Development Shakespeare Quarterly conducted an experiment in open peer review for its special issue 61 3 <ORGANIZATION>Shakespeare</ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION>New Media</ORGANIZATION> available in Project Muse at <ORGANIZATION>Mina Rees</ORGANIZATION> The peer review process was conducted online at <ORGANIZATION>MediaCommons</ORGANIZATION> a project of the <ORGANIZATION>Institute</ORGANIZATION> for the Future of the Book and is available for viewing there It also received coverage in the <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> Times <PERSON>Paul Fyfe</PERSON> s talk Open Access Open Secrets Peer Review and Alternative Scholarly Production provides an excellent overview of the issues and how scholars are responding bookmark Text 2FData_Mining 2C_Analysis_ 26_Visualization <ORGANIZATION>Text Data Mining Analysis amp Visualization TAPoR Text Analysis Portal for Research</ORGANIZATION> a suite of text analysis tools that can be used to analyze user provided texts housed at <ORGANIZATION>University of Alberta Canada MONK Metadata Offer New Knowledge</ORGANIZATION> an open source digital environment providing texts and tools for textual analysis a collaboration of multiple <LOCATION>US</LOCATION> institutions based at <ORGANIZATION>Maryland Institute for Technology in the Humanities MITH</ORGANIZATION> HyperCities a collaborative research and educational platform for traveling back in time to explore the historical layers of city spaces in an interactive hypermedia environment Spatial Humanities an initiative by the Scholars Lab at the <ORGANIZATION>University of Virginia Library</ORGANIZATION> is a community driven resource sharing house for those interested in using spatial methods in humanistic inquiry <ORGANIZATION>Stanford University</ORGANIZATION> s Republic of Letters project visualizes the social network of Enlightenment writers through analysis of their correspondence On the Origin of Species The Preservation of Favoured Traces Ben Fry s visualization of the changes between editions of <PERSON>Darwin</PERSON> s On the Origin of Species See also the work of <PERSON>Lev Manovich</PERSON> and team at <ORGANIZATION>Cultural Analytics Work</ORGANIZATION> in progress The Digging into Data Challenge a range of projects recently funded by the <ORGANIZATION>NEH Office of Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> The work of <PERSON>Franco Moretti</PERSON> and <PERSON>Matthew Jockers</PERSON> at <ORGANIZATION>Stanford</ORGANIZATION> s Literature Lab covered in the Chronicle of Higher Education here is <PERSON>Jockers</PERSON> s response Projects funded by <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> that will leverage its <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> Books corpus see <PERSON>Dan Cohen</PERSON> s recent discussion of CHNM s text mining work on Victorian novels <PERSON>Cohen</PERSON> and team have set up a site where they re describing their research making their data available and inviting input Voyant text analysis tool developed by <ORGANIZATION>St</ORGANIZATION> fan <PERSON>Sinclair</PERSON> and <PERSON>Geoffrey Rockwell Wordseer</PERSON> see it in action here <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> gets into the game itself partnering with scientists at <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> to create the <ORGANIZATION>Google Books Ngram Viewer The Harvard</ORGANIZATION> team launched the project under the rubric of a neologism culturomics or the application of high throughput data collection and analysis to the study of human culture via a paper in Science The DH community has engaged with the project but with reservations to get a sense of the views of DHers already working in this space see posts by <PERSON>Dan Cohen</PERSON> who provides a nice summary of reactions and <PERSON>Matt Jockers</PERSON> The Culturomics team has provided a list of FAQs in response to issues raised bookmark 40CUNY CUNY In addition to the major initiatives listed under Networked Pedagogy and Scholarly Communication above See the great work going on at the <ORGANIZATION>CUNY Graduate Center New Media Lab</ORGANIZATION> Also the graduate projects funded by the Provost s Digital Innovation Grants <PERSON>Jesse Merandy</PERSON> s <ORGANIZATION>Crossing Brooklyn Ferry</ORGANIZATION> an online critical edition of <PERSON>Whitman</PERSON> s poem with links to criticism commentary and multimedia also tracks the edition s evolution over <PERSON>Whitman</PERSON> s lifetime and provides an audio walking tour of <LOCATION>Brooklyn</LOCATION> that traces the poet s footsteps CUNY DHers please add your projects to this list Previous Defining the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> CUNY DHI Resource Guide Home Next Some Reading Want to make a suggestion or correction Please visit Using This Guide for more information Search for Categories <ORGANIZATION>ADA Compliance</ORGANIZATION> 2 Art 2 Art on the Commons 1 Assessment 5 <ORGANIZATION>Blackboard</ORGANIZATION> 19 Blogging 8 Capitalism 1 <ORGANIZATION>CCRC</ORGANIZATION> 8 Citation Managers 2 Composition 15 Copyright 4 Course Development 4 <ORGANIZATION>Course Management Systems</ORGANIZATION> 1 Course Site Assessment 2 Creative practices 2 CUNY Academic Commons 2 CUNY ITunes U 32 <ORGANIZATION>CUNY ITunes U Campus Home Pages</ORGANIZATION> 18 <ORGANIZATION>CUNYDHI</ORGANIZATION> 24 <ORGANIZATION>DH Guide 23 Digital Humanities 23 Directory of Academic Commons Group Wikis</ORGANIZATION> 11 Distance Learning 6 E Learning 4 <ORGANIZATION>Educational Technology</ORGANIZATION> 10 <ORGANIZATION>Eportfolios</ORGANIZATION> 25 ESL 2 <ORGANIZATION>Faculty Development</ORGANIZATION> 3 Featured 4 <ORGANIZATION>FERPA</ORGANIZATION> 1 <ORGANIZATION>FYE</ORGANIZATION> 2 <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> 2 <ORGANIZATION>Gravatars</ORGANIZATION> 1 <ORGANIZATION>Help 41 Information Literacy</ORGANIZATION> 3 <ORGANIZATION>Intellectual Property</ORGANIZATION> 2 Librarians 10 <ORGANIZATION>Libraries 11 Library Science</ORGANIZATION> 3 <ORGANIZATION>Lincoln Center</ORGANIZATION> 1 Literature 1 Math 1 Math on the Commons 1 <ORGANIZATION>Metadata</ORGANIZATION> 2 <ORGANIZATION>Moodle</ORGANIZATION> 4 <ORGANIZATION>NCC</ORGANIZATION> 9 <ORGANIZATION>Omeka</ORGANIZATION> 4 On Line Lectures 5 Online Program Assessment 1 Open Access OA 7 Open Source 9 Philosophy 2 Plugin 1 Podcasting 6 Poetry 1 Political Science 1 Politics 1 Powerpoint 1 Privacy 3 Resources 4 Rhetoric 9 Sample online courses 2 <ORGANIZATION>Sandbox</ORGANIZATION> 1 <ORGANIZATION>Social Bookmarking</ORGANIZATION> 2 <ORGANIZATION>Social Networking</ORGANIZATION> 2 Suggestions 3 Teaching and Learning with Technology 71 The Arts CUNY 1 Twitter 4 Web 2 0 32 Web Publishing 19 Wikis 8 WordPress 8 Built with Make Your friendly WordPress page builder theme image css php Need help with the Commons Visit our help page Send us a message Skip to toolbar CUNY Academic Commons Home People Groups Sites Papers Events News Help About About the Commons Contact Us Publications on the <ORGANIZATION>Commons Image Credits Privacy Policy Project Staff Terms of Service</ORGANIZATION> Log in Register Help This site is part of the CUNY Academic Commons an academic social network for the entire 24 campus CUNY system Unless otherwise stated all content on the <ORGANIZATION>CUNY Academic Commons</ORGANIZATION> is licensed under a Creative Commons license image Help Contact Us Privacy Policy Terms of Service Image Credits image CUNY Logo Built with WordPress Protected by Akismet Powered by CUNY</ner>
