<ner>text mining Q676880 From Wikidata Jump to navigation search text data mining roughly equivalent to text analytics text data mining textmining text mining edit Language Label Description Also known as English text mining text data mining roughly equivalent to text analytics text data mining textmining text mining Statements subclass of data mining 0 references image image Tripletsnew2012 png Tripletsnew2012 png538 574 387 <ORGANIZATION>KB</ORGANIZATION> 0 references use science 1 reference imported from English Wikipedia Commons category Text mining 0 references topic s main category Category Text mining 1 reference imported from English Wikipedia Stack Exchange tag https stackoverflow com tags text mining 0 references Identifiers <ORGANIZATION>NDL Auth</ORGANIZATION> ID 01119322 0 references Freebase ID m 01v59d 1 reference stated in Freebase Data Dumps publication date 28 October 2013 Quora topic ID Text Mining 1 reference imported from Quora JSTOR topic ID text analytics 0 references BabelNet ID 02540773n 1 reference imported from BabelNet Elhuyar ZTH ID 139385 0 references <ORGANIZATION>Sitelinks Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> 23 entries edit arwiki bgwiki cswiki Dolov n z textu dewiki Text Mining enwiki Text mining eswiki Miner a de textos euwiki <PERSON>Testu</PERSON> meatzaritza fawiki frwiki Fouille de textes huwiki Sz vegb ny szat idwiki Penambangan teks jawiki nlwiki Textmining plwiki Text mining ptwiki Minera o de texto ruwiki slwiki Rudarjenje besedil svwiki Text mining thwiki trwiki Metin madencili i ukwiki viwiki <PERSON>Khai</PERSON> th c v n b n zhwiki Wikibooks 0 entries edit <ORGANIZATION>Wikinews</ORGANIZATION> 0 entries edit Wikiquote 0 entries edit <ORGANIZATION>Wikisource</ORGANIZATION> 0 entries edit <ORGANIZATION>Wikiversity</ORGANIZATION> 0 entries edit <ORGANIZATION>Wikivoyage</ORGANIZATION> 0 entries edit <ORGANIZATION>Wiktionary</ORGANIZATION> 0 entries edit Other sites 1 entry edit commonswiki Category Text mining image Retrieved from https www wikidata org w index php title Q676880 amp oldid 674737108 Navigation menu Personal tools English Not logged in Talk Contributions Create account Log in Namespaces Item Discussion Variants Views Read View history More Search Navigation Main page Community portal Project chat Create a new item Recent changes Random item Query Service Nearby Help Donate Print export Download as PDF Tools What links here Related changes Special pages Permanent link Page information Concept URI Cite this page This page was last edited on 5 May 2018 at 21 14 All structured data from the main and property namespace is available under the Creative Commons CC0 License text in the other namespaces is available under the Creative Commons Attribution ShareAlike License additional terms may apply By using this site you agree to the Terms of Use and Privacy Policy Privacy policy About Wikidata Disclaimers Developers Cookie statement Mobile view Data access image <ORGANIZATION>Wikimedia Foundation</ORGANIZATION> image Powered by <PERSON>MediaWiki</PERSON></ner>
