<ner>Sign in Join Help Contact Search form Search image Home image Home Menu About History Leadership Membership Staff Members HASTAC Hubs Acknowledgements Newsletters Explore Initiatives HASTAC Scholars The <ORGANIZATION>University Worth Fighting For Future ED Digital Badges DML</ORGANIZATION> Competitions 2006 2017 Events amp Opportunities Events Jobs and Fellowships Calls for Papers Grants and Funding HASTAC <ORGANIZATION>Conferences Teaching amp Learning Practices Humanities Arts amp Media Technology Networks amp Sciences Social amp Political Issues Educational amp Cultural Institutions Publishing amp Archives Fostering</ORGANIZATION> innovative and open methods and tools in the classroom and beyond <ORGANIZATION>View all Teaching amp Learning Practices</ORGANIZATION> blogs Members Groups Organizations Collections News image Are There Signs That Educators and Nations Are Rethinking 40 Years of Defunding and Demeaning Higher Education Are There Signs That Educators and Nations Are image Censorship in Real Time The Case of <PERSON>Chester Himes</PERSON> A Video by <PERSON>Daniel Carlson</PERSON> Censorship in Real Time The Case of <PERSON>Chester</PERSON> image The Question I m Asked the Most The Question I m Asked the Most image MOOC Review LLG 5 <ORGANIZATION>MOOC</ORGANIZATION> Review LLG 5 Expanding the scope and impact of traditional and digital humanities for the contemporary world <ORGANIZATION>View all Humanities Arts amp Media</ORGANIZATION> blogs Members Groups Organizations Collections News image A Reflection on Digital Textuality Theories of P <PERSON>Robinson</PERSON> amp P Shillingsburg A Reflection on Digital Textuality Theories of P image Twenty Things Higher Ed Can Learn from the <ORGANIZATION>Parkland High School Kids</ORGANIZATION> MarchforOurLives REV Twenty Things Higher Ed Can Learn from the image How To Give Great Feedback The Architect Versus the Critic How To Give Great Feedback The Architect Versus image Black Listed Evolving Student Designed Syllabus Black Listed Evolving Student Designed Syllabus Thinking critically about the role and design of technology data and the social sciences in our lives and learning View all <ORGANIZATION>Technology Networks amp Sciences</ORGANIZATION> blogs Members Groups Organizations Collections News image Postmortem Bodies Games and Boundaries Postmortem Bodies Games and Boundaries image How To Give Great Feedback The Architect Versus the Critic How To Give Great Feedback The Architect Versus image Easy Ways to Enliven Any Classroom Any Size Easy Ways to Enliven Any Classroom Any Size image Interview with <ORGANIZATION>Purdom Lindblad Interview</ORGANIZATION> with <PERSON>Purdom Lindblad</PERSON> Promoting openness access and diversity in technology and education in service of an equitable society View all Social amp Political Issues blogs Members Groups Organizations Collections News image Scholar Speaker and Strategist An Interview with <PERSON>Marcia Chatelain</PERSON> Scholar Speaker and Strategist An Interview image Twenty Things Higher Ed Can Learn from the <ORGANIZATION>Parkland High School Kids</ORGANIZATION> MarchforOurLives REV Twenty Things Higher Ed Can Learn from the image Black Listed Evolving Student Designed Syllabus Black Listed Evolving Student Designed Syllabus image Interview with <ORGANIZATION>Purdom Lindblad Interview</ORGANIZATION> with <PERSON>Purdom Lindblad</PERSON> Promoting change in schools museums libraries and other organizations <ORGANIZATION>View all Educational amp Cultural Institutions</ORGANIZATION> blogs Members Groups Organizations Collections News image How To Give Great Feedback The Architect Versus the Critic How To Give Great Feedback The Architect Versus image Digital Storytelling for the 21st <ORGANIZATION>Century Digital Storytelling</ORGANIZATION> for the 21st Century image Digital Scholarship Lab Thoughts on Laboratories and Libraries from <ORGANIZATION>MSU Digital</ORGANIZATION> Scholarship Lab Thoughts on Laboratories image Hey Postdocs Let s meet Hey Postdocs Let s meet Advocating for new forms of scholarly communications including blogging multimedia open publishing and academic journals and presses <ORGANIZATION>View all Publishing amp Archives</ORGANIZATION> blogs Members Groups Organizations Collections News image How To Give Great Feedback The Architect Versus the Critic How To Give Great Feedback The Architect Versus image Interview with <PERSON>Purdom Lindblad</PERSON> Interview with <PERSON>Purdom Lindblad</PERSON> image New is Now Now is Then Exploring <PERSON>Rob Feulner</PERSON> s Analog Remix of Off the Air s NEWNOW as a Case Study in Digital Aesthetics New is Now Now is Then Exploring <PERSON>Rob Feulner</PERSON> s image <PERSON>Lorraine Hansberry</PERSON> Documentary on PBS <PERSON>Lorraine Hansberry</PERSON> Documentary on PBS Home About HASTAC About HASTAC Page Views 77106 586 image Changing the Way We Teach and <ORGANIZATION>Learn HASTAC Humanities Arts Science and Technology Alliance</ORGANIZATION> and Collaboratory is an interdisciplinary community of humanists artists social scientists scientists and technologists changing the way we teach and learn Our 16 000 members from over 400 affiliate organizations share ideas news tools research insights pedagogy methods and projects including <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> and other born digital scholarship and collaborate on various HASTAC initiatives Founded in 2002 HASTAC is reputed to be the world s first and oldest academic social network with annual pageview counts approaching the half million mark HASTAC is governed by a dynamic interdisciplinary Steering Committee Go here to learn more about current leadership HASTAC s leadership and administration is shared between hubs located at <ORGANIZATION>Arizona State University</ORGANIZATION> and the Graduate Center at the <ORGANIZATION>City University of New York Learn</ORGANIZATION> more about HASTAC s leadership and administration here HASTAC International Conferences HASTAC is an active community of 16 000 members who are engaging in critical conversation about how we teach and learn year round While these discussions are occurring primarily online and within individual institutions of education during most of the year each year hundreds of scholars from the HASTAC community come together in one space for a conference These conferences are truly incredible environments for collaboration networking and transformative change hosted by affiliate organizations at locations around the globe Visit HASTAC Conferences to learn more and to find out how you can join us for the HASTAC 2019 Conference Initiatives HASTAC initiatives are where much of the work of this community happens Key initiatives like HASTAC Scholars The Futures Initiative and The <ORGANIZATION>University Worth Fighting For</ORGANIZATION> offer lightly organized spaces of collaboration and dialogue on creating meaningful transformations in how we teach and learn In many cases these initiatives take the form of groups allowing HASTAC members to join collaborate and contribute To learn more about all the initiatives we are working on now and see where our past initiatives have already taken us please visit our Initiatives page Join us HASTAC is a free and open community that values collaboration diversity openness innovation and creative contribution As a member you can connect with other members receive newsletters and announcements blog participate in relevant groups post funding and job opportunities showcase new tools find collaborators for projects and share CFPs Our community benefits immensely from the perspective participation and experience each new member brings so join us See our Membership page for more information or join now image image image image image image image Image credits Collage 1 left to right <PERSON>Nick Sousanis</PERSON> former HASTAC Scholar spinweaveandcut com <PERSON>Rebecca Itow</PERSON> HASTAC Scholar hastac org users rcitow <PERSON>Jade Davis</PERSON> <ORGANIZATION>HASTAC Scholar and Steering Committee</ORGANIZATION> member jadedid com <ORGANIZATION>Duke University</ORGANIZATION> today duke edu 2012 10 gagafern DevInfo <ORGANIZATION>GameWorks</ORGANIZATION> digw org Collage 2 left to right <PERSON>Bethany Bradshaw</PERSON> HASTAC Scholar bethanybradshaw com <PERSON>Alex Fledderjohn</PERSON> for The <ORGANIZATION>MacArthur Foundation</ORGANIZATION> macfound org <PERSON>David Sparks</PERSON> hastac org blogs dsparks <PERSON>Kevin Gotkin</PERSON> HASTAC Scholar kevingotkin com 586 About History Leadership Membership Staff Members Staff Alumni HASTAC Hubs Acknowledgements Newsletters image <ORGANIZATION>DML</ORGANIZATION> 6 Playlists for Learning Digital Media amp Learning Competition Learn More image image image Tags HASTAC Conferences amp Events HASTAC org HASTAC Scholars HASTAC image image image image image image By accessing this site you agree to be bound by the Legal Agreement We respect your privacy Read the HASTAC privacy policy Except where otherwise noted all content on this site is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution NonCommercial ShareAlike 3 0 License</ner>
