<ner>skip to primary navigationskip to content image <ORGANIZATION>University of Cambridge Study at Cambridge About the University Research at Cambridge Search</ORGANIZATION> site Home Study at <LOCATION>Cambridge</LOCATION> Undergraduate Courses Applying Events and open days Fees and finance Student blogs and videos Graduate Why Cambridge Course directory How to apply Fees and funding Frequently asked questions International students <ORGANIZATION>Continuing education Executive</ORGANIZATION> and professional education Courses in education About the <ORGANIZATION>University How the University</ORGANIZATION> and Colleges work <ORGANIZATION>History Visiting the University Term</ORGANIZATION> dates and calendars Map For media Video and audio Find an expert <ORGANIZATION>Publications Global Cambridge News Events Public engagement Jobs Give to Cambridge Research at Cambridge Give to Cambridge For</ORGANIZATION> staff For current students For alumni For business Colleges amp departments Libraries amp facilities Museums amp collections Email amp phone search Log in <ORGANIZATION>Home Cambridge Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> image <ORGANIZATION>Cambridge Digital Humanities Department</ORGANIZATION> A Z Home CDH CDH Overview CDH Team <ORGANIZATION>CDH Team Overview CDH Directorate CDH Steering Committee CDH Staff CDH Methods Fellows Defining Digital Humanities CDH Vacancies Research Research Overview Research Themes Research Projects Research Centres and Strategic Initiatives Research Funding Scholarly Communication Cambridge Digital Library Lab Lab Overview Project Concept Project Start up Project Start up Overview Digital Imaging Metadata</ORGANIZATION> and Standards Hosting and Sustainability Tools and Development Impact High Performance Computing Project Implementation Project Sustainability Learning Learning Overview Learning Themes Learning Themes Overview Machine Reading the Archive Machine Reading the Archive Overview Machine Reading the Archive Projects overview Machine Reading the Archive Projects FAQ Ethics of <ORGANIZATION>Big Data Ways of Machine Seeing Scholarly Practice</ORGANIZATION> in the Digital Age Strand 1 Doing Research in the Digital Age Strand 1 Doing Research in the Digital Age Overview Registration Doing research in the digital age Strand 2 <ORGANIZATION>Advanced Digital Methods Workshops Strand</ORGANIZATION> 3 Critical Coding Text and Data Mining Test Kitchen All CDH Learning Events Other DH Training Events External Training and Resources Network Network Overview Join the CDH Mailing List Collaboration Contact image CUDL Support for world class initiatives in DH research image 3D image 1 Technical advice on innovative DH methods and tools image Digitisation Assistance with identifying digitising and licensing research materials image Learning jpg Entry level and advanced training through the CDH Learning curriculum image Research RESEARCH Cambridge DH researchers have been involved in over 100 major projects many of which have attracted significant financial support from external funders Read more image Lab LAB The Lab collaborates with researchers in many fields and provides support guidance and technical solutions tailored to their project goals Read more image Learning LEARNING The CDH Learning programme helps <ORGANIZATION>Cambridge</ORGANIZATION> students researchers and staff equip themselves with the tools and methods they need to carry on delivering world class research and teaching Read more image Network NETWORK We are a network of researchers at <LOCATION>Cambridge</LOCATION> who are interested in how the use of digital tools is transforming scholarship in the humanities and social sciences Read more Upcoming events Introduction to <LOCATION>Omeka</LOCATION> build and publish a simple digital archive or collection May 08 2018 <ORGANIZATION>B3 Institute of Criminology Collaborating</ORGANIZATION> with the machine Opportunities challenges and caveats May 15 2018 B4 <ORGANIZATION>Institute of Criminology Lenses</ORGANIZATION> or Mirrors How Algorithms Affect Ways of Seeing Race and Gender May 21 2018 SG2 <PERSON>Alison Richard</PERSON> Building Introduction to archival photography May 22 2018 Digital Content Unit <ORGANIZATION>University Library Digital Collaboration Tools</ORGANIZATION> Jun 05 2018 S1 <PERSON>Alison Richard</PERSON> Building Re search do search engines shape scholarship Jun 12 2018 S1 <PERSON>Alison Richard</PERSON> Building Machine Reading the Archive 2018 end of programme showcase Jun 14 2018 S1 <PERSON>Alison Richard</PERSON> Building Upcoming events What is <ORGANIZATION>CDH Cambridge Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> is a creative and collaborative space where students researchers and international visitors can come together to engage in dialogue experiment with technology and advance scholarship DH links <ORGANIZATION>Cambridge Digital Library Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> at the <ORGANIZATION>UL Research Operations Office Office of Scholarly Communication UIS Training CDH</ORGANIZATION> on Twitter Tweets by <ORGANIZATION>CamDigHum Contact us Information</ORGANIZATION> provided by webmaster cdh cam ac uk <ORGANIZATION>Site Privacy amp Cookie Policies Contact us Postal Address CDH Office South Front Cambridge University Library West Road Cambridge</ORGANIZATION> CB3 9DP Information provided by webmaster cdh cam ac uk image <ORGANIZATION>University of Cambridge 2017 University of Cambridge University</ORGANIZATION> A Z Contact the University Accessibility Freedom of information Terms and conditions Study at <ORGANIZATION>Cambridge Undergraduate Graduate International</ORGANIZATION> students Continuing education Executive and professional education Courses in education About the University How the <ORGANIZATION>University</ORGANIZATION> and Colleges work Visiting the <ORGANIZATION>University Map News Events Jobs Give to Cambridge Research at Cambridge News Features Discussion Spotlight on About</ORGANIZATION> research at <LOCATION>Cambridge</LOCATION> This Site Uses Cookies We may use cookies to record some preference settings and to analyse how you use our web site We may also use external analysis systems which may set additional cookies to perform their analysis These cookies and any others in use are detailed in our site privacy and cookie policies and are integral to our web site You can delete or disable these cookies in your web browser if you wish but then our site may not work correctly I have read and understood this message Hide this message</ner>
