<ner>NYTimes com no longer supports Internet Explorer 9 or earlier Please upgrade your browser LEARN MORE Sections Home Search Skip to content Skip to navigation View mobile version The <ORGANIZATION>New York Times Arts Digital Keys</ORGANIZATION> for Unlocking the Humanities Riches Search Subscribe Now Log In 0 Settings Close search Site Search Navigation Search NYTimes com Clear this text input Go Loading See next articles See previous articles Site Navigation Site Mobile Navigation Advertisement Supported by <ORGANIZATION>Arts Humanities</ORGANIZATION> 2 0 <ORGANIZATION>Digital Keys</ORGANIZATION> for Unlocking the Humanities Riches By <PERSON>PATRICIA COHENNOV</PERSON> 16 2010 Continue reading the main story Share This Page Continue reading the main story Photo image <PERSON>Martin K Foys</PERSON> a medievalist at <ORGANIZATION>Drew University</ORGANIZATION> with a detail of an 11th century map of the world Credit <PERSON>James Leynse</PERSON> for The <ORGANIZATION>New York Times</ORGANIZATION> A history of the humanities in the 20th century could be chronicled in isms formalism Freudianism structuralism postcolonialism grand intellectual cathedrals from which assorted interpretations of literature politics and culture spread The next big idea in language history and the arts Data Members of a new generation of digitally savvy humanists argue it is time to stop looking for inspiration in the next political or philosophical ism and start exploring how technology is changing our understanding of the liberal arts This latest frontier is about method they say using powerful technologies and vast stores of digitized materials that previous humanities scholars did not have These researchers are digitally mapping Civil War battlefields to understand what role topography played in victory using databases of thousands of jam sessions to track how musical collaborations influenced jazz searching through large numbers of scientific texts and books to track where concepts first appeared and how they spread and combining animation charts and primary documents about <PERSON>Thomas Jefferson</PERSON> s travels to create new ways to teach history This alliance of geeks and poets has generated exhilaration and also anxiety The humanities after all deal with elusive questions of aesthetics existence and meaning the words that bring tears or the melody that raises goose bumps Are these elements that can be measured Advertisement Continue reading the main story The digital humanities do fantastic things said the eminent <ORGANIZATION>Princeton</ORGANIZATION> historian <PERSON>Anthony Grafton</PERSON> I m a believer in quantification But I don t believe quantification can do everything So much of humanistic scholarship is about interpretation Continue reading the main story Advertisement Continue reading the main story It s easy to forget the digital media are means and not ends he added <ORGANIZATION>Digital</ORGANIZATION> humanities scholars also face a more practical test What knowledge can they produce that their predecessors could not I call it the Where s the beef question said <PERSON>Tom Scheinfeldt</PERSON> managing director of the <ORGANIZATION>Center for History and New Media at George Mason University Hoping</ORGANIZATION> to find the beef the <ORGANIZATION>National Endowment for the Humanities</ORGANIZATION> teamed up with the <ORGANIZATION>National Science Foundation</ORGANIZATION> and institutions in <LOCATION>Canada</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Britain</LOCATION> last year to create the Digging Into Data Challenge a grant program designed to push research in new directions As <PERSON>Brett Bobley</PERSON> director of the endowment s office of digital humanities explained analyzing unprecedented amounts of data can reveal patterns and trends and raise unexpected questions for study He offered the human genome project as an example of how an area of study can be transformed Technology hasn t just made astronomy biology and physics more efficient It has let scientists do research they simply couldn t do before Mr <PERSON>Bobley</PERSON> said the emerging field of digital humanities is probably best understood as an umbrella term covering a wide range of activities from online preservation and digital mapping to data mining and the use of geographic information systems Some pioneering efforts began years ago but most humanities professors remain unaware uninterested or unconvinced that digital humanities has much to offer Even historians who have used databases before have been slow to embrace the trend Just one of the nearly 300 main panels scheduled for next year s annual meeting of the <ORGANIZATION>American Historical Association</ORGANIZATION> covers digital matters Still universities professional associations and private institutions are increasingly devoting a larger slice of the pie to the field The humanities and social sciences are the emerging domains for using high performance computers said <PERSON>Peter Bajcsy</PERSON> a research scientist at the <ORGANIZATION>National Center for Supercomputing Applications</ORGANIZATION> at the <ORGANIZATION>University of Illinois Urbana Champaign In Europe</ORGANIZATION> 10 nations have embarked on a large scale project beginning in March that plans to digitize arts and humanities data Last summer <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> awarded 1 million to professors doing digital humanities research and last year the <ORGANIZATION>National Endowment for the Humanities</ORGANIZATION> spent 2 million on digital projects Photo image A digital project created by <ORGANIZATION>University of Virginia</ORGANIZATION> students allows users to examine <PERSON>Thomas Jefferson</PERSON> s life through primary documents The map at right visualizes part of <PERSON>Jefferson</PERSON> s 1786 trip to <LOCATION>England</LOCATION> Credit <PERSON>Bill Ferster</PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION>Scot French University of Virginia One</ORGANIZATION> of the endowment s grantees is <PERSON>Dan Edelstein</PERSON> an associate professor of French and Italian at <ORGANIZATION>Stanford University</ORGANIZATION> who is charting the flow of ideas during the Enlightenment The era s great thinkers <PERSON>Locke Newton Voltaire</PERSON> exchanged tens of thousands of letters <PERSON>Voltaire</PERSON> alone wrote more than 18 000 Advertisement Continue reading the main story You could form an impressionistic sense of the shape and content of a correspondence but no one could really know the whole picture said Mr <PERSON>Edelstein</PERSON> who along with collaborators at <ORGANIZATION>Stanford</ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION>Oxford University</ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION>England</LOCATION> is using a geographic information system to trace the letters journeys He continued Where were these networks going Did they actually have the breadth that people would often boast about or were they functioning in a different way We re able to ask new questions Newsletter Sign Up Continue reading the main story Please verify you re not a robot by clicking the box Invalid email address Please re enter You must select a newsletter to subscribe to Sign Up You agree to receive occasional updates and special offers for The <ORGANIZATION>New York Times</ORGANIZATION> s products and services Thank you for subscribing An error has occurred Please try again later You are already subscribed to this email View all <ORGANIZATION>New York Times</ORGANIZATION> newsletters See Sample Manage Email Preferences Not you Privacy Policy Opt out or contact us anytime One surprising revelation of the Mapping the Republic of Letters project was the paucity of exchanges between <LOCATION>Paris</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>London</LOCATION> Mr <PERSON>Edelstein</PERSON> said The common narrative is that the Enlightenment started in <LOCATION>England</LOCATION> and spread to the rest of <LOCATION>Europe</LOCATION> You would think if <LOCATION>England</LOCATION> was this fountainhead of freedom and religious tolerance he said there would have been greater continuing interest there than what our correspondence map shows us Mr <PERSON>Edelstein</PERSON> said that many of his senior colleagues view his work as whimsical the result of playing with technological toys But he argues such play can lead to discoveries In Mr <PERSON>Scheinfeldt</PERSON> s view academia has moved into a post theoretical age This methodological moment he said is similar to the late 19th and early 20th centuries when scholars were preoccupied with collating and cataloging the flood of information brought about by revolutions in communication transportation and science The practical issues of discipline building of assembling an annotated bibliography of defining the research agenda and what it means to be a historian were the main work of a great number of scholars he said Figuring out how to collect house and connect more than 350 years of scholarship motivated <PERSON>Martin K Foys</PERSON> a medievalist at <ORGANIZATION>Drew University in Madison N J</ORGANIZATION> to create a digital map of the <ORGANIZATION>Bayeux Tapestry</ORGANIZATION> a gargantuan 11th century embroidery displayed in a museum in <LOCATION>Bayeux France</LOCATION> that depicts the Battle of <PERSON>Hastings</PERSON> when the Normans conquered <LOCATION>England</LOCATION> At 224 feet long about two thirds the length of a football field this tapestry is both a work of art and a historical document that mingles text and image It is almost impossible to study traditionally Mr <PERSON>Foys</PERSON> said No one person could digest the work s enormous amount of material and no single printing could render it accurately so Mr <PERSON>Foys</PERSON> created a prize winning digital version with commentary that scholars could scroll through Such digital mapping has the potential to transform medieval studies Mr <PERSON>Foys</PERSON> said His latest project which he directs with <PERSON>Shannon Bradshaw</PERSON> a computer scientist at Drew and <PERSON>Asa Simon Mittman</PERSON> an art historian from <ORGANIZATION>California State University Chico</ORGANIZATION> is an online network of medieval maps and texts that scholars can work on simultaneously Once specific areas of maps are identified and tagged with information it becomes possible to analyze and compare quantifiable data about images and sources he explained adding We have a whole new set of tools not dominated by the written word Advertisement Continue reading the main story The online network of maps is distinct from most scholarly endeavors in another respect It is communal The traditional model of the solitary humanities professor toiling away in an archive or spending years composing a philosophical treatise or historical opus is replaced in this project with contributions from a global community of experts The ease with which a community can collaborate on the production of scholarship is something that is fundamentally changing the way we do our work said Mr Foys whose 2007 book Virtually Anglo <PERSON>Saxon</PERSON> discusses the influence of technology on scholarship <ORGANIZATION>Digital humanities</ORGANIZATION> is so new that its practitioners are frequently surprised by what develops When the collected published works of <PERSON>Abraham Lincoln</PERSON> were posted online a few years ago the director of the Papers of <PERSON>Abraham Lincoln Daniel W Stowell</PERSON> said he expected historians to be the most frequent visitors to his project s site But he was surprised to discover that the heaviest users were connected to <ORGANIZATION>Oxford University Press</ORGANIZATION> editors of the Oxford English Dictionary had been searching the papers to track down the first appearance of particular words People will use this data in ways we can t even imagine yet Mr <PERSON>Stowell</PERSON> said and I think that is one of the most exciting developments in the humanities HUMANITIES 2 0 This is the first in a series about how digital tools are changing scholarship in history literature and the arts A version of this article appears in print on November 17 2010 on Page C1 of the <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> edition with the headline HUMANITIES 2 0 A <ORGANIZATION>New Enlightenment Digital Keys</ORGANIZATION> to the Humanities Riches Order Reprints Today s Paper Subscribe Continue reading the main story We re interested in your feedback on this page Tell us what you think Related Coverage Mapping the Enlightenment NOV 16 2010 ARTSBEAT BLOG Digitally Mapping the Republic of Letters NOV 16 2010 Related Coverage Mapping the Enlightenment NOV 16 2010 ARTSBEAT BLOG Digitally Mapping the Republic of Letters NOV 16 2010 What s Next Loading Go to Home Page Site Index The <ORGANIZATION>New York Times Site Index Navigation News World U S Politics N Y Business Tech Science Health Sports Education Obituaries Today</ORGANIZATION> s Paper Corrections Opinion Today s Opinion Op Ed Columnists Editorials Op Ed Contributors Letters Sunday Review Video Opinion Arts Today s Arts Art amp Design Books Dance Movies Music N Y <ORGANIZATION>C Events Guide Television Theater Video Arts Living Automobiles Crossword Food Education Fashion amp Style Health Jobs Magazine N Y C Events Guide Real Estate T Magazine Travel Weddings amp Celebrations Listings amp More Reader Center Classifieds Tools amp Services N Y C Events Guide Multimedia</ORGANIZATION> Photography Video NYT Store Times Journeys Subscribe Manage My Account NYTCo Subscribe Subscribe Home Delivery Digital Subscriptions Crossword Email Newsletters Alerts Gift Subscriptions Group Subscriptions Education Rate Mobile Applications Replica Edition Site Information Navigation 2018 The <ORGANIZATION>New York Times Company Home</ORGANIZATION> Search Accessibility concerns Email us at accessibility nytimes com We would love to hear from you Contact Us Work With Us Advertise Your Ad Choices Privacy Terms of Service Terms of Sale Site Information Navigation Site Map Help Site Feedback Subscriptions</ner>
