<ner>Support the Archive The <ORGANIZATION>Walt Whitman Archive Ed Folsom amp Kenneth M Price Editors Published Works Books</ORGANIZATION> by <ORGANIZATION>Whitman Periodicals Translations In Whitman s Hand Manuscripts Notebooks Scribal Documents Life</ORGANIZATION> amp Letters Biography Chronology Letters Commentary Bibliography Criticism Disciples Reviews Pictures amp Sound Audio Portraits of Whitman Resources Downloads Manuscript Catalogs Links More About the Archive Follow Us Tour People Policies More News amp Updates December 2017 We have just published a bibliography of over 100 translations of <PERSON>Whitman</PERSON> into Polish annotated by <ORGANIZATION>Marta Skwara University of Szczecin</ORGANIZATION> September 2017 We have just published transcriptions of 39 editorials likely written by <PERSON>Whitman</PERSON> as the editor of the <LOCATION>New York Aurora</LOCATION> We have also created a new section of the Archive devoted to <PERSON>Whitman</PERSON> s newspaper editing August 2017 With support from the <ORGANIZATION>National Historical Publications and Records Commission</ORGANIZATION> we ve published 252 letters from the Old Age period image facebook favicon image twitter favicon image blogger favicon More News Funding and support provided by the <ORGANIZATION>National Endowment for the Humanities the US Department of Education the Institute of Museum and Library Services the National Historical Publications and Records Commission University of Iowa University of Nebraska Lincoln</ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION>Institute for Advanced Technology in the Humanities</ORGANIZATION> at the <ORGANIZATION>University of Virginia The Walt Whitman Archive</ORGANIZATION> edited by <PERSON>Ed Folsom</PERSON> and <PERSON>Kenneth M Price</PERSON> is published by the <ORGANIZATION>Center for Digital Research</ORGANIZATION> in the Humanities at the <ORGANIZATION>University of Nebraska Lincoln</ORGANIZATION> under a Creative Commons License</ner>
