<ner>Skip to main content Return to the main NEH site image Humanities logo Secondary Menu Back Issues Magazine Staff Search this site <ORGANIZATION>YouTube Twitter Facebook</ORGANIZATION> Instagram Snapchat NEH Gov Delivery Main Menu Magazine Home Features Conversations Statements IQ Executive Function One Off Ednote You are here Humanities Back Issues November December 2013 Feature Mapping the Republic of Letters By <PERSON>Meredith Hindley</PERSON> HUMANITIES November December 2013 Volume 34 Number 6 Click on image to enlarge image A depiction by <PERSON>Achille Devaria</PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION>Voltaire</ORGANIZATION> greeting <PERSON>Ben Franklin</PERSON> and his nephew A depiction by <PERSON>Achille Devaria</PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION>Voltaire</ORGANIZATION> greeting <PERSON>Ben Franklin</PERSON> and his nephew as they visit <LOCATION>France</LOCATION> DeA Picture Library Art Resource NY Click on image to enlarge image Watercolor portraits of <ORGANIZATION>Voltaire</ORGANIZATION> by Denon Watercolor portraits of <ORGANIZATION>Voltaire</ORGANIZATION> by <PERSON>Denon Gianni Dagli Orti</PERSON> The Art Archive at Art Resource NY Click on image to enlarge image An image of <ORGANIZATION>Voltaire</ORGANIZATION> s correspondence An image of <ORGANIZATION>Voltaire</ORGANIZATION> s correspondence as visualized by Mapping the Republic of Letters RPLVIZ tool Courtesy of Mapping the Republic of Letters with data provided by Electronic Enlightenment Project Click on image to enlarge image <PERSON>Edward Fisher</PERSON> s engraving of <PERSON>Ben Franklin Edward Fisher</PERSON> s engraving of <ORGANIZATION>Ben Franklin National Portrait Gallery Smithsonian</ORGANIZATION> Institution Art Resource NY image A depiction by <PERSON>Achille Devaria</PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION>Voltaire</ORGANIZATION> greeting <PERSON>Ben Franklin</PERSON> and his nephew image Watercolor portraits of Voltaire by <PERSON>Denon</PERSON> image An image of <ORGANIZATION>Voltaire</ORGANIZATION> s correspondence image <PERSON>Edward Fisher</PERSON> s engraving of <PERSON>Ben Franklin</PERSON> In 1734 <PERSON>Voltaire</PERSON> fled <LOCATION>Paris</LOCATION> to the region of Champagne trading the sophisticated and malodorous capital for acres of precisely plotted vineyards Once again the sharp tongued philosopher had run afoul of French censors Eight years earlier he d escaped to <LOCATION>England</LOCATION> after the <PERSON>Duc de Rohan</PERSON> accused him of defamation After a three year exile he received permission to return to <LOCATION>Paris</LOCATION> in 1729 Now he was fleeing again this time to escape the storm surrounding the publication of Lettres philosophiques also known as Letters Concerning the English Nation The epistolary style book cataloged <LOCATION>Britain</LOCATION> s religious political and cultural life praising the island nation for championing liberty and trade It also took more than a few swipes at the French nobility The illicit volume which had not been cleared by the royal censors was burned by the royal hangman for all of <LOCATION>Paris</LOCATION> to see An arrest warrant was issued which if executed would land <PERSON>Voltaire</PERSON> in the Bastille Instead of rotting in a dank prison cell <PERSON>Voltaire</PERSON> was more than 140 miles away having sought sanctuary under the roof of the Ch teau de Cirey and the protection offered by the familial connections of the Marquis <PERSON>Florent Claude</PERSON> du Ch telet For the next fifteen years <PERSON>Voltaire</PERSON> lived at <LOCATION>Cirey</LOCATION> writing a steady stream of letters to stay connected with his friends in <LOCATION>Paris</LOCATION> and others who were abroad Those same letters helped promote his plays historical works and essays while keeping him abreast of the latest intellectual developments He also carried on a torrid affair of the heart and mind with <PERSON>Emilie du Ch</PERSON> telet the wife of the marquis and a scholarly force in her own right While at <ORGANIZATION>Cirey Voltaire</ORGANIZATION> wrote and published one of the most remarkable books of his very productive career l ments de la <LOCATION>Philosophie de Newton</LOCATION> the first distillation of the English scientist s metaphysics to appear in French By declaring himself for <PERSON>Newton</PERSON> and against <PERSON>Ren Descartes</PERSON> whose views of time space and matter dominated scientific and philosophical thinking <PERSON>Voltaire</PERSON> touched off a war within the Republic of Letters the loose grouping of learned men and women who comprised <LOCATION>Europe</LOCATION> s intellectual community Letters flew across <LOCATION>Europe</LOCATION> and the English Channel dissecting <ORGANIZATION>Voltaire</ORGANIZATION> s arguments Pamphlets and books were printed in response and <PERSON>Voltaire</PERSON> answered in kind Republic of Letters sounds like a term coined by a historian but it was one used by the participants themselves In an era defined by monarchical government class hierarchy and religious divisions the members of the republic saw themselves as engaging each other on intellectual and therefore equal terms Letters refers to both learning and the way that intellectual and scholarly developments spread throughout <LOCATION>Europe</LOCATION> and abroad In thousands upon thousands of letters members tried out new theories critiqued ideas relayed the newest gossip and chronicled the mundane matters of life The more international your network the more cosmopolitan you were thought to be Correspondence was such an integral part of scholarly life that <LOCATION>Montesquieu</LOCATION> mocked it in his Persian Letters when he has a boorish astronomer brag I have very little contact with people and among those I do see there are none that I know But there is a man in <LOCATION>Stockholm</LOCATION> another in <LOCATION>Leipzig</LOCATION> and another in <LOCATION>London</LOCATION> whom I have never seen and no doubt shall never see that I maintain such a regular correspondence that I never fail to write each of them with every mail Scholars have used these letters to trace networks of friendships and shared knowledge Who wrote to whom Where did that idea come from Did the English influence the French Or mon dieu did the French influence the English What about the Dutch Have you heard the latest about <PERSON>Voltaire</PERSON> and his endorsement of <LOCATION>Newton</LOCATION> To reconstruct these networks scholars have naturally focused on the content of the letters But what could they learn if they took a step back and focused on a correspondence network as a whole and used cutting edge software to render it in maps or graphs What new discoveries might they make That s the big question undergirding the Mapping the Republic of Letters project at <ORGANIZATION>Stanford University</ORGANIZATION> Ignoring the content of the letters seems like a radical proposition but the availability of increasingly sophisticated digital technologies presents historians with new ways to explore the past The hard part is figuring out how to make the messy and often incomplete historical record mesh with the strictures of computer programming THE PROOF IS IN THE MAP <PERSON>Dan Edelstein</PERSON> professor of French at <ORGANIZATION>Stanford</ORGANIZATION> didn t plan on embarking on a big digital humanities project but that s what he and his colleague <PERSON>Paula Findlen</PERSON> the <PERSON>Ubaldo Pierotti</PERSON> Professor of Italian History found themselves with in late 2008 after a chance conversation with <PERSON>Robert McNamee</PERSON> of the <ORGANIZATION>Electronic Enlightenment Project at Oxford University McNamee</ORGANIZATION> had been looking for a way to map the information he had on 6 400 authors and 55 000 letters Since <ORGANIZATION>Oxford</ORGANIZATION> had the archive <ORGANIZATION>Stanford</ORGANIZATION> agreed to take on the task of making the visualizations a reality <PERSON>Edelstein</PERSON> and <PERSON>Findlen</PERSON> turned to <PERSON>Nicole Coleman</PERSON> an academic technology specialist at <ORGANIZATION>Stanford</ORGANIZATION> to help them navigate the software development Although it was clearly a digital project <PERSON>Edelstein</PERSON> says they began with fairly traditional questions about the Republic of Letters some that people had been asking for decades Did the reality match the rhetoric of the Republic of Letters Really how global and cosmopolitan were these networks Was there one network Or were there lots of little networks that weren t connected he asks <PERSON>Findlen</PERSON> was also intrigued by the chance to step back from looking at an archive letter by letter I m very aware that one of the problems with working with large correspondences is how much you can keep in your head she says Using visualizations would provide an opportunity to examine the whole in a way that can t be done by close reading alone Working with the <ORGANIZATION>Packard Humanities Institute</ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION>Electronic Enlightenment Project the Stanford</ORGANIZATION> team created a database that logged the metadata for each letter including sender recipient date and location A team of students led by <PERSON>Jeffrey Heer</PERSON> then an assistant professor at <ORGANIZATION>Stanford</ORGANIZATION> designed the visualization software The tool RPLVIZ lets users select which authors to display along with options to render the full correspondence or only letters sent or received The resulting maps not only proved that correspondence could be visualized in a useful way but also yielded surprising results Most of the correspondence networks were far more national than you would gather from reading the letters says <PERSON>Edelstein Voltaire</PERSON> s network explodes like a firework over <LOCATION>France</LOCATION> with tails to <LOCATION>England Russia</LOCATION> and the Swiss cantons <PERSON>John Locke</PERSON> s covers <LOCATION>England</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Scotland</LOCATION> with a foray to <LOCATION>Dublin</LOCATION> Correspondence by <PERSON>Joseph Addison</PERSON> who founded The Spectator sprawls from <LOCATION>London</LOCATION> to <LOCATION>Dublin Paris Chennai</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Venice</LOCATION> For <PERSON>Edelstein</PERSON> who works on <ORGANIZATION>Voltaire</ORGANIZATION> and the Enlightenment the Franco centric nature of the philosopher s network was startling You don t necessarily focus on the short letter to <LOCATION>Paris</LOCATION> he says You get more excited about that letter to <PERSON>Catherine the Great</PERSON> and there s enough of them that it makes it seem like wow <PERSON>Voltaire</PERSON> was writing regularly to St Petersburg Then you see the overwhelming number of letters to <LOCATION>Paris</LOCATION> and the rest of <LOCATION>France</LOCATION> and the balance shifts The <ORGANIZATION>Stanford</ORGANIZATION> team proved that it could map a correspondence network no small feat in itself but the tool they created had a serious limitation It didn t tell the user how much data was missing from the map In the case of <ORGANIZATION>Voltaire</ORGANIZATION> the visualization represented less than 12 percent of his 19 000 letters because the tool couldn t accommodate letters with missing or incomplete location data Our social scientist friends said oh you can fix the data you can interpolate says <PERSON>Coleman</PERSON> clearly appalled by the idea of tinkering with the historical record to fit a computer program The point for us was to make visualizations that actually suit our data and tell us what we want to know or help us discover things If they wanted to reflect the untidiness of the historical record the <ORGANIZATION>Stanford</ORGANIZATION> team realized they were going to have to make the tools themselves None of the out of the box analytics packages could manage ambiguity We re not using visualization for analytics says <PERSON>Coleman</PERSON> When you re looking at the past you re looking at incompleteness and fragmentary data That s just a given And none of those packages know how to handle that TRIAL AND ERROR In 2009 the Mapping the Republic of Letters project won a Digging into Data Challenge grant an international program supported by <ORGANIZATION>NEH</ORGANIZATION> that funds scholars to develop tools to help humanists parse the growing body of digital archives For the Digging into Data grant <PERSON>Edelstein Findlen</PERSON> and <PERSON>Coleman</PERSON> assembled a team at the <ORGANIZATION>Stanford Humanities Center</ORGANIZATION> that included scholars programmers and graduate students from the <ORGANIZATION>University of Oklahoma Oxford University</ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION>Stanford</ORGANIZATION> They also formed a partnership with <ORGANIZATION>DensityDesign Research Lab</ORGANIZATION> at <ORGANIZATION>Politecnico</ORGANIZATION> di Milano to develop the visualization tools For this new phase the project expanded its dataset to include correspondence by Italian physician and naturalist <PERSON>Antonio Vallisneri</PERSON> 13 600 letters Dutch scholar <PERSON>Joseph Scaliger</PERSON> 1 650 letters <ORGANIZATION>Linnaeus</ORGANIZATION> 6 000 letters <ORGANIZATION>Descartes</ORGANIZATION> 20 000 letters German Jesuit scholar <PERSON>Athanasius Kircher</PERSON> 2 291 letters and <PERSON>Benjamin Franklin</PERSON> 22 700 letters along with the correspondences collected by the International Centre for the History of Universities and Science at the <ORGANIZATION>University of Bologna</ORGANIZATION> The first tool developed <ORGANIZATION>Corrispondenza</ORGANIZATION> not only mapped letters but also generated charts showing how many letters had been plotted on the map and how many lacked sufficient data to be represented Next came Inquiry which sought to rethink how scholars access an online collection Typically when a user searches a digital archive they start by typing something into a query box click go and wait to see what the database churns out With Inquiry a user can browse the collection via map or timeline To help users dig deeper they developed Ink which combines a clickable map with charts that show how many letters were sent by year It also uses another tool called Fineo that can sort the biographical data of correspondents When <PERSON>Giovanna Ceserani</PERSON> a professor of classics at <ORGANIZATION>Stanford</ORGANIZATION> joined the project she introduced a new challenge how to visualize people visiting the same city Scholars are always interested in figuring out if historical figures might have crossed paths It raises fun and sometimes productive what if questions What if they attended the same lecture What if they were invited to the same dinner party What if they stayed at the same hotel Friendships made during travel could generate correspondences that last for years and expand social circles If two Englishmen previously unknown to each other struck up a friendship while on holiday in <LOCATION>Florence</LOCATION> that friendship might continue when they returned home to <LOCATION>London</LOCATION> The shared connection of travel can become a springboard for politics business deals and marriage Since the letters dataset wouldn t work for mapping travel <PERSON>Ceserani</PERSON> proposed using the information contained in A Dictionary of British and Irish <ORGANIZATION>Travelers</ORGANIZATION> to <LOCATION>Italy</LOCATION> 1701 1800 The latter part of the Republic of Letters coincides with the era of the Grand Tour when lords ladies budding artists and young men of means embarked on extensive trips throughout <LOCATION>Europe</LOCATION> The dictionary contains information about more than six thousand Britons who toured the Italian peninsula An entry on the Earl of <LOCATION>Abingdon</LOCATION> for example notes that he journeyed to <LOCATION>Rome</LOCATION> February 1763 <LOCATION>Naples</LOCATION> March 1763 <LOCATION>Turin</LOCATION> September 1764 <LOCATION>Rome</LOCATION> February to April 1765 and <LOCATION>Florence</LOCATION> May 1765 The entry also notes that <PERSON>Voltaire</PERSON> who met <LOCATION>Abingdon</LOCATION> in <LOCATION>Geneva</LOCATION> thought the earl had a weakness for drink dogs and women After experimenting with different approaches the team hit upon the idea of representing the travelers itineraries in a chronological view rather than grouping them geographically By doing it this way users can see who was in <LOCATION>Italy</LOCATION> in 1732 and then dig down to find out who was in the same city at the same time The experiment with the British travelers prompted the <ORGANIZATION>Stanford</ORGANIZATION> team to return to the idea of using graphs to represent correspondence networks Initially we were concerned with a literal map said <PERSON>Findlen</PERSON> The more time goes on we ve come to see that as a limit Although they were getting closer to visualizing the complexities of a correspondence network the software kept weighting the lines on the map to favor heavy traffic routes The team wanted something that would treat each connection as having equal value It would be even better if users could make connections between correspondents to identify commonalities Think of it as the Republic of Letters version of Six Degrees of Separation In August 2012 the <ORGANIZATION>Stanford</ORGANIZATION> team assembled scholars programmers and designers to build a tool that could apply network graph logic to a historical data set Or to put it a different way They wanted a tool that would let users decide what to emphasize and what connections to explore rather than having the tool decide for them They came up with Knot VOLTAIRE ENCORE What do all these tools mean for looking at a correspondence network Let s return to Voltaire When <PERSON>Edelstein</PERSON> and his colleagues first mapped <PERSON>Voltaire</PERSON> s correspondence they could account for only about 12 percent of his network They didn t know the location of both sender and recipient for the other 88 percent The map generated from that 12 percent showed <ORGANIZATION>Voltaire</ORGANIZATION> s network centered primarily in <LOCATION>France</LOCATION> Was <ORGANIZATION>Voltaire</ORGANIZATION> who is usually considered one of the most cosmopolitan men of his time really so Franco centric Location data might have been sparse but ample biographical information revealed that 70 percent of <ORGANIZATION>Voltaire</ORGANIZATION> s correspondents were French One of the dominant narratives of the Enlightenment posits a direct line connecting <PERSON>John Locke</PERSON> to the Glorious Revolution to the advent of liberty and freedom of expression in <LOCATION>England</LOCATION> which is then transferred to <LOCATION>France</LOCATION> where <ORGANIZATION>Voltaire</ORGANIZATION> and others run with it Scholars frequently portray <PERSON>Voltaire</PERSON> as having a special connection to <LOCATION>England</LOCATION> and are fond of highlighting <ORGANIZATION>Voltaire</ORGANIZATION> s letters to <PERSON>Jonathan Swift</PERSON> and <PERSON>Alexander Pope</PERSON> The map however showed only a tiny number of letters between <LOCATION>France</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>England</LOCATION> At first <PERSON>Edelstein</PERSON> thought it might be a data problem but when he used Ink to drill down into the nationalities of <ORGANIZATION>Voltaire</ORGANIZATION> s correspondents he found few Englishmen <PERSON>Voltaire</PERSON> s primary English correspondents are Sir <PERSON>Everard Fawkener</PERSON> a silk merchant he met before his <LOCATION>London</LOCATION> exile and <PERSON>George Keate</PERSON> an English poet he met in <LOCATION>Rome</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Geneva</LOCATION> As for Swift and <PERSON>Pope</PERSON> you can count those letters on one hand Looking for an answer <PERSON>Edelstein</PERSON> went back to <PERSON>Voltaire</PERSON> s writings It s right there in front of us <ORGANIZATION>Voltaire</ORGANIZATION> is pretty clear that after the death of <LOCATION>Newton</LOCATION> nothing interesting is happening in <LOCATION>England</LOCATION> The <LOCATION>England</LOCATION> problem was a clear example of the map and visualizations serving a discovery function It s inspired <PERSON>Edelstein</PERSON> to rethink the place of English thought in <ORGANIZATION>Voltaire</ORGANIZATION> s work WHAT ABOUT BEN If <PERSON>Voltaire</PERSON> left an indelible mark on eighteenth century <LOCATION>France</LOCATION> then the same can be said of <PERSON>Benjamin Franklin</PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION>America Before Franklin</ORGANIZATION> became one of the Founding Fathers he made a name for himself in <LOCATION>Philadelphia</LOCATION> as a publisher and innovator In 1727 at the age of twenty one he formed Junto a group of tradesmen and artisans who gathered to discuss key issues of the day Four years later he came up with the idea of creating a subscription library which made it possible for members to read and share books they might not otherwise be able to afford He also founded the <ORGANIZATION>Academy and College of Philadelphia now the University of Pennsylvania</ORGANIZATION> becoming its first president in 1749 Along with running his own printing business <PERSON>Franklin</PERSON> also served as the publisher of the <LOCATION>Pennsylvania</LOCATION> Gazette When he wasn t moving type and discussing politics <ORGANIZATION>Franklin</ORGANIZATION> conducted scientific experiments inventing the <ORGANIZATION>Franklin</ORGANIZATION> stove a metal lined fireplace and bifocal glasses not to mention his famous proposal of flying a kite with a key during an electrical storm to prove that lightning is electricity If the Republic of Letters was an imagined community of Western thinkers then <PERSON>Franklin</PERSON> was certainly a member But as a resident of <LOCATION>Philadelphia</LOCATION> which had a population of 25 000 in 1750 Franklin didn t have the same resources as someone who lived in a European capital <LOCATION>Paris</LOCATION> had 565 000 residents while <LOCATION>London</LOCATION> was bursting with 700 000 There s also the matter of the <LOCATION>Atlantic Ocean</LOCATION> which presented a vast physical obstacle to connecting with his European counterparts Intellectual life as it has to be formed in a colonial setting has a whole series of different features says <PERSON>Caroline Winterer</PERSON> who was recently appointed director of the <ORGANIZATION>Stanford Humanities Center For Winterer</ORGANIZATION> a historian of colonial <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> one of the attractions of joining the project was getting at the question of how cosmopolitan <PERSON>Franklin</PERSON> was Did he have an international network of correspondents like his European counterparts More than 15 000 letters written or received by <PERSON>Franklin</PERSON> have survived making his network ripe for mapping But unlike the dataset for <ORGANIZATION>Voltaire Franklin</ORGANIZATION> s had to be made from scratch To manage <PERSON>Winterer</PERSON> and her team limited the scope to letters from 1756 to 1763 the period during which <PERSON>Franklin</PERSON> visited <LOCATION>England</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Scotland</LOCATION> for the first time The idea was to see what <PERSON>Franklin</PERSON> s network was like before during and after the trip The project discovered that before <PERSON>Franklin</PERSON> ventured to <LOCATION>London</LOCATION> he received no letters from across the <LOCATION>Atlantic</LOCATION> His correspondence was geographically 100 percent American By January 1762 five years into his time abroad all of his letters came from <LOCATION>England</LOCATION> In December 1763 after <PERSON>Franklin</PERSON> had returned home his correspondence returned to its American centric focus but now one quarter of his letters came from overseas One of the big findings of the <ORGANIZATION>Franklin</ORGANIZATION> project is that until he goes to <LOCATION>Paris</LOCATION> in 76 for the American Revolution he s not nearly as cosmopolitan as we thought he was says Winterer The people who were writing to <PERSON>Franklin</PERSON> from foreign places turn out to be Americans or Britons who happen to be someplace exotic For example one of the outliers on the map is a letter from <LOCATION>Tunis</LOCATION> It s not written by an Islamic scholar or Italian expatriate but a woman named <PERSON>Amelia Evans</PERSON> who has ties to <LOCATION>Philadelphia</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Boston</LOCATION> and is looking to enlist <PERSON>Franklin</PERSON> s help in settling her affairs The American slant is also evident when it comes to <PERSON>Franklin</PERSON> s most frequent correspondents At the top of the list is <ORGANIZATION>Isaac Norris Quaker</ORGANIZATION> politician and speaker of the <LOCATION>Pennsylvania</LOCATION> Assembly Number two is <PERSON>Mary Stevenson</PERSON> the daughter of <ORGANIZATION>Franklin</ORGANIZATION> s landlady in <LOCATION>London Franklin</LOCATION> s third most frequent correspondent is his business partner <PERSON>David Hall</PERSON> who minded the day to day operations of <ORGANIZATION>Franklin and Hall</ORGANIZATION> the printing business they owned together <PERSON>Deborah Franklin</PERSON> his common law wife comes in fourth Fearful of sea travel <PERSON>Franklin</PERSON> didn t accompany her husband on his trip to <LOCATION>England</LOCATION> And in fifth position is <PERSON>William Strahan</PERSON> director of the <ORGANIZATION>Stationers Company</ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION>London</LOCATION> which published works by <PERSON>Edward Gibbon David Hume</PERSON> and <PERSON>Samuel Johnson Franklin</PERSON> and <PERSON>Hall</PERSON> served as the agent for <PERSON>Strahan</PERSON> s books in the American colonies With two women at the top of list you might surmise <PERSON>Franklin</PERSON> had a healthy correspondence with women which would fit with his reputation as a lady s man But if you sort <ORGANIZATION>Franklin</ORGANIZATION> s correspondents by gender <PERSON>Mary Stevenson</PERSON> and <PERSON>Deborah Franklin</PERSON> prove to be anomalies as <PERSON>Franklin</PERSON> corresponded primarily with men <ORGANIZATION>Franklin</ORGANIZATION> s network is a long tail network says Winterer He has five people that he writes to voluminously and weekly And then there is a whole bunch of people who he writes to just once or mostly write him just once to get a favor out of him Given that <PERSON>Franklin</PERSON> and <PERSON>Voltaire</PERSON> were contemporaries <PERSON>Voltaire</PERSON> being born in 1694 and <ORGANIZATION>Franklin</ORGANIZATION> in 1706 it would be natural to wonder if they ever corresponded The two luminaries never wrote to each other but a comparison of their datasets revealed that they had correspondents in common making them part of the same intellectual network FORWARDING ADDRESS As news started to trickle out about what the Mapping the Republic of Letters project was up to other scholars clamored to use the tools Unfortunately those requests had to be turned down because the tools were still prototypes bare bones with no instructions and no <PERSON>Coleman</PERSON> at hand to fix any glitches that arose With the help of an <ORGANIZATION>NEH Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> Implementation Grant the project began work this fall on an open source web application that will allow historians and other humanists to apply visualization techniques to datasets The application named <PERSON>Athanasius</PERSON> will debut in 2015 <PERSON>Edelstein Findlen</PERSON> and Winterer are well aware that their new digital bent doesn t necessarily sit well with some in the profession but they point to the benefits of expanding their analytical toolbox After all no single methodology can answer all of a historian s questions There s always the healthy skepticism that you re going to skip some essential steps in reading the nuances of the content by doing this says <PERSON>Findlen</PERSON> I don t think any of us have thought that we should skip anything that is important or valuable about traditional research because it s what we do day in and day out <PERSON>Winterer</PERSON> agrees noting that the visualizations work in tandem with close readings of the letters It s like adding another dimension another layer of paint You just look for different things in the letters when you re reading them knowing that Oh this is the only letter from <LOCATION>Tunis</LOCATION> in the <LOCATION>London</LOCATION> decades Isn t that interesting What was it like for Franklin to open this It s also clear that they have all benefited from the collaboration required by the project Discussing their datasets and the problems they ve encountered has led to sharing their research in ways that don t normally occur among colleagues at the same university We have a tendency to mostly share work when it s all beautiful with a little bow says Winterer But in fact for a lot of people including me that s not the most interesting part of the work The most interesting part is accompanying the author on the path of inquiry Aside from the opportunity to try out new methodologies and better know her colleagues <PERSON>Findlen</PERSON> also sees the project as a chance to invest in the future of the profession She points to the increasing number of jobs being advertised that call for historians with digital skills Not all of her students will be digitally inclined but for the ones who are she believes she should facilitate their interest Why not better understand the process so that we can introduce students to these skills and see where they want to take the field in the future About the Author <PERSON>Meredith Hindley</PERSON> is senior writer of <ORGANIZATION>Humanities Funding Information Dan Edelstein of Stanford University</ORGANIZATION> has received two grants from NEH to support digital humanities projects in which correspondence collections are visualized The first grant in 2009 for Mapping the Republic of Letters totaled 99 244 the second in 2013 amounted to 297 137 and is supporting further development of visualization techniques and applying them to other historical periods <ORGANIZATION>Keywords Benjamin Franklin Correspondence Dan Edelstein Digital</ORGANIZATION> humanities eighteenth century Electronic Enlightenment Project <LOCATION>London</LOCATION> maps <ORGANIZATION>Oxford University Paris Philadelphia Stanford University Voltaire</ORGANIZATION> image PRINT PRINT Email Related Stories image Cartoonist <PERSON>Clifford Berryman</PERSON> s illustration of 1912 presidential candidates 1912 Presidential Candidates image Bruce Cole Renaissance Scholar at Work image Portrait of <PERSON>Martha Jefferson Randolph</PERSON> Impertinent Questions with <PERSON>Cynthia A Kierner</PERSON> image <PERSON>Tom Wolff</PERSON> photo of <PERSON>William Adams</PERSON> The Education of <PERSON>William Adams</PERSON> image Exhibition Hall at <ORGANIZATION>Wagner Free Institute of Science in Philadelphia Wagner Free Institute</ORGANIZATION> of Science 2018 Spring image Cover illustration of <PERSON>Frederick Douglass</PERSON> read the latest issue Subscribe To Humanities Magazine Now Browse Back Issues image Portrait of Ulysses S Grant Winter 2018 image Americans and Vietnamese refugees in Hue in 1968 Fall 2017 image Illustration of <PERSON>Henry David Thoreau</PERSON> Summer 2017 image Matha C Nussbaum Spring 2017 image Illustration of <ORGANIZATION>Mary Moody Emerson</ORGANIZATION> Winter 2017 image Illustration of T S Eliot Fall 2016 image Photo of man in boat supervising swimming children Summer 2016 image 2016 Jefferson Lecturer <PERSON>Ken Burns</PERSON> Spring 2016 image Ballerinas standing in window alcove of ballet school January February 2016 image Illustration of Pilgrims during clearing of land November December 2015 image Alabaster piece from King <PERSON>Tut</PERSON> exhibit that toured the U S in the 1970s September October 2015 image <PERSON>Willa Cather</PERSON> July August 2015 image <PERSON>Robert Riggs</PERSON> s July 4 at <LOCATION>Coney Island</LOCATION> May June 2015 image <PERSON>Anna Deavere Smith</PERSON> March April 2015 image C zanne self portrait January February 2015 image Illustration of H L Mencken November December 2014 image Portrait of <PERSON>James McNeill</PERSON> Whistler September October 2014 image Photo of U S troops preparing to cross English Channel on D Day July August 2014 image <PERSON>Walter Isaacson</PERSON> 2014 Jefferson Lecturer May June 2014 image Illustration of Eudora Welty March April 2014 image Count of <LOCATION>Santiago</LOCATION> de Calimaya January February 2014 image Neo sign in <LOCATION>Tucson</LOCATION> November December 2013 image Illustration based on poem by Amy Lowell September October 2013 image Cover for July August 2013 Humanities magazine July August 2013 image Beach Landscape May June 2013 image Photo portrait of Martin Scorsese March April 2013 image Humanities Civil Rights Special Edition 2013 Cover Special Edition 2013 image Portrait of Alessandro de Medici January February 2013 image Oyster Bar Grand Central Terminal <LOCATION>New York City</LOCATION> November December 2012 image Rain god vessel September October 2012 image Book buying along the <LOCATION>Seine</LOCATION> in 1940 July August 2012 image <PERSON>Wendell Berry</PERSON> photo portrait May June 2012 image Secret Kiss illustration by <PERSON>Georges Barbier</PERSON> March April 2012 image Philip Larkin January February 2012 image molded plywood chair November December 2011 image Dictionary of American Regional English September October 2011 image Balinese bird mask July August 2011 image Drew Gilpin Faust 2011 Jefferson Lecturer May June 2011 image Humanities Magazine March April 2011 cover March April 2011 image Unidentified Civil War soldier in a <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> Zouave uniform January February 2011 image Black Swan Record label 1921 November December 2010 image Humanities September October 2010 Cover September October 2010 image Freud vs Kierkegaard July August 2010 image <PERSON>Jonathan Spence</PERSON> 2010 Jefferson Lecturer May June 2010 image The Yankee Driver Thomas Hart Benton March April 2010 image Image of January February 2010 Humanities cover January February 2010 image Detail from the Kangxi Emperor s Southern Inspection Tour Scroll Three November December 2009 image Humanities Magazine September October 2009 cover September October 2009 image Humanities Magazine July August 2009 cover July August 2009 image <PERSON>Leon Kass</PERSON> the 38th Annual Jefferson Lecturer May June 2009 image San Baudelio de Berlanga circa 1000 March April 2009 image Cover of January February 2009 Humanities January February 2009 image Church of Odigitria November December 2008 image Humanities Magazine September October 2008 cover September October 2008 image Humanities Magazine July August 2008 cover July August 2008 image Caricature of <PERSON>John Updike</PERSON> May June 2008 image <PERSON>Gary Cooper</PERSON> fashion portrait March April 2008 image Portrait of Richa Franks January February 2008 image Fashion showroom in <LOCATION>Miami</LOCATION> in the 1950s November December 2007 image Painting of The Midnight Ride of Paul Revere 1931 September October 2007 image Humanities Magazine July August 2007 cover July August 2007 image 2007 Jefferson Lecturer <PERSON>Harvey Mansfield</PERSON> May June 2007 image Humanities Magazine March April 2007 cover March April 2007 image Recreation of Susan Constant largest of three boats that landed at <LOCATION>Jamestown</LOCATION> January February 2007 image <PERSON>Leslie Caron</PERSON> and <PERSON>Gene Kelly</PERSON> in the 1951 film An American in <LOCATION>Paris</LOCATION> November December 2006 image Humanities Magazine September October Cover September October 2006 image Matrak i Nasuh s Account of the Military Campaigns of Sultan S leyman 1537 38 July August 2006 image Humanities Magazine May June 2006 cover May June 2006 image Humanities Magazine March April 2006 cover March April 2006 image Humanities Magazine January February 2006 cover January February 2006 image Humanities Magazine November December 2005 cover November December 2005 image Humanities Magazine September October 2005 cover September October 2005 image Humanities Magazine July August 2005 cover July August 2005 image Humanities Magazine May June 2005 cover May June 2005 image Humanities Magazine March April 2005 cover March April 2005 image Humanities Magazine January February 2005 cover January February 2005 image Humanities Magazine November December 2004 cover November December 2004 image Humanities Magazine September October 2004 cover September October 2004 image Humanities Magazine July August 2004 cover July August 2004 image Humanities Magazine May June 2004 cover May June 2004 image Humanities Magazine March April 2004 cover March April 2004 image Humanities Magazine January February 2004 cover January February 2004 image Humanities Magazine November December 2003 cover November December 2003 image Humanities magazine September October 2003 cover September October 2003 image Humanities Magazine July August 2003 cover July August 2003 image Humanities Magazine May June 2003 cover May June 2003 image Humanities Magazine March April 2003 cover March April 2003 image Humanities Magazine January February 2003 cover January February 2003 image Humanities Magazine November December 2002 cover November December 2002 image Humanities Magazine September October 2002 cover September October 2002 image Humanities Magazine July August 2002 cover July August 2002 image Humanities Magazine May June 2002 cover May June 2002 image Humanities Magazine March April 2002 cover March April 2002 image Humanities Magazine January February 2002 cover January February 2002 image Humanities Magazine November December 2001 cover November December 2001 image Humanities Magazine September October 2001 cover September October 2001 image Humanities Magazine July August 2001 cover July August 2001 image Humanities Magazine May June 2001 cover May June 2001 image Humanities Magazine March April 2001 cover March April 2001 image Humanities Magazine January February 2001 cover January February 2001 Back Next Browse All Issues Classics A selection of old favorites What Sets Italian Americans Off From Other Immigrants Family and work for starters according to a new TV documentary By <PERSON>Vincent J Cannato</PERSON> The Strange Politics of <PERSON>Gertrude Stein</PERSON> Was the den mother of modernism a fascist By <PERSON>Barbara Will King Andrew</PERSON> and the Bank <PERSON>Andrew Jackson</PERSON> stares down the national bank and wins By <PERSON>Daniel Feller</PERSON> The Quiet Greatness of <PERSON>Eudora Welty</PERSON> Even toward the end of her life the writer revealed a youthful zest for life and art By <PERSON>Danny Heitman</PERSON> Why Spinoza Was Excommunicated Before writing a single book Bento de <PERSON>Spinoza</PERSON> was considered a dangerous thinker By <PERSON>Steven Nadler</PERSON> <ORGANIZATION>View All Edsitement Standing Together Chronicling America Created Equal About NEH Contact NEH National Council on the Humanities State Humanities</ORGANIZATION> Councils Awards and Honors Budget Performance and Legal Information Plain Writing at <ORGANIZATION>NEH Office of the Inspector General Equal Employment Opportunities Career</ORGANIZATION> Opportunities Website Disclaimers Grants Search for a Grant Not sure what to do Let us help you Become a Peer Reviewer Manage Your Grant The Application Review Process Brand Materials Divisions and <ORGANIZATION>Offices Education Programs Preservation and Access Public Programs Research Programs Federal State Partnership Office of Challenge Grants Office of Digital Humanities News Press</ORGANIZATION> Releases News Archive NEH in the <ORGANIZATION>News NEH Impact Reports Events Humanities Back Issues Subscribe Magazine Staff Explore Contact Us National Endowment for the Humanities</ORGANIZATION> 400 <ORGANIZATION>7th Street SW Washington DC</ORGANIZATION> 20506 General Information 1 800 NEH 1121 202 606 8400 Federal Relay TTY Users 800 877 8399 questions at neh dot gov Connect With Us <ORGANIZATION>YouTube Twitter Facebook NEH Social Media</ORGANIZATION> www neh gov FOIA No Fear Act Office of the Inspector General Accessibility Privacy Policy and Terms of Use Website Disclaimers Open Gov Plain Writing at <ORGANIZATION>NEH</ORGANIZATION></ner>
