<ner>Jump to Navigation Advertise About Contact Subscribe X News Quick Takes Views Blog U <ORGANIZATION>Career Advice Admissions Digital Learning Diversity Search News</ORGANIZATION> amp Opinions Find A Job Events Data amp Surveys Booklets Audio Topics Sponsored Content AAUP Compensation Data Around the Web Events amp People Subscribe Free Hire Faculty amp Staff Contact About Advertise News amp Opinion Jobs image image image image News Opinions Data amp Surveys Events Rejecting Business Major Trustee Becomes President <PERSON>Monopsony</PERSON> and Jobs in Higher Ed image Admissions Digital Learning Diversity Careers Subscribe Free Advertise Hire Faculty amp Staff Find a <ORGANIZATION>Job News Admissions Insider Digital Learning Diversity Matters Views Career Advice Blog U Surveys Webinars Events amp People Jobs Capital Campaigns Admissions Books Technology Community Colleges Diversity Teaching</ORGANIZATION> amp Learning Global Audio Booklets More News Topics Teaching and Learning Print This image <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> as Corporatist Restructuring Controversial article argues digital humanities scholars are intentionally or not leading a neoliberal takeover of colleges and universities By <PERSON>Carl Straumsheim</PERSON> May 6 2016 Comments image Many humanities scholars have praised the digital humanities as one of the more promising developments for their disciplines But a recent article in the <ORGANIZATION>Los Angeles Review of Books</ORGANIZATION> compares digital humanities scholars to <LOCATION>Silicon Valley</LOCATION> disruptors saying they are leading a corporatist restructuring of their fields The article written by three digital culture studies and English professors at <ORGANIZATION>Carleton University in Canada Virginia Commonwealth University</ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION>University of the West of England</ORGANIZATION> has once again brought to light the polarization among humanities scholars Some have applauded co authors <PERSON>Daniel Allington Sarah Brouillette</PERSON> and <PERSON>David Golumbia</PERSON> for their devastating critique while others have dismissed the article outright for being too one sided What digital humanities is not about despite its explicit claims is the use of digital or quantitative methodologies to answer research questions in the humanities the article which ran on Sunday reads It is instead about the promotion of project based learning and lab based research over reading and writing the rebranding of insecure campus employment as an empowering alt ac career choice and the redefinition of technical expertise as a form indeed the superior form of humanist knowledge In a follow up email the authors added When the focus is on skills training the building of highly expensive tools and archives and the management of teams critical thought tends to be pushed to the margins The article is the latest think piece questioning the value of using digital tools and techniques in humanities disciplines In 2014 for example a trio of columns in Slate Ozy and the <LOCATION>New Republic</LOCATION> criticized the hype around the digital humanities questioning whether the interest was a passing fad <PERSON>Allington Brouillette</PERSON> and <PERSON>Golumbia</PERSON> do not treat the digital humanities as a joke however They trace the history of the digital humanities movement back to the subfields of textual studies and humanities computing writing that it was born from disdain and at times outright contempt not just for humanities scholarship but for the standards procedures and claims of leading literary scholars The argument exposes the conflict at the heart of the article between traditional interpretive literary scholarship and research that produces digital archives and tools Connected to that conflict is a debate about the role of organizations such as the <ORGANIZATION>Andrew W Mellon Foundation Google</ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION>National Endowment for the Humanities</ORGANIZATION> whose earmarked grants for digital humanities projects are funding a shift away from the former and toward the latter a topic others have previously touched on Finally the article concludes with critical look at the diversity within the digital humanities movement whose key figures remain mostly white men Together those three points of criticism add up to an argument that digital humanities are promoting a neoliberal takeover of universities leading to a <LOCATION>Silicon Valley</LOCATION> like situation where tech skills are valued more highly than other skills where diversity is yet another buzzword and where success as faculty members in the humanities is defined by how much they are able to secure in grant money the authors write From the viewpoint of the neoliberal university the best kind of research and the kind to be most handsomely rewarded is the kind that brings in the most external funding the article reads This is one of the main reasons why the digitization of archives and the development of software tools conspicuously expensive activities that influential funding bodies have enthusiastically supported can exert such powerful attraction effectively enabling scholarship to be reconfigured on the model of the tech start up with public private and charitable funding in place of <LOCATION>Silicon Valley</LOCATION> venture capital Instead of expanding the scope of their departments digital humanities scholars are making gains by displacing other forms of scholarship the authors write It unavoidably also suggests that other approaches in the humanities fit less well into the contemporary university because the implied measure of success is economic Critics have responded to the article differently some addressing the issue of diversity others unpacking the term neoliberalism One commonly heard counterargument is that the article generalizes the digital developments in the various humanities disciplines and across colleges of different size and type You can t say digital humanities is one thing <PERSON>Martha Nell Smith</PERSON> founding director of the <ORGANIZATION>Maryland Institute for Technology in the Humanities</ORGANIZATION> said in an interview When tools are emphasized at the expense of the scholarship being produced there have been problems On the other hand there are some terrific movements within the digital humanities <PERSON>Smith</PERSON> said the article is another example of the conglomeration of arguments against the digital humanities that crop up from time to time <PERSON>Smith</PERSON> was quoted in the article which she said contained points she agreed with and others she disagreed with I don t see a reason for the discussion to be polarized and its seems like that s happened in the responses to the article <PERSON>Smith</PERSON> professor of English at the <ORGANIZATION>University of Maryland at College Park</ORGANIZATION> said It s not black and white <PERSON>Alan Liu</PERSON> a professor of English at the <ORGANIZATION>University of California at Santa Barbara</ORGANIZATION> whose 2012 essay was quoted in the article to make a point about the influence of funding agencies tweeted a similar critique He criticized the article for being an attempt at a last word foreclosing the critical potential of digital humanities saying it doesn t see the nuance that digital humanists have real critical goals too <PERSON>Roopika Risam</PERSON> assistant professor of English at <ORGANIZATION>Salem State University</ORGANIZATION> in a blog post debated the ethical imperative for digital humanities scholars She pointed out that institutions like hers regional public universities are often left out of the debate about the digital humanities even though they and community colleges make up the largest segment of higher education by student enrollment In fact our undergraduate and graduate students are our only rationale for doing digital humanities <PERSON>Risam</PERSON> wrote We couldn t be farther from the cartoonish fantasy of digital humanities that circulates in the clickbait du jour Read more by <PERSON>Carl Straumsheim</PERSON> jump to comments image Be the first to know Get our free daily newsletter Topics Adjuncts Admissions Assessment and <ORGANIZATION>Accountability Books and Publishing Community Colleges Diversity For Profit Higher Ed Global Health</ORGANIZATION> Professions Religious Colleges Retirement Issues Student Aid and Loans Students and Violence Teaching and Learning Technology image Want to advertise Click here image Browse Jobs by Category Subscribe for free today Related Jobs from Inside Higher Ed <ORGANIZATION>Careers image Arts amp Humanities</ORGANIZATION> jobs Visiting <ORGANIZATION>Instructor Instrumental Music University of Mary Hardin Baylor image Arts amp Humanities</ORGANIZATION> jobs Assistant Associate Professor Music Education choral track <ORGANIZATION>University of Mary Hardin Baylor image Arts amp Humanities</ORGANIZATION> jobs <ORGANIZATION>Performing Arts Theatre Technician Antelope Valley College Search Jobs Hiring Post</ORGANIZATION> Your Job bookmark comment target Expand commentsHide comments Join the conversation View the discussion thread Today s News from Inside Higher Ed image No Deal on Business Major image No Academic Experience Necessary image Presidents Back Free Speech Inside Higher Ed s Quick Takes <ORGANIZATION>Mercyhurst Ends Honors for Former President University Press Group Decries Censorship Arizona Court</ORGANIZATION> DACA Students Ineligible for In <ORGANIZATION>State Tuition Adams State</ORGANIZATION> President Resigns U British <ORGANIZATION>Columbia Apologizes for Role</ORGANIZATION> in Indian Residential School System President Resigns After Discrimination Complaint What Others Are Reading Viewed Past Day Week Month Year Back to Top Inside Higher Ed 1150 <LOCATION>Connecticut Avenue NW</LOCATION> Suite 400 <LOCATION>Washington DC</LOCATION> 20036 Ph 1 202 659 9208 Fax 1 202 659 9381 image image image image image image 1150 <LOCATION>Connecticut Avenue</LOCATION> NW Suite 400 PH 1 202 659 9208 Copyright 2018 Secondary menu Contact Us About Us For Employers Advertise Work For Us Testimonials Rights and Permissions Privacy Share our content Get our Daily News Update Copyright 2018</ner>
