<ner>CLIR Fellowships amp Grants <ORGANIZATION>DLF Publications Join Give CLIR Programs Digital Library Federation DLF Forum Digital Library</ORGANIZATION> of the Middle East Digitizing Hidden Special Collections and Archives Recordings at Risk <ORGANIZATION>Mellon Fellowships for Dissertation Research Leading Change Institute DLF</ORGANIZATION> eResearch Network Postdoctoral Fellowship Program image CLIR image CLIR CLIR Toggle navigation About President s Message News Staff Governance Become a CLIR Sponsor or <ORGANIZATION>DLF</ORGANIZATION> Member Current Sponsors Members and Funders History CLIR Brandmark Publications Reports CLIR Issues Annual Report Other Resources Archives Ordering and <ORGANIZATION>Customer Service Initiatives amp Partnerships Digital Library Federation</ORGANIZATION> Chief Information Officers in <ORGANIZATION>Liberal Arts Colleges CLIR Affiliates Digital Library of the Middle East Leading Change Institute National Digital Stewardship Residency NDSR Assessment Fellowships amp Grants Digitizing Hidden Collections Mellon Fellowships for Dissertation Research</ORGANIZATION> in Original Sources Postdoctoral Fellowship Program Recordings at Risk Rovelstad Scholarship in International Librarianship Connect Communities Directory Re Thinking Blog Job Connect image CLIR image CLIR CLIR Toggle navigation About President s Message News Staff Governance Become a CLIR Sponsor or <ORGANIZATION>DLF</ORGANIZATION> Member Current Sponsors Members and Funders History CLIR Brandmark Publications Reports CLIR Issues Annual Report Other Resources Archives Ordering and <ORGANIZATION>Customer Service Initiatives amp Partnerships Digital Library Federation</ORGANIZATION> Chief Information Officers in <ORGANIZATION>Liberal Arts Colleges CLIR Affiliates Digital Library of the Middle East Leading Change Institute National Digital Stewardship Residency NDSR Assessment Fellowships amp Grants Digitizing Hidden Collections Mellon Fellowships for Dissertation Research</ORGANIZATION> in Original Sources Postdoctoral Fellowship Program Recordings at Risk Rovelstad Scholarship in International Librarianship Connect Communities Directory Re Thinking Blog Job Connect One <ORGANIZATION>Culture Computationally Intensive Research</ORGANIZATION> in the <ORGANIZATION>Humanities and Social Sciences Home</ORGANIZATION> CLIR Publications CLIR Reports One Culture Computa image One Culture Computationally Intensive Research in the Humanities and Social Sciences A Report on the Experiences of First Respondents to the Digging Into Data Challenge by <PERSON>Christa Williford</PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION>Charles Henry Research Design</ORGANIZATION> by <PERSON>Amy Friedlander</PERSON> June 2012 44 pp 20 ISBN 978 1 932326 40 6 CLIR pub151 PDF Download of Main Report excluding case studies 1 MB file gt gt Full Text of Main Report gt gt This report culminates two years of work by CLIR staff involving extensive interviews and site visits with scholars engaged in international research collaborations involving computational analysis of large data corpora These scholars were the first recipients of grants through the Digging into Data program led by the <ORGANIZATION>NEH</ORGANIZATION> who partnered with JISC in the <LOCATION>UK SSHRC</LOCATION> in <LOCATION>Canada</LOCATION> and the <ORGANIZATION>NSF</ORGANIZATION> to fund the first eight initiatives The report introduces the eight projects and discusses the importance of these cases as models for the future of research in the academy Additional information about the projects is provided in the individual case studies below this additional material is not included in the print or PDF versions of the published report Report Recommendations 1 Expand our concept of research 2 Expand our concept of research data and accept the challenges that digital research data present 3 Embrace interdisciplinarity 4 Take a more inclusive approach to collaboration 5 Address gaps in training 6 Adopt models for sharing credit 7 Adopt models for sharing resources 8 Re envision scholarly publication 9 Make greater sustained investments in human and cyberinfrastructure Case Studies Introduction Using Zotero and TAPOR on the Old Bailey Proceedings Data Mining with Criminal Intent DMCI Digging into the Enlightenment Mapping the Republic of Letters Towards Dynamic Variorum Editions DVE Mining a Year of Speech Harvesting Speech Datasets for <ORGANIZATION>Linguistic Research</ORGANIZATION> on the Web Structural Analysis of Large Amounts of Music Information SALAMI Digging into Image Data to Answer Authorship Related Questions DID ARQ Railroads and the Making of <LOCATION>Modern America</LOCATION> CLIR wishes to acknowledge the support and assistance of the four funders of the 2009 Digging into <ORGANIZATION>Data Challenge National Endowment for the Humanities JISC National Science Foundation Social Sciences and Humanities Research Council of Canada</ORGANIZATION> as well as the lead program officers for the 2009 grant program <PERSON>Alastair Dunning</PERSON> JISC Mika Oehling SSHRC <PERSON>Jennifer Serventi</PERSON> NEH and <PERSON>Elizabeth Tran</PERSON> NSF One <ORGANIZATION>Culture Computationally Intensive Research</ORGANIZATION> in the <ORGANIZATION>Humanities and Social Sciences</ORGANIZATION> A Report on the Experiences of First Respondents to the Digging into Data Challenge by <PERSON>Christa Williford</PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION>Charles Henry Research Design</ORGANIZATION> by <PERSON>Amy Friedlander</PERSON> is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution NonCommercial ShareAlike 3 0 Unported License Based on a work at www clir org ORDER PRINT COPIES Order One Culture Computationally Intensive Research in the <ORGANIZATION>Humanities and Social Sciences</ORGANIZATION> here Simply indicate the Quantity and click on We use an independent online retailer to take online orders for us and ship publications directly to you Find more details about the ordering process gt gt Contact CLIR 1707 L <ORGANIZATION>St NW Suite</ORGANIZATION> 650 <LOCATION>Washington DC</LOCATION> 20036 P 202 939 4750 Privacy amp Cookies This site uses cookies To find out more as well as how to remove or block these see here Our Cookie Policy Elsewhere <ORGANIZATION>Facebook Twitter LinkedIn YouTube</ORGANIZATION> RSS Stay in Touch Email First Name Last Name Sorry You must have JavaScript enabled to fill out this form Please complete the reCAPTCHA below to join our email list About CLIR CLIR is an independent nonprofit organization that forges strategies to enhance research teaching and learning environments in collaboration with libraries cultural institutions and communities of higher learning All content on this site is available for re use under <ORGANIZATION>CC BY SA</ORGANIZATION> 4 0 License CLIR</ner>
