<ner>Skip to navigation Skip to main content Skip to footer image Menu image The <ORGANIZATION>University of Manchester</ORGANIZATION> image Menu image Search the <ORGANIZATION>University of Manchester</ORGANIZATION> site Search Search text Search type Website Staff directory Alternatively use our A Z index Home Study Undergraduate Undergraduate Courses Undergraduate Teaching and learning Expanding your study undergraduate After you graduate undergraduate Download a prospectus undergraduate Undergraduate Applications Undergraduate Student finance Aspiring students Mature students Parents and supporters Contact us undergraduate Taught master s Why <ORGANIZATION>Manchester</ORGANIZATION> taught master s Taught master s Courses Teaching and learning taught master s After you graduate taught master s Download a prospectus taught master s Admissions process taught master s Fees for taught master s study Funding for taught master s study Contact us taught master s <ORGANIZATION>Postgraduate</ORGANIZATION> research Why <ORGANIZATION>Manchester</ORGANIZATION> postgraduate research Research areas Postgraduate research Programmes People postgraduate research Download a prospectus postgraduate research Admissions postgraduate research Fees for postgraduate research Funding for postgraduate research Contact us postgraduate research Postgraduate certificates and diplomas Online and distance learning Open days Undergraduate open days visits and fairs Master s open days and study fairs Postgraduate research open days and study fairs The Manchester Experience Stellify Our reputation Student life Accommodation Meet our students International Why study at <LOCATION>Manchester</LOCATION> for international students Accommodation for international students English education system Download a prospectus international students International admissions Finance for international students Arrival international students Study abroad programmes Country specific information Exhibitions and visits in your country Contact the international team <ORGANIZATION>Research Research</ORGANIZATION> beacons Advanced materials research beacon Cancer research beacon <ORGANIZATION>Energy</ORGANIZATION> research beacon Global inequalities research beacon Industrial biotechnology research beacon Research Explorer Researchers Faculties and Schools Publications Projects REF 2014 Impact of our research Our structure research Postgraduate research Researcher development Research environment Research posts Collaborate Areas of expertise Business engagement services Policy Give to <ORGANIZATION>Manchester Inspiring</ORGANIZATION> local communities <ORGANIZATION>Manchester</ORGANIZATION> worldwide Discover News The <ORGANIZATION>University of Manchester Magazine Events Key</ORGANIZATION> dates Maps and travel <ORGANIZATION>Manchester University</ORGANIZATION> institutionsOpen to the public History and heritage Social responsibility <ORGANIZATION>People Conference</ORGANIZATION> venues Facilities Facts and figures Structure Vision Governance Global reputation Connect Jobs Alumni Teachers and careers advisers Social media Contact us The <ORGANIZATION>University of Manchester</ORGANIZATION> image Discover Days at The <ORGANIZATION>University of Manchester Discover Days</ORGANIZATION> for Year 12 students Want to know more about what it s like to study your favourite subject at university Come to a Discover Day to find out Discover more and register Study Course and programme finder Choose your study level Undergraduate 2019 entry Undergraduate 2018 entry Taught master s <ORGANIZATION>Postgraduate research Programme</ORGANIZATION> keywords A Z lists Undergraduate courses 2019 entry Undergraduate courses 2018 entry Taught master s courses Postgraduate research areas image Stellify logo image Stellify logo Stellify Learn how you can do more and be more as a <ORGANIZATION>Manchester</ORGANIZATION> student in order to make your mark upon the world as a <ORGANIZATION>Manchester</ORGANIZATION> graduate Research image Research beacons image Research beacons Research beacons Our pioneering interdisciplinary and collaborative research is tackling some of the world s biggest challenges image Research people image Research people Researchers Almost 6 000 people make up our research and academic staff Find a researcher image Research structure image Research structure Structure Researchers from our Faculties and Schools join forces to tackle the world s biggest challenges News See all news image <LOCATION>Manchester Museum</LOCATION> image <LOCATION>Manchester</LOCATION> Museum New galleries and exhibition space planned for <ORGANIZATION>Manchester Museum Manchester Museum</ORGANIZATION> part of the <ORGANIZATION>University</ORGANIZATION> has received a confirmed grant of over 4 million from the <ORGANIZATION>Heritage Lottery Fund</ORGANIZATION> for a major capital project image <ORGANIZATION>Manchester China Institute</ORGANIZATION> image <ORGANIZATION>Manchester China Institute University</ORGANIZATION> s new <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> institute launches The new <ORGANIZATION>Manchester China Institute</ORGANIZATION> will work to improve understanding between the <LOCATION>UK</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> by promoting world leading research community outreach and public lectures image Innovation at Mancehster image Innovation at <LOCATION>Mancehster Manchester</LOCATION> is top ten for innovation among <LOCATION>Europe</LOCATION> s universities The <ORGANIZATION>University of Manchester</ORGANIZATION> has moved up to seventh place in the <ORGANIZATION>Reuters</ORGANIZATION> ranking of <LOCATION>Europe</LOCATION> s most innovative universities image Space technology being used to measure tumours image Space technology being used to measure tumours Space technology being used to measure tumours Technology developed by <ORGANIZATION>Manchester</ORGANIZATION> scientists to map the surface of <LOCATION>Mars</LOCATION> has been adapted to measure the treatment of tumours image <LOCATION>Manchester</LOCATION> top for <LOCATION>UK</LOCATION> business research income image <LOCATION>Manchester</LOCATION> top for <LOCATION>UK</LOCATION> business research income <ORGANIZATION>Manchester</ORGANIZATION> top for <LOCATION>UK</LOCATION> business research income The <ORGANIZATION>University</ORGANIZATION> attracted 24 831 000 of research income from <LOCATION>UK</LOCATION> industry in 2016 17 more than any other institution in the country image Strong grip image Strong grip Research reveals stronger people have healthier brains A study of nearly half a million people has revealed that muscular strength measured by handgrip is an indication of how healthy our brains are image Flexible TVs and wearable smart tech a step closer image Flexible TVs and wearable smart tech a step closer Flexible TVs and wearable smart tech a step closer Researchers at <LOCATION>Manchester</LOCATION> and <PERSON>Shandon</PERSON> have created a transistor that brings flexible televisions and truly wearable tech a step closer image Over 2 000 people join the Purple Wave image Over 2 000 people join the Purple Wave Over 2 000 people join the Purple Wave A Purple Wave of more than 2 000 staff students and alumni will take part in the <LOCATION>Great Manchester Run</LOCATION> to raise money for the <ORGANIZATION>University</ORGANIZATION> s Undergraduate Access Scholarship Manchester worldwide image The <ORGANIZATION>University of Manchester</ORGANIZATION> s reputation is recognised across the globe image The <ORGANIZATION>University of Manchester</ORGANIZATION> s reputation is recognised across the globe Global reputation Our reputation for education and innovation resonates across the world image Collaborations image Collaborations International collaborations We collaborate with organisations and institutions worldwide in our research innovation and teaching image International student at The <ORGANIZATION>University of Manchester</ORGANIZATION> image International student at The <ORGANIZATION>University of Manchester Global</ORGANIZATION> education Each year we welcome more international students than any other <LOCATION>UK</LOCATION> university Collaborate image Cityscape image Cityscape Areas of expertise We collaborate across disciplines cultures and countries to solve global problems image Research taking place in our siemens lab in <ORGANIZATION>Chemical</ORGANIZATION> engineering <PERSON>James Chadwick</PERSON> building image Research taking place in our siemens lab in <ORGANIZATION>Chemical</ORGANIZATION> engineering <PERSON>James Chadwick</PERSON> building Services for business We know the value of working together Our expertise can help you achieve your business objectives image Placeholder alt text image Placeholder alt text Give to Manchester Your support helps our researchers and graduates to build a more progressive responsible world Discover Maps Come and visit us Events What s on at the <ORGANIZATION>University Heritage Explore</ORGANIZATION> our past Connect image Tutor helping students in Life Sciences lab image Tutor helping students in <ORGANIZATION>Life Sciences</ORGANIZATION> lab Jobs We offer every kind of role imaginable From local talent to global experts we want to hear from you image Students sat chatting beneath stained glass window image Students sat chatting beneath stained glass window Alumni Enjoy the benefits of being a part of the largest global alumni community of any campus based university in the <LOCATION>UK</LOCATION> image Teacher in a classroom image Teacher in a classroom Teachers and careers advisers Our tailored support services and engaging activities for pupils of all ages will help make your job easier Explore <LOCATION>Manchester</LOCATION> image <ORGANIZATION>Jodrell Bank</ORGANIZATION> image <ORGANIZATION>Jodrell Bank Jodrell Bank</ORGANIZATION> Explore the wonders of the universe and the giant <ORGANIZATION>Lovell Telescope</ORGANIZATION> at <ORGANIZATION>Jodrell Bank</ORGANIZATION> Discovery Centre image The Alchemy of Colour image The Alchemy of Colour The Alchemy of Colour Poisonous paints and chemical concoctions The Alchemy of Colour exhibition on display at The <ORGANIZATION>John Rylands Library</ORGANIZATION> until 27 August 2018 image <LOCATION>Manchester Museum</LOCATION> image <LOCATION>Manchester Museum Manchester Museum From Darwin</LOCATION> to Turing dinosaur skeletons to mummies discover more than four million fascinating objects image The city of <LOCATION>Manchester</LOCATION> image The city of <LOCATION>Manchester</LOCATION> The city of <LOCATION>Manchester</LOCATION> image <PERSON>Alison Wilding</PERSON> at the <PERSON>Whitworth</PERSON> image <PERSON>Alison Wilding</PERSON> at the <PERSON>Whitworth Alison Wilding</PERSON> at the <LOCATION>Whitworth</LOCATION> See three major sculptures by <ORGANIZATION>Turner Prize</ORGANIZATION> nominee <PERSON>Alison Wilding</PERSON> on display at the <PERSON>Whitworth</PERSON> until 12 August 2018 Quick links Select a quick link Select Maps and travel <ORGANIZATION>University Gift Shop Conference</ORGANIZATION> venues The <ORGANIZATION>University of Manchester Library Key</ORGANIZATION> academic dates Faculties and Schools Interdisciplinary research <ORGANIZATION>Jodrell Bank</ORGANIZATION> Discovery Centre The <ORGANIZATION>John Rylands Library Manchester Museum The Whitworth StaffNet My Manchester</ORGANIZATION> for students Your <ORGANIZATION>Manchester</ORGANIZATION> for alumni Information for investors Modern Slavery Act statement Criminal Finance Act statement A Z index Maps and travel <ORGANIZATION>University Gift Shop Conference</ORGANIZATION> venues The <ORGANIZATION>University of Manchester Library Key</ORGANIZATION> academic dates Faculties and Schools Interdisciplinary research <ORGANIZATION>Jodrell Bank</ORGANIZATION> Discovery Centre The <ORGANIZATION>John Rylands Library Manchester Museum The Whitworth StaffNet My Manchester</ORGANIZATION> for students Your <ORGANIZATION>Manchester</ORGANIZATION> for alumni Information for investors Modern Slavery Act statement Criminal Finance Act statement A Z index Contact us 44 0 161 306 6000 Contact details Find us The <ORGANIZATION>University of Manchester Oxford Rd Manchester</ORGANIZATION> M13 9PL <LOCATION>UK</LOCATION> Connect with us image Facebook page for The <ORGANIZATION>University of Manchester</ORGANIZATION> image Facebook page for The <ORGANIZATION>University of Manchester</ORGANIZATION> image Twitter page for The <ORGANIZATION>University of Manchester</ORGANIZATION> image Twitter page for The <ORGANIZATION>University of Manchester</ORGANIZATION> image YouTube page for The <ORGANIZATION>University of Manchester</ORGANIZATION> image YouTube page for The <ORGANIZATION>University of Manchester</ORGANIZATION> image <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> page for The <ORGANIZATION>University of Manchester</ORGANIZATION> image <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> page for The <ORGANIZATION>University of Manchester</ORGANIZATION> image Instagram page for The <ORGANIZATION>University of Manchester</ORGANIZATION> image Instagram page for The <ORGANIZATION>University of Manchester Social</ORGANIZATION> media directory Disclaimer Privacy Copyright notice Accessibility Freedom of information Charitable status Royal Charter Number RC000797 Close menu Home Study Research Collaborate Discover Connect</ner>
