<ner>About Books Authors Blog Events Login Sign in Email Password Forgot your password <PERSON>Don</PERSON> t have an account Sign up here for discounts and quicker purchasing Subscribe to our newsletter Email image Graphs maps trees 1050st image 9781844671854 frontcover Graphs Maps Trees Abstract Models for Literary History by <ORGANIZATION>Franco Moretti Afterword</ORGANIZATION> by <PERSON>Alberto Piazza</PERSON> 1 0 Paperback Paperback 19 95 13 9630 off 119 pages September 2007 9781844671854 Hardback Hardback 26 00 119 pages July 2005 9781844670260 Not in stock Where to buy <ORGANIZATION>Amazon Barnes</ORGANIZATION> amp Noble <PERSON>IndieBound Powell</PERSON> s The great iconoclast of literary criticism reinvents the study of the novel In this groundbreaking book <PERSON>Franco Moretti</PERSON> argues that literature scholars should stop reading books and start counting graphing and mapping them instead In place of the traditionally selective literary canon of a few hundred texts <PERSON>Moretti</PERSON> offers charts maps and time lines developing the idea of distant reading into a full blown experiment in literary historiography in which the canon disappears into the larger literary system Charting entire genres the epistolary the gothic and the historical novel as well as the literary output of countries such as <LOCATION>Japan Italy Spain</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Nigeria</LOCATION> he shows how literary history looks significantly different from what is commonly supposed and how the concept of aesthetic form can be radically redefined Reviews It s a rare literary critic who attracts so much public attention and there s a good reason few are as hell bent on rethinking the way we talk about literature Times Literary Supplement The great iconoclast of literary criticism <PERSON>Moretti</PERSON> s discourse as has often been noted is marked by the same subtlety and unpredictability as his fellow Italian <ORGANIZATION>Umberto Eco Guardian</ORGANIZATION> Mr <PERSON>Moretti</PERSON> makes his most forceful case yet for his approach a heretical blend of quantitative history geography and evolutionary theory <ORGANIZATION>New York Times Related</ORGANIZATION> blog posts Mike Watson24 March 2015 comments image New_left_review_92 9759439426fa4c012dc2a4e20299c411 New Left Review Issue 92 out now Maya Osborne03 February 2015 comments image Nlr91cover b01959efb7247ba4eddc79057780ecb5 New Left Review gt Issue 91 out now Clement Petitjean10 January 2014 comments image Nlr84cover 67193645114b956d77c5bc5ca553c2a9 New Left Review issue 84 out now <PERSON>Verso</PERSON> recommends image 9781784787691 f_medium If They Come in the Morning Edited by <PERSON>Angela Y Davis</PERSON> image 9781784784294 f_medium Feminism and Nationalism in the Third World by <PERSON>Kumari Jayawardena</PERSON> image 9781786631732 f_medium Threads by <PERSON>Kate Evans</PERSON> image 9781786633477 f_medium Deport Deprive Extradite by <PERSON>Nisha Kapoor</PERSON> image 9781786634962 f_medium The Zad and NoTAV by Mauvaise Troupe Collective image 9781784787394 f_medium Municipal Dreams by <PERSON>John Boughton</PERSON> image Close button image 9781844671854 frontcover image Graphs maps trees 1050st AboutBooksAuthorsBlogEvents Terms and ConditionsFrequently Asked Questions Sign up for our email newsletter</ner>
