<ner>Skip to main content Home About the Project About the Project History Project Personnel Acknowledgments Image Counts by Country Terms of Use Contact Us Additional Resources Additional Resources Resulting Scholarship SSDA in the <ORGANIZATION>News Useful Links Teaching Tools Conferences and Workshops University of Florida</ORGANIZATION> talk Dr <PERSON>Jane Landers Orienta</PERSON> o Oficinas na <ORGANIZATION>Para ba Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION>History of Slavery Vanderbilt Conference Brazil Brazil Project Descriptions Rio de Janeiro Para ba Ecclesiastical and Secular Para ba Criminal and Notarial Minas Gerais Project Teams and Acknowledgments Documents Rio de Janeiro Para ba Transcriptions and Volume Descriptions Additional Resources Media Gallery Church Histories Scholarship Bibliography Links Colombia Colombia Project Description Choc La Guajira C rdoba Project Teams and Acknowledgments Documents El Choc La Guajira Transcriptions and Volume Descriptions Additional Resources Media Gallery Church Histories Bibliography Links Cuba Cuba Project Description Havana Matanzas Ecclesiastical Matanzas</ORGANIZATION> Secular Seven Original Villas Project Teams and Acknowledgments Documents Havana Matanzas Transcriptions and Volume Descriptions Additional Resources Media Gallery Church Histories Bibliography Links Spanish <ORGANIZATION>Florida Spanish Florida Project Description Project Teams and Acknowledgments Documents Transcriptions and Volume Descriptions Additional Resources Media Gallery Church Histories Bibliography Links Angola Angola Benin Benin Cape Verde Cape Verde Slave Societies Digital Archive</ORGANIZATION> image Slave Societies Digital Archive The Slave Societies Digital Archive formerly Ecclesiastical and Secular Sources for Slave Societies directed by <PERSON>Jane Landers</PERSON> and hosted at <ORGANIZATION>Vanderbilt University</ORGANIZATION> preserves endangered ecclesiastical and secular documents related to Africans and African descended peoples in slave societies This <ORGANIZATION>Digital Archive</ORGANIZATION> currently holds 500 000 unique images dating from the 16th to the 20th centuries and documents the history of between 6 and 8 million individuals They are the most extensive serial records for the history of Africans in the <LOCATION>Atlantic World</LOCATION> and also include valuable information on the indigenous European and Asian populations who lived alongside them On this website you will find areas dedicated to each geographic entity <LOCATION>Angola Benin Brazil Cape Verde Colombia Cuba</LOCATION> and Spanish <LOCATION>Florida</LOCATION> and additional resources to assist in your research We welcome feedback and encourage researchers to share any work that they develop using the Slave Societies Digital Archive image British Library Endangered Archives image acts logo image mellon image nehlogo image tubman image hsari image staugustine image labhoi image librarylogo Connect with <ORGANIZATION>Vanderbilt Facebook Twitter Pinterest Instagram YouTube Flickr</ORGANIZATION> Tumblr RSS Feed Your Vanderbilt Alumni Current Students Faculty amp Staff International Students Media Parents amp Family Prospective Students Researchers Sports Fans Visitors amp Neighbors Popular Now Commencement Rites of Spring THE PARTY Find a Job Contact Us <ORGANIZATION>Slave Societies Digital Archive Vanderbilt University College of Arts and Science Department of History PMB</ORGANIZATION> 351802 2301 <LOCATION>Vanderbilt Place Nashville Tennessee</LOCATION> 37235 1802 <ORGANIZATION>Vanderbilt University</ORGANIZATION> All rights reserved <ORGANIZATION>Site Development University Web Communications Vanderbilt University</ORGANIZATION> is committed to principles of equal opportunity and affirmative action <ORGANIZATION>Vanderbilt Vanderbilt University V Oak Leaf Design Star V Design</ORGANIZATION> and Anchor Down are trademarks of The <ORGANIZATION>Vanderbilt University</ORGANIZATION></ner>
