<ner>Skip to content Skip to navigation Personal tools <ORGANIZATION>Navigation University of Minnesota Press Coming</ORGANIZATION> soon Disciplines American Studies Anthropology Architecture and Design Art and Performance Cultural Criticism Economics and Business Education and Law Environment Film and Media Geography History Literature <LOCATION>Minnesota</LOCATION> and the Upper Midwest Native American and Indigenous Studies Political Science Psychology Sociology Theory and Philosophy Home Current Catalogs Blog View Cart Checkout Personal tools About the Press Explore Books News amp Events Information Book Division Test Division Journal Division Menu About the Press Explore Books News amp Events Information Book Division Test Division Journal Division Home Current Catalogs Blog View Cart Checkout Search Site only in current section Advanced Search You are here Home Book Division Books Debates in the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities Share Info Info Debates</ORGANIZATION> in the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> 2012 Matthew K Gold Editor image Debates in the Digital Humanities OPEN ACCESS EDITION Leading figures in the digital humanities explore the field s rapid revolution Debates in the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> brings together leading figures in the field to explore its theories methods and practices and to clarify its multiple possibilities and tensions Together the essays suggest that the digital humanities is uniquely positioned to contribute to the revival of the humanities and academic life Is there such a thing as digital humanities From statistical crunches of texts to new forms of online collaboration and peer review it s clear something is happening This book is an excellent primer on the arguments over just how much is changing and how much more ought to in the way scholars study the humanities <PERSON>Clive Thompson</PERSON> columnist for Wired and contributing writer for the <ORGANIZATION>New York Times Magazine</ORGANIZATION> image Debates in the Digital Humanities Tags Education and Law American Studies Cultural Criticism Film and Media Theory and <ORGANIZATION>Philosophy Higher Education Database Networks Digital</ORGANIZATION> humanities Academia 2016 Cultural Studies catalog Archive Encompassing new technologies research methods and opportunities for collaborative scholarship and open source peer review as well as innovative ways of sharing knowledge and teaching the digital humanities promises to transform the liberal arts and perhaps the university itself Indeed at a time when many academic institutions are facing austerity budgets digital humanities programs have been able to hire new faculty establish new centers and initiatives and attract multimillion dollar grants Clearly the digital humanities has reached a significant moment in its brief history But what sort of moment is it Debates in the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> brings together leading figures in the field to explore its theories methods and practices and to clarify its multiple possibilities and tensions From defining what a digital humanist is and determining whether the field has or needs theoretical grounding to discussions of coding as scholarship and trends in data driven research this cutting edge volume delineates the current state of the digital humanities and envisions potential futures and challenges At the same time several essays aim pointed critiques at the field for its lack of attention to race gender class and sexuality the inadequate level of diversity among its practitioners its absence of political commitment and its preference for research over teaching Together the essays in Debates in the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> which will be published both as a printed book and later as an ongoing open access website suggest that the digital humanities is uniquely positioned to contribute to the revival of the humanities and academic life <ORGANIZATION>Contributors Bryan Alexander National Institute for Technology in Liberal Education Rafael Alvarado U of Virginia Jamie Skye Bianco U of Pittsburgh Ian Bogost Georgia Institute of Technology Stephen Brier CUNY</ORGANIZATION> Graduate Center <PERSON>Daniel J Cohen George Mason</PERSON> U <ORGANIZATION>Cathy N Davidson Duke U Rebecca Frost Davis National Institute for Technology in Liberal Education Johanna Drucker U of California Los Angeles Amy E Earhart Texas A amp M U Charlie Edwards Kathleen Fitzpatrick Pomona College Julia Flanders Brown U Neil Fraistat U of Maryland Paul Fyfe Florida State</ORGANIZATION> U <PERSON>Michael Gavin Rice</PERSON> U <PERSON>David Greetham</PERSON> <ORGANIZATION>CUNY Graduate Center Jim Groom U of Mary Washington Gary Hall Coventry U UK Mills Kelly George Mason U Matthew Kirschenbaum U of Maryland Alan Liu U of California Santa Barbara Elizabeth Losh U of California San Diego Lev Manovich U of California San Diego Willard McCarty King s College London Tara McPherson U of Southern California Bethany Nowviskie U of Virginia Trevor Owens Library of Congress William Pannapacker Hope College Dave Parry U of Texas</ORGANIZATION> at <ORGANIZATION>Dallas Stephen Ramsay U of Nebraska Lincoln Alexander Reid SUNY</ORGANIZATION> at <ORGANIZATION>Buffalo Geoffrey Rockwell Canadian Institute for Research Computing</ORGANIZATION> in the Arts Mark L Sample <PERSON>George Mason</PERSON> U <PERSON>Tom Scheinfeldt George Mason</PERSON> <ORGANIZATION>U Kathleen Marie Smith Lisa Spiro National Institute for Technology in Liberal Education Patrik Svensson Ume U Luke Waltzer Baruch College Matthew Wilkens U of Notre Dame George H Williams U of South Carolina Upstate Michael Witmore Folger Shakespeare Library</ORGANIZATION> 34 95 paper ISBN 978 0 8166 7795 5 105 00 cloth ISBN 978 0 8166 7794 8 532 pages 27 b amp w photos 7 x 10 January 2012 Series Debates in the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> image Debates in the Digital Humanities <PERSON>Matthew K Gold</PERSON> is associate professor of English and digital humanities at the Graduate Center of the <ORGANIZATION>City University of New York</ORGANIZATION> where he is advisor to the Provost for digital initiatives and director of the GC Digital Scholarship Lab image Debates in the Digital Humanities Is there such a thing as digital humanities From statistical crunches of texts to new forms of online collaboration and peer review it s clear something is happening This book is an excellent primer on the arguments over just how much is changing and how much more ought to in the way scholars study the humanities <PERSON>Clive Thompson</PERSON> columnist for Wired and contributing writer for the <ORGANIZATION>New York Times Magazine</ORGANIZATION> I look forward to the day when anxieties about the disruptive nature of digital humanities fade into memory and the innovative methods theories and approaches championed by those who have contributed to this valuable volume are respected across academia for their rigor and utility This book will go a long way toward clarifying the debates within and about digital humanities <PERSON>Siva Vaidhyanathan</PERSON> author of The Googlization of Everything and Why We Should Worry The book reflects the diversity openness and community spirit of the digital humanities Inside Higher Ed Though Debates in the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> is well over 500 pages in length there is no fat in it all essays contain important information and concepts relating to DH Taken together the book as a whole and every essay in it is a must read for anyone who claims to be a digital humanist whether she or he works in theory pedagogy and or practice <ORGANIZATION>Leonardo Reviews</ORGANIZATION> A substantial collection whose contributors include most of the scholars who have been most prominent in the emergence of digital humanities over the past few years Times Literary Supplement The essays in Gold s collection demonstrate the positive effects of a cross fertilization of ideas as the authors often refer to one another in their work The result is an anthology that reads like a conversation dynamic capacious and at times diffuse but one that always returns to core concerns about the meaning function and future of this emerging field American Quarterly Provides not only a valuable primer for any newcomer interested in exploring digital humanities but also a detailed exploration and critique <PERSON>Gold</PERSON> has managed to balance the need to provide a detailed survey of the subject with an incisive look at the complexities inherent in both the making aspect and the thinking aspect of digital humanities <ORGANIZATION>Information Communication amp Society</ORGANIZATION> This collection of some fifty articles and blog posts by leading scholars in the field elegantly printed provides a rich exploration by way of self reflection on the field as it has emerged in academic departments in the humanities particularly in English and History in recent years The Key Reporter Gold s anthology is absolutely the necessary starting point for those who want to catch up on debates in the field learn about the history of digital humanities and contemplate a future application to their art historical work Gold should be highly commended given that he gives us a book so far reaching but also honest about its moment Visual Resources image Debates in the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities Contents Introduction The Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> Moment <PERSON>Matthew K Gold</PERSON> Part I Defining the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> 1 What Is <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> and What s It Doing in English Departments <PERSON>Matthew Kirschenbaum</PERSON> 2 The Humanities Done Digitally <PERSON>Kathleen Fitzpatrick</PERSON> 3 This Is Why We Fight Defining the Values of the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities Lisa Spiro</ORGANIZATION> 4 Beyond the Big Tent Patrik Svensson Blog Posts The <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities Situation</ORGANIZATION> <PERSON>Rafael Alvarado</PERSON> Where s the Beef Does Digital Humanities Have to Answer Questions <PERSON>Tom Scheinfeldt</PERSON> Why Digital Humanities Is Nice <PERSON>Tom Scheinfeldt</PERSON> An Interview with <PERSON>Brett Bobley Michael Gavin</PERSON> and <PERSON>Kathleen Marie Smith Day</PERSON> of DH Defining the Digital Humanities Part II Theorizing the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> 5 Developing Things Notes toward an Epistemology of Building in the Digital Humanities <PERSON>Stephen Ramsay</PERSON> and <PERSON>Geoffrey Rockwell</PERSON> 6 Humanistic Theory and Digital Scholarship <PERSON>Johanna Drucker</PERSON> 7 <ORGANIZATION>This Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> which Is Not One <PERSON>Jamie Skye Bianco</PERSON> 8 A Telescope for the Mind <PERSON>Willard McCarty</PERSON> Blog Posts Sunset for Ideology Sunrise for Methodology <PERSON>Tom Scheinfeldt</PERSON> Has Critical Theory Run Out of Time for Data Driven Scholarship Gary Hall There Are No Digital Humanities Gary Hall Part III Critiquing the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> 9 Why Are the Digital Humanities So White or Thinking the Histories of Race and Computation <PERSON>Tara McPherson</PERSON> 10 Hacktivism and the <ORGANIZATION>Humanities Programming Protest</ORGANIZATION> in the Era of the <ORGANIZATION>Digital University</ORGANIZATION> <PERSON>Elizabeth Losh</PERSON> 11 Unseen and Unremarked On <PERSON>Don DeLillo</PERSON> and the Failure of the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities Mark L Sample</ORGANIZATION> 12 Disability Universal Design and the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> <PERSON>George H Williams</PERSON> 13 The <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> and Its Users Charlie Edwards Blog Posts Digital Humanities Triumphant <PERSON>William Pannapacker</PERSON> What Do Girls Dig <PERSON>Bethany Nowviskie</PERSON> The Turtlenecked Hairshirt Ian Bogost Eternal September of the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities Bethany Nowviskie Part IV Practicing the Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> 14 Canons Close Reading and the Evolution of Method <PERSON>Matthew Wilkens</PERSON> 15 <ORGANIZATION>Electronic Errata Digital Publishing Open Review</ORGANIZATION> and the Futures of Correction <PERSON>Paul Fyfe</PERSON> 16 The <ORGANIZATION>Function of Digital Humanities Centers</ORGANIZATION> at the Present Time <PERSON>Neil Fraistat</PERSON> 17 <ORGANIZATION>Time Labor and Alternate Careers in Digital Humanities Knowledge Work Julia Flanders</ORGANIZATION> 18 Can Information Be Unfettered Race and the <ORGANIZATION>New Digital Humanities Canon Amy E Earhart</ORGANIZATION> Blog Posts The Social Contract of Scholarly Publishing <PERSON>Daniel J Cohen</PERSON> Introducing Digital Humanities Now <PERSON>Daniel J Cohen</PERSON> Text A Massively Addressable Object <PERSON>Michael Witmore</PERSON> The Ancestral Text Michael Witmore Part V Teaching the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> 19 <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> and the Ugly Stepchildren of American Higher Education <PERSON>Luke Waltzer</PERSON> 20 <ORGANIZATION>Graduate Education</ORGANIZATION> and the Ethics of the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities Alexander Reid 21 Should Liberal Arts Campuses Do Digital Humanities Process</ORGANIZATION> and Products in the <ORGANIZATION>Small College World</ORGANIZATION> <PERSON>Bryan Alexander</PERSON> and <PERSON>Rebecca Frost Davis</PERSON> 22 Where s the Pedagogy The Role of Teaching and Learning in the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> <PERSON>Stephen Brier</PERSON> Blog Posts Visualizing Millions of Words Mills Kelly What s Wrong with Writing Essays Mark L Sample Looking for Whitman A Grand Aggregated Experiment <PERSON>Matthew K Gold</PERSON> and <PERSON>Jim Groom</PERSON> The Public Course Blog The Required Reading We Write Ourselves for the Course that Never Ends Trevor Owens Part VI Envisioning the Future of the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities 23 Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> As Is a Tactical Term <PERSON>Matthew Kirschenbaum</PERSON> 24 The <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> or a Digital Humanism <PERSON>Dave Parry</PERSON> 25 The Resistance to Digital Humanities <PERSON>David Greetham</PERSON> 26 Beyond Metrics Community Authorization and Open Peer Review <PERSON>Kathleen Fitzpatrick</PERSON> 27 Trending The Promises and the Challenges of <ORGANIZATION>Big Social Data Lev Manovich 28 Humanities</ORGANIZATION> 2 0 Promise Perils Predictions <PERSON>Cathy N Davidson</PERSON> 29 Where Is Cultural Criticism in the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities Alan Liu Acknowledgments</ORGANIZATION> image Debates in the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> image DDH_infographic Download an infographic The <ORGANIZATION>University of Minnesota s Institute for Advanced Study</ORGANIZATION> has posted video from Debates in the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> editor <PERSON>Matt Gold</PERSON> s visit to campus UMP blog Representation and the digital environment Essential challenges for humanists By <PERSON>Johanna Drucker</PERSON> The basic challenge for humanists comes from adopting visualizations that don t suit our fundamental epistemological values Obviously humanism is not monolithic But methods of statistical analysis and empirical observation are grafted onto the humanities they were not created from within the traditions of textual analysis and study Put simply the distinction between humanistic and empirical methods is the difference between interpretation and scientific positivism I have no quarrel with the latter only with the ways visualization techniques from the natural and social sciences have been adopted for use in the humanities The result is reductive and in most instances produces a reification of misinformation Exceptions exist Read the full article Purchase Paperback 34 95 Paperback 34 95 About E books About This Book Overview Full Details Author Bio Reviews Table of Contents Beyond the Book Related Publications image <ORGANIZATION>Comparative Textual Media Transforming the Humanities</ORGANIZATION> in the <ORGANIZATION>Postprint Era Comparative Textual Media Transforming the Humanities</ORGANIZATION> in the Postprint Era Proposes a new paradigm for the humanities by recognizing print as a medium within a comparative context image The Imperial University Academic Repression and Scholarly Dissent The <ORGANIZATION>Imperial University Academic Repression</ORGANIZATION> and Scholarly Dissent From the front lines of the war on academic freedom linking the policing of knowledge to the relationship between universities militarism and neoliberalism image Reading Writing Interfaces From the <ORGANIZATION>Digital</ORGANIZATION> to the Bookbound Reading Writing Interfaces From the <ORGANIZATION>Digital</ORGANIZATION> to the Bookbound Uncovers a lineage of writers and thinkers who have rebelled against the means of production image Debates in the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities 2016 Debates</ORGANIZATION> in the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> 2016 If the publication of Debates in the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> in 2012 marked the digital humanities moment this book the first in a series of annual volumes will chart the possibilities and tensions of the field as it grows image Deaf Gain Raising the Stakes for Human Diversity Deaf Gain Raising the Stakes for Human Diversity Understanding deafness not as a disability but as a benefit and vital aspect of humanity s diversity image Digitize This Book The Politics of New Media or Why We Need Open Access Now Digitize This Book The Politics of New Media or Why We Need Open Access Now How open access can transform academia for the better image Open Your Eyes Deaf Studies Talking Open Your Eyes Deaf Studies Talking A landmark work on the history future and implications of deaf studies image From A to lt A gt Keywords of Markup From A to lt A gt Keywords of Markup Essays exploring the role of markup in contemporary discourse image Making Things International 1 Circuits and <ORGANIZATION>Motion Making Things International</ORGANIZATION> 1 Circuits and Motion Considering the movements of things expands our notions of globalization Related News amp Events In the <ORGANIZATION>News Debates</ORGANIZATION> in the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> featured on Delicious com <ORGANIZATION>Leonardo Debates</ORGANIZATION> in the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> ProfHacker Summer Reading Guide 2012 <ORGANIZATION>All Related News Debates</ORGANIZATION> in the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> featured on Delicious com Delicious com features articles and posts surrounding Debates in the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities Leonardo Debates</ORGANIZATION> in the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities Leonardo</ORGANIZATION> reviews this volume edited by <ORGANIZATION>Matthew Gold Though Debates</ORGANIZATION> in the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> is well over 500 pages in length there is no fat in it all essays contain important information and concepts relating to DH ProfHacker Summer Reading Guide 2012 DEBATES IN THE DIGITAL HUMANITIES featured among summer reading guide picks Inside Higher Ed The <ORGANIZATION>Prison House of Data Inside Higher Ed</ORGANIZATION> discusses the digital humanities and mentions DEBATES IN THE DIGITAL HUMANITIES edited by Matt Gold Mind Your P s and B s The <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> and Interpretation Stanley Fish mentions DEBATES IN THE DIGITAL HUMANITIES in the <ORGANIZATION>New York Times Coming</ORGANIZATION> soon Disciplines American Studies Anthropology Architecture and Design Art and Performance Cultural Criticism Economics and Business Education and Law Environment Film and Media Geography History Literature <LOCATION>Minnesota</LOCATION> and the Upper Midwest Native American and Indigenous Studies Political Science Psychology Sociology Theory and Philosophy 2011 2016 <ORGANIZATION>University of Minnesota Press Privacy Policy The University of Minnesota</ORGANIZATION> is an equal opportunity educator and employer</ner>
