<ner>Warning The <ORGANIZATION>NCBI</ORGANIZATION> web site requires JavaScript to function more <ORGANIZATION>NCBI</ORGANIZATION> image NCBI Logo Skip to main content Skip to navigation Resources All <ORGANIZATION>Resources Chemicals amp Bioassays BioSystems</ORGANIZATION> PubChem BioAssay PubChem Compound PubChem Structure Search <ORGANIZATION>PubChem Substance All Chemicals</ORGANIZATION> amp Bioassays Resources DNA amp RNA BLAST Basic Local Alignment Search Tool BLAST Stand alone <ORGANIZATION>E Utilities GenBank GenBank BankIt GenBank Sequin GenBank</ORGANIZATION> tbl2asn Genome Workbench Influenza Virus Nucleotide Database PopSet Primer BLAST ProSplign Reference Sequence RefSeq RefSeqGene Sequence Read Archive SRA Splign Trace Archive UniGene All DNA amp RNA Resources Data amp Software BLAST Basic Local Alignment Search Tool BLAST Stand alone Cn3D Conserved Domain Search Service CD Search E Utilities <ORGANIZATION>GenBank BankIt GenBank Sequin GenBank</ORGANIZATION> tbl2asn Genome ProtMap Genome Workbench Primer BLAST ProSplign PubChem Structure Search SNP Submission Tool Splign Vector Alignment Search Tool VAST <ORGANIZATION>All Data amp Software Resources Domains amp Structures BioSystems</ORGANIZATION> Cn3D Conserved Domain Database CDD Conserved Domain Search Service CD Search Structure Molecular Modeling Database Vector Alignment Search Tool VAST All <ORGANIZATION>Domains amp Structures Resources Genes amp Expression BioSystems Database of Genotypes</ORGANIZATION> and Phenotypes dbGaP E Utilities Gene Gene Expression Omnibus GEO Database Gene Expression Omnibus GEO Datasets Gene Expression Omnibus GEO Profiles Genome Workbench HomoloGene Online Mendelian Inheritance in Man OMIM RefSeqGene <ORGANIZATION>UniGene All Genes amp Expression Resources Genetics amp Medicine Bookshelf Database of Genotypes</ORGANIZATION> and Phenotypes dbGaP Genetic Testing Registry Influenza Virus Online Mendelian Inheritance in Man OMIM PubMed PubMed Central PMC PubMed Clinical Queries <ORGANIZATION>RefSeqGene All Genetics amp Medicine Resources Genomes amp Maps Database of Genomic Structural Variation dbVar GenBank tbl2asn Genome Genome Project Genome ProtMap Genome Workbench Influenza Virus Nucleotide Database</ORGANIZATION> PopSet ProSplign Sequence Read Archive SRA Splign Trace Archive All Genomes amp Maps Resources Homology BLAST Basic Local Alignment Search Tool BLAST Stand alone BLAST Link BLink Conserved Domain Database CDD Conserved Domain Search Service CD Search Genome ProtMap HomoloGene Protein Clusters All Homology Resources Literature Bookshelf E Utilities Journals in <ORGANIZATION>NCBI Databases MeSH Database NCBI Handbook NCBI Help Manual NCBI News</ORGANIZATION> amp Blog PubMed PubMed Central PMC PubMed Clinical Queries PubMed Health All Literature Resources Proteins BioSystems BLAST Basic Local Alignment Search Tool BLAST Stand alone BLAST Link BLink Conserved Domain Database CDD Conserved Domain Search Service CD Search E Utilities ProSplign Protein Clusters Protein Database Reference Sequence RefSeq All Proteins Resources Sequence Analysis BLAST Basic Local Alignment Search Tool BLAST Stand alone BLAST Link BLink Conserved Domain Search Service CD Search Genome ProtMap Genome Workbench Influenza Virus Primer BLAST ProSplign Splign All Sequence Analysis Resources Taxonomy Taxonomy Taxonomy Browser Taxonomy Common Tree All Taxonomy Resources Training amp Tutorials <ORGANIZATION>NCBI Education Page NCBI Handbook NCBI Help Manual NCBI News amp Blog All Training amp Tutorials Resources Variation Database of Genomic Structural Variation dbVar Database of Genotypes</ORGANIZATION> and Phenotypes dbGaP Database of Single Nucleotide Polymorphisms dbSNP SNP Submission Tool All Variation Resources How To All How To Chemicals amp Bioassays DNA amp <ORGANIZATION>RNA Data amp Software Domains amp Structures Genes amp Expression Genetics amp Medicine Genomes amp Maps Homology Literature Proteins Sequence Analysis Taxonomy Training amp</ORGANIZATION> Tutorials Variation About NCBI Accesskeys My NCBISign in to NCBISign Out PubMed <ORGANIZATION>US National Library of Medicine National Institutes of Health Search databaseAll Databases Assembly Biocollections BioProject BioSample BioSystems Books</ORGANIZATION> ClinVar Clone Conserved Domains dbGaP dbVar EST Gene Genome GEO DataSets GEO Profiles GSS GTR HomoloGene Identical Protein Groups MedGen MeSH NCBI Web Site NLM Catalog Nucleotide OMIM PMC PopSet Probe Protein Protein Clusters PubChem BioAssay PubChem Compound PubChem Substance PubMed PubMed Health SNP Sparcle SRA Structure Taxonomy ToolKit ToolKitAll ToolKitBookgh <ORGANIZATION>UniGene</ORGANIZATION> Search term Search Advanced bookmark help Help Result Filters bookmark Display Format Abstract Format Summary Summary text Abstract Abstract text MEDLINE XML PMID List ApplySend to Choose Destination File Clipboard Collections E mail Order My Bibliography Citation manager FormatSummary text Abstract text <ORGANIZATION>MEDLINE</ORGANIZATION> XML PMID List CSV Create File 1 selected item 21170383 FormatSummary Summary text Abstract Abstract text MEDLINE XML PMID List MeSH and Other Data E mail Subject Additional text E mailDidn t get the message Find out why Add to Clipboard Add to Collections Order articles Add to My Bibliography Generate a file for use with external citation management software Create File PLoS One 2010 Dec 8 5 12 e14243 doi 10 1371 journal pone 0014243 The structure of the <LOCATION>EU</LOCATION> mediasphere Flaounas I1 <PERSON>Turchi M Ali O Fyson N De Bie</PERSON> T Mosdell N <PERSON>Lewis J Cristianini</PERSON> N Author information 1 <ORGANIZATION>Intelligent Systems Laboratory University of Bristol Bristol United</ORGANIZATION> Kingdom Abstract BACKGROUND A trend towards automation of scientific research has recently resulted in what has been termed data driven inquiry in various disciplines including physics and biology The automation of many tasks has been identified as a possible future also for the humanities and the social sciences particularly in those disciplines concerned with the analysis of text due to the recent availability of millions of books and news articles in digital format In the social sciences the analysis of news media is done largely by hand and in a hypothesis driven fashion the scholar needs to formulate a very specific assumption about the patterns that might be in the data and then set out to verify if they are present or not METHODOLOGY PRINCIPAL FINDINGS In this study we report what we think is the first large scale content analysis of cross linguistic text in the social sciences by using various artificial intelligence techniques We analyse 1 3 M news articles in 22 languages detecting a clear structure in the choice of stories covered by the various outlets This is significantly affected by objective national geographic economic and cultural relations among outlets and countries e g outlets from countries sharing strong economic ties are more likely to cover the same stories We also show that the deviation from average content is significantly correlated with membership to the eurozone as well as with the year of accession to the <LOCATION>EU</LOCATION> CONCLUSIONS SIGNIFICANCE While independently making a multitude of small editorial decisions the leading media of the 27 <ORGANIZATION>EU</ORGANIZATION> countries over a period of six months shaped the contents of the <LOCATION>EU</LOCATION> mediasphere in a way that reflects its deep geographic economic and cultural relations Detecting these subtle signals in a statistically rigorous way would be out of the reach of traditional methods This analysis demonstrates the power of the available methods for significant automation of media content analysis PMID 21170383 PMCID PMC2999531 DOI 10 1371 journal pone 0014243 Indexed for <ORGANIZATION>MEDLINE</ORGANIZATION> Free PMC Article Share Images from this publication See all images 3 Free text image Figure 1 Figure 1The communities of news outlets in the <LOCATION>EU</LOCATION> mediasphere We created the network of the top news outlets per <LOCATION>EU</LOCATION> country We connected two outlets if they reported the same stories more than expected by chance as measured by chi square testing A high threshold on the chi square results that maximizes the modularity of the network was used for the current plot This network is comprised of 147 nodes outlets and 263 edges organized in 31 communities Each outlet is coloured by the country of its origin Disconnected nodes are omitted This way the relation of the strongest connected components and countries is revealed The Structure of the <ORGANIZATION>EU</ORGANIZATION> Mediasphere PLoS One 2010 5 12 e14243 image Figure 2 Figure 2The co coverage network of <LOCATION>EU</LOCATION> countries This is the network of the most significant relations among <LOCATION>EU</LOCATION> countries that cover the same stories in their media The network has 27 nodes that correspond to the <LOCATION>EU</LOCATION> countries and 112 links between them The sparseness was chosen as high as possible with the restriction that all countries must link to at least one other country The Structure of the <ORGANIZATION>EU</ORGANIZATION> Mediasphere PLoS One 2010 5 12 e14243 image Figure 3 Figure 3The co coverage map of the <LOCATION>EU</LOCATION> This is a 2D representation of the relative positions of <LOCATION>EU</LOCATION> countries based on their media content At the centre is the average content of the <LOCATION>EU</LOCATION> media The Eurozone members are coloured in blue and the rest are coloured in gray Eurozone countries are closer to each other and to the average <LOCATION>EU</LOCATION> behaviour than non Eurozone countries The Structure of the <LOCATION>EU</LOCATION> Mediasphere PLoS One 2010 5 12 e14243 Publication type MeSH terms Publication type Research Support Non U S Gov t MeSH terms <ORGANIZATION>Automation Books Culture Data Collection European Union Humans Mass Media Research Social Sciences</ORGANIZATION> LinkOut more resources Full Text Sources Public Library of <LOCATION>Science Europe</LOCATION> PubMed Central PubMed Central Other Literature Sources COS Scholar Universe Supplemental Content Full text links image Icon for Public Library of Science image Icon for PubMed Central image Loading You are here NCBI gt Literature gt PubMed Support Center image Simple NCBI Directory Getting Started <ORGANIZATION>NCBI Education NCBI Help Manual NCBI Handbook Training amp Tutorials Submit Data Resources Chemicals amp Bioassays Data amp Software DNA amp RNA Domains amp Structures Genes amp Expression Genetics amp Medicine Genomes amp Maps Homology Literature Proteins Sequence Analysis Taxonomy Variation Popular PubMed Bookshelf PubMed Central PubMed Health</ORGANIZATION> BLAST Nucleotide Genome <ORGANIZATION>SNP Gene Protein PubChem Featured Genetic Testing Registry PubMed Health GenBank Reference Sequences Gene Expression Omnibus Genome Data Viewer Human Genome Mouse Genome Influenza Virus Primer</ORGANIZATION> BLAST Sequence Read Archive NCBI Information About <ORGANIZATION>NCBI Research</ORGANIZATION> at <ORGANIZATION>NCBI NCBI News</ORGANIZATION> amp Blog NCBI FTP Site NCBI on <ORGANIZATION>Facebook NCBI</ORGANIZATION> on Twitter NCBI on YouTube External link Please review our privacy policy <ORGANIZATION>NLM NIH DHHS USA gov National Center for Biotechnology Information U S National Library of Medicine 8600 Rockville Pike Bethesda MD</ORGANIZATION> 20894 USA Policies and Guidelines Contact</ner>
