<ner>skip to primary navigationskip to content image <ORGANIZATION>University of Cambridge Study at Cambridge About the University Research at Cambridge Search</ORGANIZATION> site Home Study at <LOCATION>Cambridge</LOCATION> Undergraduate Courses Applying Events and open days Fees and finance Student blogs and videos Graduate Why Cambridge Course directory How to apply Fees and funding Frequently asked questions International students <ORGANIZATION>Continuing education Executive</ORGANIZATION> and professional education Courses in education About the <ORGANIZATION>University How the University</ORGANIZATION> and Colleges work <ORGANIZATION>History Visiting the University Term</ORGANIZATION> dates and calendars Map For media Video and audio Find an expert <ORGANIZATION>Publications Global Cambridge News Events Public engagement Jobs Give to Cambridge Research at Cambridge Give to Cambridge For</ORGANIZATION> staff For current students For alumni For business Colleges amp departments Libraries amp facilities Museums amp collections Email amp phone search Log in <ORGANIZATION>Home Digital Humanities Network</ORGANIZATION> image <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities Network Department A Z Home News Events Funding Technical Advice Technical Advice Overview Data Support People amp Projects People amp Projects Overview Committee Committee Overview Steering Committee Browse</ORGANIZATION> by people Browse by project Browse by project <ORGANIZATION>Overview Africa s Voices Arthur Schnitzler Digital Board of Longitude JISC Cambridge Centre for Digital Knowledge Cambridge Digital Library Casebooks Chopin</ORGANIZATION> s First Editions Online The Concept Lab Conspiracy and Democracy Darwin Correspondence <LOCATION>Egypt</LOCATION> s Contentious Media Transnational Dimensions Freeze Frame Kaiserchronik Project Mapping the Jewish Communities of the <ORGANIZATION>Byzantine Empire Music Information Retrieval New ICT</ORGANIZATION> and citizen led governance in <LOCATION>Africa</LOCATION> FrontlineSMS Radio Occupational Structure of <LOCATION>Britain</LOCATION> Online Chopin Variorum Edition Personal Histories Re Enlightenment Scriptorium Social Media Knowledge Exchange Technology Democracy and the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Society University</ORGANIZATION> and Life Experience Visual Representations of the Third Plague Pandemic Wrongdoing in <LOCATION>Spain</LOCATION> Social Media and Human Rights Browse by theme Browse by theme <ORGANIZATION>Overview Digital Editions Social Networks</ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION>Social Media Digital Mapping About About Overview Mailing</ORGANIZATION> list Visit us Governance External collaboration <ORGANIZATION>Digital Methods Digital Methods Overview Doing Research</ORGANIZATION> in the Digital Age Doing Research in the Digital Age Overview Doing Research in the Digital Age programme 2017 8 Advanced workshops Advanced workshops <ORGANIZATION>Overview Advanced Digital Methods Workshops</ORGANIZATION> programme 2017 8 <ORGANIZATION>Machine Reading the Archive Machine Reading the Archive Overview Machine Reading</ORGANIZATION> the Archive programme overview Machine Reading the Archive Projects FAQ Machine Reading the Archive meet our 2018 supported projects Ethics of <ORGANIZATION>Big Data Ways of Machine Seeing Ways of Machine Seeing Overview Ways of Machine Seeing</ORGANIZATION> workshop 2017 Call for proposals <ORGANIZATION>Ways of Machine Seeing 2017 Expression of Interest Form Text</ORGANIZATION> and Data Mining Test Kitchen Digital History Seminar Digital History Seminar Overview Digital History Program Michaelmas 2016 Previous Digital History Seminars Previous Digital History Seminars Overview Digital History Seminar Easter 2016 Digital History Seminar Lent 2016 Digital History Seminar Michaelmas 2015 Digital History programme Easter Term 2017 Past workshops and events Past workshops and events Overview Crowdsourcing Researching Social Movements World Factory Data Expedition Ways of Machine Seeing Mobile Collections project image toledo_algorithm png Text and Data Mining Test Kitchen image MRtA_web_banner png Machine Reading the Archive registration now open for 2017 8 image toledo_algorithm png Doing Research in the Digital Age Doing Research in the Digital Age is the introductory strand of the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Methods</ORGANIZATION> programme offered by <ORGANIZATION>Cambridge Digital Humanities Our</ORGANIZATION> varied programme of events is aimed at making a broad community of researchers from graduate students to senior academics familiar with the key concepts methods and tools required to do research in the digital age Read more image <ORGANIZATION>Circuit</ORGANIZATION> board <ORGANIZATION>Advanced Workshops Cambridge Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> offers a year long programme of advanced digital methods workshops which are often run in collaboration with research projects or external partners Our advanced workshops are aimed at a wide range of researchers from PhD students to academics who are leaders in their field Many of the workshops are open for registration or application from participants outside the <ORGANIZATION>University of Cambridge Read</ORGANIZATION> more image Plaguelogo jpg Showcased Project Visual Representations of the Third Plague Pandemic is an interdisciplinary research project led by social anthropologist Dr <PERSON>Christos Lynteris</PERSON> As Yersinia pestis spread from country to country and from continent to continent it left behind it not only a trail of death and terror but also a growing visual archive on the first global pandemic to be captured by the photographic lens Read more Directory The <ORGANIZATION>Cambridge Digital Humanities Network</ORGANIZATION> brings together dh researchers across the <ORGANIZATION>University Read</ORGANIZATION> more About We are a network of researchers at the <ORGANIZATION>University of Cambridge</ORGANIZATION> who are interested in how the use of digital tools is transforming scholarship in the humanities and social sciences This transformation spans both the content and practice of humanities research as the diffusion of digital technologies opens up new fields of study and generates research questions which breach traditional disciplinary boundaries image RSS Feed Latest news New project aims to support text and data mining research in <LOCATION>Cambridge</LOCATION> Jan 29 2018 Want to explore the possibilities of text and data mining using the collections of <ORGANIZATION>Cambridge University Library and Cambridge University Press</ORGANIZATION> Our new project may be able to help Machine Reading the Archive 2017 8 registration now open Sep 18 2017 Register now to join our <ORGANIZATION>Machine Reading the Archive</ORGANIZATION> programme for 2017 8 <ORGANIZATION>View all news Contact us Postal Address Digital Humanities Network Alison Richard Building</ORGANIZATION> 7 <LOCATION>West Road Cambridge</LOCATION> CB3 9DT Information provided by digitalhumanities crassh cam ac uk Site Privacy amp Cookie Policies image <ORGANIZATION>University of Cambridge 2017 University of Cambridge University</ORGANIZATION> A Z Contact the University Accessibility Freedom of information Terms and conditions Study at <ORGANIZATION>Cambridge Undergraduate Graduate International</ORGANIZATION> students Continuing education Executive and professional education Courses in education About the University How the <ORGANIZATION>University</ORGANIZATION> and Colleges work Visiting the <ORGANIZATION>University Map News Events Jobs Give to Cambridge Research at Cambridge News Features Discussion Spotlight on About</ORGANIZATION> research at <LOCATION>Cambridge</LOCATION> This Site Uses Cookies We may use cookies to record some preference settings and to analyse how you use our web site We may also use external analysis systems which may set additional cookies to perform their analysis These cookies and any others in use are detailed in our site privacy and cookie policies and are integral to our web site You can delete or disable these cookies in your web browser if you wish but then our site may not work correctly I have read and understood this message Hide this message</ner>
