<ner>image Logo of the <ORGANIZATION>American Historical Association Skip</ORGANIZATION> to content Show Menu AHA Today Join Donate AHA Communities MY AHA Login Login Help <ORGANIZATION>Search News amp Advocacy AHA Announcements AHA</ORGANIZATION> in the News Statements and Resolutions of Support and Protest Guiding Principles on Taking a Public Stance AHA Procedures for Making Statements on Alleged Violations of Foreign and <LOCATION>US</LOCATION> Historians Abroad 2001 Letter to <ORGANIZATION>Commerce</ORGANIZATION> Secretary on <ORGANIZATION>Citizenship Question Letter</ORGANIZATION> from the <ORGANIZATION>Coalition for International Education Concerning Title VI</ORGANIZATION> and Fulbright Hays Funding AHA President Expresses Concerns about Proposed Elimination of the History Major at <ORGANIZATION>University of Wisconsin Stevens Point AHA</ORGANIZATION> President Sends Letter Protesting Access Restrictions to <ORGANIZATION>Phillips Library AHA Condemns Polish Law Criminalizing Public Discussion of Polish Complicity in Nazi War Crimes Letter</ORGANIZATION> from the <ORGANIZATION>American Anthropological Association on Banned Words Statement on Right to Engage in Collective Bargaining Letter</ORGANIZATION> from the <ORGANIZATION>Coalition for International Education Supporting Title VI International Education Programs</ORGANIZATION> Statement Opposing <LOCATION>US</LOCATION> Proposal to <ORGANIZATION>Tax Tuition Waivers AHA Statement on Confederate Monuments Letter of Support for Title VI Education Letter</ORGANIZATION> to Archivist of the <LOCATION>US</LOCATION> Concerning Discontinuing of Saturday Research Room Hours Statement Protesting Proposed FY18 <ORGANIZATION>Budget Reduction of Department of Education AHA Letter</ORGANIZATION> in Support of <ORGANIZATION>Central European University AHA Statement of Protest Regarding Arkansas Howard Zinn Controversy AHA</ORGANIZATION> Protests Detainment of French Historian <PERSON>Henry Rousso</PERSON> <ORGANIZATION>AHA Condemns Second Draft of Executive Travel</ORGANIZATION> Ban AHA Statement of Support for National March for Science AHA Statement on Right to Nonviolent Political Action AHA Condemns Executive Order Restricting Entry to the <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> AHA Statement in Aftermath of 2016 Election Letter of Support for National Monument to <ORGANIZATION>Reconstruction Letter of Concern</ORGANIZATION> to Polish Government regarding Treatment of Historian Jan Gross Letter of Concern Regarding Mexican American <ORGANIZATION>Heritage Textbook Advocacy for Academic Freedom and Institutional Integrity in Turkey Letter of Concern Regarding the Port of Los Angeles Archive Letter</ORGANIZATION> of Concern Regarding <LOCATION>Poland</LOCATION> s Museum of the Second World War Letter of Support for Nomination of Dr <PERSON>Carla Hayden</PERSON> as Librarian of <ORGANIZATION>Congress AHA Signs Memo</ORGANIZATION> in Support of Foreign Language and Area Studies Fellowships Letter Protesting the Persecution of Turkish Scholars Letter Protesting Potential Closure of <LOCATION>Musee des Tissus</LOCATION> in <ORGANIZATION>Lyon American Scholarly Societies Joint Statement on Campus Carry Legislation Public Statement</ORGANIZATION> on Oral History and Human Subjects Regulation Letter of Concern Regarding the Possible Closure of the <LOCATION>Illinois</LOCATION> State Museum Letter Opposing <LOCATION>Georgia</LOCATION> s Policy Denying Higher Ed Access to Undocumented Students Letter of Concern Regarding the Reductions in Resources for the <ORGANIZATION>State Historical Society of Iowa Statement Defending Tenure and Academic Freedom</ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION>Wisconsin</LOCATION> Letter of Support for the <ORGANIZATION>History of Medicine Division</ORGANIZATION> of the <ORGANIZATION>National Library of Medicine Letter of Concern Regarding Georgia</ORGANIZATION> s Religious Freedom Restoration Act Letter Encouraging Social Studies Funding in <ORGANIZATION>ESEA Letter of Concern Regarding the Virginia Executive Order for Conflict of Interest Reporting Letter of Concern Regarding the New York Board of Regents Proposed Modifications</ORGANIZATION> to Annual Exams AHA Commentary on Revision of K 12 <ORGANIZATION>History Social Science Framework Endorsement of Durbin Bill</ORGANIZATION> to Expand Student Loan Forgiveness Program to Adjunct Faculty Letter of Concern About NHPRC s Requirements Regarding Digital Publication Letter of Concern Regarding the Destruction of <ORGANIZATION>El Salvadorian Archives Letter of Concern to University of Illinois Chancellor Regarding Salaita Case Letter of Opposition to Relocation of National Archives for Black Women</ORGANIZATION> s History 2014 Letter of Support for the Federal Records Act Amendments of 2013 Letter to the <ORGANIZATION>Board of Education for Jefferson County Colorado Public Schools Statement of Support for AAUP Opposition to Kansas Board of Regents Social Media Policy Statement of Support for College Board s Revised Advanced Placement US History Course Framework Statement of Support</ORGANIZATION> for the Council on Graduate Schools Resolution on Deadlines for Accepting Offers of Admission AHA Statement on Academic Freedom and the <LOCATION>Indiana</LOCATION> Governor Letter of Support for Cuban Scholars to Attend <ORGANIZATION>LASA Conference Statement of Concern</ORGANIZATION> about <ORGANIZATION>Senate</ORGANIZATION> Initiative to Restrict Funding of Political Science Research Statement of Support for Russian Scholars Statement of Concern about <ORGANIZATION>Texas State Board</ORGANIZATION> of Education Amendments Resolution Regarding the 2010 <ORGANIZATION>AHA Annual Meeting Letter of Concern</ORGANIZATION> about Russian Raid on <ORGANIZATION>Human Rights Organization AHA Council Endorses the National Council for History Education</ORGANIZATION> s Statement on Teacher Qualifications AHA Supports Adding History to No Child Left Behind Act Letter of Concern about Jaywalking Arrest Resolution on <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> Government Practices Inimical to the Values of the Historical Profession Resolution Opposing the Use of Free Speech Zones to <ORGANIZATION>Restrict Academic Freedom Support for Middle East Studies Association</ORGANIZATION> s Protest of the Detention of Scholars in <LOCATION>Iran</LOCATION> Letter of Concern about Denial of Visa to <ORGANIZATION>Georgetown University</ORGANIZATION> PhD from <LOCATION>Bolivia</LOCATION> AHA Statement on the 2006 <LOCATION>Florida</LOCATION> Education Bill Resolution on the <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> Government s Abusive Policies toward Foreign Prisoners Resolution Opposing Academic and Student Bills of Rights Protest to Secretary of <ORGANIZATION>State</ORGANIZATION> <PERSON>Colin Powell</PERSON> over Rejection of Cuban Scholars Visa Applications Resolution on Part Time and Adjunct Employees Resolution on the Michael Bellesiles Case Resolution on the Smithsonian Institution Resolution on Funding for the <ORGANIZATION>National Historical Publications and Records Commission</ORGANIZATION> Historians Making News Placeholder component More News AHA Today Everything Has a History Historians on the <ORGANIZATION>Confederate Monument Debate Everything Has a History Video Library America Inside Out Welcome Page Coalitions Advocacy</ORGANIZATION> with <ORGANIZATION>COSSA Advocacy</ORGANIZATION> with the <ORGANIZATION>National Coalition for History Advocacy</ORGANIZATION> with the <ORGANIZATION>National Humanities Alliance Calendar Add</ORGANIZATION> a Calendar Item Calendar Item Details News Archives All News 2018 All News 2017 All News 2016 All News 2015 AHA Announcements 2018 AHA Announcements 2017 AHA Announcements 2016 Historians Making News 2018 Historians Making News 2017 Historians Making News 2016 Historians Making News 2015 <ORGANIZATION>Publications amp Directories American Historical Review Perspectives</ORGANIZATION> on History Submissions Search Past Issues Mobile Perspectives on History Perspectives on History Staff AHA Today AHA Today Blog_RSS Publications Orders for Members Publications Orders for Nonmembers Directories Listing in the <ORGANIZATION>Directory Directory of History Departments Directory of Doctoral Programs Directory of Dissertations Directory of Journals Archives Wiki Subscriptions Commenting Policy Advertising Mailing Lists Permissions Teaching</ORGANIZATION> amp Learning Why Study History Questionnaire Why Study History Teaching Resources for Historians Classroom Materials Approaches to Teaching Teaching with DigHist Resources for Globalizing the <LOCATION>US</LOCATION> History Survey Resources for Tuning the History Discipline The Decision to Secede and Establish the Confederacy A Selection of Primary Sources Plagiarism Curricular Materials for History Instructors How to Detect and Demonstrate Plagiarism Teaching and Learning in the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Age Sixteen Months to Sumter National History Center Mock Policy Briefing Program Reacting</ORGANIZATION> to the Past Globalizing the <LOCATION>US</LOCATION> History Survey About Bridging Cultures Tuning the History Discipline About Tuning Past Events 2016 History Discipline Core 2013 History Discipline Core Tuning Participants Future of the African American Past Video Resources Digital History Resources Resources for Getting Started in Digital History Evaluation of Digital Scholarship in History Digital Primary Sources Extending the Reach of Scholarly Society Work to <ORGANIZATION>HBCU Faculty Jobs amp Professional Development AHA Career Center Post</ORGANIZATION> a <ORGANIZATION>Job Career Diversity for Historians About Career Diversity Career Diversity Resources Career Diversity</ORGANIZATION> in Perspectives and AHA Today Career Diversity Implementation Grants <ORGANIZATION>Career Resources Careers for History Majors Careers for Students of History Careers in Public History Data</ORGANIZATION> on the History Profession Resources for Job Candidates and Search Committees Why Become a Historian Are You Thinking of a Career in Secondary Schools An Option Worth Pursuing Teaching Opportunities for History Graduate Students in Secondary Schools Professional Life Mentoring Disability Mentorship Program Statements Standards and Guidelines of the Discipline Statement on Standards of Professional Conduct Best Practices on Spousal Partner Hiring Guidelines for the Hiring Process Standards for Museum Exhibits Dealing with Historical Subjects Statement on Age Discrimination Statement on Diversity and Affirmative Action Statement on Excellent Classroom Teaching of History Statement on Right to Engage in Collective Bargaining Tenure Promotion and the Publicly Engaged Academic Historian Guidelines for the Doctoral Dissertation Process 2016 Guidelines for the Preparation of Teachers of History 2016 Best Practices for Accessible Publishing 2016 Statement of Support for Academic Freedom 2016 Statement on Dual Enrollment Concurrent Enrollment 2016 Guidelines on the Professional Evaluation of Digital Scholarship by Historians 2015 Statement on Graduate School Offers of Financial Support 2014 Statement on Policies Regarding the Option to Embargo Completed History PhD Dissertations Statement on Productivity Statement on Scholarly Journal Publishing When Academic Departments Merge First Principles Best Practices Telephone and Video Interviews for Academic Hiring Some Guidelines Best Practices on Transparency in Placement Records Standards for Part Time Adjunct and Contingent Faculty 2011 Equity for Minority Historians in the Academic History Workplace A Guide to Best Practices Guidelines for Job Offers in History Statement on Peer Review for Historical Research Statement on Oral History and Institutional Review Boards Benchmarks for Professional Development Criteria for Standards in <ORGANIZATION>History Social Studies Social Sciences Guidelines</ORGANIZATION> for the Preparation Evaluation and <ORGANIZATION>Selection of History Textbooks Meetings amp Seminars Calendar Annual Meeting Program Sponsors amp Exhibits Sponsorship Opportunities Dates amp Deadlines Registration Refund Policy Logos for Participant Use Hotels and Travel Information for International Participants Job Center and Career Fair Career Fair Job Center Recommendations for Interviews</ORGANIZATION> in Non Job Center Facilities Resources and Guides Business Meeting Future Meetings Submit a Proposal Past Meetings Past Meetings Archive Affiliated Societies at the Annual Meeting Process for Affiliate Sessions and Events Instructions for Affiliate Sessions and Events Awards amp Grants Awards amp Prizes <PERSON>Herbert Baxter Adams</PERSON> Prize Troyer <PERSON>Steele Anderson</PERSON> Prize <PERSON>Eugene Asher</PERSON> Award George Louis Beer Prize <PERSON>Jerry Bentley</PERSON> Prize <PERSON>Albert J Beveridge</PERSON> Award Beveridge Family Teaching Prize <PERSON>Paul Birdsall</PERSON> Prize <PERSON>James Henry</PERSON> Breasted Prize <PERSON>Albert B Corey</PERSON> Prize <PERSON>Raymond J Cunningham</PERSON> Prize <PERSON>John H Dunning</PERSON> Prize Equity Award <PERSON>John K Fairbank</PERSON> Prize Herbert Feis Award <PERSON>Morris</PERSON> D Forkosch Prize <PERSON>Leo Gershoy</PERSON> Award <PERSON>William</PERSON> and <PERSON>Edwyna Gilbert</PERSON> Award Clarence H Haring Prize Honorary Foreign Member <PERSON>J Franklin Jameson</PERSON> Award <PERSON>Friedrich Katz</PERSON> Prize <PERSON>Joan Kelly</PERSON> Memorial Prize Martin A Klein Prize <PERSON>Waldo G Leland Prize Littleton Griswold</PERSON> Prize J Russell Major Prize <PERSON>Helen amp Howard R Marraro Prize George</PERSON> L Mosse Prize John E O Connor Film Award Eugenia M Palmegiano Prize <PERSON>James A Rawley</PERSON> Prize Premio del Rey John F Richards Prize <PERSON>James Harvey Robinson</PERSON> Prize <PERSON>Nancy Lyman</PERSON> Roelker Mentorship Award <PERSON>Dorothy Rosenberg</PERSON> Prize Award for Scholarly Distinction <PERSON>Theodore Roosevelt Woodrow Wilson</PERSON> Award <PERSON>Roy Rosenzweig</PERSON> Prize Wesley Logan Prize Grants amp Fellowships <PERSON>Albert J Beveridge Grant Michael Kraus</PERSON> <ORGANIZATION>Research Grant Littleton Griswold Research Grant Bernadotte</ORGANIZATION> E <PERSON>Schmitt Grant J Franklin Jameson</PERSON> Fellowship Fellowships in Aerospace History Past Recipients <PERSON>Herbert Baxter Adams</PERSON> Prize Recipients <ORGANIZATION>AHA Council Annual Meeting Travel Grant Recipients Troyer Steele Anderson</ORGANIZATION> Prize Recipients <PERSON>Eugene Asher</PERSON> Award Recipients George Louis Beer Prize Recipients <PERSON>Jerry Bentley</PERSON> Prize Recipients <PERSON>Jerry Bentley</PERSON> World History Travel Grant Recipients Beveridge Family Teaching Prize Recipients <PERSON>Albert J Beveridge</PERSON> Award Recipients <PERSON>Albert J Beveridge Grant</PERSON> Recipients <PERSON>Paul Birdsall</PERSON> Prize Recipients <PERSON>James Henry</PERSON> Breasted Prize Recipients <PERSON>Albert B Corey</PERSON> Prize Recipients <PERSON>Raymond J Cunningham</PERSON> Prize Recipients <PERSON>John H Dunning</PERSON> Prize Recipients Equity Award Recipients Extraordinary Service Award Recipients John E Fagg Prize Recipients <PERSON>John K Fairbank</PERSON> Prize Recipients Herbert Feis Award Recipients <PERSON>Morris</PERSON> D Forkosch Prize Recipients <PERSON>Leo Gershoy</PERSON> Award Recipients <PERSON>William</PERSON> and <PERSON>Edwyna Gilbert</PERSON> Award Recipients <PERSON>Gutenberg</PERSON> e Prize Recipients Clarence H Haring Prize Recipients Honorary Foreign Member Recipients J <PERSON>Franklin Jameson</PERSON> Award Recipients J <PERSON>Franklin Jameson</PERSON> Fellowship Recipients <PERSON>Friedrich Katz</PERSON> Prize Recipients <PERSON>Joan Kelly</PERSON> Memorial Prize Recipients <PERSON>Martin</PERSON> A <ORGANIZATION>Klein Prize Recipients Michael Kraus Research Grant Recipients Waldo G Leland Prize Recipients Littleton Griswold Grant Recipients Littleton Griswold</ORGANIZATION> Prize Recipients J Russell Major Prize Recipients <PERSON>Helen amp Howard R Marraro</PERSON> Prize Recipients George L Mosse Prize Recipients Fellowship in Aerospace History Recipients John E O Connor Film Award Recipients Eugenia M Palmegiano Prize Recipients <PERSON>James</PERSON> A Rawley Prize Recipients Premio del Rey Recipients John F Richards Prize Recipients <PERSON>James Harvey Robinson</PERSON> Prize Recipients <PERSON>Nancy Lyman</PERSON> Roelker Mentorship Award Recipients <PERSON>Theodore Roosevelt Woodrow Wilson</PERSON> Award Recipients <PERSON>Dorothy Rosenberg</PERSON> Phi Beta Kappa Travel Grant Recipients <PERSON>Dorothy Rosenberg</PERSON> Prize Recipients <PERSON>Roy Rosenzweig</PERSON> Prize Recipients <PERSON>Bernadotte Schmitt Grant</PERSON> Recipients Award for Scholarly Distinction Recipients Wesley Logan Prize Recipients Discontinued Awards Awards amp Fellowships Calendar About AHA amp Membership About Us Membership Why Join the AHA Member Benefits Individual Member Rates Institutional Membership Login Help Donate Contributing and <ORGANIZATION>Life Members Donors</ORGANIZATION> to the Association July 1 2016 June 30 2017 Donors to the Association July 1 2015 June 30 2016 Donors to the Association July 1 2014 June 30 2015 Donors to the Association July 1 2013 June 30 2014 Donors to the Association July 1 2012 June 30 2013 Donors to the Association July 1 2011 June 30 2012 <ORGANIZATION>Governance Council Divisions Committees Pacific Coast Branch Constitution</ORGANIZATION> and Bylaws Policies and Documents of the <ORGANIZATION>Association Reports of Committees and Divisions Affiliated Societies Affiliated Society Meetings AHA History and Archives Brief History of the AHA Annual Reports Historical Archives Presidential Addresses GI</ORGANIZATION> Roundtable Series FAQ AHA Staff Job Openings at the AHA Intern for the <ORGANIZATION>American Historical Association</ORGANIZATION> Sign Up to Learn More about AHA AHA Teaching amp Learning Digital History Resources Evaluation of Digital Scholarship in History Guidelines for the Professional Evaluation of Digital Scholarship by Historians Guidelines for the Professional Evaluation of Digital Scholarship by Historians Download the Guidelines PDF Defining the Challenge The context of historical scholarship is changing rapidly and profoundly Disciplines and universities that emerged two centuries ago in a profusion of print now find themselves confronted with new digital forms The historical discipline needs to address directly and frankly its particular disciplinary position at this historical juncture Historical scholarship is of course already digital in many ways Historians conduct research in digital libraries use digital tools in their teaching and participate in conversations on digital networks Many colleges and universities have created centers and laboratories to foster digital innovation across the disciplines New forms of scholarship and teaching are now taking shape and contributing to our understanding of the past These forms of scholarship in the judgement of the AHA are no less deserving of professional evaluation than print scholarship Despite this ferment broadly accepted guidelines for the professional evaluation of digital scholarship have not yet emerged Digital innovation receives widely varying levels of formal recognition when scholars are hired or evaluated for tenure or promotion That disconnect between emerging practice and the evaluation of that practice discourages scholars at all levels from engaging with the new capacities It also prevents the profession and the departments in which it is grounded from creatively confronting ways in which historical knowledge increasingly will be created and communicated <ORGANIZATION>The American Historical Association</ORGANIZATION> has established this committee to help ensure that our profession acts in far sighted ways as the digital presence grows Most concretely it seeks to help clarify the policies associated with the evaluation of scholarly work in digital forms More broadly the goal of the <ORGANIZATION>Association</ORGANIZATION> and of the committee is to align our best traditions with our best opportunities Because academic contributions in the emergent digital environment can take many forms the <ORGANIZATION>AHA</ORGANIZATION> has asked the committee to examine not only work that can be seen as analogous to print scholarship that is reviewable by peers i e journal articles and books but also to address the myriad uses of digital technology for research teaching pedagogy and even some that might be described as service The AHA offers a broad working definition of digital history as scholarship that is either produced using computational tools and methods or presented using digital technologies That definition will embrace a steadily growing proportion of historical scholarship in coming years and so it is important that departments chairs and committees develop a clear understanding of these developments At its heart scholarship is a documented and disciplined conversation about matters of enduring consequence Hiring tenure and promotion involve peer based judgments evaluating the significance of a scholar s contribution to one or more of those conversations Because scholarship is always evolving departments should continually adapt their policies and practices to take advantage of new opportunities In the same ways that historians have broadened their expertise to embrace many new subfields over the last several decades so we must expand our understanding of the rapidly evolving digital environment to take advantage of the possibilities and opportunities it presents Forms and Functions of Digital Scholarship Digital scholarship takes many forms and so will departments judgments regarding that work Some digital publication can be very nearly indistinguishable from print publication in every respect but its medium A high quality peer reviewed journal article or long form manuscript published only in digital form is the equivalent of a similar publication printed on paper Historians whose expressive and methodological practices differ very little from print era scholars should carry no special burden for explaining why their work appears in digital form save to provide basic information about practices of peer review editorial control and circulation that any scholar might be asked to supply about any publication during an evaluation process Other digital publication by contrast uses methodologies argumentation and archival practices that differ from print practices For those historians an interest in digital media and tools often stems from a more substantial shift in the methodologies they use to work with archival evidence oral testimony or other source material They may turn to digital media primarily for its potential to support a communicative transformation providing new ways to connect the professional work of expert historical scholarship with the ways in which wider publics memorialize represent and engage history Digital history in various forms often represents a commitment to expanding what history is and can do as a field as well as the audiences that it addresses Historians who take a strong interest in digital media and information technology or who choose to work exclusively in digital environments should be evaluated in terms of their overall ability to use sustained expressive substantive and institutional innovation to advance scholarship This is a commitment that is scholarly in some instances pedagogical in others or represents a collegial commitment to the discipline of history Some scholars seek to incubate genuinely new approaches to historical reasoning Those strategies might include new digital short form genres such as blogs social media or multimedia storytelling developing and using new pedagogical methods participating in strong activist forms of open access distribution of scholarly work or creating digital platforms and tools as alternative modalities of scholarly production Wherever possible historians should be ready to explore and consider new modes and forms of intellectual work within the discipline and to expand their understanding of what constitutes the discipline accordingly The shared commitment of all historians to the informed and evidence based conversation that is history can smooth our discipline s integration of new possibilities With agreement on the purpose of our work new and varying forms of that work can be seen as strengths rather than impediments Roles and <ORGANIZATION>Responsibilities Work</ORGANIZATION> done by historians using digital methodologies or media for research pedagogy or communication should be evaluated for hiring promotion and tenure on its scholarly merit and the contribution that work makes to the discipline through research teaching or service Any search or promotion process that is described as open to or requiring digitally based scholarship needs to embrace at a fundamental level the possible even the probable appearance of highly qualified candidates whose preferred practice of digital history significantly challenges print and perhaps other forms of disciplinary orthodoxy Even departments not explicitly hiring a digital historian need to reckon with digital engagement in the discipline and to be prepared to face the challenges and take advantage of the opportunities it provides For their part scholars who embark upon digital scholarship have a responsibility to be as clear as possible at each stage of conceiving building and sharing that scholarship about the implications and significance of using the digital medium for their contribution to the scholarly conversation Historians whose use of information technology produces new methodological capacities and modes of analysis need to provide explanatory narratives as a prelude to the professional evaluation of their scholarship by disciplinary colleagues Accordingly these guidelines make recommendations for departments for individual digital historians and finally for how the AHA can help to promote digital scholarship in the discipline Responsibilities of Departments Departments of history should ask themselves the following questions How are your department and your institution responding to the opportunities and challenges presented by the emerging digital environment How is your department planning to evaluate work presented as part of hiring promotion tenure or other review in a digital medium Do your hiring plans include positions that involve research teaching and scholarly communication employing the use of digital media After these initial conversations the AHA recommends that departments explore their situation more deeply The AHA recognizes that most departments will not be able to address all the following points immediately One approach would be to form a committee to address the issues another would be to start addressing them in the course of their regular meetings and this process may take some time But given the likelihood that most departments will eventually face the question of how to evaluate digital work and to integrate such work into its spectrum of activities consideration of these issues should begin before actual cases present themselves They should inform themselves about developments in the digital context of our work Most colleges and universities have staff in place whose job it is to monitor and promote new technologies Librarians in particular have long been involved in professional conversations regarding new technologies of teaching and scholarship Many of them will be delighted to hold workshops and address faculty in groups or as individuals Before hiring and encouraging fellow historians who have responsibility for fostering these capacities it is advisable that chairs and committee heads specify what will count as scholarly contributions toward tenure and promotion Departments should review and revise written guidelines that define the expectations of ways that colleagues might use digital resources tools and networks in their scholarship Digital scholarship should be evaluated in its native digital medium not printed out for inclusion in review materials Evaluators need to understand how a project works what capacities it possesses and how well those capacities perform This can only be done by actually using the interface Departments should consider how to evaluate as scholarship the development of sophisticated digital tools Departments need to consider how they will deal with work in a digital medium that exists in a process of continual revision and therefore never exists as a finished product Since digital scholarship often includes collaborations departments should consider developing protocols for evaluating collaborative work such as co authored works undergraduate research crowdsourcing and development of tools The development of tools and other significant methodological contributions to digital scholarship often require funding to enable collaborations within and across disciplines Since obtaining funding of this kind may involve undergoing a rigorous peer review process departments should consider how to evaluate a candidate s record of successful grant proposals of this kind Departments without expertise in digital scholarship should consider enlisting colleagues who possess expertise in particular forms of digital scholarship to help them evaluate the strengths and weaknesses of the work before them Responsibilities of Scholars Individual scholars doing digital work in history will need to consider their own set of questions How would you explain your use of digital means to accomplish your scholarly goals and the commitment of time and energy you will invest in that work How will your department and institution support and evaluate digital scholarship What are your plans for dissemination sustainability and preservation Once you have answered these questions the AHA recommends the following Before initiating a digital project and throughout the course of the project you should be prepared to explain and document its development and progress and its contributions to scholarship These statements should be discussed with chairs and committee heads to make sure everyone is operating with the same expectations Seek support and guidance in preparing your promotion or tenure portfolio Resources maintained by departments the AHA and scholars can provide important help in crafting your case for the scholarly value of your digital work Bring colleagues into your project taking advantage of opportunities to explain how your work contributes to the scholarly conversation in on campus forums professional meetings and print or online publications If you establish collaborations and alliances make sure your department and institution are fully informed at each step Consider how the processes and procedures by which your department and institution evaluate and support digital scholarship and teaching will have on your plans You should be clear at each step about the expectations of deadlines final products and evaluation Historians who are experimenting with new forms need to be especially clear about what they are doing what opportunities it offers what challenges their work presents to their colleagues and the impact of their work on the intended audiences The <ORGANIZATION>American Historical Association</ORGANIZATION> s Role The AHA has long sought to advance the possibilities for scholarship in all forms Over the last two decades a series of presidents has focused on the opportunities afforded by digital tools and networks the organization s Perspectives on History has featured projects and overviews the <ORGANIZATION>American Historical Review</ORGANIZATION> has experimented with articles that contain digital components and added reviews of digital scholarship and the annual meeting has featured venues for the presentation and discussion of digital history Building on this work the AHA will increase its advocacy on several related fronts The first step is this committee itself which will work collaboratively with departments to help clarify just what needs to be done and why The committee further recommends that The AHA gather historians experienced in digital scholarship into a working group that will keep itself informed of developments in the field and maintain a directory of historians qualified to assist departments looking for expert outside reviewers for candidates at times of tenure and promotion The AHA consider this working group as a resource that could also help to foster conversations using AHA Communities and produce regular pieces for the AHA s blog AHA Today and Perspectives on History related to digital scholarship The AHA sustain a curated gallery of ongoing digital scholarship so that historians can learn directly from one another as they conceive build and interpret new forms of scholarship The editor of the <ORGANIZATION>American Historical Review</ORGANIZATION> consider implementing more regular reviews of digital scholarship means for featuring digital projects and peer review of those projects <ORGANIZATION>Digital History Working Group</ORGANIZATION> The AHA is establishing a <ORGANIZATION>Digital History Working Group</ORGANIZATION> that will be available to advise departments on issues raised by the guidelines help them define their own guidelines and recommend external reviewers Members of the working group include <ORGANIZATION>David Bell Princeton</ORGANIZATION> co chair ex officio <PERSON>Kalani Craig Indiana Univ Paula Findlen Stanford Univ Walter Hawthorne</PERSON> <LOCATION>Michigan</LOCATION> State Univ <PERSON>Jason Kelly IUPUI Andrew H Lee NYU Jeff McClurken</PERSON> <ORGANIZATION>Univ of Mary Washington co chair Michelle Moravec Rosemont College</ORGANIZATION> <PERSON>Stephen Robertson George Mason</PERSON> Univ If you wish to contact the working group please email <PERSON>Seth Denbo</PERSON> who will connect you with the right person Meet the DH Working Group Japanese Translation of the Guidelines In February of 2016 the <ORGANIZATION>Japanese Association for Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> released a Japanese translation of the Guidelines for the Professional Evaluation of Digital Scholarship by Historians View the translation on JADH AHA Site <ORGANIZATION>Map News amp Advocacy Publications amp Directories Teaching amp Learning Jobs</ORGANIZATION> amp Professional Development Annual Meeting Awards amp Grants About AHA amp Membership Full Site Map Get Involved Why should I join the AHA How can I support the AHA Connect image image image image image Contact 400 A St SE <LOCATION>Washington DC</LOCATION> 20003 Directions gt Phone 202 544 2422 Fax 202 544 8307 Email info historians org 2017 American Historical Association</ner>
