<ner>Jump to Navigation Advertise About Contact Subscribe X News Quick Takes Views Blog U <ORGANIZATION>Career Advice Admissions Digital Learning Diversity Search News</ORGANIZATION> amp Opinions Find A Job Events Data amp Surveys Booklets Audio Topics Sponsored Content AAUP Compensation Data Around the Web Events amp People Subscribe Free Hire Faculty amp Staff Contact About Advertise News amp Opinion Jobs image image image image News Opinions Data amp Surveys Events Parental Bigotry and Admissions Tour Sexism or Humor Diversity Chief to College President image Admissions Digital Learning Diversity Careers Subscribe Free Advertise Hire Faculty amp Staff Find a <ORGANIZATION>Job News Admissions Insider Digital Learning Diversity Matters Views Career Advice Blog U Surveys Webinars Events amp People Jobs Audio Capital Campaigns Admissions Books Technology Community Colleges Diversity Teaching</ORGANIZATION> amp Learning Global Audio Booklets More News Topics Technology Print This image Digital Humanities Bubble A series of critical articles have some digital humanists saying the trend has been oversold particularly with regard to producing academic jobs By <PERSON>Carl Straumsheim</PERSON> May 8 2014 Comments Digital humanities scholars have recently found their work the topic of a number of snarky columns and the arguments are now drawing support from some unexpected allies digital humanities scholars themselves Last month the Slate columnist <PERSON>Rebecca Schuman</PERSON> warned readers not to spend eight years getting a doctorate with the sole purpose of becoming digital humanist Writing for <PERSON>Ozy Sanjena Sathian</PERSON> argued that English doesn t need to be code s sidekick On Friday <PERSON>Adam Kirsch</PERSON> dismissed the breathless prophecies about big data in education as mere hype and blasted the language seen in digital humanities publications as inspired by the spirit of salesmanship seen at an Apple product unveiling Despite all this enthusiasm the question of what the digital humanities is has yet to be given a satisfactory answer <PERSON>Kirsch</PERSON> senior editor of The <LOCATION>New Republic</LOCATION> wrote Indeed no one asks it more often than the digital humanists themselves The recent proliferation of books on the subject from sourcebooks and anthologies to critical manifestos is a sign of a field suffering an identity crisis trying to determine what if anything unites the disparate activities carried on under its banner Snark aside the central argument in <PERSON>Kirsch</PERSON> s column about the digital humanities that the bubble of expectations may have popped is gaining traction among digital humanities scholars I agree that people are starting to realize that DH isn t the kind of savior of humanities jobs it was touted as being a while ago <PERSON>Adeline Koh</PERSON> director of <ORGANIZATION>DH Stockton the Center for the Digital Humanities at Richard Stockton College</ORGANIZATION> said in an email <PERSON>Koh</PERSON> and other digital humanities scholars distanced themselves from some of the most zealous predictions about the digital humanities made years ago namely the idea that incorporating digital tools into research and teaching would launch the humanities disciplines into the national conversation increase the supply of tenure track positions and send students scrambling to declare themselves as English and history majors There was a sense and I think that some people in the digital humanities are complicit in this that the digital humanities would save the humanities or at least save humanities jobs said <PERSON>Marc Bousquet</PERSON> associate professor of English at <ORGANIZATION>Emory University</ORGANIZATION> Part of what s happened is that many institutions have invested in one or two digital people and expected an increase in their major or some other evidence of a revived humanities discourse and so they re feeling some disappointment or rather a bursting of the bubble Instead <PERSON>Bousquet</PERSON> said students are opting to study journalism mass communication and rhetoric and composition to learn how to use digital tools What students are choosing is production based studies production meaning what we used to call composing across a broad range of media he said <ORGANIZATION>Digital</ORGANIZATION> humanities scholars have also criticized the columns for focusing much of their attention on English departments <PERSON>Roopika Risam</PERSON> assistant professor of English at <ORGANIZATION>Salem State University</ORGANIZATION> said the production based fields <PERSON>Bousquet</PERSON> mentioned should also be considered important genealogies of digital humanities The idea of technology taking over English or other humanities disciplines is overblown <PERSON>Risam</PERSON> said in an email <ORGANIZATION>Digital</ORGANIZATION> humanities tends to appear on the <ORGANIZATION>MLA</ORGANIZATION> job list as a desirable secondary specialty but there are few primarily digital humanities tenure track jobs While the digital humanities gave scholars a name for the work they had been doing for decades it hasn t always been easy to define Some Ph D students therefore attest to having doubled up on traditional scholarship such as journal articles to make themselves more attractive to hiring committees In some respects digital humanities poses bigger challenges than other fields <PERSON>Risam</PERSON> wrote So on top of scholarly labor to produce a result there s an additional layer of labor making results legible as scholarship The noise that comes along with claims about digital humanities as savior or killer is a distraction to that complex task <PERSON>Mark Bauerlein</PERSON> professor of English at <ORGANIZATION>Emory</ORGANIZATION> and a self described traditionalist who has been speaking on the issue said he welcomed the scaling back of expectations The digital humanities will produce some interesting and important work but it will suffer the same diminution that the humanities have <PERSON>Bauerlein</PERSON> said It s not going to make the humanities seem more hip and up to date and cutting edge The digital humanities will operate within the larger umbrella of the humanities which is shrinking Instead he repeated an argument for the softer digital humanities such as using technology to work with texts That practice has been going on for years without controversy he said We ve had 30 000 items of scholarship on Shakespeare in the last 30 to 35 years <PERSON>Bauerlein</PERSON> said There could be things to reveal to display about <PERSON>Hamlet</PERSON> using these new technologies That s the promise of digital humanities The revolutionary claims The savior of the humanities claim Forget it This is hype Read more by <PERSON>Carl Straumsheim</PERSON> jump to comments image Be the first to know Get our free daily newsletter Topics Adjuncts Admissions Assessment and <ORGANIZATION>Accountability Books and Publishing Community Colleges Diversity For Profit Higher Ed Global Health</ORGANIZATION> Professions Religious Colleges Retirement Issues Student Aid and Loans Students and Violence Teaching and Learning Technology image Want to advertise Click here image Browse Jobs by Category Subscribe for free today Related Jobs from Inside Higher Ed <ORGANIZATION>Careers image Arts amp Humanities Art Education Temporary Faculty Position Kutztown University of Pennsylvania Kutztown image Arts amp Humanities</ORGANIZATION> Adjunct Assistant Professor of <ORGANIZATION>Drama Hofstra University Hempstead image Arts amp Humanities</ORGANIZATION> Assistant Professor in African <ORGANIZATION>American History Texas State University San Marcos Search Jobs Hiring Post</ORGANIZATION> Your Job bookmark comment target Expand commentsHide comments Join the conversation View the discussion thread Inside Digital Learning Articles image Technology Can Address Digital Accessibility to an Extent image Are Etextbooks Affordable Now image How a Digital Textbook Initiative Achieved Liftoff Today s News from Inside Higher Ed image From Diversity Chief to College President image Bad Humor image Cliff Adelman Analyst Extraordinaire Inside Higher Ed s Quick Takes University Removes Sex Offender s Art Anger Over How Black Students Were Treated at <ORGANIZATION>Graduation University Backs</ORGANIZATION> President Who Is Subject of Suit Columbia Art Students Want Tuition Refund Facing Harassment Charges <ORGANIZATION>Rio Salado VP Resigns Ohio State</ORGANIZATION> Investigates Possible Abuse by Team Doctor What Others Are Reading Viewed Past Day Week Month Year Back to Top Inside Higher Ed 1150 <LOCATION>Connecticut Avenue NW</LOCATION> Suite 400 <LOCATION>Washington DC</LOCATION> 20036 Ph 1 202 659 9208 Fax 1 202 659 9381 image image image image image image 1150 <LOCATION>Connecticut Avenue</LOCATION> NW Suite 400 PH 1 202 659 9208 Copyright 2018 Secondary menu Contact Us About Us For Employers Advertise Work For Us Testimonials Rights and Permissions Privacy Share our content Get our Daily News Update Copyright 2018</ner>
