<ner>image Page Header Open Journal Systems Journal Help User Username Password Remember me Journal Content Search Search Scope All Authors Title Abstract Index terms Full Text Browse By Issue By Author By Title Other Journals Font Size Current Issue image Atom logo image RSS2 logo image RSS1 logo Article Tools image Abstract image Print this article image Indexing metadata image How to cite item image Supplementary files image Email this article Login required image Email the author Login required About The Authors <PERSON>Andrea L Kavanaugh</PERSON> http cs vt edu user kavanaugh <ORGANIZATION>Virginia Tech United States Senior Research Scientist</ORGANIZATION> and Associate Director <ORGANIZATION>Center for Human Computer Interaction Ziqian Song Virginia Tech</ORGANIZATION> <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> PhD candidate <ORGANIZATION>Computer Science Department Home</ORGANIZATION> About Login Register Search Current Archives Announcements SUBMISSIONS Home gt Volume 23 Number 4 2 April 2018 gt <PERSON>Kavanaugh</PERSON> image First Monday image Engaging a community through social media based topics and interactions by <PERSON>Andrea L Kavanaugh</PERSON> and Ziqian Song image Abstract Social media collected over time using keywords hashtags and accounts associated with a particular geographic community might reflect that community s main events topics of discussion and social interactions We are interested in evidence for the support of community involvement that the aggregated Web pages and social media might help to create We collected and analyzed Twitter data related to a geographic area over a two year period to identify and characterize relevant topics and social interactions and to evaluate the support for community involvement that such Twitter use might indicate This kind of data collection has built in biases of course just as local print media or online newsgroups do We analyzed our data using the open source tool NodeXL to identify topics and their changes over time and to create social graphs based on retweets and mentions that suggest interactions around topics Our findings show 1 distinct topics 2 large and small clusters of social interactions around a variety of topics and 3 patterns suggesting what are called community clusters and tight crowd types of conversations and 4 evidence that <ORGANIZATION>Twitter</ORGANIZATION> supports local community involvement among users Modeling topics over time and displaying visualizations of social interactions around different topics in a community can offer insights into the important events and issues during a given period Such visualizations also reveal hidden or obscure topics due to a smaller number of participants whether government representatives voluntary associations or citizens There is clear evidence that <ORGANIZATION>Twitter</ORGANIZATION> supports social interaction and informal discussion or exchange around local topics among users thereby facilitating community involvement Contents Introduction Theoretical framework and prior research <ORGANIZATION>Twitter</ORGANIZATION> data from local content aggregator Methods Results Topic modeling with LDA Social interactions Social interactions and Twitter conversations Interactions around the April 16th Memorial Discussion and conclusion bookmark p1 Introduction Web pages and social media generated by and related to a geographic community may reflect many of the local events and social interactions of that place When aggregated and analyzed over time these data can capture trends and ongoing exchanges among users similar to an extended set of local newspaper stories letters to the editor opinion editorials or the public comments kept by the town or city hall records Given the lack of local newspapers and other local media coverage of small towns and city neighborhoods in the U S the Internet is becoming the source for local news information and citizen exchange The aggregation and display of such online content and social media exchange among individuals and local organizations including government can facilitate users awareness of and involvement in community events interests and issues <PERSON>Ahuja</PERSON> et al 2009 <PERSON>Cohill</PERSON> and <PERSON>Kavanaugh</PERSON> 1997 <PERSON>Kavanaugh</PERSON> et al 2005 <PERSON>Tauro</PERSON> et al 2008 We have identified and collected syndicated RSS feeds of news and information of interest to the general public that have been posted by local organizations including government local voluntary associations and community groups on their own Web sites In addition we identified and collected local oriented Twitter data as well as blogs and <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> content posted by local organizations and individuals We collected these data not only to archive and analyze topics and interactions over time but also to display them through an online content aggregator that is an online community Web site that through RSS subscription automatically scrapes Web content and displays the daily news stories and information for the region and the social commentary around that information We call this community Web site the <LOCATION>Virtual Town Square</LOCATION> VTS <PERSON>Kavanaugh</PERSON> et al 2010 <PERSON>Kavanaugh Ahuja</PERSON> et al 2014 <PERSON>Kavanaugh Krishnan</PERSON> et al 2014 VTS is no longer active but was developed and evaluated as a prototype between 2011 and 2015 with a set of less than a hundred testers and beta users in a geographic area known as the <LOCATION>New River Valley</LOCATION> in southwest <LOCATION>Virginia Local</LOCATION> government like other contributors not only provided content to VTS through its RSS feed that VTS was subscribed to but government could also see what community members were interested in complaining about or appreciating by reading content likes tags and comments on VTS Through VTS local government could hear from community members that might not be as vocal or outspoken as others especially if it was a minority group or opinion or a topic of more focused interest In this paper we present results from analyses of Twitter data comprised of tweets that relate to the <LOCATION>New River Valley</LOCATION> NRV We collected tweets based on the associated account holder keywords or the terms or hashtags pertaining to the local area We analyzed the <ORGANIZATION>Twitter</ORGANIZATION> data to model topics build social graphs measure interactions and characterize conversations over a two year period between September 2012 and October 2014 Our goal in this paper is to present an analysis of the aggregated <ORGANIZATION>Twitter</ORGANIZATION> data we collected from VTS with a view to identifying the topics social interactions and related metadata of users individuals and organizations For example what kinds of topics predominate What topics are obscure Are small or obscure conversations and social interactions more discoverable due to visualizations of multi year Twitter collections Is there much talk about government or civic affairs What are the most active set of Twitter users among organizations and individuals Our primary research question is Does Twitter use help support local community involvement That is what evidence is there of community related discussions and information sharing among local Twitter users Such evidence would support the claim that Twitter use at the local level can enable and support local community involvement image bookmark p2 Theoretical framework and prior research We draw on the idea of political talk which comes from political participation theory to guide our analysis of multi year Twitter data <PERSON>Kim</PERSON> et al 1999 Political talk is one form of political and civic participation specifically political expression discussion and interaction that occurs typically with members of a person s social network but also with local groups and the larger public whether off line or online Specifically we are examining not only narrowly political talk but more broadly community talk that is topics issues and interests that are related to the local geographic community Community talk would encompass many topics from everyday life such as weather and recreation to time specific events such as sports competitions or music performances to long term planning such as infrastructure or land use Community talk can be considered a form of community involvement just as political talk is a form of political participation The act of getting together with other people who know what s going on in the local community is one of four measures in <LOCATION>Rothenbuhler</LOCATION> s index of community involvement Rothenbuhler 1991 The concept of community involvement has roots in sociology and more recently in the field of community informatics <ORGANIZATION>CI Community</ORGANIZATION> informatics is the study of online interaction content creation system use and social impact at the local level Gurstein 2000 Most studies of community informatics have shown that the use of these locally focused systems platforms and content strengthens democratic processes through information sharing and discussion raising local awareness and engagement among users <PERSON>Cohill</PERSON> and <PERSON>Kavanaugh</PERSON> 1997 Gurstein 2000 <PERSON>Kavanaugh</PERSON> et al 2003 <PERSON>Kavanaugh</PERSON> et al 2005 Purcell 2006 Schuler 1996 We build on community informatics to examine specifically the use of Twitter as displayed and archived by our VTS local content aggregator site discussed below Online interactions among community members using Twitter may constitute an informal discussion and show some underlying consistency that reflects the involvement in local interests of organizations and individuals in the geographic area Within digital government community involvement is part of the research on online citizen participation or e participation at the local level Online citizen participation is part of the larger concept of online and off line civic engagement which has a rich literature Most studies agree that Internet use has contributed to information sharing and social interaction <PERSON>Cohill</PERSON> and <PERSON>Kavanaugh</PERSON> 1997 <PERSON>Hanrahan</PERSON> et al 2011 <PERSON>Kavanaugh</PERSON> et al 2005 <PERSON>Kavanaugh Krishnan</PERSON> et al 2014 Purcell 2006 Tauro et al 2008 These studies have not addressed however how Twitter use might affect local community involvement Related to civic engagement research and the work presented in this paper is the concept of weak social ties in geographic communities Granovetter 1973 <PERSON>Kavanaugh</PERSON> et al 2003 Putnam 2000 Compared with strong social ties such as close friends and family weak social ties acquaintances are relations between individuals that are less intimate frequent or mutually demanding Individuals can also act as weak ties when they belong to two distinct groups such as a church and a sports club These individuals tend to share information of interest to both groups thereby helping to disseminate information broadly throughout a community As a result communities that have many weak ties across groups are able to raise awareness stimulate discussion and solve collective problems more quickly than communities that do not have many weak ties across diverse groups Putnam 2000 In relevant prior studies of social media and local communities the Livehoods Project <PERSON>Cranshaw</PERSON> et al 2012 has represented the dynamics structure and character of areas within the city of <LOCATION>Pittsburgh</LOCATION> based on social media data specifically FourSquare check ins Researchers developed an algorithm that maps the geographic areas of the city to suggest their distinguishing social cultural and economic characteristics Unlike the Livehoods Project we do not seek to characterize the economic social and cultural nature of our community Rather we explore the social interactions and topics of discussion among local residents government and other organizations as reflected in their tweets Other arenas in which interaction and discussion topics appear include the <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> pages of local organizations and anonymous platforms such as Yik Yak now extinct once popular among colleges and universities in the U S We focused on <ORGANIZATION>Twitter</ORGANIZATION> data because we sought a data collection based on keyword terms and specific user accounts related to a geographic area as well as a dataset of user identified posts that would show social interaction In Twitter people connect to others by following accounts replying to tweets retweeting tweets using the symbol to refer to mention others by their account name or using the hashtag symbol to connect with people interested the same terms or topics boyd and colleagues boyd et al 2010 have claimed that users who retweet and or mention others create a kind of conversation especially when those behaviors are more than just a one off action Retweeting has been characterized as a diffuse conversation as well as a form of information diffusion similar to link based blogging <PERSON>Ahuja</PERSON> et al 2009 boyd et al 2010 <PERSON>Tauro</PERSON> et al 2008 Of the various incentives for using Twitter Java et al 2007 according to boyd et al 2010 those more likely to retweet others are users who are trying to engage in conversations or share information In a <ORGANIZATION>Pew Internet amp American Life</ORGANIZATION> study of Twitter topic networks researchers have identified at least six types of conversations in Twitter Polarized Crowd Tight Crowd Brand Clusters Community Clusters <ORGANIZATION>Broadcast Network and Support Network Smith</ORGANIZATION> et al 2014 We consider these different conversation types in this paper based on the patterns of our data and the implications of the conversation types for future research on community computing The Polarized Crowd type has two large groups that have little connection between them These are common in separate political discussions on the same topic The Tight Crowd type of conversations is characterized by highly interconnected people and few isolated participants This type is common with professional topics conferences and hobby groups or other subjects that attract participants who make up an interest community for example the community of shared interest could be around growing tomatoes or artificial intelligence or it could be anything to do with the geographic community of residents and organizations that make up a city neighborhood a small town or rural county The pattern of communication in this type of conversation represents networked learning communities with sharing and mutual support facilitated by social media The Community Cluster pattern of conversation appears when there are popular topics that attract multiple groups often forming around a few hubs with their own audiences This type can represent diverse angles on a subject and a diversity of opinions image bookmark p3 Twitter data from local content aggregator In our prior work related to this research we designed developed and evaluated a prototype local aggregator Web site we called the Virtual Town Square VTS <PERSON>Hanrahan</PERSON> et al 2011 <PERSON>Kavanaugh</PERSON> et al 2010 <PERSON>Kavanaugh Ahuja</PERSON> et al 2014 <PERSON>Kavanaugh Krishnan</PERSON> et al 2014 VTS existed as a prototype between 2012 and 2015 when <ORGANIZATION>National Science Foundation</ORGANIZATION> funding ended after 2016 we had to shut down the site due to security breaches and hacks because we were no longer able to monitor it on a daily basis Although the Web site is no longer live all content was archived Web pages photos tweets and <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> posts representing its three year operational period This paper is an analysis of <ORGANIZATION>Twitter</ORGANIZATION> data from that archive We gave VTS a list of RSS feeds from local organization Web sites and social media such as local government sites community organizations public <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> groups and <ORGANIZATION>Twitter</ORGANIZATION> accounts of known local users and organizations that post content and information of general public interest We did not subscribe to any commercial sites or information VTS refreshed the collection twice daily and displayed the first few sentences of news items thereby directing users to source pages for further reading see Figure 1 for a screenshot of VTS bookmark fig1 image A screenshot of local content aggregator Virtual Town Square Figure 1 A screenshot of local content aggregator <LOCATION>Virtual Town Square</LOCATION> VTS Anyone could create an account in order to comment and post content directly on VTS When users were logged in they could comment on new items post photos or blog entries directly on the site itself If they choose to reply to a tweet the site not only showed this on VTS it also reflected their reply on the original tweet as shown via Twitter com In this way comments and posts appeared not only in the aggregator but also in the original source page including Web pages tweets and <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> groups The geographic location encompassed by <LOCATION>Virtual Town Square</LOCATION> is known as the <LOCATION>New River Valley</LOCATION> NRV so called due to the presence of the New River The NRV spans four rural counties two towns and one small city in southwest <LOCATION>Virginia Christiansburg Blacksburg</LOCATION> and the city of <LOCATION>Radford</LOCATION> are the three principal municipalities of the Metropolitan Statistical Area MSA that encompasses those municipalities and the rural counties of <LOCATION>Montgomery Floyd Pulaski</LOCATION> and <PERSON>Giles</PERSON> for statistical purposes The <ORGANIZATION>MSA</ORGANIZATION> has an estimated population of 159 587 and is currently one of the faster growing MSAs in <LOCATION>Virginia</LOCATION> The total population of this mixed rural suburban area potentially served by VTS is about 180 000 according to 2010 <ORGANIZATION>U S Census</ORGANIZATION> http www census gov quickfacts The population that would have been most closely served by VTS is <LOCATION>Montgomery County</LOCATION> and the town of <LOCATION>Blacksburg</LOCATION> with it which is home to the land grant university <ORGANIZATION>Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University Virginia Tech</ORGANIZATION> The 2010 census showed the county population was 94 392 about 47 000 of which lived in <LOCATION>Blacksburg</LOCATION> The county population was predominantly Caucasian 87 6 percent 5 4 percent Asian 3 9 percent Black or African American 0 2 percent Native American and 2 7 percent were Hispanic or Latino U S Census n d Within <LOCATION>Montgomery County Blacksburg</LOCATION> is the most active user population of the VTS due to the presence of Virginia Tech The town population was 42 620 according to the 2010 Census of which 23 895 or 60 percent were college students The median income for a family in 2010 was <LOCATION>US</LOCATION> 51 810 By contrast with <LOCATION>Blacksburg</LOCATION> the median income for a family in <LOCATION>Montgomery County</LOCATION> within which the town is located was <LOCATION>US</LOCATION> 47 239 in 2010 About nine percent of families or 23 percent of the population were below the poverty line including 14 6 percent of those under age 18 and 8 8 percent of the population age 65 or over In identifying Web pages <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> groups and Twitter accounts and hashtags for VTS to collect we used our local knowledge and that of our <ORGANIZATION>Virginia Tech</ORGANIZATION> collaborators and local partner organizations <LOCATION>Blacksburg</LOCATION> town government <LOCATION>Montgomery County</LOCATION> government <ORGANIZATION>Citizens First for Blacksburg Literacy Volunteers of the NRV</ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION>Christiansburg Civic League Twitter</ORGANIZATION> collection was based on local terms hashtags and accounts it encompassed many of the multiple diverse interconnected communities making up the geographic area called <LOCATION>New River Valley</LOCATION> As noted earlier modeling the topics over time in a geographic area can provide us with insights into important community events and civic affairs during this period and local commentary around these events and issues It also reveals hidden or obscure topics and conversations that were emerging in the community thereby making it easier to discover those conversations become more familiar with them and possibly join them image bookmark p4 Methods Ruby on Rails was utilized to collect tweets by keyword hashtag or account name from <LOCATION>New River Valley</LOCATION> The first year data collection ran from 13 September 2012 to 6 October 2013 the collection was interrupted for three months in the summer between 11 June 2013 and 14 September 2013 due to server problems The second year data collection ran from 28 October 2013 to 31 October 2014 Although we collected tweets in the second year during the three summer months between 11 June and 14 September 2014 we omitted them in the analyses reported here in order to make the two collections more similar We used primarily the open source tool NodeXL to analyze the <ORGANIZATION>Twitter</ORGANIZATION> data collection <PERSON>Hansen</PERSON> et al 2012 <PERSON>Hansen</PERSON> et al 2011 and checked it for comparison of topics using Latent Dirichlet Allocation LDA Blei and <PERSON>Lafferty</PERSON> 2009 Blei et al 2003 The analysis of Twitter data by topic distinguishes groups based on topical interest from groups based on social affinity e g friends followers <PERSON>Bhattacharya</PERSON> et al 2014 We focused in this paper on topical interest groups not on social affinity as measured by friends and followers We generated a social graph of user interactions using NodeXL based on retweets and mentions NodeXL is a social media analysis tool that facilitates the exploration and visualization of social network data Using NodeXL we measured the following 1 frequencies of total tweet counts over time 2 changes in tweet counts by hashtag and account over time 3 centrality i e popularity influence of tweets by hashtag and account to indicate popular topics or influential users and 4 social interactions among all users during an extended period based on re tweets and mentions by accounts We wrote a Python script to count the number of tweets that contain symbols hashtags retweet symbols RT and hyperlinks In some analyses reported here we separated Twitter accounts into two types organizations vs individuals While some researchers distinguish a third group journalists media bloggers we did not because we did not seek to test differences in this paper based on the authority that journalists tweets might have offered de Choudhury et al 2012 We manually evaluated the topics derived from NodeXL that seemed to predominate within each of the distinct clusters of the social graphs resulting from re tweets and mentions To compare our manual examination of topics using NodeXL we ran probabilistic analyses using a slightly modified version of the classic unsupervised algorithm Latent Dirichlet Allocation LDA to perform topic modeling <ORGANIZATION>LDA</ORGANIZATION> is one of various algorithms used for topic modeling Topic models are powerful tools to identify latent text patterns in content <PERSON>Blei</PERSON> and Lafferty 2009 Probabilistic topic models are based on statistical algorithms for discovering latent semantic structures of an extensive text body Blei et al 2003 In a topic model including <ORGANIZATION>LDA</ORGANIZATION> a topic is typically considered a distribution over words and a document is in turn modeled as a distribution over topics It assumes that documents are generated in two stages i specify a distribution over topics ii to generate words for a given document sample a topic and then sample words from the chosen topic s distribution of words repeating as necessary Blei et al 2003 The standard modification of the <ORGANIZATION>LDA</ORGANIZATION> algorithm we applied gave the learning algorithm a pre conceived notion or a priori knowledge of what obvious topics would appear in the data e g football and essentially looked beyond that to find more latent topics e g <LOCATION>Pulaski</LOCATION> elections This weighting was executed by forcing the algorithm to reduce the assigned weight it would give in the default implementation to known topics This gives the algorithm the opportunity to discover hidden or not so obvious topics Through this algorithm we sought to identify diverse topics that were smaller and or more obscure We used the entire tweet data for the two year period of our study minus the missing data during summer months as the corpus for analyses using both NodeXL and LDA techniques image bookmark p5 Results Our first year of Twitter data has a total of 289 760 tweets published by 125 881 unique Twitter accounts i e users our second year has a total of 300 147 tweets published by 146 206 unique users Among the 125 881 unique Twitter accounts in the first year data set the overwhelming majority 94 6 percent or 119 071 accounts sent only 1 5 tweets during the nine month period of the collection 4 9 percent N 6 121 posted 6 30 tweets Figure 2 left side Less than one percent 0 5 percent of all accounts N 689 posted more than 30 tweets in the first year Very similar proportions emerged from the data in the second year as well shown in Figure 2 right side Specifically 93 6 percent posted 1 5 tweets total 5 6 percent posted 6 30 tweets and only 0 8 percent posted more than 30 tweets during the nine month period of the second year Among the less than one percent that were active Twitter users during both years many user accounts were the same bookmark fig2 image User distribution by number of tweets image User distribution by number of tweets Figure 2 User distribution by number of tweets Year 1 on left Year 2 on right Note Larger version of left figure available here Note Larger version of right figure available here The top 20 Twitter accounts in the first year ranked by the frequency of tweets range from <LOCATION>Blacksburg Stuff</LOCATION> being the most prolific in both years 6 650 in Year 1 and 7 236 in Year 2 to Hokie nation in 20th place 436 tweets in Year 1 and <ORGANIZATION>Radford University</ORGANIZATION> 1 213 tweets in Year 2 as shown in Figure 3 These were all organization accounts rather than individuals suggesting that the <ORGANIZATION>Twitter</ORGANIZATION> account was used for public announcements news and regular updates bookmark fig3 image Top 20 Twitter account ranked by the number of tweets Figure 3 Top 20 Twitter account ranked by the number of tweets We examined all the hashtags and ranked them by degree using NodeXL to demonstrate the number of edges connected to a vertex The degree of a given hashtag shows the popularity of the hashtag The hashtag Virginia Tech including other common forms has the highest degree followed by Hokie and <LOCATION>Blacksburg</LOCATION> Figure 4 bookmark fig4 image Top 10 hashtags ranked by degree Figure 4 Top 10 hashtags ranked by degree Among the 289 760 total tweets in Year 1 119 542 tweets contain mention symbol 93 148 tweets contain hashtags and 94 251 tweets were retweeted RT from other Twitter accounts 124 386 tweets contain a hyperlink or URL Figure 5 shows the proportion of RT and URL in the first year versus the second year data set bookmark fig5 image Proportion of RT URL image Proportion of RT URL Figure 5 Proportion of RT URL Year 1 on left Year 2 on right Note Larger version of left figure available here Note Larger version of right figure available here In the second year of <ORGANIZATION>Twitter</ORGANIZATION> data Figure 5 on the right collected from many of the same accounts terms and hashtags as well as new accounts the proportion of each of these features rose mentions rose from about 30 percent to 55 percent hashtags rose from about 22 percent to 36 percent re tweets RT increased from about 22 percent to 45 percent and the proportion of URLs embedded in tweets rose from about 35 percent to 55 percent We mapped the distribution of tweets by date during the 10 months of our first year collection Figure 6 It shows a distinct peak in mid April 2013 When we examined this peak of Twitter activity carefully we found the frequency of mentions for the <ORGANIZATION>Twitter</ORGANIZATION> account MMFlint was very high and driving up the peak with 1 627 mentions by the other Twitter users MMFlint is an account associated with <PERSON>Michael Moore</PERSON> filmmaker activist living in <LOCATION>Flint Michigan</LOCATION> who posted a tweet This is the anniversary week of the Columbine massacre the <LOCATION>Oklahoma City</LOCATION> bombing the <LOCATION>Virginia Tech</LOCATION> massacre the <LOCATION>Bay of Pigs Boston Marathon</LOCATION> bombing and <LOCATION>Waco</LOCATION> bookmark fig6 image Distribution of tweets over first year Figure 6 Distribution of tweets over first year Note Larger version of figure available here Given <PERSON>Michael Moore</PERSON> s celebrity status and high visibility he has many Twitter followers Many of them re tweeted his tweet to their own followers leading to a spike in mid April 2013 In addition his listing of multiple tragic events in a single tweet seemed to have resonated with diverse audiences who identified perhaps with only one of the multiple tragic events over that time period mid April in multiple years This gave relevance of the tweet to a large set of users In the second year data there was a peak in mid April but nowhere near as striking as in 2012 since there was not a similar tweet e g by a popular celebrity that was re tweeted by many followers image bookmark p6 Topic modeling with LDA To test our results from NodeXL we also used <ORGANIZATION>LDA</ORGANIZATION> to model topics over the two year combined <ORGANIZATION>Twitter</ORGANIZATION> data set We obtained very similar results for topics using LDA as with the NodeXL results There was a dominance of <ORGANIZATION>Virginia Tech</ORGANIZATION> football and other sports <ORGANIZATION>Virginia Tech</ORGANIZATION> news and <LOCATION>Blacksburg</LOCATION> information Roble et al 2014 Using weighted LDA to discount the presence of most common topics related to football and other sports we were able to discover latent topics such as the <LOCATION>Pulaski County</LOCATION> local elections Also with weighting the distribution of top topics was fairly even Most of the topic LDA derived topics were still related to <ORGANIZATION>Virginia Tech Blacksburg</ORGANIZATION> and athletics so the weighting did not distort overall distribution but rather made the smaller hidden topics more discoverable In addition to the <LOCATION>Pulaski</LOCATION> elections there were topics centered around fairly minor shooting incidents local and non local specific events These LDA results helped confirm topics derived from NodeXL analyses Another finding from the <ORGANIZATION>LDA</ORGANIZATION> analysis over the two year period was a time series correlation with topics presented The topics distributed themselves in a seasonal pattern That is in the autumn there were more football related topics and in spring there were more posts around the memorial events of 16 April 2007 image bookmark p7 Social interactions After eliminating outliers in the data we clustered the whole data set using NodeXL based on relationships among accounts indicated by mentions and re tweets RT in order to represent social interactions among users We eliminated organizational accounts in order to focus on individual account activity in order to consider social interactions among citizens versus organizations given the differences in motivation audiences and resources Based on the mentions and or re tweets Twitter accounts in our data set formed a huge social network Figure 7 The most active accounts in terms of interaction appeared as three big clusters with many smaller clusters The gray edges between accounts represented a retweet and or mention among accounts individuals Since individuals still referred to organizations with mentions and re tweets organizational accounts appeared in the groups shown in Figure 7 as well as Table 1 bookmark fig7 image Social graph of interactions based on retweets and mentions Figure 7 Social graph of interactions based on retweets and mentions Note Larger version of figure available here As shown in Figure 7 there were three very large groups in the local Twitter community and several medium sized and smaller groups intensively connected with the three large groups We show in Table 1 the top accounts in the two largest groups ranked by the number of edges mentions and or re tweets We also show the interests of the account holder based on profile data and or a manual inspection of the content of their tweets In the largest group shown in Figure 7 the top 10 most active users are shown in Table 1 along with the general topics appearing in their tweets over the two year period of the data collection These users also appeared in some of the other groups as active twitterers The general topics of interest based on a manual examination relate to sports particularly football at <ORGANIZATION>Virginia Tech</ORGANIZATION> bookmark tab1 Table 1 Groups 1 and 2 User names and interests GROUP 1 G1 Interests GROUP 2 G2 Interests RTD_MikeBarber Basketball football mehudsonme <LOCATION>Blacksburg</LOCATION> VT civic thekeyplay football BlacksburgStuff <LOCATION>Blacksburg</LOCATION> life AndyBitterVT football PhilthePill <LOCATION>New River Valley</LOCATION> virginia tech VT everything AndyBitterVT Football writer HokiesJournal football michaelsutphin <ORGANIZATION>Town Council</ORGANIZATION> MattB4VT VT sports virginia_tech VT everything JordanLong_4 VT Sports vtnews VT news TheClubhouseKB sports <ORGANIZATION>GardnerCampbell VT</ORGANIZATION> professor VTechFanBlog VT sports Mike_TheBurgs <LOCATION>New River Valley</LOCATION> VT_Baseball baseball girlinblack <ORGANIZATION>Blacksburg Roanoke Group</ORGANIZATION> 2 also one of the three largest in our data shows some of the same users as Group 1 and some of the same topics notably football as indicated in Table 1 But this group also had more diversity of topics such as <LOCATION>Blacksburg</LOCATION> the city of <LOCATION>Radford</LOCATION> and NRV area related messages as well as <ORGANIZATION>Virginia Tech</ORGANIZATION> news There was also a <LOCATION>Blacksburg</LOCATION> town council member in the group who posted tweets related to the council its agenda items upcoming meetings highlights from committees and other aspects of its work Group 3 is also large Table 2 However it also contained more diverse topics than sports including weather student affairs relationship problems girlfriend boyfriend issues <ORGANIZATION>Pulaski County Pulaski High School</ORGANIZATION> football and local social activities and entertainment bookmark tab2 Table 2 Groups 3 and 4 Plus User names and interests GROUP 3 G3 Interests GROUP 4 Plus Interests <ORGANIZATION>BlacksburgStuff Everything Blacksburg 1News2News World</ORGANIZATION> news TheHokieBird <LOCATION>Virginia</LOCATION> tech activity michaelsutphin Town council VTGirlProblems VT student activity melissarichards <ORGANIZATION>Town council VT</ORGANIZATION> vtnews VT news PulaskiCountyVC <LOCATION>Pulaski</LOCATION> stuff BlackSheep_VT <LOCATION>Blacksburg</LOCATION> social <ORGANIZATION>Pulaski Football Pulaski</ORGANIZATION> football OverheardVT VT activity and news <ORGANIZATION>River Valley Church Church</ORGANIZATION> activity BlacksburgWx <LOCATION>Blacksburg</LOCATION> weather ReporterToniaM New river valley news plaidavenger VT faculty member BestofVirginia Local deals Kait_Ashley VT student wsls <LOCATION>Roanoke</LOCATION> activity vtdsa VT Student Affairs various miscellaneous Table 2 shows Group 4 and the other groups shown in Figure 7 that are medium sized and smaller clusters with even more diverse topics such as church events and activities elections in neighboring <LOCATION>Pulaski County</LOCATION> references to the <LOCATION>New River Valley</LOCATION> and other local area information and news image bookmark p8 Social interactions and Twitter conversations A relatively small number of users interacting around a hashtag i e specific topic can add up to a lot of interactions among users as shown in Table 3 Column A shows the name of the hashtag column B shows the number of tweets using that hashtag column C is the number of people who sent tweets with that hashtag and column D shows the number of accounts interacting with others using the same hashtag measured by mentions and retweets among these users Column E shows how many times these users interacted with each other using this hashtag To clarify whether accounts were held by individuals or organizations we show in column F the number of hashtags that remained when we deleted organizational accounts this allowed us to better understand the extent to which individuals were interacting around a given hashtag Column G is the number of interactions remaining after we deleted organizational accounts Overall Table 3 illustrates that there was a great deal of interaction among users around these hashtags or topics bookmark tab3 Table 3 Number of user interactions around hashtags Hashtag Number of tweets with hashtag Number of users with hashtag Number of users who interact w Number of interactions Number of tweets w no orgs Number of interactions no orgs <ORGANIZATION>Hokies</ORGANIZATION> 8 253 3 449 2 821 12 805 4 259 4 460 <ORGANIZATION>Blacksburg</ORGANIZATION> 6 958 2 141 1 402 10 385 3 356 2 726 VirginiaTech 4 613 3 012 1 600 6 627 1 487 1 536 virginia 2 443 1 743 664 2 179 872 479 ACC 1 943 1 257 879 3 264 821 1 263 jobs 1 688 259 48 291 573 6 <ORGANIZATION>Christansburg</ORGANIZATION> 978 306 209 2 104 457 468 VA 788 384 161 962 409 96 neVerforgeT 700 665 266 539 237 145 HokieNation 688 585 325 908 310 214 VTGP 530 385 370 884 393 574 <ORGANIZATION>NRA</ORGANIZATION> 524 463 155 167 28 2 UVA 483 392 296 764 189 95 <LOCATION>Newtown</LOCATION> 465 391 169 315 136 39 NoMoreNames 456 433 101 113 27 0 DemandAction 453 408 66 86 31 1 swvawx 430 155 145 1 427 199 326 Based on the idea of six types of Twitter conversations we suggest our community communication shown in Figure 7 contains two types of Twitter conversations Tight Crowd and Community Cluster The Group 1 G1 G2 G3 demonstrate an obvious character of Tight Crowd conversations The Tight Crowd structure typically contains two six medium groups The groups interconnectivity was very high and there were very few isolated groups Our three big groups G1 G2 G3 matched the Tight Crowd conversation pattern There were intensive connections between these three groups However in further exploring the group cluster we found that the community contained several small groups which was variant from the Tight Crowd The many small groups in the right bottom of Figure 7 Groups 4 5 etc were barely connected to other groups except for a few connected with the three large groups The conversation type called Community Cluster usually contains very small groups and the connections between groups are very few It also contains many isolated groups For the small groups in the right bottom we think their communication forms a pattern of Community Cluster conversation image bookmark p9 Interactions around the April 16th Memorial For a more focused look at social interactions around a key topic we examined the hashtag neVerforgeT in honor of the April 16th Memorial held annually for the tragic shooting at <ORGANIZATION>Virginia Tech</ORGANIZATION> on that day in 2007 Figure 8 shows the social graph of mentions and retweets among all accounts in our collection using this hashtag just before 16 April 2014 Figure 8 left side and just after 16 April 2014 Figure 8 right side bookmark fig8 image Social interactions among Twitter accounts just before 16 April 2014 image Social interactions among Twitter accounts just after 16 April 2014 Figure 8 Social interactions among Twitter accounts just before and after 16 April 2014 Note Larger version of left figure available here Note Larger version of right figure available here At the center of the graph in Figure 8 left side before April 16 is the account BlacksburgStuff the self declared all about <LOCATION>Blacksburg</LOCATION> account established in 2010 whose stated mission is to connect residents and visitors with the greater <LOCATION>Blacksburg</LOCATION> community It had over 61 000 tweets and 12 000 followers This average day type of pattern with a few retweets and mentions among followers was in stark contrast with the social interactions on the day of 16 April Figure 9 bookmark fig9 image Social interactions on April 16 Memorial Day 2014 Figure 9 Social interactions on April 16th Memorial Day 2014 Note Larger version of figure available here There was clearly a large cluster with a high number of interactions on the day of the April 16th Memorial At the center of the cluster was an account ears_of_JMU that had been retweeted and mentioned by a lot of its followers and by followers of its followers A closer look at the account and the tweet content on that day is shown in Figure 10 bookmark fig10 image Account ears_of_JMU and tweet post on 16 April 2013 Figure 10 Account ears_of_JMU and tweet post on 16 April 2013 Note Larger version of figure available here The Twitter account ears_of_JMU at the center of the social graph was an account that seems to belong to a college student at <ORGANIZATION>James Madison University</ORGANIZATION> a private <LOCATION>Virginia</LOCATION> university about a two hour drive from Virginia Tech The content of the tweet from ears_of_JMU on 16 April 2013 read New avatar for this week in honor of VT 4 16 07 neVerforgeT The twitterer added S O to got_wilk for the design The new avatar is the <ORGANIZATION>JMU</ORGANIZATION> logo re done in the colors of <ORGANIZATION>Virginia Tech</ORGANIZATION> orange and maroon The bulldog logo normally appears in purple and gold Note that the account BlacksburgStuff which was central in the days before the 16 April Memorial was at the far right bottom corner of the social graph on 16 April The logo art work of the ears_of_JMU tweet i e modified <ORGANIZATION>JMU</ORGANIZATION> bulldog in VT colors combined with its sentiment honoring <ORGANIZATION>Virginia Tech</ORGANIZATION> may account for much of its popularity among followers who retweeted and or mentioned the original tweet image bookmark p10 Discussion and conclusion We have presented results from analyses of Twitter data collected over a two year period through a local aggregator site <LOCATION>Virtual Town Square</LOCATION> or VTS developed as a prototype to serve geographic communities that make up the <LOCATION>New River Valley</LOCATION> in southwest <LOCATION>Virginia</LOCATION> The display of this local content provided news and discussion updates as well as an archive for analysis of longer term trends changes over time and social interaction patterns VTS acted as a sensor for a geographic area capturing key events location specific information and exchange and informal discussion among users comprised of individuals and organizations such as government voluntary associations and citizens Our analyses of Twitter hashtags keywords and local accounts over the two year period of the study shows some underlying consistency in certain topics and reflects some of the key interests and concerns of residents and local organizations including government agencies There were clear changes in topics over time based on seasonal activities as well as critical events Since the data set was dominated by a few specific topics such as <ORGANIZATION>Virginia Tech</ORGANIZATION> football it was potentially difficult for users of VTS to discover less popular topics Therefore in addition to a manual examination of tweet contents among each cluster of users visualized in our social graph we used a weighted implementation of the LDA algorithm over the entire data set to identify less popular topics Using weighted LDA we discovered the same latent topics such as the <LOCATION>Pulaski County</LOCATION> local elections that also showed up in a more time consuming manual examination of topics within the social graph in NodeXL The <ORGANIZATION>LDA</ORGANIZATION> analysis served as a confirmation of topics identified manually The social graph in NodeXL shows three very large groups in the <ORGANIZATION>Twitter</ORGANIZATION> data and several other groups intensively connected with these three large groups We looked deeply into the three large groups of users and found the top accounts have the most edges in these groups Most of the top accounts in the same group shared the same interests There were also several small groups that appeared in the social graph Some of the small groups were connected to the three large groups but most of them were separate from the three big groups with distinct topics These connections across the clusters suggest weak social ties in the user community The clusters in the social graphs showed patterns consistent with Twitter conversation types called Tight Crowd and Community Clusters These types have distinct clusters with interconnections among them as well as medium sized and smaller clusters with much interaction among participants even though they are fewer in number Given that the pattern of communication in the tight crowd type of conversation represents networked learning communities with sharing and mutual support facilitated by social media these conversations at the local level represent a form of community involvement The community cluster pattern of conversation appears when there are popular topics that attract multiple groups often forming around a few hubs with their own audiences This type can represent diverse angles on a subject and diversity of opinion with weak social ties across groups Given that a community with many weak social ties across groups is more capable of collective problem solving than a community with few weak ties a platform such as VTS and social media that support weak ties such as <ORGANIZATION>Twitter</ORGANIZATION> should help to contribute to the collective problem solving capability of these communities Among our key findings is that the number of interactions among Twitter users around a single hashtag can be quite large This clearly indicates that these users are actively engaged with others in relation to a given subject These findings support prior work by boyd and colleagues boyd et al 2010 showing that the retweet and mention functions and interactions in Twitter constitute at least informal discussions especially when those behaviors are repeated communications i e more than one or two retweets and mentions of the same account As boyd argues those more likely to retweet others are users who are trying to engage in conversations or share information Engagement in conversations and local information sharing is clearly evident in our data which points to the impact of Twitter use at the local level to enable and facilitate community involvement through discussion and information sharing We expect the predominant discussions and exchanges in a community would be about typical events of everyday life such as weather sports activities and school as is seen in our data But the familiar practice of communicating with others routinely on social media about local events and interests makes it easy for users to switch to more civic oriented topics when necessary such as local elections zoning controversies or weather crises Our data show a lot of exchange around university football and other sports which are very popular topics in a college town but there is also clear evidence of interactions about civic concerns such as county elections and the VT memorial The greater ease of switching from brief posts and comments about football to brief exchanges about more civic minded issues as they arise is an additional basis for increasing local awareness collective response and problem solving in a community Ultimately these kinds of content aggregators computational analyses and visualization tools when available to local communities could help increase social interaction and community involvement With fewer traditional local newspapers the analytic techniques and visualizations we describe in this paper should make it easier for interested users to find and participate in more localized information sharing and exchange of ideas and opinions whether about a local sports team or revisions to a comprehensive town plan When visualized and displayed online as they are through an aggregator like VTS the topics and social interactions are easier for users to discover and as a result to become aware of and possibly more involved in Civic technology such as VTS and related visualization techniques and interaction tools contribute to community informatics research and to the e participation area of digital government research because they advance our understanding of the use and impact of platforms that are designed to enable and facilitate topic discovery and informal discussion or exchange among government local community groups and citizens In future work we are interested in a couple of follow on studies We will test some of the analytical tools that have emerged more recently such as social media integration and participant based approaches to event summarization among others to compare our results using NodeXL and LDA for topic modeling and social graphing of user populations and their local community involvement We will also investigate the role of opinion leaders among our individual users in our Twitter data since it is well known that these persons are highly influential and that a predominance of Twitter users are opinion leaders image End of article bookmark author About the authors <PERSON>Andrea L Kavanaugh</PERSON> Ph D is a senior research scientist and the associate director of the <ORGANIZATION>Center for Human Computer Interaction at Virginia Tech</ORGANIZATION> E mail kavan at vt dot edu Ziqian Song is Ph D candidate in the <ORGANIZATION>Department of Computer Science at Virginia Tech</ORGANIZATION> E mail ziqian at vt dot edu Acknowledgements We thank the <ORGANIZATION>U S National Science Foundation NSF</ORGANIZATION> for supporting the VTS project SES 1111239 of which this work is part Any opinions findings and conclusions or recommendations expressed in this material are those of the authors and do not necessarily reflect the views of <ORGANIZATION>NSF</ORGANIZATION> We would also like to thank our collaborators and colleagues <PERSON>Manuel</PERSON> P rez Qui ones <PERSON>John Tedesco Naren Ramakrishnan</PERSON> and <PERSON>Siddharth Krishnan</PERSON> for their collaboration on the VTS project References S <PERSON>Ahuja</PERSON> M P rez Qui ones and A Kavanaugh 2009 Rethinking local conversations on the Web In T <PERSON>Davies</PERSON> and S P Gangadharan editors Online deliberation Design research and practice <ORGANIZATION>Stanford Calif Center for the Study of Language and Information</ORGANIZATION> pp 123 129 P <PERSON>Bhattacharya</PERSON> S <PERSON>Ghosh</PERSON> J Kulshrestha M Modal M B <PERSON>Zafar N Ganguly</PERSON> and K P Gummadi 2014 Deep Twitter diving Exploring topical groups in microblogs at scale <ORGANIZATION>CSCW</ORGANIZATION> 14 Proceedings of the 17th ACM Conference on <ORGANIZATION>Computer Supported Cooperative Work amp Social Computing</ORGANIZATION> pp 197 210 doi https doi org 10 1145 2531602 2531636 accessed 7 March 2018 D Blei and J Lafferty 2009 Topic models In A Srivastava and M Sahami editors Text mining <PERSON>Classificaton</PERSON> clustering and applications <PERSON>London Chapman</PERSON> amp Hall pp 71 94 version at http www cs columbia edu blei papers BleiLafferty2009 pdf accessed 7 March 2018 D M Blei A Y Ng and M I Jordan 2003 Latent dirichlet allocation <ORGANIZATION>Journal of Machine Learning Research</ORGANIZATION> volume 3 numbers 4 5 pp 993 1 022 d boyd S <PERSON>Golder</PERSON> and G Lotan 2010 Tweet tweet retweet Conversational aspects of retweeting on Twitter HICSS 10 Proceedings of the 2010 43rd <ORGANIZATION>Hawaii International Conference on System Sciences</ORGANIZATION> pp 1 10 doi https doi org 10 1109 HICSS 2010 412 accessed 7 March 2018 A <PERSON>Cohill</PERSON> and A <PERSON>Kavanaugh</PERSON> editors 1997 Community networks Lessons from <ORGANIZATION>Blacksburg Virginia Boston Mass Artech House</ORGANIZATION> J <PERSON>Cranshaw R Schwartz J Hong</PERSON> and N <PERSON>Sadeh</PERSON> 2012 The Livehoods Project Utilizing social media to understand the dynamics of a city Proceedings of the Sixth International AAAI Conference on Weblogs and <ORGANIZATION>Social Media</ORGANIZATION> at https www aaai org ocs index php ICWSM ICWSM12 paper view 4682 accessed 7 March 2018 M de Choudhury N Diakopoulos and M Naaman 2012 Unfolding the event landscape on Twitter Classification and exploration of user categories <ORGANIZATION>CSCW</ORGANIZATION> 12 Proceedings of the ACM 2012 conference on Computer Supported Cooperative Work pp 241 244 doi https doi org 10 1145 2145204 2145242 accessed 7 March 2018 M Granovetter 1973 The strength of weak ties <ORGANIZATION>American Journal of Sociology</ORGANIZATION> volume 78 number 6 pp 1 360 1 380 doi https doi org 10 1086 225469 accessed 7 March 2018 M Gurstein editor 2000 Community informatics Enabling communities with information and communications technologies <ORGANIZATION>Hershey Pa Idea Group</ORGANIZATION> B <PERSON>Hanrahan</PERSON> S <PERSON>Ahuja</PERSON> M P rez Qui ones and A Kavanaugh 2011 Evaluating software for communities using social affordances CHI EA 11 CHI 11 Extended Abstracts on Human Factors in Computing Systems pp 1 621 1 626 doi https doi org 10 1145 1979742 1979818 accessed 7 March 2018 D L <PERSON>Hansen</PERSON> D <PERSON>Rotman</PERSON> E <PERSON>Bonsignore</PERSON> N <PERSON>Milic Frayling</PERSON> E M Rodriges M <PERSON>Smith B Shneiderman</PERSON> and T Capone 2012 Do you know the way to SNA A process model for analyzing and visualizing social media data SOCIALINFORMATICS 12 Proceedings of the 2012 International Conference on <ORGANIZATION>Social Informatics</ORGANIZATION> pp 304 313 doi https doi org 10 1109 SocialInformatics 2012 26 accessed 7 March 2018 D <PERSON>Hansen B Shneiderman</PERSON> and M Smith 2011 Analyzing social media networks with NodeXL Insights from a connected world <ORGANIZATION>Burlington Mass Morgan Kaufmann</ORGANIZATION> A Java T Finin X Song and B Tseng 2007 Why we Twitter Understanding microblogging usage and communities WebKDD SNA KDD 07 Proceedings of the Ninth WebKDD and First SNA KDD 2007 workshop on Web Mining and <ORGANIZATION>Social Network Analysis</ORGANIZATION> pp 56 65 doi https doi org 10 1145 1348549 1348556 accessed 7 March 2018 A <PERSON>Kavanaugh</PERSON> D <PERSON>Reese J M Carroll</PERSON> and M B <PERSON>Rosson</PERSON> 2003 Weak ties in networked communities In M <PERSON>Huysman</PERSON> E <PERSON>Wenger</PERSON> and V <PERSON>Wulf</PERSON> editors Communities and technologies Proceedings of the <ORGANIZATION>First International Conference on Communities and Technologies C amp T 2003 Boston Mass Kluwer Academic</ORGANIZATION> pp 265 286 A <PERSON>Kavanaugh</PERSON> J M <PERSON>Carroll</PERSON> M B <PERSON>Rosson T T Zin</PERSON> and D D Reese 2005 Community networks Where offline communities meet online <ORGANIZATION>Journal of Computer Mediated Communication</ORGANIZATION> volume 10 number 4 doi https doi org 10 1111 j 1083 6101 2005 tb00266 x accessed 7 March 2018 A Kavanaugh M P rez Qui ones J C <PERSON>Tedesco</PERSON> and W Sanders 2010 Toward a virtual town square in the Era of Web 2 0 In J <PERSON>Hunsinger L Klastrup</PERSON> and M <PERSON>Allen</PERSON> editors International handbook of <ORGANIZATION>Internet Research New York Springer</ORGANIZATION> pp 279 294 doi https doi org 10 1007 978 1 4020 9789 8_17 accessed 7 March 2018 A Kavanaugh A <PERSON>Ahuja</PERSON> S <PERSON>Gad</PERSON> S <PERSON>Neidig</PERSON> M A P rez Qui ones N <PERSON>Ramakrishnan</PERSON> and <PERSON>J Tedesco</PERSON> 2014 Hyper local news aggregation Designing for social affordances Government Information Quarterly 31 1 pp 30 41 doi https doi org 10 1016 j giq 2013 04 004 accessed 7 March 2018 A <PERSON>Kavanaugh</PERSON> S <PERSON>Krishnan</PERSON> M P rez Qui ones <PERSON>J Tedesco K Madondo</PERSON> and A Ahuja 2014 Encouraging civic participation through news aggregation <ORGANIZATION>Information Polity</ORGANIZATION> volume 19 numbers 1 2 pp 35 56 doi https doi org 10 3233 IP 140332 accessed 7 March 2018 J <PERSON>Kim</PERSON> R O <PERSON>Wyatt</PERSON> and E <PERSON>Katz</PERSON> 1999 News talk opinion participation The part played by conversation in deliberative democracy Political Communication volume 16 number 4 pp 361 385 doi https doi org 10 1080 105846099198541 accessed 7 March 2018 P <PERSON>Purcell</PERSON> editor 2006 Networked neighbourhoods The connected community in context <LOCATION>London</LOCATION> Springer Verlag doi https doi org 10 1007 1 84628 601 8 accessed 7 March 2018 R D Putnam 2000 Bowling alone The collapse and revival of American community <ORGANIZATION>New York Simon</ORGANIZATION> amp Schuster B <PERSON>Roble J Cheng</PERSON> and M Sbitani 2014 Tweets region X CS 4624 Hypertext and <ORGANIZATION>Multimedia Capstone Course Report Computer Science Virginia Tech</ORGANIZATION> E Rothenbuhler 1991 The process of community involvement Communication Monographs volume 58 number 1 pp 63 78 doi https doi org 10 1080 03637759109376214 accessed 7 March 2018 D Schuler 1996 New community networks Wired for change Reading Mass <PERSON>Addison Wesley</PERSON> M A Smith L <PERSON>Rainie B Shneiderman</PERSON> and I Himelboim 2014 Mapping Twitter topic networks From polarized crowds to community clusters <ORGANIZATION>Pew Research Center</ORGANIZATION> 20 February at http www pewinternet org 2014 02 20 mapping twitter topic networks from polarized crowds to community clusters accessed 7 March 2018 C Tauro S <PERSON>Ahuja</PERSON> M P rez Qui ones A <PERSON>Kavanaugh</PERSON> and P Isenhour 2008 Deliberation in the wild A visualization tool for blog discovery and citizen to citizen participation dg o 08 Proceedings of the 2008 International Conference on <ORGANIZATION>Digital Government Research</ORGANIZATION> pp 143 152 <ORGANIZATION>U S Census Bureau</ORGANIZATION> n d QuickFacts at http www census gov quickfacts accessed 7 March 2018 Editorial history Received 31 October 2017 revised 1 February 2018 accepted 7 March 2018 Copyright 2018 <PERSON>Andrea L Kavanaugh</PERSON> and Ziqian Song Engaging a community through social media based topics and interactions by <PERSON>Andrea L Kavanaugh</PERSON> and Ziqian Song First Monday Volume 23 Number 4 2 April 2018 http firstmonday org ojs index php fm article view 8146 6660 doi http dx doi org 10 5210 fm v23i4 8146 image Bookmark and Share A Great Cities Initiative of the <ORGANIZATION>University of Illinois at Chicago University Library First</ORGANIZATION> Monday 1995 2018 ISSN 1396 0466</ner>
