<ner>The Chicago_Reader revisits the ambient dreamscapes of <PERSON>Midori Takada</PERSON> A handful of tickets remain for <PERSON>Midori Taka</PERSON> https t co KpQ8ABofKS This Monday Join us for a rare after hours event presented in collaboration with chicagosymphony Celebrate Musi https t co T1pOzcGMjq THURSDAY Exhibition Opening <PERSON>Judy Ledgerwood</PERSON> Chromatic Patterns Join us for the public opening of <PERSON>Judy Ledgerwood</PERSON> https t co <PERSON>VjqZYdFZlg Kay Rosen</PERSON> recognizes the potential of everyday language to reframe meaning which she explores through strategies o https t co ZiPa6GhXqG The <ORGANIZATION>Art Institute</ORGANIZATION> is proud to partner with lollapalooza again this year Win a pair of one day tickets for Sunday https t co 6uj7BTXpuq NOW OPEN Flesh <PERSON>Ivan Albright</PERSON> at the <ORGANIZATION>Art Institute of Chicago</ORGANIZATION> A retrospective of shocking obsessively detailed https t co 5zvz58GDcd Prints and drawings are sensitive to light and can only be displayed for short periods of time ARTicle explores a https t co X3qoueFGPw OPENING MAY 12 Never a Lovely So Real Photography and Film in <LOCATION>Chicago</LOCATION> 1950 1980 A poetic survey of photographe https t co xuFjesvD8T Join a Sketch Class at the <ORGANIZATION>Art Institute</ORGANIZATION> and draw in the museum s galleries under the guidance of experienced instr https t co 321V2y4vL3 In Railroad Sunset <PERSON>Edward Hopper</PERSON> contrasts the sharp lines of manmade structures with undulating green hills Hi https t co L4iJzJGxUB MAY 14 Experience a rare US concert performed by Japanese composer and percussionist <PERSON>Midori Takada</PERSON> This event has https t co 6xgV6DJiQo This Monday Join us for a rare after hours event presented in collaboration with chicagosymphony Celebrate Musi https t co unnIyp6iUm THURSDAY Artist Talk Ilit <PERSON>Azoulay Ilit Azoulay</PERSON> s constructed photographs charged with history remind us in her w https t co NtXdQmnUlW The Suntimes highlights the work of one of <LOCATION>Chicago</LOCATION> s most uncompromising artists in Flesh <PERSON>Ivan Albright</PERSON> opening https t co 1LgGBHN6Ag En garde Explore a variety of swords and other implements of war and sport on view in Medieval and Renaissance Arm https t co wjYzFRINQw MAY 20 Concert Spektral Quartet In Search of Futures Past Schoenberg the Visionary Discover <PERSON>Schoenberg</PERSON> s impact https t co cYmERF8QiK CLOSING SOON Mirroring <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> s Past Emperors and Their Bronzes Beneath the layers of centuries a rich history https t co ppLjPZp6mC MAY 10 Exhibition Opening <PERSON>Judy Ledgerwood</PERSON> Chromatic Patterns Celebrate the opening of <PERSON>Judy Ledgerwood</PERSON> s new site https t co zCYZBIB9Ea THURSDAY Artist Talk Ilit <PERSON>Azoulay Ilit Azoulay</PERSON> s constructed photographs charged with history remind us in her w https t co 46jMrRiqW4 Associate curator of European Painting and Sculpture <PERSON>Emerson Bowyer</PERSON> meets <PERSON>Sophie Renoir</PERSON> great granddaughter of Pier https t co kY9M8MAapL SUNDAY Panel Discussion Living Histories from the <LOCATION>Middle East</LOCATION> Experience the personal stories of people affected https t co PicHBtmn3H OPENING MAY 4 Flesh <PERSON>Ivan Albright</PERSON> at the <ORGANIZATION>Art Institute of Chicago Albright</ORGANIZATION> s enduring masterpieces retain the p https t co BWPU3XbyPm CLOSING SUNDAY I strongly believe in our right to be frivolous <PERSON>Mounira Al Solh</PERSON> collects histories and personal e https t co psfiFe0MsK MAY 14 Experience a rare US concert performed by Japanese composer and percussionist <PERSON>Midori Takada</PERSON> This event has https t co nASc4XhFjB TOMORROW at 3 00 Hear from <PERSON>Christopher de Hamel</PERSON> one of the world s leading experts on medieval manuscripts as he https t co iQu7u2rrG1 Stop by on the double to explore jewelry and other ornate objects in pairs now on view in Art of the <LOCATION>Americas</LOCATION> https t co XJtcDzgMag Tomorrow evening Enjoy a cash bar complimentary snacks and West African records spun by <PERSON>Florent Mazzoleni</PERSON> at the https t co ZkvJNTh555 TOMORROW at 6 00 Explore the museum s collection in a Gallery Talk presented in in American Sign Language Free to https t co QiJ8iiXqH9 Our <LOCATION>North Garden</LOCATION> is partially closed through the end of the week as we install work for the <ORGANIZATION>Society of Contemporary</ORGANIZATION> https t co qxPiUJwjl7 RT 1book1chicago REMINDER this is TOMORROW amp gt We re partnering with artinstitutechi for a unique program featuring art and artists de THURSDAY Exhibition Opening Volta Photo Enjoy a cash bar complimentary snacks and West African records spun b https t co XIT5aIYxVl Born <PERSON>OnThisDay Willem de Kooning</PERSON> was a central figure in Abstract Expressionism Aptly titled Excavation reflec https t co cr3aDMSEyv MAY 20 Concert Spektral Quartet In Search of Futures Past Schoenberg the Visionary Discover <PERSON>Schoenberg</PERSON> s impact https t co CakV7pt9ew MAY 3 Artist Talk Ilit <PERSON>Azoulay Ilit Azoulay</PERSON> s constructed photographs of places and objects charged with history https t co uT4Btf0HvH <PERSON>Cornelis Visscher</PERSON> s engraving is one of the softest most tactile renditions of a cat ever printed The breathless https t co WVD54AhLdL SUNDAY Panel Discussion Living Histories from the <LOCATION>Middle East</LOCATION> Experience the personal stories of people affected https t co zod7mmZ50X WEDNESDAY at 6 00 An Unfurling People in This Town Explore the role our city plays in American creativity with https t co fruTo1zQGn Explore trompe l oeil French for deceives the eye with examples from the museum s collection ARTicle https t co Dr1BCxXhj3 NOW OPEN <PERSON>Helen Frankenthaler</PERSON> Prints The Romance of a New Medium <PERSON>Helen Frankenthaler</PERSON> is best known for her boldl https t co TKBxFcegZ6 COMING SOON The <ORGANIZATION>Art Institute</ORGANIZATION> presents garish and haunting work from the master of the macabre OPENING MAY 4 https t co e0ybWn8DjC APRIL 26 <ORGANIZATION>Exhibition Opening Volta Photo Enjoy</ORGANIZATION> a cash bar complimentary snacks and West African records spun b https t co tyWPOeC3DB RT 1book1chicago We re partnering with artinstitutechi for a unique program featuring art and artists dealing with music and civil right Among <LOCATION>Mali</LOCATION> s Bamana people ritual objects like this amorphously shaped boli function as a mediating force betwee https t co RPJnhUp5dm Tonight at 6 00 Kid <PERSON>Koala</PERSON> presents Music To Draw To Sketch in the gallery as world renowned scratch DJ kidkoala https t co xIx4MOoJhu Admission is free today for <LOCATION>Illinois</LOCATION> residents 5 00 8 00 Join us tonight at 6 00 as Lebanese artist actor and https t co RSclkENaef Unlike the other Surrealists of his time <PERSON>Ren Magritte</PERSON> found mystery not in fantastical imagery but in everyday r https t co RmutdlOaNT Redesigning a gallery space takes a great deal of planning research and ingenuity Explore the transformation of https t co SfKL3mOORK FRIDAY Panel Discussion <PERSON>Helen Frankenthaler</PERSON> Scholars and curators discuss <PERSON>Helen Frankenthaler</PERSON> s work and process https t co GhvDpPxDsI APRIL 25 An Unfurling People in This Town Join us at <ORGANIZATION>Harold Washington Library</ORGANIZATION> 6 00 8 00 to explore the role o https t co Ny1aJ8y1tR THURSDAY Kid <PERSON>Koala</PERSON> presents Music To Draw To Our kidkoala performances are sold out You can still catch him in https t co RRoTFQWVDa Artist <PERSON>Alex Katz</PERSON> poses with <ORGANIZATION>Yellow House</ORGANIZATION> 2 a new addition to the <ORGANIZATION>Art Institute</ORGANIZATION> s permanent collection now on view https t co ODn903XPth THURSDAY Lebanese artist actor and playwright <PERSON>Rabih Mrou</PERSON> delivers a non academic lecture on the image politics https t co 54QbDdjVwM <PERSON>Hubert Robert</PERSON> s paintings of imaginary ruins are fantasies of expansive space filled with arches Roman statuary https t co X6u30sMmxP CLOSING SOON Our current rotation in Gallery 10 spans the full history of photography from 19th century daguerreot https t co 2iAguQMBpL MAY 14 Concert <PERSON>Midori Takada</PERSON> Experience a rare US concert performed by Japanese composer and percussionist <PERSON>Midori</PERSON> https t co tLd79HhGpM <PERSON>Marc Chagall</PERSON> presented <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> Windows as a gift to the <ORGANIZATION>Art Institute</ORGANIZATION> in 1977 Made forever famous less than ten https t co WHYl4qYQam APRIL 17 18 Our 7 00 performances for kidkoala s Satellite Turntable Orchestra are SOLD OUT A limited supply of https t co 3N7z2ehyOD COMING SOON Volta Photo Starring <PERSON>Sanl Sory</PERSON> and the People of <PERSON>Bobo Dioulasso</PERSON> in the <ORGANIZATION>Small but Musically Mighty Co</ORGANIZATION> https t co wvnuiqLFFz RT ChiTribEnt Mounira <PERSON>Al Solh</PERSON> s show at the artinstitutechi is intense devastating and essential https t co cuPwK2dpRk https t co <ORGANIZATION>TBT</ORGANIZATION> Chicagoans take in the sights downtown at the <ORGANIZATION>Art Institute</ORGANIZATION> 1940s https t co BNotQT60X6 Our Department of Conservation and Science in collaboration with the museum s curators have undertaken extensive re https t co kUm4wEBUbL SATURDAY Lecture After Actium Discovering <LOCATION>Egypt</LOCATION> in Augustan <LOCATION>Rome</LOCATION> and Beyond Explore how the Romans conquest of E https t co Pjs8plr7DR The <ORGANIZATION>Art Institute</ORGANIZATION> s gardens have opened signaling the arrival of spring with far greater reliability than the weat https t co qnDdLTswwo Winslow Homer s paintings of the sea are unparalleled in American art Depicting the heroic efforts of fishermen at https t co 61ZHV3NcdA MAY 14 Concert <PERSON>Midori Takada</PERSON> Experience a rare US concert performed by Japanese composer and percussionist <PERSON>Midori</PERSON> https t co 6Zbvwl3qvB APRIL 19 Lecture Rabih Mrou Lebanese artist actor and playwright <PERSON>Rabih Mrou</PERSON> delivers a non academic lecture https t co PITBsESHjM NOW OPEN Experience the transformation of our newly redesigned galleries of Indian Southeast Asian and Himalayan https t co wRoju4p15Y https t co 39OENFrYLx APRIL 20 Panel Discussion <PERSON>Helen Frankenthaler</PERSON> Scholars and curators discuss <PERSON>Helen Frankenthaler</PERSON> s work and proces https t co WmBqNWj2pJ douard <PERSON>Vuillard</PERSON> explored the decorative potential of painting using a harmonious palette to convey a scene s emot https t co wXlZnh8XtY APRIL 19 Kid <PERSON>Koala</PERSON> presents Music To Draw To Join us for this Drop In Workshop and sketch in the gallery as world https t co EUDadNf8PK He s made a name for himself as a master turntablist both on his own and as part of the supergroup <ORGANIZATION>Deltron</ORGANIZATION> 3030 https t co W5mxQZrm34 SATURDAY Lecture After Actium Discovering <LOCATION>Egypt</LOCATION> in Augustan <LOCATION>Rome</LOCATION> and Beyond Explore how the Romans conquest of E https t co jO0gVDTxHq APRIL 19 Lecture Rabih Mrou Lebanese artist actor and playwright <PERSON>Rabih Mrou</PERSON> delivers a non academic lecture https t co 0Km4CxWgyJ Your perfect <LOCATION>Chicago</LOCATION> day begins with a journey through the Art Institute TICKETS https t co IfYp2HFCt5 https t co jbztbW6m7X Frank <PERSON>Lloyd Wright</PERSON> anticipates the later abstractions of <PERSON>Piet Mondrian</PERSON> in this colorful whimsical triptych window https t co ApnhANMXvq COMING SOON <PERSON>Helen Frankenthaler</PERSON> Prints The Romance of a New Medium This exhibition reveals <PERSON>Helen Frankenthaler</PERSON> https t co 6ktZXGG63V APRIL 19 Kid <PERSON>Koala</PERSON> presents Music To Draw To Join us for this Drop In Workshop and sketch in the gallery as world https t co 5CDlDbBCSm Learn how <PERSON>Roberto Matta</PERSON> influenced American Abstract Expressionism https t co oBwjrp2hPm And see The Earth Is https t co yPvyvYy3Zz APRIL 20 Panel Discussion <PERSON>Helen Frankenthaler</PERSON> Scholars and curators discuss <PERSON>Helen Frankenthaler</PERSON> s work and proces https t co akfM0QfYON WEDNESDAY Conversation <PERSON>Alex Katz</PERSON> and <PERSON>Ann Goldstein Alex Katz</PERSON> is one of the most recognized and widely exhibited a https t co YTGWlGMMFi COMING SOON An extensive reinstallation of the <ORGANIZATION>Alsdorf Galleries</ORGANIZATION> promises to dramatically change the ways visitors https t co CejFfxBBYh RT CHIRPRadio Ticket Giveaway We ve got a pair of tickets to <PERSON>KidKoala</PERSON> s interactive live performance artinstitutechi on 4 17 feat a CLOSING SUNDAY Paintings reflect the social values and environmental concerns of Chinese artists during the Ming an https t co agszR9JZsL CLOSING SOON Unslumbrous Night presents a new series of bronze and ceramic sculptures by Andrew Lord See this in https t co 0ov9xnCr9s APRIL 17 18 Get your tickets to join kidkoala s Satellite Turntable Orchestra This live performance invites th https t co DddKk5rB5R RT cbcradioq Artist <PERSON>Mounira Al Solh</PERSON> draws portraits of Syrian people in exile She talks about her series I strongly believe in our rig COMING SOON Modern Japanese Portraits The 1940s and 1950s were a pivotal time for the creative prints movement https t co AbZLRVp70k AndyMarfia The gardens are open now As for the warm weather I m afraid we can t say We hope you ll stop by tomorrow either way Coming soon Warm weather in <LOCATION>Chicago</LOCATION> Stop by and enjoy our gardens now open every day of the week https t co m1WuY0t827 Planning your perfect day in <ORGANIZATION>Chicago Start</ORGANIZATION> at the <ORGANIZATION>Art Institute</ORGANIZATION> TICKETS https t co rR4DZhqF2A https t co dyp9J9mQ30 APRIL 7 Beginners Sketching Workshop Level 2 Ready to take the next step in developing your drawing skills This w https t co TV5Qf4Evr7 CLOSING SUNDAY The Arranged Flower <LOCATION>Ikebana</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Flora</LOCATION> in Japanese Prints Explore the art of flower arranging wit https t co ZfINUxTjUo spudart The feeling is mutual sir and we encourage our followers to do the same on your account We always enjoy hearing from you TFW you reach 300 000 followers on Twitter Thank you to all of our followers Something you d like us to share L https t co O6fpyLKACZ <PERSON>Max Ernst</PERSON> was one of the most gifted artists associated with Surrealism exhibiting a versatile imagination that le https t co 2lTq3Scrzm SUNDAY CSO Chamber Music Series The Sacred and the Divine Join us for a live performance of <PERSON>Messiaen</PERSON> s Quartet f https t co ELa1k0T8ia Born <PERSON>OnThisDay Vincent van Gogh</PERSON> s short nomadic life was characterized by a constant search for a home and place https t co qWOBNIZfD1 Submit your pitch by tomorrow to join the <ORGANIZATION>Art Institute s Block Party</ORGANIZATION> this summer Share your story idea or art https t co hdWRfj56xv Today is the final day to register for Stop Making Sense Building Creative Confidence Professionals from differe https t co mYsbsCBXU2 <LOCATION>Chicago</LOCATION> is always ready for a parade We couldn t be more proud of our LoyolaRamblers Bring home the trophy guys https t co PFCDyGUQiz The ongoing drawing and embroidery series I strongly believe in our right to be frivolous by <PERSON>Mounira Al Solh</PERSON> coll https t co JG7OA8pyDK TONIGHT at 6 00 Join us for a gallery tour presented in American Sign Language Free to IL residents https t co HOjCoqFUyQ This portrait depicts a man in a luxurious fur lined robe on one side and a lively cadaver above an open grave on t https t co kMebZK497l Join the <ORGANIZATION>Art Institute s Block Party</ORGANIZATION> this summer Do you have a story idea or artistic practice you d like to sha https t co 1WTiw1PDtm <PERSON>Cauleen Smith</PERSON> populated her first group of hand sewn banners with the famous closing line from a <PERSON>Gwendolyn Brooks</PERSON> p https t co oP5IbAdRCt APRIL 20 Stop Making Sense Building Creative Confidence Professionals from different industries come together for https t co 4TZPc2C84t In the <ORGANIZATION>American Southwest</ORGANIZATION> there is an Indian ceramic tradition that began to take form in the early centuries AD a https t co 9e4u3yDU85 TONIGHT Artist Talk <PERSON>Wu Tsang</PERSON> Performance artist and award winning filmmaker <PERSON>Wu Tsang</PERSON> joins us to discuss her prac https t co 34iU0Hcxi7 lois_wetzel Hi <PERSON>Lois</PERSON> no set date yet It will largely depend on the seasonal change It s coming soon though We w https t co c7zyjk5ndz A member of the first generation of Abstract Expressionists <PERSON>Joan Mitchell</PERSON> was known for painting big light filled https t co AL7aKHEYw2 Spring Break plans Your picture perfect <LOCATION>Chicago</LOCATION> adventure starts at the <ORGANIZATION>Art Institute BUY TICKETS</ORGANIZATION> https t co eqotmPWnkE Photography is a major force in explaining man to man <PERSON>Edward Steichen</PERSON> born OnThisDay in 1879 Explore Steich https t co XRm19kK9tO Please note that Thursday s Gallery Talk The Art of Noise with <PERSON>Wolfgang Voigt</PERSON> has been CANCELLED We apologize for https t co o7qlatyKk4 FRIDAY Artists Connect Open TV Join us for a Gallery Talk and Screening with weareotv a research based initiativ https t co lVearCbmUJ WEDNESDAY Artist Talk <PERSON>Wu Tsang</PERSON> Performance artist and award winning filmmaker <PERSON>Wu Tsang</PERSON> considers intersections o https t co CXw1I4DEnS chitakestime Not sure if this helps at all but <PERSON>Adam</PERSON> and Eve appear to have belly buttons in many of our works on https t co wTtE5WOudB Wang Dongling is a leading artist best known for large abstract works he calls calligraphic paintings Combining https t co KSWSXhjH4v Join the <ORGANIZATION>Art Institute s Block Party</ORGANIZATION> this summer Do you have a story idea or artistic practice you d like to sha https t co ZJkh8mA6Cx A leader of the Russian avant garde <PERSON>Natalia Goncharova</PERSON> was among the first to rediscover folk art and icons drawi https t co WCKReqD0IT RT artnet From Ferris Bueller s Day Off to Black Panther When the World s Greatest Museums Become Movie Sets https t co JlO0tg7c1 No female artist enjoyed greater success or exerted more influence on the art of her era than <PERSON>Rosalba Carriera</PERSON> In https t co WQrYJ45fZs ONE WEEK left to submit your pitch and join the <ORGANIZATION>Art Institute s Block Party</ORGANIZATION> this summer Do you have a story idea https t co jnIkhw9unK FatherJabroni Hi there thanks for reaching out Any bags 13 x 17 x 4 inches or larger will need to be checked in https t co kiwLTK32Gb ARTicle explores the story of <PERSON>John L Sullivan</PERSON> the last great bare knuckle American boxer depicted in this crazy https t co 7XGEOVe6fE NOW OPEN Max Lamb Exercises in Seating The chair is the holy grail of objects for many designers including Max https t co jQP7UCGfRy TBT The <PERSON>Graf Zeppelin</PERSON> was the world s largest airship when it embarked on the first ever flight around the world i https t co 0eEnuMF563 RT kidkoala <LOCATION>CHICAGO</LOCATION> TurntableOrchestra shows APR 17 18 v limited seating Come Play in our 50 turntable orchestra artinstitutec Spring is upon us We hope this selection of <ORGANIZATION>Art Institute</ORGANIZATION> works evoking springtime brightens up your day https t co Su90kCGfcN SUNDAY Join us for a concert by the Avalon String Quartet inspired by the exhibition Mirroring <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> s Past Empe https t co Pe8Mvtrtxu The Medieval World at Our Fingertips presents illuminated manuscripts of the Middle Ages offering a fascinating https t co q8or5iMNlG APRIL 20 Stop Making Sense Building Creative Confidence Cultivate your creativity in an immersive hands on week https t co BvxUfcVRhJ <PERSON>Pablo Picasso</PERSON> was nearly penniless when he painted The Old Guitarist and many of his works at this time depict ou https t co FpOfHxmg0H Young female musicians from <LOCATION>Persia Centra Asia</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Turkestan</LOCATION> captivated <PERSON>Tang</PERSON> aristocrats by playing both Chinese https t co qJOgbfsNg0 APRIL 17 18 Join kidkoala s Satellite Turntable Orchestra This live performance invites the audience to play al https t co UhlVlKb9sZ MARCH 30 Artists Connect Open TV Join us for a Gallery Talk and Screening with weareotv a research based initiat https t co 5elVlxY70q <PERSON>Philippe Parreno</PERSON> s immersive installations create space for alternate worlds and states of being See his work on v https t co dcD1MKDd8A Exploring <LOCATION>Chicago</LOCATION> for Spring Break Visit the Art Institute we make a great first impression TICKETS https t co NtGJRGqSh3 In Self Portrait of My Sister <PERSON>Gertrude Abercrombie</PERSON> hints at a desire to be a different person a longing she cou https t co yElZlNPPiz CLOSING SOON Shockingly Mad <PERSON>Henry Fuseli</PERSON> and the Art of Drawing <PERSON>Henry Fuseli</PERSON> s passionate unrestrained approac https t co kow9G5yZ4g TONIGHT Last chance to get tickets to After Dark in the <ORGANIZATION>Modern Wing Catch</ORGANIZATION> live performances by Drama and DJ Will https t co Bj9DxO3UBX APRIL 20 Stop Making Sense Building Creative Confidence Cultivate your creativity in an immersive hands on weeke https t co 7AXuoD6VUf <PERSON>Wanda Pimentel</PERSON> emerged within <LOCATION>Brazil</LOCATION> s 1960s New Figuration movement which used Pop inflected representation as a https t co evZhm0Xki8 Tomorrow night <PERSON>Don</PERSON> t miss After Dark an evening of cocktails live performances and art in the Modern Wing Expe https t co 9u7yW6HBrR CLOSING SOON Rodin Sculptor and <PERSON>Storyteller Don</PERSON> t miss the chance to experience the powerfully expressive work https t co 5C1FJZP4HT As magnificent as the Magnificent Mile See why the <ORGANIZATION>Art Institute</ORGANIZATION> is <ORGANIZATION>TripAdvisor</ORGANIZATION> s top <LOCATION>Chicago</LOCATION> destination TIC https t co 9YkSq1So18 Among the Baga and Nalu peoples of coastal <LOCATION>Guinea</LOCATION> masquerade is often used to connect with supernatural forces and https t co WjhvC8sIiT Don t miss After Dark in the <ORGANIZATION>Modern Wing</ORGANIZATION> this Friday Experience the work of <PERSON>Mounira Al Solh</PERSON> enjoy signature cock https t co QWtdt7e0Oc Join the <ORGANIZATION>Art Institute s Block Party</ORGANIZATION> this summer Do you have a story idea or artistic practice you d like to sh https t co PfNC6wMP0O <PERSON>Gladys Nilsson</PERSON> is a founding member of the Hairy Who a group of <LOCATION>Chicago</LOCATION> based artists who exhibited together in th https t co r9qG7u9hXs MARCH 29 Gallery Talk The Art of Noise with <PERSON>Wolfgang Voigt Wolfgang Voigt</PERSON> a leading pioneer in electronic music https t co VwjLYDMjxA APRIL 17 18 Join kidkoala s Satellite Turntable Orchestra This live performance invites the audience to play al https t co 85xJSMK9LL This Friday Come out to After Dark for an evening of cocktails live performances and art in the Modern Wing Ex https t co UmetwxmtKa <PERSON>Bertrand Goldberg</PERSON> was a visionary <LOCATION>Chicago</LOCATION> architect whose designs for housing urban planning and industrial desig https t co <ORGANIZATION>K4sTMvCIVo RT</ORGANIZATION> ChicagoParent The <ORGANIZATION>Art Institute</ORGANIZATION> is the coolest place for <LOCATION>Chicago</LOCATION> teens this spring https t co TUGe0FJZxb artinstitutechi <ORGANIZATION>Chicago Join</ORGANIZATION> a Sketch Class at the <ORGANIZATION>Art Institute</ORGANIZATION> and draw in the museum s galleries under the guidance of experienced instr https t co 0UNA5YkVQK Dress Codes Portrait Photographs from the Collection explores the power of clothing to shape self representation https t co gj4CqkSrhF <PERSON>Karl Schmidt Rottluff</PERSON> was a founding member of Br cke Formed in 1905 the group sought to promote a more intuitive https t co g2BpjnQkyz Dance to DRAMA_CHICAGO and DJ willgalvan_ next Friday at After Dark an evening of cocktails live performances a https t co JrIJGlIfxP Join the <ORGANIZATION>Art Institute</ORGANIZATION> in celebrating InternationalWomensDay with works by female artists across the centuries https t co Yv4Gg04d29 MARCH 29 Tickets are going fast for this rare multimedia performance by <PERSON>Wolfgang Voigt</PERSON> one of the most influential https t co UO4Fr5bqnv This Roman marble relief depicts a wounded Greek warrior sinking to the ground after being struck from behind appr https t co YvnzhqxWOK Everything is expressed through relationships <PERSON>Piet Mondrian</PERSON> born OnThisDay The roots of abstract art can be https t co 8bUfjIRN3L MARCH 15 Artists Connect <PERSON>Barak</PERSON> ad <PERSON>Soleil</PERSON> Navigate the intersections of race and disability in up n down a perf https t co TX7Yp2zJ5Y The <ORGANIZATION>WSJ</ORGANIZATION> recommends Mirroring <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> s Past an unexpectedly engaging and layered journey only at the Art Institu https t co LceR9IBeHy MARCH 16 Join us for After Dark an evening of cocktails live performances and art in the Modern Wing Dance to https t co ErU0DyGG9C <PERSON>Mary Cassatt</PERSON> s sensitive portrayal of a mother and child reflects the most advanced 19th century ideas about parent https t co klVeCzATCq Born OnThisDay in 1696 Find spirited examples of <PERSON>Giovanni Battista Tiepolo</PERSON> s Rococo style on display in this serie https t co gjCthvIYS6 EXTENDED Join the <ORGANIZATION>Art Institute s Block Party</ORGANIZATION> this summer Do you have a story idea or artistic practice you d l https t co vI3VdXdomx CLOSING SOON Gods and Super heroes Drawing in an Age of Revolution As the old order in <LOCATION>Europe</LOCATION> faced the rising https t co 76MBDb8c2H THURSDAY Panel and Screening TIGERMAN This event premiers rough cut footage of a documentary film in progress a https t co Nxh3woFUyS Unlock the stories behind rare ancient vessels that illuminate <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> s fascinating past LEARN MORE https t co wh0RqBvnMx Spring Break plans Your perfect <LOCATION>Chicago</LOCATION> day starts at the Art Institute BUY TICKETS https t co rM4DRf1TA3 https t co YxCE75NLwU Since the 1970s <PERSON>Cindy Sherman</PERSON> has served as both photographer and model for a large cast of fictional personalities https t co KtAjDtY0TU MARCH 16 Come out to After Dark for an evening of cocktails live performances and art in the <ORGANIZATION>Modern Wing Experi</ORGANIZATION> https t co qg5TPnRTxd Tomorrow Celebrate the close of Chinese New Year Year at our FREE Lantern Celebration Enjoy festive food and drin https t co boQHJXC5Ut Explore ikebana the art of flower arranging with prints from <LOCATION>Japan</LOCATION> s Edo period depicting harmonious floral arran https t co SF8RT4FTx6 Already singular as a female sculptor of the 19th century F licie de Fauveau was at once a radical royalist a fer https t co 6JGxkro9cd APRIL 17 18 Join kidkoala s Satellite Turntable Orchestra in this interactive live performance that invites the a https t co ch5c44zTD1 RT chicagotribune <ORGANIZATION>Art Institute</ORGANIZATION> s Chinese bronzework exhibit brings ancient objects to American soil for the first time https t co a2Ku APRIL 20 Stop Making Sense Building Creative Confidence Cultivate your creativity in an immersive hands on weeke https t co ya8xdA7YR7 These gilded panels painted in <LOCATION>Italy</LOCATION> during the early 15th century were made for the predella of an altarpiece a z https t co Y48Gjr52Eo <PERSON>Henry Ossawa Tanner</PERSON> was perhaps the most renowned American painter of religious works at the turn of the 20th centu https t co 6MJ3coH0iZ Two weeks left to submit a proposal and join the <ORGANIZATION>Art Institute s Block Party</ORGANIZATION> this summer Do you have a story ide https t co 6vQxWeXey7 RT kidkoala <ORGANIZATION>CHICAGO</ORGANIZATION> IL 4 SHOWS at artinstitutechi APRIL 17 18 https t co tnKhLvuRzm https t co H4b0KtrIns Paintings reflect the social values and environmental concerns of Chinese artists during the Ming and Qing dynastie https t co cu610dkE0o MARCH 15 Artists Connect <PERSON>Barak</PERSON> ad <PERSON>Soleil</PERSON> Navigate the intersections of race and disability in up n down a perf https t co iQcsKajAZv EXTENDED Rodin Sculptor and Storyteller continues at the <ORGANIZATION>Art Institute</ORGANIZATION> due to visitor demand Take advantage of https t co SDHvq1gLq1 Born OnThisDay in 1808 After serving six months in prison for a caricature of King <PERSON>Louis Philippe Honor Victorin</PERSON> https t co bqhnqiF0KB THURSDAY Performance <PERSON>Christine Sun Kim Lautplan</PERSON> Artist chrisunkim explores her relationship to church bells and https t co vjIA08MPIU <PERSON>Lorraine O Grady</PERSON> s Miscegenated Family Album is a series pairing images of the artist s family with those of anci https t co GsEcRhOiqJ CLOSING SOON <LOCATION>India</LOCATION> Modern The Paintings of M F <PERSON>Husain</PERSON> Explore the work of <LOCATION>India</LOCATION> s most important 20th century https t co obAwIt4Ryz NOW OPEN Mirroring <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> s Past Emperors and Their Bronzes Explore the rich history of ancient Chinese bronzes https t co QdWbRkYDtx <PERSON>Jean Louis Forain</PERSON> burst upon the Parisian art scene after joining the fourth Impressionist exhibition Produced imm https t co GQnrv8mJXA Become a part of the <ORGANIZATION>Art Institute s Block Party</ORGANIZATION> this summer Do you have a story idea or artistic practice you https t co gNxWEKA245 APRIL 17 18 Join kidkoala s Satellite Turntable Orchestra in this interactive live performance that invites the a https t co ol8cRtWoYQ Explore over 3 000 years of art that illuminates the histories of the ancient inhabitants of modern day <LOCATION>Mexico</LOCATION> inc https t co EvdjMg4QXp MARCH 1 Performance <PERSON>Christine Sun Kim Lautplan</PERSON> Artist chrisunkim explores her relationship to church bells and h https t co y7iePCuIGS Born OnThisDay Cabin in the Cotton brought <PERSON>Horace Pippin</PERSON> to the attention of the art world when the painting was https t co MqTYWqDqUX Tonight at 6 00 QuatuorBozzini an original voice in contemporary classical music performs their energetic program https t co Uin6N9tM13 MARCH 16 Come out to After Dark for an evening of cocktails live performances and art in the <ORGANIZATION>Modern Wing Experi</ORGANIZATION> https t co Y5b6gKUNmH TheCut explores <PERSON>Mounira Al Solh</PERSON> I strongly believe in our right to be frivolous at once an oral history and l https t co RlN3BSUv4S Born OnThisDay <LOCATION>Chicago</LOCATION> native <PERSON>Ivan Albright</PERSON> remains one of the most provocative artists of the 20th century Explo https t co v4SnvcrWVz COMING SOON Mirroring <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> s Past Emperors and Their Bronzes Beneath the layers of centuries a rich history e https t co tXaT2u3xCQ THURSDAY <PERSON>Don</PERSON> t miss this energetic performance by QuatuorBozzini an original voice in new experimental and class https t co 6cRfC3seLZ <PERSON>Marion Perkins</PERSON> s Man of Sorrows depicts the suffering of a black Christ wearing a crown of thorns When asked to https t co 8azVp2wPE7 THURSDAY at 6 00 Stop by for a gallery tour presented in American Sign Language Free to IL residents https t co qt80ByAhTh Things are not difficult to make what is difficult is putting ourselves in the state of mind to make them Born https t co YxVo3LO1a1 Our current rotation in Gallery 10 spans the full history of photography from 19th century daguerreotypes to conte https t co a7qlElKmFF Happy Year of the Dog This ferocious pup served as the guardian of a tomb to stand alert as a watchdog in th https t co ZAt1mLBGMn Become a part of the <ORGANIZATION>Art Institute s Block Party</ORGANIZATION> this summer Do you have a story idea or artistic practice you https t co yLsgmLxdwx THURSDAY Join us for an energetic performance by QuatuorBozzini an original voice in new experimental and classi https t co dUA7TH4lAm CubsJoeMadd We hear the <ORGANIZATION>Cubs</ORGANIZATION> are finding inspiration in the world of art this year at spring training You know w https t co UQxCJrJkUh NOW OPEN Artist <PERSON>Philippe Parreno</PERSON> creates spaces that allow us to speculate about alternate worlds and states of bei https t co 7MZB1jcqJS What is The Thinker thinking Post your own picture of The Thinker and tell us what s on his mind using the https t co rNPXWsCfcr <PERSON>Joshua Johnson</PERSON> was the nation s first professional African American painter of prominence He was born into slavery https t co wjNBzA9Fw1 TONIGHT at 6 00 Join us for an interactive sound workshop with artist and designer <PERSON>Yuri Suzuki</PERSON> FREE https t co Ewzzv7VvcN Don t just buy flowers for your loved one take some time to arrange them with help from ARTicle in our Work of the https t co iyQc6qZO8d Love is in bloom at the Art Institute Enjoy these fresh picked paintings from the museum s collection <ORGANIZATION>Happy Vale</ORGANIZATION> https t co TcmLEAlQmx NEW ACQUISITION Bottle Rack one of <PERSON>Marcel Duchamp</PERSON> s earliest readymades challenged and eventually transformed https t co FU9p63gQHb NOW OPEN Xu Longsen Light of Heaven <PERSON>Xu Longsen</PERSON> has earned international acclaim for his groundbreaking work dr https t co uBsj4uYzVS MARCH 3 Lantern Celebration Celebrate the close of Chinese New Year with storytelling Chinese music and a lanter https t co kHD75QocI7 MARCH 1 Performance <PERSON>Christine Sun Kim Lautplan</PERSON> Artist chrisunkim explores her relationship to church bells and h https t co ImIenANTOq Whether they depict an event celebrate the lives of individuals or offer a fantastical escape quilts embody memo https t co lRvW0o8RYq APRIL 17 18 Join kidkoala s Satellite Turntable Orchestra in this interactive live performance inviting the audie https t co FSMqqMRowg FEBRUARY 22 Join us for an energetic performance of contemporary works by the <LOCATION>Montreal</LOCATION> based QuatuorBozzini an ori https t co qfvp9W0H5x Still scratching your head about <PERSON>Valentine</PERSON> s Day Show that special someone how you feel with powerfully expressiv https t co eB71F1sixc SATURDAY Mini Course Asian Art at the Art Institute Get to know the collection of Asian Art through lively in gal https t co S2YaRee2k7 RT TheCut These are the faces of Syrian people in exile as captured by a Lebanese artist https t co wPuwYkhcBF https t co zQHdHjsNCr In this colorful work <ORGANIZATION>Harlem Renaissance</ORGANIZATION> painter <PERSON>Jacob Lawrence</PERSON> depicts both the solemnity and joy of a marriage c https t co o1y0uZDnGF TOMORROW at 6 00 Artist Talk <PERSON>Yuri Suzuki</PERSON> Sound artist designer and musician yurisuzuki introduces his work wh https t co AsBBh2P8AL thibaud_denolle Hi Thibaud Happy you enjoyed your visit Let me put you in touch with our Membership team for mor https t co NAUGHvP6b2 Sometimes I had to refrain from making portraits I wasn t able to it was too intense for me NowOnView https t co xH9j0wlC1X MAY 14 Concert <PERSON>Midori Takada</PERSON> Experience a rare US concert performed by Japanese composer and percussionist <PERSON>Midori</PERSON> https t co LFNz5zB7Gn Weather comes and weather goes but we don t flake The <ORGANIZATION>Art Institute</ORGANIZATION> is open today during normal hours 10 30 5 00 https t co 8Zpb0tqB5m The main thing is to be moved to love to hope to tremble to live <PERSON>Auguste Rodin</PERSON> Celebrate love and devotion https t co zh1s5Dv3sl Curator <PERSON>Hendrik Folkerts</PERSON> sits down with artist <PERSON>Mounira Al Solh</PERSON> to discuss her new exhibition opening today at the A https t co OxcGJibc87 In July 1919 race riots heightened tensions in <LOCATION>Chicago</LOCATION> The violence convinced <PERSON>Archibald Motley</PERSON> he should use his a https t co ddzqkKqFHW Looking at art is an art form unto itself Gain a new perspective with this behind the scenes exploration of our co https t co s3jzDnIx7c FEBRUARY 22 Join us for an energetic performance of contemporary works by the <LOCATION>Montreal</LOCATION> based QuatuorBozzini an ori https t co EV20wIHNrr MARCH 1 Performance <PERSON>Christine Sun Kim Lautplan</PERSON> Artist chrisunkim explores her relationship to church bells in a https t co i8hCBV67dO This Saturday Join us for the <ORGANIZATION>Auxiliary Board After Party</ORGANIZATION> as we celebrate the 45th anniversary of one of the oldes https t co LNmPAZvsEv Find your place in the sun at the <ORGANIZATION>Art Institute</ORGANIZATION> where admission is FREE for <LOCATION>Illinois</LOCATION> residents Monday through Fri https t co 1S2vk6fN7m midwestanalog It has our name written all over it Statuette of a Striding Figure is one of the oldest objects at the museum Created 5 000 years ago in modern day https t co FoNr9IIaN7 FEBRUARY 22 Join us for an energetic performance of contemporary works by the <LOCATION>Montreal</LOCATION> based QuatuorBozzini an ori https t co 8Xhhqt1xZX THURSDAY Join us for a conversation with artist <PERSON>Mounira Al Solh</PERSON> on the opening of her exhibition I strongly belie https t co rj0lfYE0rT <PERSON>Eldzier Cortor</PERSON> wrote This painting shows the overcrowded condition of people who are obliged to carry out their https t co aNKymOQoo5 FEBRUARY 13 Artist Talk <PERSON>Yuri Suzuki</PERSON> Sound artist designer and musician yurisuzuki introduces his work which l https t co qdtslwjdjW <PERSON>Claude Monet</PERSON> s On the <ORGANIZATION>Bank of the Seine Bennecourt</ORGANIZATION> documents an unprecedented artistic breakthrough Known as th https t co OJwttO1TsV SATURDAY Join us for the official <ORGANIZATION>Auxiliary Board After Party</ORGANIZATION> as we celebrate the 45th anniversary of one of the ol https t co ktOX1OiRGZ The Earth Is a Man features apocalyptic imagery almost vibrating with nervous energy ARTicle s Work of the Week https t co J71cWCqxyY THURSDAY Gallery Talk Reading Egyptian Art Join us as we bring works of Egyptian art out of storage for a pop up https t co 62K1d0EknE Like many artists of his generation <PERSON>Charles White</PERSON> believed that art could be an influential force in the struggle https t co QCPK1EcBl4 THURSDAY Conversation <PERSON>Mounira Al Solh</PERSON> On the opening of her exhibition <PERSON>Mounira Al Solh</PERSON> discusses her multi year https t co Zv1eWt26mh APRIL 17 18 <ORGANIZATION>Kid Koala s Satellite Turntable Orchestra Join</ORGANIZATION> kidkoala s band This interactive live performance in https t co 4sffpxrcC2 TBT This 1894 drawing sketches out the plan for a proposed staircase and dome for the Art Institute The dome was https t co G72WimxxuR FEBRUARY 10 <ORGANIZATION>Auxiliary Board 45th Anniversary Celebration After Party Join</ORGANIZATION> us for the official after party as we c https t co jZtJ5OVech TONIGHT at 6 00 Don t miss this program highlighting work by emerging game designers and digital artists presented https t co PFwy1xTqvY Wild beasts monsters demons and other fantastical creatures populate these hauntingly detailed prints of the 15t https t co dMHn2hDaZN RT chiphopopotamus Thought you d enjoy a little life imitating art artinstitutechi https t co hZmiO0sVW4 FEBRUARY 9 Performance I want to be a party Join us for an intimate performance by artist <PERSON>Mounira Al Solh</PERSON> as she https t co Ti1uCl4xQO FEBRUARY 22 Concert Bozzini Quartet Join us for an energetic performance of contemporary works by the <LOCATION>Montreal</LOCATION> ba https t co dyDYUtbIAO TOMORROW BitBashChicago <LOCATION>Chicago</LOCATION> s alternative video game festival presents a program highlighting work by emergi https t co lbe2c8oj9w This female figurine belongs to the sophisticated Chup cuaro artistic tradition The uncanny visual quality of its https t co sef4vvlzBY FRIDAY Join us for a conversation on <PERSON>Auguste Rodin</PERSON> with experts <PERSON>Antoinette Le Normand Romain</PERSON> and <PERSON>Emerson Bowyer</PERSON> F https t co 70UewmoUnM NOW OPEN The Medieval World at Our Fingertips Travel through 400 years of the Middle Ages in this exhibition of https t co UISKzY4RvF FEBRUARY 8 Conversation <PERSON>Mounira Al Solh Mounira Al Solh</PERSON> discusses her multi year drawing and embroidery project r https t co bZnWel32p4 THURSDAY BitBashChicago <LOCATION>Chicago</LOCATION> s alternative video game festival presents a program highlighting work by emergi https t co soEA7YIdne Fighting roosters a lurking cat and a pickpocket enliven the overflowing abundance of a Flemish market stall in t https t co uEn3oL2KVC WEDNESDAY Drinking with Dionysos and Sekhmet s Wrath Beer and Wine in <LOCATION>Egypt</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Greece</LOCATION> Raise your rhyton to the a https t co 28lFs9YXd7 ARTicle travels back a century to explore the work of a dangerous madman in 100 Years Later <LOCATION>Mir Mir</LOCATION> On the https t co iKvyVs2Tzp jdamats whitneymuseum Yes that s right They don t often travel but when they do they manage to visit the world https t co AxjyGdcMow TOMORROW at 11 00 Dance and performance project boomerangdance lead an interactive movement workshop free with mus https t co gxnfBGAezz <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> s most famous couple takes their show on the road with a trip to <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> Bid them bon voyage at the Art I https t co USHM6DeyuI Explore the wonder of art and make your own mini masterpiece in the Ryan Learning Center Admission is always free https t co igJVTvDujB FEBRUARY 22 Concert Bozzini Quartet The <LOCATION>Montreal</LOCATION> based QuatuorBozzini an original voice in new experimental an https t co VWStWpuo7l TBT Established in 1926 outside the <ORGANIZATION>Art Institute Route</ORGANIZATION> 66 brought American travelers directly to the museum s fr https t co bM7EPSFfHz factiomagazine They re on Thursday Evenings 5 00 8 00 You can find more information at the link below Thanks https t co CLSM3RybG0 COMING SOON I strongly believe in our right to be frivolous <PERSON>Mounira Al Solh</PERSON> s ongoing series collects histories https t co 2NHqBgNROi TONIGHT The daringly physical and poetically nuanced dance and performance project boomerangdance perform a series https t co 3hI8fbieOr esoesrevir You re right Vir We appreciate the feedback Our address is 111 South <LOCATION>Michigan Avenue Chicago</LOCATION> IL 6 https t co BD9HzbKCWB <PERSON>Georgia O Keeffe</PERSON> was 77 when she painted Sky Above Clouds IV a monumental work stretching 24 feet across the lar https t co BoCiRYXel8 Skillfully forged of steel this composite armor from the 16th century achieves its beauty with the simple elegance https t co 4sKyhKNsWp TOMORROW Stop by for a gallery tour presented in American Sign Language Free to <LOCATION>Illinois</LOCATION> residents https t co qlMomJVr3t The museum is a journey and a destination a statement and a conversation a place for contemplation and community https t co V9AZFzeq1Q THURSDAY Performance Boomerang The daringly physical and poetically nuanced dance and performance project https t co uRKDLQOrsu Every new painting is like throwing myself into the water without knowing how to swim douard <PERSON>Manet</PERSON> born https t co GaJYRrd0FQ The <ORGANIZATION>Art Institute</ORGANIZATION> offers free museum admission for <LOCATION>Chicago</LOCATION> teens providing rich opportunities for the exchange of https t co NRtPHQDP2g They learned to leave the house door wide Until they had lit the lamp inside <PERSON>Siah Armajani</PERSON> s Fireplace Mantel https t co rkilbpM3uq FEBRUARY 10 <ORGANIZATION>Auxiliary Board</ORGANIZATION> 45th Anniversary Celebration After Party One of the oldest and most recognized charit https t co 636rDFvGsS FEBRUARY 1 Artists Connect Bit Bash Interactive Influence BitBashChicago <LOCATION>Chicago</LOCATION> s alternative video game festi https t co PFMX3f07y5 AndyDisco KQuilt I d resent the swearing <PERSON>Andy</PERSON> but what can I say we re quilty as charged For what it s worth https t co iJgUBHOldy AndyDisco Hi <PERSON>Andy</PERSON> so cool you found a relative in our collection Our 2008 Homer exhibition focused on his waterc https t co i4E5egD1kQ I am the primitive of the method I have invented <PERSON>Paul</PERSON> C zanne born OnThisDay in 1839 See five paintings by https t co GYnuOtXACm Starting January 25 Sketch Class Portraiture Interpreted Six sessions with experienced instructors All materia https t co GSk7LFDbHV Museums empower us to explore expressions of creativity that challenge our assumptions provoke us to learn more s https t co cnyyPY4C3A hoodmd2 Hi It s in Gallery 394 of Modern Art on the third floor of the Modern Wing Hope you can stop by and see it FEBRUARY 2 Conversation <PERSON>Antoinette Le Normand Romain</PERSON> with <ORGANIZATION>Emerson Bowyer Join</ORGANIZATION> us for a discussion of <PERSON>Auguste Rodi</PERSON> https t co C9mKX7wmyy Following the aftermath of World War I artists across <LOCATION>Europe</LOCATION> sought to put the chaos of war behind them and forge https t co SFDi0K6m6V Two GameChangers meet on the <ORGANIZATION>Art Institute</ORGANIZATION> s Grand Staircase art provocateur <PERSON>Marcel Duchamp</PERSON> and <PERSON>Katharine Kuh</PERSON> th https t co BEyX7ynhpp FEBRUARY 22 Concert Bozzini Quartet The Montreal based QuatuorBozzini performs a diverse program of works by con https t co qWIoBZLFyA ChicagoMuseumWeek is here Experience the city s most beloved institutions with discounted admissions and more https t co i2LHTrFaok CLOSING SUNDAY Color Studies Explore color s intriguing if at times understated roles in the history of archit https t co T3GsbeUinN RT hannahdrew__ MuseumSelfieDay at artinstitutechi art imitates art https t co OuLiw81M1l RT MJ_Mouton MuseumSelfieDay artinstitutechi https t co baMhdMcMpT Turn that frown upside down it s MuseumSelfieDay Share your best selfie moment at the <ORGANIZATION>Art Institute</ORGANIZATION> https t co Hw29oFLdht JANUARY 25 Performance Boomerang boomerangdance a daringly physical and poetically nuanced dance and performanc https t co UVejjfyYse FRIDAY Lecture Burgkmair s <ORGANIZATION>Gold Printing Authority</ORGANIZATION> in 16th Century Germany Explore early modern printing material https t co hie7gWx5KX Explore <PERSON>Rodin</PERSON> s incomparable ability to bring bronze and stone to life in the exhibition <LOCATION>Rodin Sculptor</LOCATION> and Story https t co 2w2DBLHwVB Starting this Saturday Join our Sketch Class The Value of Light and Dark Six sessions with experienced instructo https t co 5hoTAuAPrZ Shockingly Mad <PERSON>Henry Fuseli</PERSON> and the Art of Drawing reveals the influence of <PERSON>Fuseli</PERSON> s radical style one character https t co jtsGYpwRWp Today we celebrate the life and legacy of <PERSON>Martin Luther King</PERSON> whose words and actions still inspire us today A me https t co 4rpI7D5dXV TOMORROW King Day Festival Say It Loud Raise your voice in celebration of <PERSON>Martin Luther King Jr</PERSON> s legacy and joi https t co Yk31IdnoFR Revoliutsiia Demonstratsiia closes this Monday LEARN MORE https t co qMqdgZsp3N https t co r6ZSKjfsdK <PERSON>John Singer Sargent</PERSON> born OnThisDay in 1856 could bring a painting to life with the flourish of a brushstroke See https t co IM7nCrEnVV SUNDAY The Avalon String Quartet performs selections from <PERSON>Shostakovich</PERSON> in conjunction with the closing exhibition https t co 48wQ38nFby The Yoruba of <LOCATION>Nigeria</LOCATION> have the highest recorded rate of twin births in the world with an estimated 45 sets in ever https t co aBQFvn7Cn6 TBT A joyride to the Art Institute 1900 Kick your inspiration into high gear with Free Winter Weekdays offeri https t co 7zAXQ3E0EJ MONDAY King Day Festival Say It Loud Raise your voice in celebration of <PERSON>Martin Luther King Jr</PERSON> s legacy and join https t co sUEsnLFbC2 FEBRUARY 22 Concert Bozzini Quartet The Montreal based QuatuorBozzini performs a diverse program of works by con https t co WaIKygBbb1 NOW OPEN The Arranged Flower <LOCATION>Ikebana</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Flora</LOCATION> in Japanese Prints Explore ikebana the art of flower arranging https t co uwR0GitNjB MARCH 29 Performance Gas <PERSON>Wolfgang Voigt</PERSON> Experience a rare multimedia performance by <PERSON>Wolfgang Voigt</PERSON> one of the https t co lWRoVNsuRS JANUARY 19 Lecture Burgkmair s <ORGANIZATION>Gold Printing Authority</ORGANIZATION> in 16th Century Germany Explore early modern printing mate https t co JVsZUqoLE8 APRIL 17 18 Kid <PERSON>Koala</PERSON> s Satellite Concert Join kidkoala s turntable orchestra in this interactive live performan https t co pSRadTOAMA THURSDAY Artists Connect <PERSON>Haley Fohr Haley Fohr</PERSON> of CircuitdesYeux gives an intimate in gallery performance in th https t co PlJouDx5SH CLOSING MONDAY Revoliutsiia Demonstratsiia Soviet Art Put to the Test Over 500 works paintings models films https t co giiIuG1sHz FREE WINTER WEEKDAYS <LOCATION>Illinois</LOCATION> residents enjoy free museum admission Monday Friday now through February 15 https t co EZWq51RSfM MONDAY King Day Festival Say It Loud Raise your voice in celebration of <PERSON>Martin Luther King Jr</PERSON> s legacy and join https t co SVbbIytV5y Remarkable for the preservation of its bold red vivid yellow and black coloration this Greek statuette reminds v https t co 7MA0Ds03cQ SUNDAY The Avalon String Quartet performs selections from <PERSON>Shostakovich</PERSON> in conjunction with the exhibition Revoliu https t co CB7AJuDiYP NOW OPEN The Wandering Landscape Chinese Topographical Paintings of the 16th through 19th Century LEARN MORE https t co BN3n7PHj0l vibecontrols CircuitdesYeux theemptybottle It will be a vocal solo performance Thanks JANUARY 15 King Day Festival Say It Loud Raise your voice in celebration of <PERSON>Martin Luther King Jr</PERSON> s legacy and j https t co r7XXgZugGP THURSDAY Artists Connect <PERSON>Haley Fohr Haley Fohr</PERSON> of CircuitdesYeux gives an intimate in gallery performance in th https t co FpKUIqbJqA TBT Determined to become a modern artist Tarsila arrived in <LOCATION>Paris</LOCATION> in 1923 where she became acquainted with artis https t co dFLqmUtlnp I don t want to escape via intellectual ruses I want affirmations via passionate embraces amp amp you can t have life un https t co v5asyntkhx TOMORROW Join us for a Gallery Talk Contemplating Contemporary a guided meditation and collaborative discussion in https t co 5h53IRBAtH Known for his portraits of celebrity figures it is perhaps unsurprising <PERSON>Andy Warhol</PERSON> would execute self portraits t https t co 7xzJZDXzmQ <PERSON>Rodin</PERSON> was a master of visual communication with an incomparable ability to bring bronze and stone to life Sculpto https t co 6sP6Nadhzf JANUARY 15 King Day Festival Say It Loud Raise your voice in celebration of <PERSON>Martin Luther King Jr</PERSON> s legacy and j https t co nd71Y7kHGj judehere Hi <PERSON>Judy</PERSON> it s by the American painter <PERSON>William Glackens</PERSON> Here s a link for more information Happy New Yea https t co 2glmVAwzbk Dress Codes Portrait Photographs from the Collection explores the power of clothing in pictures with selections https t co SQtvvTpGXW ARTicle explores the obscure artistic legacy of <PERSON>William Bonnell</PERSON> through his expressive portraits NowOnView in our https t co oCqjCXOB2Y Happy New Year s Eve from the <ORGANIZATION>Art Institute of Chicago Please</ORGANIZATION> note that the museum is closed tomorrow for New https t co XJgoD1leE1 Start off your new year inspired by a world renowned art collection only at the <ORGANIZATION>Art Institute</ORGANIZATION> https t co 9jSfeXFRpi RT richardroeper Even Right Lion artinstitutechi looks like he could use a hot chocolate and a hug https t co ZfcLfZIrTK Since the museum opened its doors in 1893 visitors have commemorated the occasion with keepsakes produced around t https t co qytMX9YoCq CLOSING SOON Revoliutsiia Demonstratsiia Soviet Art Put to the Test Explore how Soviet art changed the course https t co LqDLr836gV Near the end of his life <PERSON>Francisco de Goya</PERSON> created a satirical series of etchings known as Los disparates meani https t co eYu79bdoFu CLOSING SOON Tarsila do Amaral Inventing Modern Art in <LOCATION>Brazil</LOCATION> Tarsila s fresh and uniquely Brazilian perspectiv https t co uSrxCuuJXG DECEMBER 27 30 Holly Days Bring the family for art making activities at the <ORGANIZATION>Art Institute FREE</ORGANIZATION> https t co ebbO0Ekexg Merry Christmas from the <ORGANIZATION>Art Institute of Chicago Please</ORGANIZATION> note we are closed on Christmas Day but will be open aga https t co 4OXCapjCPJ richseld We were only able to include four works on Twitter but you can find a larger photo album on Facebook Th https t co GXrr6Y6N52 Depictions of the Virgin and Child throughout the centuries From all of us at the <ORGANIZATION>Art Institute</ORGANIZATION> have a Merry Chr https t co rjTBhyN1zL Winter days offer a beauty all their own and time to spend with friends and family Enjoy this selection of paintin https t co XB2UDfQSRe The <ORGANIZATION>Art Institute</ORGANIZATION> earns five mentions in the chicagotribune s Best museum shows of 2017 https t co txVrJt6LyL https t co 3iT6xCHTXI elishario_ Hi there yes admission will continue to be free for IL residents every Thursday evening and also durin https t co IDYMsNqE85 The Yoruba masquerade festival called <LOCATION>Gelede</LOCATION> is a dazzling spectacle that honors the spiritual power of female elde https t co 2xNSVFCUBb DECEMBER 27 30 Holly Days Bring the family for art making activities at the <ORGANIZATION>Art Institute FREE</ORGANIZATION> https t co MND860E7Ar TBT Few traditions at the <ORGANIZATION>Art Institute</ORGANIZATION> are as beloved as the wreathing of our lions See them spruced up for the https t co to1PoVn0YM RT wttw An exhibit artinstitutechi features the artistic outpouring of Russian artists after the October Revolution of 1917 https t These posters from a series focused on <LOCATION>Chicago</LOCATION> destinations celebrate <LOCATION>Lake Michigan</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Lincoln Park</LOCATION> and were cre https t co ytn7aN53ty Making Memories Quilts as Souvenirs presents visually captivating and technically masterful quilts produced betw https t co zbavH6YBAt This Roman statue was inspired by the most famous Greek sculpture of a goddess the Aphrodite of Knidos But what h https t co JdRHRR8aGl Explore artworks across the collection with Spotlight Talks every day through the end of the year SPOTLIGHT TALK https t co <ORGANIZATION>PAqdWsuvof Elizabeth Price</ORGANIZATION> s work grants a new agency to historical artifacts through the artist s institutional and feminist https t co T7bgw6DRIu Still looking for last minute gifts It s not too late to give the gift of art this season Purchase a gift members https t co Wwl2lMM2eQ Color is the place where our brain and the universe meet <PERSON>Paul Klee</PERSON> born OnThisDay in 1879 See six works https t co VOUxqJrcoE DECEMBER 27 30 Holly Days Bring the family for art making activities at the <ORGANIZATION>Art Institute FREE</ORGANIZATION> https t co 2eb4l5wXAa As an evocative mingling of the real and supernatural <PERSON>Morris Kantor</PERSON> s Haunted <ORGANIZATION>House</ORGANIZATION> inflects the American past w https t co t00LQUJnJ3 What is The Thinker thinking Post your own picture of The Thinker and tell us what s on his mind using the https t co YIBcxtdAaj CLOSING SOON City and Country Prints from Early 20th Century <LOCATION>Japan</LOCATION> Explore idealized visions of urban and rural https t co mFtD6erBGG Experience the dramatic history of the Russian Revolution with an audio tour of <PERSON>Revoliutsiia Demonstratsiia Sov</PERSON> https t co 2J44yje8WJ This Saturday Create an edible dream home with your family while listening to classic holiday tunes Decorate You https t co ESZroqiGWY Celebrate the season with family friends and the <ORGANIZATION>Art Institute of Chicago HOLIDAYS</ORGANIZATION> https t co uVd564mXnL https t co vlMKb9pW3f TOMORROW Join us for Drawing for World Revolution a lecture by <PERSON>Maria Gough</PERSON> professor of modern art at <ORGANIZATION>Harvard U</ORGANIZATION> https t co Tv6U5B1DnW This Friday Graphic designer <PERSON>James Goggin</PERSON> presents Pop Culture Colour Theory a body of research on the evocativ https t co uity0bgNk4 TOMORROW Join us for a lecture on <PERSON>Jasper Johns</PERSON> with art historian and author <PERSON>Roberta Bernstein Free</PERSON> to IL resident https t co 7JiH9vcY5C CLOSING SOON <PERSON>Leigh Ledare</PERSON> pushes social systems to lay bare their underlying structures In The Plot he adapts an https t co ZTJqYKAit3 The <ORGANIZATION>Art Institute</ORGANIZATION> unveils its rare Nativity scene the Neapolitan cr che on view for just six weeks each Christmas https t co QipNfIWfK3 This impressive silver female <PERSON>Buddha</PERSON> from <LOCATION>Tibet</LOCATION> is known as a Vajrayogini one who has attained enlightenment throu https t co fSJ7jNnqDJ AustenLied Sadly these are in the galleries and not ideal for recording You can find lectures on our YouTube chan https t co R5JkHwD076 Explore artworks across the collection with our Spotlight Talks every day beginning December 18 through the end of https t co W2KvfoFQT0 Explore the pioneering work of <PERSON>Helen Frankenthaler</PERSON> born OnThisDay in 1928 in <PERSON>Helen Frankenthaler</PERSON> Prints The <ORGANIZATION>Roma</ORGANIZATION> https t co bfKw3Ek4le SATURDAY Decorate Your Own Gingerbread House Create an edible dream home with your family while listening to class https t co E0giACh8IF THURSDAY Join us for a lecture on <PERSON>Jasper Johns</PERSON> with art historian and author <PERSON>Roberta Bernstein Free</PERSON> to IL resident https t co grEf1TDJVa See the exhibition the Suntimes calls both a revelation and a pure smile inducing pleasure Tarsila do <PERSON>Amaral</PERSON> https t co xPbgYcQHLN FRIDAY Graphic designer <PERSON>James Goggin</PERSON> presents Pop Culture Colour Theory a body of research on the evocative conc https t co dUeU5cgasv AmbientRelish Did you see it around these parts It s possible the cat s wandered off to another part of the crech https t co FFod7QXre1 DECEMBER 16 Decorate Your Own Gingerbread House Create an edible dream home with your family while listening to cl https t co aCkFKsXQIa SUNDAY Join us for the 36th Annual Holiday Treasure Hunt and <ORGANIZATION>Tea Party</ORGANIZATION> a one of a kind festive family tradition at https t co dy6O0wDhzC FBF The <ORGANIZATION>Art Institute</ORGANIZATION> opens its doors to the public with a celebration in the streets December 8 1893 Happy 124t https t co u786hEZPrm Sculptor and Storyteller explores <PERSON>Rodin</PERSON> s incomparable ability to bring bronze and stone to life on view through https t co <ORGANIZATION>NcWVXZFcms Reliquaries</ORGANIZATION> are an especially vibrant form of medieval art that served the important function of housing the relics https t co ewlyH49WSA This bright and energetic painting by the modernist <PERSON>Stuart Davis</PERSON> born OnThisDay in 1892 celebrates the American in https t co 6BCoq6nZTD DECEMBER 15 Artists Connect <PERSON>James Goggin</PERSON> Graphic designer <PERSON>James Goggin</PERSON> presents Pop Culture Colour Theory a mu https t co Qf8mBEdz4O Fr d ric <PERSON>Bazille</PERSON> born OnThisDay in 1841 painted this startlingly direct self portrait while sharing an apartment w https t co je8RZZF8HI We ve decked the tiny halls of our Thorne Miniature Rooms with holiday trimmings and other festive decorations of t https t co 989EWVSNpV DECEMBER 16 Decorate Your Own Gingerbread House Create an edible dream home with your family while listening to cl https t co yLLfdLwhb6 This Sunday Join us for the 36th Annual Holiday Treasure Hunt and <ORGANIZATION>Tea Party</ORGANIZATION> a one of a kind festive family tradit https t co CmLOnr6D4I CLOSING SOON Doctrine and Devotion Art of the Religious Orders in the Spanish Andes presents iconographies in So https t co TSxQt7XALh RT wttw Rare Holiday Cr che on Display at <ORGANIZATION>Art Institute of Chicago</ORGANIZATION> https t co vFdCp3sAAQ ChicagoTonight artinstitutechi https t co THURSDAY Lecture Epiphany Coming Face to Face with the Divine at the Monastery of <ORGANIZATION>St Catherine</ORGANIZATION> Explore some of t https t co QE6IG1LZ1v Local high school choirs fill the museum with songs of the season every day this week 11 30 12 00 LEARN MORE https t co vVu5u9qfYH <PERSON>Katharina Fritsch</PERSON> makes meticulous reproductions of everyday objects creating a strong sense of otherworldliness t https t co hTcyPhlFDa DECEMBER 15 Artists Connect <PERSON>James Goggin</PERSON> Graphic designer <PERSON>James Goggin</PERSON> presents Pop Culture Colour Theory a pe https t co GGiEUZr03t SUNDAY 36th Annual Holiday Treasure Hunt and Tea Party Join us for a one of a kind exploration of art during this https t co 5Ga5WSmH11 See elegantly designed furniture by <PERSON>Frank Lloyd Wright NowOnView</PERSON> in Gallery 179 of American Art <ORGANIZATION>ARS</ORGANIZATION> https t co BfXssBbiez DECEMBER 14 Join us for a lecture on <PERSON>Jasper Johns</PERSON> with art historian and author <PERSON>Roberta Bernstein Free</PERSON> to IL resid https t co j5EHw0oQYd Over 500 rare works of art and expert life size reconstructions tell the story of the Russian Revolution 100 years https t co YeK5oesk7T SUNDAY 36th Annual Holiday Treasure Hunt and Tea Party Join us for a one of a kind exploration of art during this https t co KXRWSGDFTI DECEMBER 16 Decorate Your Own Gingerbread House Create an edible dream home with your family while listening to cl https t co sa9CZebHD2 mckra1g Thanks for reaching out <PERSON>Molly</PERSON> I m sending your comments to our Membership team We appreciate the feedback TUESDAY Lecture The Neapolitan Cr che A Closer Look Join us for a closer look at the wondrously theatrical Neapol https t co 7BT5lXbGYf knifegames I m forwarding this to our Membership team now Jessica Thanks for bringing it to our attention <PERSON>Georges Seurat</PERSON> born OnThisDay in 1859 worked for two years on A Sunday on <ORGANIZATION>La Grande Jatte</ORGANIZATION> a monumental composit https t co 4MZ7rDJIgq These ritual objects represent the life giving spirits of the earth and sky for the <LOCATION>Salado</LOCATION> branch of the <LOCATION>Mogollon</LOCATION> c https t co uD1JT5oRTK Explore the colorful art of <LOCATION>Tarsila Brazil</LOCATION> s most famous modernist in the exhibition Tarsila do Amaral Inventing https t co fJgplQVC7P The figure of <LOCATION>Shukongojin</LOCATION> the Japanese thunderbolt deity who protects the laws of Buddhism originally stood guard a https t co SlC3yR6OX5 THIS WEEKEND Don t miss this special performance as evryhshsadr presents This is not a dream generating echoes b https t co zkPqyLmPd6 Local high school choirs fill the museum with songs of the season every day next week 11 30 12 00 LEARN MORE https t co kGRA06Qo2i SATURDAY Artful Play Strike a Pose Make your own sculptural works of art in this workshop for children ages 3 5 https t co 7ehaJsj8hK NOW OPEN Gods and Super heroes Drawing in an Age of Revolution As the old order in <LOCATION>Europe</LOCATION> faced the rising for https t co BVxDjbhYmj THIS WEEKEND ONLY evryhshsadr presents This is not a dream A performance generating echoes between 1917 and 201 https t co ShhQ1D6GhO Today Join us for The Future of Public Art as ChicagoDCASE commissioner <PERSON>Mark Kelly</PERSON> joins a panel discussion Fr https t co SlYwTqfH3v Color Studies explores color s intriguing if at times understated roles in the history of architecture and desi https t co lOafbdXphx In Cupid Chastised <PERSON>Bartolomeo Manfredi</PERSON> captures a moment of high drama as Mars the god of war beats <PERSON>Cupid</PERSON> for https t co 0TFZJFKxSu THIS WEEKEND ONLY evryhshsadr presents This is not a dream A performance generating echoes between 1917 and 201 https t co k5I7CNfBVi spudart adamgopnik Hi <PERSON>Matt Great</PERSON> to hear from you We do archive select lectures including I m happy to say A https t co yVSPNFB252 DECEMBER 10 36th Annual Holiday Treasure Hunt and Tea Party Join us for a one of a kind exploration of art during https t co Ne7lB6lkjt mfaboston <LOCATION>Philbrook</LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION>LACMA</ORGANIZATION> MFAH crystalbridges DallasMuseumArt PDXArtMuseum Thanks Philbrook Presenting Ci https t co bmv5CZmzPN What is The Thinker thinking Post your own picture of The Thinker and tell us what s on his mind using the https t co bZxZUQNyvt THIS WEEKEND ONLY evryhshsadr presents This is not a dream A performance generating echoes between 1917 and 201 https t co tTOCJaZFO4 During her short career <PERSON>Eva Hesse</PERSON> produced an extraordinarily influential body of work that explored the expressiv https t co IdNXEqXp0i Tomorrow Catch this rare screening of the 1967 film Through the Eyes of a Painter written amp amp directed by the pai https t co PKQQ6AvU2h CLOSING SUNDAY For Shakers work was a form of worship and the objects they made were an attempt to create heaven on https t co ABOERee0na This Saturday and Sunday evryhshsadr brings a commissioned performance to the <ORGANIZATION>Art Institute</ORGANIZATION> echoing themes in R https t co YmdhFA2HlS The large lively eyes of this votive head are hallmarks of Etruscan figural representation See this example from https t co VD7rbIdh7c WEDNESDAY See the award winning 1967 film Through the Eyes of a Painter written amp amp directed by the painter M F H https t co nWxnuBGwvA DECEMBER 10 36th Annual Holiday Treasure Hunt and Tea Party Join us for a one of a kind exploration of art during https t co N0Czr9QH35 NOW OPEN Shockingly Mad <PERSON>Henry Fuseli</PERSON> and the Art of Drawing <PERSON>Henry Fuseli</PERSON> forged a radical new drawing style wit https t co Xr34YZeTIR Thanks to everyone who joined us for another special Wreathing of the Lions We couldn t have done it without the https t co RsJUwx0TcP RT montegoglover My morning was EVERYTHING wreathingthelions artinstitutechi w ChiSoulChildren amp amp my co host treco27 https t co W Born OnThisDay in 1864 The famous artist and chronicler of Parisian nightlife <PERSON>Henri de Toulouse Lautrec</PERSON> depicts ma https t co dweS6W0uGr TOMORROW <PERSON>Don</PERSON> t miss our annual Wreathing of the <ORGANIZATION>Lions</ORGANIZATION> a beloved family tradition at the <ORGANIZATION>Art Institute</ORGANIZATION> with this yea https t co xEiqiUEEAc The <ORGANIZATION>Art Institute</ORGANIZATION> wishes you a happy Thanksgiving this year filled with family friends and plenty to eat May you https t co rBWIGN41ve The <ORGANIZATION>Art Institute</ORGANIZATION> is closed today for Thanksgiving We ll be open again tomorrow and throughout the weekend Stop b https t co zx9naQgLJQ CLOSING SOON As the Story Unrolls explores real and imaginary stories in the scroll paintings of premodern <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> https t co PTAjh3OgHo DECEMBER 2 3 evryhshsadr brings a commissioned performance to the <ORGANIZATION>Art Institute</ORGANIZATION> echoing themes in <LOCATION>Revoliutsiia</LOCATION> https t co SZpodmDv6w This Friday Join us for the 26th Annual Wreathing of the <ORGANIZATION>Lions</ORGANIZATION> with this year s emcees members of the <LOCATION>Chicago</LOCATION> ca https t co lTMtN6HpX9 What is The Thinker thinking Post your own picture of The Thinker and tell us what s on his mind using the https t co qxhyPJlL7Z Give the gift of art this holiday season with a membership to the <ORGANIZATION>Art Institute</ORGANIZATION> for that special someone or yourse https t co XNJkDSWhsh Our new audio tour explores the past and present of American identity with help from <ORGANIZATION>HamiltonMusical</ORGANIZATION> s <LOCATION>Chicago</LOCATION> cas https t co zxUL5nHitR DECEMBER 2 3 evryhshsadr brings a commissioned performance to the <ORGANIZATION>Art Institute</ORGANIZATION> echoing themes in <LOCATION>Revoliutsiia</LOCATION> https t co lrUYO5UxiA DECEMBER 10 36th Annual Holiday Treasure Hunt and Tea Party Join us for a one of a kind exploration of art during https t co qqGI12BmtH The Surreal is but reality that has not been disconnected from its mystery See seven works NowOnView by Ren M https t co QodcWrxaVr stasiaross It s part of our permanent collection and should be on display for the foreseeable future Hope you can https t co H4s5LIVkZf Monkey Band serves as a witty example of singerie a popular French genre of the 18th century in which monkeys li https t co 7kwjJoPwoR NOVEMBER 30 Join us for a conversation with ChicagoDCASE commissioner <PERSON>Mark Kelly</PERSON> on the future of public art Fre https t co PXCfZ5lSd1 The holidays have officially arrived at the <ORGANIZATION>Art Institute</ORGANIZATION> with seasonal trimmings in our Thorne Miniature Rooms an https t co RhX0axiy0D FRIDAY Join us for the 26th Annual Wreathing of the <ORGANIZATION>Lions</ORGANIZATION> with this year s emcees members of the <LOCATION>Chicago</LOCATION> cast of https t co CaXf5BE0Yr NOVEMBER 29 See the 1967 film Through the Eyes of a Painter written amp amp directed by the painter M F <PERSON>Husain</PERSON> REGI https t co xnmj2v6bOk Tomorrow Join us for a special performance by AxiomBrass presenting the music of 20th century <LOCATION>Brazil</LOCATION> REGISTER https t co X5B4V8nkxJ OPENING TOMORROW Dress Codes Portrait Photographs from the Collection Explore the power of clothing in pictures https t co J7nrisdQcN Interested in a career as a museum curator Apply to the <ORGANIZATION>Andrew W Mellon Summer Academy</ORGANIZATION> and Undergraduate Curatori https t co 3zsRA1TL8l On the centennial of his death today museums around the world celebrate <PERSON>Rodin</PERSON> s incomparable ability to bring bron https t co izC3czWJxd SUNDAY Join us for a special performance by AxiomBrass presenting the music of 20th century <LOCATION>Brazil</LOCATION> REGISTER https t co OGmycTlU4L NOVEMBER 24 Join us for the 26th Annual Wreathing of the <ORGANIZATION>Lions</ORGANIZATION> with this year s emcees members of the <LOCATION>Chicago</LOCATION> cas https t co QHlWQ7bwJ4 Admission is free today for <LOCATION>Illinois</LOCATION> residents 5 00 8 00 <PERSON>Don</PERSON> t miss our Artist Talk with <PERSON>Leigh Ledare</PERSON> https t co WxQt7yK8O3 While this Peruvian breastplate boasts the same splendor and craftsmanship as European armor of the same time its https t co 8Yze6gZxey City and Country Prints from Early 20th Century <LOCATION>Japan</LOCATION> presents idealized visions of urban and rural life in <PERSON>Japa</PERSON> https t co Iz87sK7DWv RT redeyechicago Check out AxiomBrass at artinstitutechi plus 4 more things to do this weekend https t co s5Joj2l2N5 https t c DECEMBER 2 3 evryhshsadr brings a commissioned performance to the <ORGANIZATION>Art Institute</ORGANIZATION> echoing themes in <LOCATION>Revoliutsiia</LOCATION> https t co tpEuGbBLZt Art can help people from different backgrounds and generations to hear and learn from one another Meet the Staf https t co 0gtBqTrEuS NOVEMBER 29 See the 1967 film Through the Eyes of a Painter written amp amp directed by the painter M F <PERSON>Husain</PERSON> REGI https t co EfiNuXlesJ These reliquary figures from <LOCATION>Gabon</LOCATION> served as the guardians of ancestral relics NowOnView in African Art https t co yrBjWOc0np SUNDAY Join us for a special performance by AxiomBrass presenting the music of 20th century <LOCATION>Brazil</LOCATION> REGISTER https t co C6mshQGQtv I ve been absolutely terrified every moment of my life and I ve never let it keep me from doing a single thing I w https t co KYZCEuMYe4 Tomorrow <PERSON>Don</PERSON> t miss our Artist Talk with <PERSON>Leigh Ledare</PERSON> as he discusses his work and interest in underlying social s https t co q8xm9jb2Ov The <ORGANIZATION>Art Institute</ORGANIZATION> celebrates the 70th anniversary of <LOCATION>India</LOCATION> s independence with eight large triptychs from <PERSON>Husain</PERSON> s https t co 7PdAejefNy DECEMBER 2 3 evryhshsadr orchestrates a multimedia performance generating echoes between 1917 and 2017 https t co wKy9uMEuQl To see we must forget the name of the thing we are looking at See 28 paintings NowOnView by Impressionist mast https t co fdxM1PLRsg FRIDAY Join us for the last After Dark of 2017 featuring art by Tarsila do <PERSON>Amaral</PERSON> and live performances by https t co FFUu1XaDcb In addition to his original paintings <PERSON>Vincent van Gogh</PERSON> also copied work from artists he admired The Drinkers pa https t co k7vW5NCAn1 Explore the colorful art of <LOCATION>Tarsila Brazil</LOCATION> s most famous modernist in the exhibition Tarsila do Amaral Inventing https t co R8e7cMsKoh What is The Thinker thinking Post your own picture of The Thinker and tell us what s on his mind using the h https t co BNcMvmaxAR THURSDAY Join us as <PERSON>Leigh Ledare</PERSON> discusses his work and ongoing interest in underlying social structures free to IL https t co XV5bxVhFpy DECEMBER 2 3 Join us for This is not a dream a performance by evryhshsadr finding echoes between 1917 and 201 https t co hfNga3mpi5 Our new rotation in Gallery 10 spans the full history of photography from 19th century daguerreotypes to contempor https t co nE3rBzrB4s THURSDAY <PERSON>Don</PERSON> t miss our Artist Talk with <PERSON>Leigh Ledare</PERSON> as he discusses his work and career Free to IL residents https t co 4OYCbJb4sv NOVEMBER 17 Join us for the last After Dark of 2017 Live performances by twinsmithmusic and <ORGANIZATION>DJ Audio Jack</ORGANIZATION> TICKET https t co pn4jiBHCIS Celebrate the holidays with <ORGANIZATION>Rodin Sculptor</ORGANIZATION> and Storyteller and festive family events throughout the season HO https t co BZl81WuMBo DECEMBER 2 3 Join us for This is not a dream a performance by evryhshsadr finding echoes between 1917 and 201 https t co xhSZAlwFXC <PERSON>Paul Klee</PERSON> s Fleeing Ghost is at once dreamlike simple and enchanted ARTicle s Work of the Week https t co GqyFCVPYm0 Join us for an Artist Talk with <PERSON>Leigh Ledare</PERSON> on November 16 free to <LOCATION>Illinois</LOCATION> residents https t co lDS6WT9WcW https t co ce8vQDVaxZ NOVEMBER 29 See the 1967 film Through the Eyes of a Painter written amp amp directed by the painter M F <PERSON>Husain</PERSON> REGIS https t co 0yp9q4FiGQ Completed just after the Civil War Constant <PERSON>Mayer</PERSON> s Love s Melancholy resonated with the American public https t co ijjKCp9lJ5 NOVEMBER 19 Join us for a special performance by AxiomBrass presenting the music of 20th century <LOCATION>Brazil</LOCATION> REGISTE https t co DrcWsloNXT <LOCATION>Chicago</LOCATION> celebrates <PERSON>Greer Lankton Day</PERSON> as the artist is honored and inducted into the <LOCATION>Chicago</LOCATION> LGBT Hall of Fame toda https t co ARH4HMzHM6 Ganesha is Hinduism s Lord of Beginnings Remover of Obstacles amp amp guardian of entrances many of which are adorned w https t co P4AmO7DKGO NOVEMBER 16 Artist Talk <PERSON>Leigh Ledare Join</PERSON> us as <PERSON>Leigh Ledare</PERSON> discusses his work and career Free to IL residents https t co rTmBcExjpA NOVEMBER 29 See the 1967 film Through the Eyes of a Painter written and directed by M F <PERSON>Husain</PERSON> REGISTER https t co SUli5t7CW1 <ORGANIZATION>MVRDV</ORGANIZATION> s City Pig Model addresses increased pork consumption among the Dutch with a typology of concentrated urb https t co tm8V126n69 NOVEMBER 19 Join us for a special performance by AxiomBrass presenting the music of 20th century <LOCATION>Brazil</LOCATION> REGISTE https t co Nl6UKcJ6Ct Congratulations sscartcenter https t co iQUmqtimiV <LOCATION>Chicago</LOCATION> based performance company evryhshsadr in rehearsal See them artinstitutechi December 2 and 3 TICKETS https t co G24szcxG3K roller_jon No the exhibition is part of general admission And admission is free on Thursdays 5 00 8 00 for <PERSON>Illi</PERSON> https t co XWR1ZdHReO Richard Hunt s Hero Construction combines mythological themes with a modern sensibility NowOnView https t co reqNlcg9lX NOVEMBER 17 Join us for the last After Dark of 2017 Live performances by twinsmithmusic and <ORGANIZATION>DJ Audio Jack</ORGANIZATION> TICKET https t co u4LqKRwuIK NOVEMBER 29 See the 1967 film Through the Eyes of a Painter written and directed by M F <PERSON>Husain</PERSON> REGISTER https t co zd9zRuy0ZZ COMING SOON Shockingly Mad <PERSON>Henry Fuseli</PERSON> and the Art of Drawing Opening November 18 https t co rf8WgVZqro https t co QxMBXvcfD6 NOVEMBER 16 Artist Talk <PERSON>Leigh Ledare Join</PERSON> us as <PERSON>Leigh Ledare</PERSON> discusses his work and career Free to IL residents https t co knlFDj2clw TOMORROW Celebrate <LOCATION>Diwali</LOCATION> the Hindu festival of lights at this FREE family event art making dance music amp amp more https t co CmA4GW3iBa NOVEMBER 29 Join us for a screening of the 1967 film Through the Eyes of a Painter directed by M F <PERSON>Husain</PERSON> INF https t co 11OUy9BSZH NOW OPEN Rodin Sculptor and Storyteller Celebrate the artist s life and work on the centenary of his death https t co 1aQX270YpL NOVEMBER 16 Artist Talk <PERSON>Leigh Ledare Join</PERSON> us as <PERSON>Leigh Ledare</PERSON> discusses his work and career Free to IL residents https t co I9gIPFNgE8 Philbrook DallasMuseumArt mfaboston <ORGANIZATION>LACMA</ORGANIZATION> MFAH <PERSON>Alice</PERSON> doesn t mind she s got three friends with her https t co lSN82Zaoo8 DECEMBER 2 3 Join us for This is not a dream a performance by evryhshsadr finding echoes between 1917 and 201 https t co QQGcUPoaGQ Tomorrow Join us for a lecture on <LOCATION>Brazil</LOCATION> s most famous Modern artist Tarsila do <PERSON>Amaral</PERSON> w the exhibition s curator https t co IXlcxeyxyU NEW ACQUISITION See this new addition to our permanent collection <PERSON>Francis Picabia</PERSON> s Painting of Madame X https t co Z9uH15RPdK NOVEMBER 19 Join us for a special performance by AxiomBrass presenting the music of 20th century <LOCATION>Brazil</LOCATION> https t co rwTUjnlY4x NOVEMBER 29 Join us for a screening of the 1967 film Through the Eyes of a Painter directed by M F <PERSON>Husain</PERSON> https t co 8V7DTF7yWh Martyred saints <PERSON>Lucy</PERSON> and <PERSON>Agatha</PERSON> carry attributes which allude to the torments that preceded their deaths NowOnView https t co Wdv11fOIxD Tarsila s fresh and uniquely Brazilian perspective influenced art for generations to come NOW ON VIEW https t co wSBZCOxxkB FRIDAY Lecture Tarsila do Amaral Brazilian Modernist Discover one of the 20th century s most influential artists https t co insUjBOGmg SATURDAY Celebrate <LOCATION>Diwali</LOCATION> the Hindu festival of lights at this FREE family event art making dance music amp amp more https t co fXURGf3yhn NOVEMBER 16 Artist Talk <PERSON>Leigh Ledare Join</PERSON> us as <PERSON>Leigh Ledare</PERSON> discusses his work and career Free to IL residents https t co H5vyYqxLoR NOW OPEN British artist <ORGANIZATION>Elizabeth Price</ORGANIZATION> presents two immersive multichannel videos in the <ORGANIZATION>Modern Wing LEARN MORE</ORGANIZATION> https t co V4ne2mbRHf NOW OPEN Revoliutsiia Demonstratsiia Soviet Art Put to the Test The radical art of revolution 100 years later https t co GRjfifrLCn THURSDAY Join us for a gallery conversation Faith in <LOCATION>Colonial South America</LOCATION> with the curator <PERSON>Free</PERSON> with admission https t co InGk2Aseo3 dianecristina12 No if you re coming from <LOCATION>Michigan</LOCATION> Ave you ll want to walk east down <PERSON>Monroe</PERSON> on the north side of https t co sWzXkhLT7K PadraigOnJ Hi this work is on long term loan and not part of our permanent collection FRIDAY Lecture Tarsila do Amaral Brazilian Modernist Discover one of the 20th century s most influential artists https t co Gkd5NXsha6 In this first century Roman sculpture a child satyr gestures both mischievously amp amp menacingly through the mouth of https t co 8tOHJr66kC OPENING FRIDAY Rodin Sculptor and Storyteller Celebrate his life and work on the centenary of his death https t co 8oBiwmgi6V dianecristina12 Hi <PERSON>Diane</PERSON> yes the Modern Wing will be open amp amp accessible on foot Let me know if you have other ques https t co fqqJ6sTQ5U NOVEMBER 17 Join us for the last After Dark of 2017 Live performances by twinsmithmusic and <ORGANIZATION>DJ Audio Jack</ORGANIZATION> TICKET https t co nVkBKbvFnY DECEMBER 2 3 Join us for This is not a dream a special commissioned performance by evryhshsadr TICKETS INFO https t co mnzyiyEFPZ Fall foliage leaves an impression in the Art Institute s <LOCATION>North Garden</LOCATION> https t co YaEQ4Jaroi MONDAY Artist Talk <PERSON>Amy Sillman</PERSON> discusses her diverse body of work and influential career Free with registration https t co Hw6QSLZuVX An enchanting eye opening new exhibit Both a revelation and a pure smile inducing pleasure via <ORGANIZATION>Suntimes</ORGANIZATION> https t co bKeZlll4Gu NOVEMBER 3 Lecture Tarsila Brazilian Modernist Discover one of the 20th century s most influential artists https t co MU4Yj503GD COMING SOON Rodin Sculptor and Storyteller Celebrate the artist s life and work on the centenary of his death https t co whp8oVEQki RT amirhusain_tx An astrolabe beautifully preserved at the <ORGANIZATION>Art Institute Chicago</ORGANIZATION> artinstitutechi These ancient computers were built in L TONIGHT Join us for a champagne reception celebrating the opening of Andrew Lord s Unslumbrous Night FREE https t co UhRBSdAEtS NOVEMBER 3 Join us for a lecture on the art amp amp influence of Tarsila do <PERSON>Amaral</PERSON> with the exhibition s curator REGISTE https t co 7pXr6wtSul TOMORROW Join us for a tour of the Architecture and Design galleries in American Sign Language free to IL residents https t co q7DWZ0XgeW Art washes away from the soul the dust of everyday life <PERSON>Pablo Picasso</PERSON> born OnThisDay in 1881 NowOnView https t co MGBMi3zBFF NOVEMBER 4 Celebrate <LOCATION>Diwali</LOCATION> the Hindu festival of lights at this FREE family event LEARN MORE https t co gVFP4kWtur TOMORROW Explore the myth and legends of the <LOCATION>Golden Rock of Burma</LOCATION> in a lecture free to IL residents LEARN MORE https t co Zhufeyycv6 nwi_jsp DIT_photo Closing after the weekend https t co 5JMXs3UdXh THURSDAY Join us for a champagne reception celebrating the opening of Andrew Lord s Unslumbrous Night FREE https t co cf2USkjjsE MONDAY Artist <PERSON>Amy Sillman</PERSON> discusses her diverse body of work and her influential career Free with registration https t co p5UkLwsMqf NOVEMBER 17 Join us for the last After Dark of 2017 Live performances by twinsmithmusic and <ORGANIZATION>DJ Audio Jack</ORGANIZATION> TICKET https t co aPhJbxktiz OPENING SUNDAY Revoliutsiia Demonstratsiia presents radical Soviet art 100 years after the Russian Revolution https t co gGnNr1IZTf Original paintings by <PERSON>Andrew Lord</PERSON> announce the opening of his new installation at the <ORGANIZATION>Art Institute</ORGANIZATION> via ARTicle https t co ZRRNnR5Mop NOVEMBER 16 Artist <PERSON>Leigh Ledare</PERSON> talks about his work now on view at the <ORGANIZATION>Art Institute</ORGANIZATION> ARTIST TALK https t co BQ2gO5oG10 CLOSING OCTOBER 29 The Photographer s Curator presents 200 photographs from across the history of the medium https t co OvqlzKUxvH FRIDAY Andrew Lord talks to the curator about his work at the opening of his new installation Unslumbrous Night https t co gYJUtYelzi DECEMBER 2 3 Join us for a special commissioned performance by evryhshsadr This is not a dream TICKETS https t co vMu3MaYcx3 <PERSON>Jean Louis Forain</PERSON> born OnThisDay in 1852 exhibited with the Impressionists on the recommendation of his friend <PERSON>Edg</PERSON> https t co 1ECUHMeJYv TONIGHT Join us for a conversation on the art of cartooning with artists <PERSON>Chris Ware Daniel Clowes</PERSON> amp amp <PERSON>Anton van Dale</PERSON> https t co hgGa55LCHo THURSDAY Explore the myth and legends of the <LOCATION>Golden Rock of Burma</LOCATION> in a lecture free to IL residents LEARN MORE https t co LM7QBYwmYc MONDAY Explore the art of cartooning with artists <PERSON>Chris Ware Daniel Clowes</PERSON> and <PERSON>Anton van Dalen</PERSON> TICKETS https t co CSXCXFOLbM <PERSON>Ivan Albright</PERSON> s Into the World There Came a Soul Called Ida serves as a haunting reminder of the fleeting nature https t co hN6xFjD13b NOVEMBER 17 Come to After Dark for live performances by twinsmithmusic saddlecreek amp amp <ORGANIZATION>DJ Audio Jack</ORGANIZATION> slomoparty https t co WtgzMWovFU TOMORROW Scholar <PERSON>Daniel Quiles</PERSON> amp amp musician artolindsay discuss cultural cannibalism and modern art in <LOCATION>Brazil</LOCATION> FRE https t co pv6mDRzzPo NOW OPEN Making Memories Quilts as Souvenirs Technically masterful quilts produced between 1840 and 2001 https t co ak1iYR7h4F TONIGHT artolindsay performs songs from his Brazilian inspired album Cuidado Madame with beautypill TICKETS https t co dCwaIzm1Gl SATURDAY Explore the history of Modern art in <LOCATION>Brazil</LOCATION> with scholar <PERSON>Daniel Quiles</PERSON> amp amp musician artolindsay FREE https t co 4litA2894X <PERSON>Charles Cordier</PERSON> born OnThisDay in 1827 depicted his subjects in great detail down to the individual strands of ta https t co V97QDRH0tl MONDAY Explore the art of cartooning with artists <PERSON>Chris Ware Daniel Clowes</PERSON> and <PERSON>Anton van Dalen</PERSON> TICKETS https t co 112gUA2f93 Tomorrow artolindsay performs songs from his latest Brazilian inspired album Cuidado Madame with beautypill https t co Hk3Fm0Q2Ms Artist Tarsila do <PERSON>Amaral</PERSON> poses in her S o Paulo home 1930 See many of these works NowOnView artinstitutechi https t co bxdQaiyruG TONIGHT at 6 00 Explore the life amp amp career of photographer <PERSON>Danny Lyon</PERSON> w his daughter <PERSON>Gabrielle</PERSON> curator <PERSON>Liz Siegel</PERSON> https t co JM03nZjxNG These expressive ceramic vessels are among the most distinctive art objects of ancient <LOCATION>Peru</LOCATION> produced between 100 B https t co YwTt5zQKCg OCTOBER 27 Artist Andrew Lord discusses his practice at the opening of his new installation Unslumbrous Night https t co NsamZDp9w4 StevenJPSS You re in luck <PERSON>Steven Admission</PERSON> is free for <LOCATION>Illinois</LOCATION> residents every Thursday 5 00 8 00 More info h https t co 69PougI2X3 FINAL DAYS Along the Lines Selected Drawings by <PERSON>Saul Steinberg</PERSON> Explore his playful inventive amp amp insightful work https t co XADEGySnLI TOMORROW at 6 00 Explore the life amp amp career of photographer <PERSON>Danny Lyon</PERSON> w his daughter <PERSON>Gabrielle</PERSON> curator <PERSON>Liz Siege</PERSON> https t co aFgNQbPd0t OCTOBER 30 Artist <PERSON>Amy Sillman</PERSON> discusses her diverse body of work and her influential career Free with registration https t co GCvSRQCNI1 OCTOBER 26 Explore the myth and legends of the <LOCATION>Golden Rock of Burma</LOCATION> in a lecture free to IL residents LEARN MORE https t co zpq0z1Zc9x RT danielclowes Catch danielclowes <PERSON>Chris Ware</PERSON> and <PERSON>Anton van Dalen</PERSON> discuss the art of cartooning at artinstitutechi on Oct 23 https NOVEMBER 17 Come to After Dark for live performances by twinsmithmusic saddlecreek amp amp <ORGANIZATION>DJ Audio Jack</ORGANIZATION> slomoparty https t co 3SmJUpktIy THURSDAY at 6 00 Explore the life amp amp career of photographer <PERSON>Danny Lyon</PERSON> w his daughter <PERSON>Gabrielle</PERSON> curator <PERSON>Liz Siege</PERSON> https t co JYHL6m6xNM COMING SOON Revoliutsiia Demonstratsiia Soviet Art Put to the Test The story of revolution 100 years later https t co Rx4gydPCjL DrSpaceCrane HamiltonMusical Hi it s a painting by Thomas Cole You can learn more about the work on our audio to https t co JNreg3oA2J FRIDAY See artolindsay perform songs from his latest Brazilian inspired album Cuidado Madame with beautypill https t co E8lwRvKzdT Our new audio tour explores the past and present of American identity with help from <ORGANIZATION>HamiltonMusical</ORGANIZATION> s <LOCATION>Chicago</LOCATION> cas https t co diZ330URVm NOVEMBER 16 Artist <PERSON>Leigh Ledare</PERSON> explores his ongoing interest in underlying social structures ARTIST TALK https t co e3nttkAj3c MONDAY Explore the art of cartooning with artists <PERSON>Chris Ware Daniel Clowes</PERSON> and <PERSON>Anton van Dalen</PERSON> TICKETS https t co Zn6Evk9B3j OCTOBER 21 Explore the history of Modern art in <LOCATION>Brazil</LOCATION> with scholar <PERSON>Daniel Quiles</PERSON> amp amp musician artolindsay https t co 1QzZDudAH2 RT Suntimes Oh my God Your artinstitutechi is so amazing GoodbyeCRobin star <PERSON>Domhnall Gleeson</PERSON> tells billzwecker https t co <ORGANIZATION>Puqx RT</ORGANIZATION> macfound MacFellow dawoudbey is a photographer creating new spaces of engagement expanding community representation https t co f This outstanding example of <PERSON>Cornelis Saftleven</PERSON> s work belongs to a traditional Dutch genre scenes of hellfire and https t co PH58D2Dmoz FRIDAY See artolindsay perform songs from his latest Brazilian inspired album Cuidado Madame with beautypill https t co ne28qkP82o NOW OPEN City and Country Prints from Early 20th Century <LOCATION>Japan</LOCATION> Idealized visions of urban amp amp rural life in <LOCATION>Japan</LOCATION> https t co WKjVaIoSb4 THURSDAY at 6 00 Explore the life amp amp career of photographer <PERSON>Danny Lyon</PERSON> w his daughter <PERSON>Gabrielle</PERSON> curator <PERSON>Liz Siege</PERSON> https t co G19UYy4BLW Brazilian artist Tarsila do <PERSON>Amaral</PERSON> combines European modernism with the subjects and vivid colors of her homeland https t co E75hSGyHRM RT JoyceCarolOates Packed galleries for old classics on a rainy <LOCATION>Chicago</LOCATION> morning https t co 6a4muTm1iI TONIGHT at 8 30 <LOCATION>Los Angeles</LOCATION> based artist <PERSON>Rodney McMillian</PERSON> performs live sscartcenter Free capacity is limited https t co F0XI182Rkv Squint and you can t miss it Do you see the iconic painting depicted in this LEGO_Group homage https t co UefLIbqpIR NOVEMBER 17 Come to After Dark Live performances by twinsmithmusic saddlecreek amp amp DJ Audio Jack of slomoparty https t co gHLvoxOqJh OCTOBER 21 Explore the history of Modern art in <LOCATION>Brazil</LOCATION> with scholar <PERSON>Daniel Quiles</PERSON> amp amp musician artolindsay https t co AqKpIXDUMr Chicago_Reader reviews experimental pop genius artolindsay s latest record Catch him live on October 20 https t co HSRvHGqnH7 The W flies once again Congratulations to the <ORGANIZATION>Cubs</ORGANIZATION> for an incredible victory last night GoCubsGo FlyTheW https t co O8DvzygGnO OCTOBER 23 Explore the art of cartooning with artists <PERSON>Chris Ware Daniel Clowes</PERSON> and <PERSON>Anton van Dalen</PERSON> LEARN MORE https t co 44Pd79BiqX <PERSON>Charlotte Perriand</PERSON> s rooms brought a pop of color to the <LOCATION>Alps</LOCATION> amp amp offered a wider range of society access to leisure https t co U5LxdWMltu OCTOBER 27 Artist Andrew Lord discusses his practice at the opening of his new installation Unslumbrous Night https t co 5MTD0gY2w8 OCTOBER 14 Artful Play Multicolored Landscapes Make colorful works of art in our workshop for children ages 3 5 https t co kQaaIa0k8S OCTOBER 20 No Wave pioneer artolindsay performs with beautypill Presented w ConstellationCh amp amp ArtInstituteEA https t co 5fL8RYkOJD FINAL DAYS Love Resist Read on Right on <ORGANIZATION>Cauleen Smith Human_3</ORGANIZATION> 0 Reading List closes October 29 https t co q89453zsWa <PERSON>Felix Gonzalez Torres</PERSON> s Untitled Golden creates a threshold of cascading beads ARTicle s Work of the Week https t co IFIsV5lv3x FRIDAY SATURDAY Artist <PERSON>Rodney McMillian</PERSON> performs sscartcenter Free capacity is limited First come first serve https t co as96OAKpgB OCTOBER 21 Join us for a talk on Tarsila and Brazilian Modernism with scholar <PERSON>Daniel Quiles</PERSON> amp amp musician artolindsay https t co 1YQLTdDfxh OCTOBER 14 Artful Play Multicolored Landscapes Make colorful works of art in our workshop for children ages 3 5 https t co NAJRPIIzSG FRIDAY Join us at Intersections our new interactive lecture series as we discuss the question of patriotism INF https t co YYUbaPrH24 WEDNESDAY <PERSON>Elizabeth Price</PERSON> s hypnotic video work comes to the <ORGANIZATION>Modern Wing Join</ORGANIZATION> her Artist Talk free w registratio https t co 9jGHhsHHJt See 7 works by artist <PERSON>Alberto Giacometti</PERSON> born OnThisDay in 1901 NowOnView in the <ORGANIZATION>Modern Wing</ORGANIZATION> https t co dvc8LDPSbC OCTOBER 23 Explore the art of cartooning with artists <PERSON>Chris Ware Daniel Clowes</PERSON> and <PERSON>Anton van Dalen</PERSON> LEARN MORE https t co LAtkSlvJVa OCTOBER 21 Join us for a talk on Tarsila and Brazilian Modernism with scholar <PERSON>Daniel Quiles</PERSON> amp amp musician artolindsay https t co rGcAAYa1ZU OCTOBER 14 Artful Play Multicolored Landscapes Make colorful works of art in our workshop for children ages 3 5 https t co EfKemvUrXY OCTOBER 20 No Wave pioneer artolindsay performs with beautypill Presented w ConstellationCh amp amp ArtInstituteEA https t co XtVcoX26Dq OCTOBER 13 14 Artist <PERSON>Rodney McMillian</PERSON> performs sscartcenter Free capacity is limited First come first served https t co aj8xDiGrsF NOW OPEN Inventing Modern Art in <LOCATION>Brazil</LOCATION> Explore Tarsila s enduring impact on modern and contemporary art https t co pEuh2pGWp0 WEDNESDAY British artist <PERSON>Elizabeth Price</PERSON> joins us to discuss her work in video Free with registration https t co tgYaeGddcF TOMORROW at 12 00 Contemporary dancer <PERSON>Ayako Kato</PERSON> and musician <PERSON>James Becker</PERSON> perform together in <LOCATION>Ando Gallery</LOCATION> INFO https t co 9svk57B5GJ NOW ON VIEW For Shakers work was a form of worship amp amp the objects they made were an attempt to create heaven on eart https t co XgHENJjiEh OCTOBER 14 Artful Play Multicolored Landscapes Make colorful works of art in our workshop for children ages 3 5 https t co LQ2WmkRjUO Like other Surrealists of the period <PERSON>Victor Brauner</PERSON> drew inspiration from dreams the unconscious mysticism amp amp myt https t co oj0cab8XeO OCTOBER 20 artolindsay has explored the intersection of music amp amp art for more than four decades See him in concert https t co Uhej24NDQP NOW ON VIEW Explore over a century of groundbreaking work in our new architecture and design galleries LEARN MORE https t co ot38qBSM0U OCTOBER 21 Join us for a talk on Tarsila and Brazilian Modernism with scholar <PERSON>Daniel Quiles</PERSON> amp amp musician artolindsay https t co Rulf8CmlMh VIDEO A good set of armor often stood between life and death for gallant knights of old via novapbs https t co 0njCS9tkfN The women in this Roman relief would have looked exotic even old fashioned and may represent cult attendants from https t co DXeqGtqvOT OCTOBER 23 A conversation on cartooning with <PERSON>Chris Ware Daniel Clowes Anton van Dalen</PERSON> and <PERSON>Hillary Chute</PERSON> TICKET https t co Ig0pFpv0nt BobEckstein Hi <PERSON>Bob</PERSON> would you be available to chat via DM Thanks A snowman expert NewYorker pays a visit to the <ORGANIZATION>Art Institute</ORGANIZATION> s <PERSON>Fischli Weiss</PERSON> installation closing October 15 https t co ETwNlZsyNX OCTOBER 27 Artist Andrew Lord discusses his practice at the opening of his new installation Unslumbrous Night https t co mx3Q4VbzHl OCTOBER 13 Join us for Intersections a new interactive lecture series as we discuss the question of patriotism https t co PhUGc68yDI Leigh Ledare The Plot uses an experiential group psychology method to call attention to underlying power relation https t co ap386hyFkC ARTicle s Work of the Week In the 19th century American artists flocked to <LOCATION>Europe</LOCATION> for its picturesque subject matte https t co UWzkVwpyaw OCTOBER 14 Artful Play Multicolored Landscapes Make colorful works of art in our workshop for children ages 3 5 https t co h2kFMB9qpf <PERSON>Frederic Remington</PERSON> born OnThisDay helped shape amp amp reinforce myths of the Old West at a time when the open range was https t co 8DLMPPZymx OCTOBER 21 Join us for a talk on <LOCATION>Brazil</LOCATION> s <PERSON>Antropofag</PERSON> a movement with scholar <PERSON>Daniel Quiles</PERSON> amp amp musician artolindsay https t co VKuu7RGkDZ OCTOBER 20 No Wave pioneer artolindsay performs with beautypill Presented w ConstellationCh amp amp ArtInstituteEA https t co eMxtQvIqS1 While <PERSON>Pollock</PERSON> made his mark in <LOCATION>America Gutai</LOCATION> introduced gestural abstraction to postwar <LOCATION>Japan</LOCATION> From ARTicle https t co ucTbmz8ZQW OCTOBER 12 <ORGANIZATION>Cauleen Smith</ORGANIZATION> solarflareark and <PERSON>Greg Tate StalkinHeads</PERSON> lead a multimedia listening party REGISTE https t co 07kbacSXDt It s not a matter of painting life It s a matter of giving life to painting <PERSON>Pierre Bonnard</PERSON> born OnThisDay https t co LZRrscOd4z RT voxdotcom How American Gothic became an icon https t co mEbMQLiK0O OCTOBER 14 Explore the colorful art of Tarsila then make your own paintings in our workshop for children ages 3 5 https t co SWEBTPRCDE Some fragment of a dream that is how writer <PERSON>Truman Capote</PERSON> himself a collector of paperweights described these b https t co 1m6Ey5doWI OCTOBER 27 Artist Andrew Lord discusses his artistic practice at the site of his installation Unslumbrous Night https t co WSbNkUpl4W In City <PERSON>Ed Ruscha</PERSON> draws on his early experiences as a sign painter to create visual amp amp conceptual tension between https t co TmD5u02Fzj OCTOBER 23 Cartoonists <PERSON>Chris Ware</PERSON> and <PERSON>Daniel Clowes</PERSON> artist <PERSON>Anton van Dalen</PERSON> amp amp scholar <PERSON>Hillary Chute</PERSON> in conversation https t co tBU1bbK2jD CLOSING SUNDAY By the Light of the Moon Nocturnal Japanese Prints Depictions of night in all its various moods https t co d9L1M7rQtO OCTOBER 21 Explore <LOCATION>Brazil</LOCATION> s <PERSON>Antropofag</PERSON> a movement w scholar <PERSON>Daniel Quiles</PERSON> amp amp musician artist artolindsay INFO https t co jp8x7V5Jj0 OCTOBER 12 Artist <PERSON>Cauleen Smith</PERSON> amp amp writer musician <PERSON>Greg Tate</PERSON> lead a multimedia listening party Free to IL resident https t co 5RsIC5EbUA OCTOBER 19 Photographer filmmaker amp amp writer <PERSON>Danny Lyon</PERSON> bleakbeautyblog discusses his work with us ARTIST TALK https t co M5SEcHBYSp Playful masks from <PERSON>Saul Steinberg</PERSON> s collaboration with photographer <PERSON>Inge Morath NowOnView</PERSON> in Along the Lines https t co 9rqIzv6plE OCTOBER 23 Cartoonists <PERSON>Chris Ware</PERSON> and <PERSON>Daniel Clowes</PERSON> artist <PERSON>Anton van Dalen</PERSON> amp amp scholar <PERSON>Hillary Chute</PERSON> in conversation https t co KYffPUeavO salgal017 I m afraid so <PERSON>Sally McCo