<ner>RT DeadlineDetroit DetroitLooksLikeThis during Louder Than a Bomb LTAB313 this weekend s <LOCATION>Michigan</LOCATION> Youth Poetry Festival at waynesta RT SalvadorSalort Thanks to DIADetroit s Friends of Asian Arts and Culture for presenting an unforgettable afternoon honoring the arts o Why do experts consider the HonusWagner card the Mona Lisa of baseball cards <PERSON>Wagner</PERSON> was a famed athlete The ca https t co 593gntJkUZ Views today DIAeveryday https t co uBBNIltJf8 TekJansen SalvadorSalort We gave away tickets to the first 200 people who attended our group photo today Tickets https t co WIfQ7EHIRg RT SalvadorSalort The first 200 aliens humanoids and droids received free exhibition tickets Visit https t co yJkzPDbUKy to reserve y MayTheFourth be with you Over 200 Star Wars fans invaded the DIA galaxy to take a galactic sized photo in celebra https t co hsc5WOaDPZ We re grateful for dedicated sitesExhibits and <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> staff who are working hard to deliver an exceptional Star Wars https t co UpcZ14wp5k Happy StarWarsDay See you tonight MayTheFourth https t co bGFm5TkHwD StarWarsatDIA https t co rQwTD1GhW3 RT sitesExhibits Happy StarWarsDay We are exactly 2 weekends out from StarWarsCostumes making it s final stop on the years long tour RT qlinedetroit The DIADetroit invites <LOCATION>Detroit</LOCATION> s biggest StarWars fans to dress up as their favorite character for a group photo at <ORGANIZATION>6pm RT</ORGANIZATION> CultureSource On view through June Making Home DIADetroit https t co oUaLb9dTG6 https t co QEAVgSZrYH DIAmembers see it first Use your complimentary exhibition tickets to see Star Wars and the <ORGANIZATION>Power of Costume Ma</ORGANIZATION> https t co 4bt4qLsteQ The Force is strong Spring is finally here StarWarsatDIA StarWarsCostumes <LOCATION>Detroit</LOCATION> magnolias https t co bLAfjMOuDJ RT SalvadorSalort DIADetroit is more than a museum it s a community anchor and an engine for the creative economy Join us in celebrati Celebrate the vital role art museums play in their communities on ArtMuseumDay May 18 The <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> will offer free ad https t co 0Ce7TqIlB6 RT skillmanfound <PERSON>Don</PERSON> t miss your chance to see artwork from Detroitk12 students on display at the DIADetroit The <ORGANIZATION>81st Detroit Public S RT</ORGANIZATION> CantonLibrary Have you been by the library yet to see our awesome DIADetroit InsideOut installation yet Come over and see it DIAD RT SalvadorSalort May is MemberAppreciationMonth I m deeply grateful for DIADetroit s 22 000 members and their longtime continued su On May 10 DIAmembers get a first look at our shop s new spring merchandise and gift selections Learn more and re https t co <ORGANIZATION>yVvOw7WlAi Cass Technical High School</ORGANIZATION> student <PERSON>Kaleigh Blevins</PERSON> discusses her artistic process You can see <PERSON>Kaleigh</PERSON> s work and t https t co kIwlv8jtXd RT WWJ950 The <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> s offering a photo op for Star Wars fans https t co AjmsytjyCc DIADetroit RT SalvadorSalort Onthisday in 1924 the cornerstone was laid for 5200 Woodward Ave which marked the commencement of the building of RT SalvadorSalort DIADetroit s <ORGANIZATION>Teen Council</ORGANIZATION> invited their peers to explore Making Home Contemporary Works from the <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> last night I Look up today DIAeveryday https t co rqVcVJEvJl Every weekend the <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> transforms into the <ORGANIZATION>Detroit Institute</ORGANIZATION> of Awesome The museum offers programs just for kids https t co 0Yo031EkY1 The May 3 panel discussion will feature Making Home Contemporary Works from the <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> exhibition artists <PERSON>Tyree Guy</PERSON> https t co q816ffN8Nt RT After5Detroit Get ready StarWars fans Next Friday the DIADetroit is taking a group photo to celebrate MayThe4th BONUS the first RT SalvadorSalort The celebration of Asian arts and culture continues this fall with the opening of DIADetroit s galleries dedicated to Join the <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> s Friends of Asian Arts and Culture in celebrating <ORGANIZATION>Asian Pacific American Heritage Month</ORGANIZATION> with a blend https t co Twp1olDQ9S RT MidtownDetroit Check out one of the coolest poetry festivals around Louder Than A Bomb May 5 6 in MidtownDetroit Supported by <ORGANIZATION>Ins RT</ORGANIZATION> AlliedIMDetroit The <ORGANIZATION>Detroit Film Theatre</ORGANIZATION> at the DIADetroit will be hosting that 50th Michigan Student Film Festival this weekend htt RT Local4News Star Wars costume exhibit coming to DIADetroit What to know https t co PB79KDLLxc Check out this tigers video about PlayBallDIA Admission is free for residents of <LOCATION>Wayne Oakland</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Macomb</LOCATION> count https t co gDei3QrMJ3 Join us dressed as your favorite StarWars character for a galactic sized photo to celebrate StarWarsDay on May 4 https t co jGwZD16N9v RT Freep_Film_Fest Some beautiful photos from the <LOCATION>Detroit</LOCATION> premiere of IAMEVIDENCEmov at <ORGANIZATION>DIADetroit Including Mariska Hargitay PAKy RT</ORGANIZATION> SalvadorSalort In 2017 DIADetroit exceeded its MacombCounty school program goal by nearly 2 000 students and its attendance target b RT LittleGuideDet We FREE Kids are expensive but doing fun things with them doesn t always have to be https t co HFWAkO366i htt Earlier this month the <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> and MidtownDetroit announced a design competition to transform the museum s exterior g https t co yvfe83TJ2d Detroitk12 student artwork is on view at the DIA for the 81st annual <ORGANIZATION>Detroit Public Schools Community District S</ORGANIZATION> https t co FB3IxurIgN RT HeidelbergProj The DIADetroit s Inside Out program is underway The power of art is helping to foster conversations and understanding Master floral designer <PERSON>Per Benjamin</PERSON> wowed us with his artistry today at the 2018 <ORGANIZATION>Elizabeth Sites Kuhlman</ORGANIZATION> Lecture C https t co QEuTpFaLdl RT SalvadorSalort Today I met with waynecountymi to discuss DIADetroit s 2017 year end review and highlight upcoming events related to DiegoRivera s <ORGANIZATION>Detroit Industry</ORGANIZATION> fresco cycle reminds us of the fragile relationship between humans and the earth https t co 4I88Uf7sxD RT CityOfWestland Did you know that <ORGANIZATION>Westland</ORGANIZATION> residents receive FREE general admission to the DIADetroit every day all year round Fr DIAInsideOut 2018 has officially begun knightfdn https t co zU8jd3fzRY RT TheWrightMuseum Tomorrow marks 2 years since <PERSON>Prince</PERSON> left this world for the afterlife Come check out this photo of him in <LOCATION>Detroit</LOCATION> cir RT SalvadorSalort Happy birthday to <PERSON>CarrieMaeWeems</PERSON> who was born onthisday in 1953 See Weems work in DIADetroit s Making Home Cont Wow According to the <ORGANIZATION>Independent Sector Organization</ORGANIZATION> the service hours DIAvolunteers contributed last fiscal yea https t co qofrOBZZRg DIA Director <PERSON>SalvadorSalort Pons</PERSON> board chairman <PERSON>Gene Gargaro</PERSON> and board member <PERSON>Tak Omitsu</PERSON> are featured on the late https t co vWIgzkZol8 Don t miss a panel discussion featuring DIA contemporary curator <PERSON>TaylorRAldridge</PERSON> tomorrow ummamuseum https t co ZEcLAnHd3a Today s break in the weather reminds us of <PERSON>Odilon Redon</PERSON> s Evocation of Butterflies See it on view in the <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> s m https t co T95FcXvDi9 RT CultureSource Remember if you re a resident of <PERSON>Wayne Oakland</PERSON> or <LOCATION>Macomb</LOCATION> counties your trip to DIADetroit is free https t co sBP You can view the complete 2017 Community Engagement Reports for each county at https t co 1rM4qqEjeA under Year https t co CmzREaacGM RT NylonMag Our guide to <LOCATION>Detroit</LOCATION> will tell you all you need to know about the <LOCATION>Motor City</LOCATION> https t co fwRG2p4H9K https t co FFRjbjgRP4 RT MidwestLiving Top things to do in <ORGANIZATION>VisitDetroit Tigers</ORGANIZATION> games ComericaPark priceless installations DIADetroit tours by puredetr <PERSON>Don</PERSON> t miss DIAInsideOut in <LOCATION>Palmer Park</LOCATION> this spring <LOCATION>Detroit</LOCATION> knightfdn https t co YFk2Liw8Oc Check out DIAInsideOut in CityofOakPark this Spring https t co qOyESTnuaR Installation of the spring 2018 DIAInsideOut season has begun Stay tuned for maps and a complete list of particip https t co ty8PFZ7d3h RT SalvadorSalort Today we remember the legacy of <PERSON>BarkleyHendricks</PERSON> who was born on this day 73 years ago He was an artist ahead of his Get ready for Star Wars and the <ORGANIZATION>Power of Costume</ORGANIZATION> at the DIA StarWarsatDIA StarWarsCostumes https t co snJPoMEzLG We re glad you enjoyed your trip https t co f6htm4w3rp HappilyH Thanks for your review RT NEHgov Today <ORGANIZATION>NEH</ORGANIZATION> s <PERSON>JonPeede</PERSON> met with representatives from <ORGANIZATION>NEH</ORGANIZATION> funded DIADetroit toured the TheWrightMuseum and a sat down for a 22 seasons 3007 hits 399 home runs <PERSON>Al Kaline</PERSON> is a <LOCATION>Detroit</LOCATION> tigers legend Explore objects from his remarkable c https t co xau2n4qFQa RT SalvadorSalort Year after year I am so impressed by the incredible talent of the Detroitk12 students whose work is on view DIADetro RT SalvadorSalort Thanks to my friends at the <LOCATION>Village Club of Bloomfield Hills</LOCATION> for hosting last night s Director s Cut talk It s always RT wdet DIADetroit Becomes 1920 s <LOCATION>Hollywood</LOCATION> for Film Festival Gala amp gt amp gt https t co vNBqI7GAQk https t co P7rplPDTbP TONIGHT MC5 guitarist <PERSON>Wayne Kramer</PERSON> leads a band of all star <LOCATION>Detroit</LOCATION> musicians including <PERSON>Dennis Coffey Robert Bra</PERSON> https t co yy0BICvCPB RT Freep_Film_Fest <ORGANIZATION>Metro Detroit Oscar</ORGANIZATION> winner <PERSON>Sue Marx</PERSON> left brought her hardware to the DIADetroit for tonight s screening of her film RT SalvadorSalort In March more than 2 300 MacombCounty students visited DIADetroit on free field trips Happy learning WeAreOneMac RT SalvadorSalort In March DIADetroit welcomed over 3 000 <ORGANIZATION>OaklandCounty</ORGANIZATION> students on free field trips OakGov OaklandSchools RT SalvadorSalort Last month DIADetroit welcomed nearly 4 000 WayneCounty students on free field trips waynecountymi CountyExecEvans Another Freep_Film_Fest highlight https t co SldjebT7L6 Join us for a panel discussion featuring Making Home Contemporary Works from the <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> exhibition artists <PERSON>Jane Ham</PERSON> https t co hk3uyhDKfk Happy NationalPetDay DiegoRivera Image <PERSON>Diego Rivera</PERSON> with Dog <PERSON>Bernard G Silberstein</PERSON> ca 1940 gelatin silv https t co lrmtpPJxsk Freep_Film_Fest https t co NNl8dClqCS The 2018 Freep_Film_Fest gets underway tonight Though The Russian Five premiere is sold out you can see it at https t co 41fpiAKCeI The Jam Handy made thousands of advertising industrial and training films in their <LOCATION>Detroit</LOCATION> studio throughout the https t co OV7SMWOoIy johnnyotto We re glad that our collection left such an impression on you TriLamJae You ll notice something unusual installed near <LOCATION>Prentis Court The DIA</LOCATION> is hosting the winning model for https t co oVWXk84bfj Celebrate NationalPoetryMonth with a workshop and readings by <PERSON>Alise Alousi</PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION>InsideOutDET Sakila Islam</ORGANIZATION> and Duny https t co 4F1ALoxcqv RT DetroitSpartans DetroitSpartans grab your tickets for Saturday at the DIADetroit and Sunday at EmagineTheatres https t co IkCmNE This Saturday join us in celebrating the decade that brought us documentaries speakeasies and prohibition during https t co YdPa7cpdY6 GeekDad248 Great photos We re glad you enjoyed your visit together GeekDad248 RT GeekDad248 We had an exceptional experience with an enthusiastic docent who shared with my daughter a number of secrets about the reno GeekDad248 PetrickSara They can touch Arty the Donkey in Prentis Court 2018 marks the 50th anniversary of the <LOCATION>Detroit</LOCATION> tigers 1968 World Series Championship Visit Play Ball Baseball https t co IGP0F6WjfC The 81st annual <ORGANIZATION>Detroit Public Schools Community District Student Exhibition</ORGANIZATION> opens in one week See 500 works by https t co 50WBFGpg0Y We re extremely grateful for our hardworking security team https t co XZ6yZY9vAl Don t miss performances of ManualCinema s The <LOCATION>Magic City</LOCATION> this weekend at the <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> https t co cGewWjLzIt Internationally renowned floral designer <PERSON>Per Benjamin</PERSON> has been honored to create his arrangements for the past thre https t co 6P5HkwI2dK RT qlinedetroit This is one of the most exciting developments in <LOCATION>Detroit</LOCATION> DIADetroit aims to increase public engagement on the grounds The DIA s <ORGANIZATION>Detroit Film Theatre</ORGANIZATION> presents <PERSON>Philippe Van Leeuw</PERSON> s harrowing drama In <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> April 20 22 Learn more and https t co x4dFhfBBkF RT techtowndetroit We know there s some <LOCATION>Detroit</LOCATION> Star Wars fans who are counting down the days until this DIADetroit exhibit opens http Star Wars and the <ORGANIZATION>Power of Costume</ORGANIZATION> opens May 20 at the DIA StarWarsatDIA StarWarsCostumes https t co WsDBE5PYCX Look who stopped by the <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> today RoamingGnome VisitDetroit ItsGOtime DetroitItsGOtime VanGogh https t co hiakcuFnEd AllenWDillard RT SalvadorSalort Latinos have deep roots in <LOCATION>Detroit</LOCATION> its history and its success In my April Director s Letter I highlight <PERSON>LouisAgui Don</PERSON> t miss the Italian Film Festival which kicks off tonight in the DIA s Detroit Film Theatre Admission is free https t co VyB1kXJyAY MLK50 https t co nYpGqZ9PGO earth2_mike Unfortunately you won t be able to try on the costumes but you ll be able to get an up close look V https t co JfHSzW4Hbp SGLabDetroit MidtownDetroit Thanks for the shout out Today the <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> announced with MidtownDetroit a design competition to transform the museum s exterior grounds into a https t co UqhWHJKDLC Legendary MC5 guitarist <PERSON>Wayne Kramer</PERSON> leads a band of all star <LOCATION>Detroit</LOCATION> musicians including <PERSON>Dennis Coffey Robert</PERSON> B https t co Ol7dvTlRZJ RT sitesExhibits Last show this is Do not miss the final opportunity to see StarWarsCostumes in the last stop on this nationwide tour Join us for the the 2018 Dr <PERSON>Coleman</PERSON> <LOCATION>Mopper Memorial</LOCATION> lecture Guido Reni The Success and Failure of the Italian R https t co OGfk1IBYGV RT SalvadorSalort Stop by to explore and learn about the creative contributions of these rich diverse cultures Admission is free for re April is ArabAmericanHeritageMonth Visit our galleries dedicated to arts of the ancient <LOCATION>Middle East</LOCATION> ancient Egyp https t co Gk5SJFSUwi PlayBallDIA https t co QKIT6dGxLV We highly encourage visitors to purchase tickets to Star Wars and the Power of Costume ahead of time https t co EKobCus5NY RT SalvadorSalort Our young visitors <PERSON>Dario Escobar</PERSON> new artwork Urban Landscape for PlayBallDIA DIADetroit The Arts amp amp Sports come to RT Freep_Film_Fest The legendary waynekramer is coming to DIADetroit s Detroit Film Theatre April 13 during FreepFilmFest Enter for a <LOCATION>Detroit</LOCATION> battle rapper <PERSON>Marv Won</PERSON> has a moment with <PERSON>Vincent van Gogh</PERSON> s Self Portrait VincentvanGogh VanGogh https t co yI3xAPkxtr While in <LOCATION>Paris</LOCATION> between 1886 and 1888 <PERSON>Van Gogh</PERSON> lightened his palette under the influence of the Impressionists He https t co y3St7nIStd RT MidwestLiving Our guide to 36 hours in VisitDetroit PureMichigan https t co VWROvfK5gz DIADetroit EasternMarket https t co Io maiainmi RT crainsdetroit No rain delay at the <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> today it reported a huge bump in attendance as it opened the Play Ball Baseball at the DIA WomensHistoryMonth is not over yet Can you name 5womenartists Be sure to add <PERSON>Rachel Ruysch</PERSON> to your list Image https t co 0mVdbg1DDw RT beckjason For fans already downtown with no game to watch the Play Ball exhibit of rare baseball cards and memorabilia is on displ CityofDetroit Thanks for the shout out RT CityofDetroit Just because OpeningDay has been postponed doesn t mean you can t still celebrate the beginning of baseball season Che RT leedevito Attn DetroitTigers fans since OpeningDay got rained out you should head over to the DIADetroit to check out the museum CUofM juliehinds freep Our beer is way less than 10 juliehinds freep Admission to Play Ball is free for residents of <LOCATION>Wayne Oakland</LOCATION> and Macomb The DIA is open until 4 p m today RT SalvadorSalort PlayBallDIA is now open In the spirit of the Ancient Greek Olympic Games DIADetroit will be a venue to celebrate th RT juliehinds If you re in <LOCATION>Detroit</LOCATION> for rained out <ORGANIZATION>Tigers</ORGANIZATION> opening day this DIADetroit baseball exhibit is a seriously fun alternative There s no rain delay at the <LOCATION>DIA Play Ball Baseball</LOCATION> at the <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> is now open Join us in celebrating <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> s pa https t co MPAlvfGD2P RT SalvadorSalort A fantastic evening celebrating the opening of Play Ball Baseball at the DIA Thanks to E <PERSON>Powell Miller</PERSON> for sharing RT HKRocafeller Student Art All of this BlackGirlMagic is courtesy of our Detroitk12 student artists Can t wait to visit DIADetroit We re proud to display <PERSON>Kimberly</PERSON> s work along with that of other DPSCD students in the 81st annual <ORGANIZATION>Detroit Public</ORGANIZATION> https t co GNQMokjnpB RT ynhnx there are 767 students at the detroit institute of art today they are visiting for free and the museum reimburses their transp Play Ball Baseball at the DIA is free for residents of <LOCATION>Wayne Oakland</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Macomb</LOCATION> counties Catch this home run e https t co VnI7VCeCeb RT SGLabDetroit While the Science of Grief team catch after their allnighter we ve got a huge thank you to all community partners per In partnership with SGLabDetroit the <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> presents The Science of Grief a 14 hour community conversation and perf https t co XofNofVG8p RT SalvadorSalort Heading to the The <ORGANIZATION>Village Club</ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION>Bloomfield Hills</LOCATION> for my next Director s Cut talk on April 12 at 7 p m It s free an The DIA showcases hundreds of imaginative works created by <ORGANIZATION>Detroit Public Schools Community District</ORGANIZATION> students in th https t co Sd15Ps2IBh You don t want to miss these performances Free for <PERSON>Wayne Oakland</PERSON> and <LOCATION>Macomb County</LOCATION> residents https t co ZyTqYFj3HP RT SGLabDetroit The Science of Grief is tonight at the Detroit Film Theatre DIADetroit For info and updates about this powerful space The 81st annual <ORGANIZATION>Detroit Public Schools Community District Student Exhibition</ORGANIZATION> opens April 14 Admission is free for https t co z3lwCoQM7J zeeinthedee ArabAmericanMus Unfortunately our screenings of In Between took place between March 16 and 18 You https t co os6u9PwfSC RT macombdaily DIADetroit exhibit Star Wars and the Power of the Costume offers fans a unique perspective https t co 2XIUthrx03 htt RT CityofDetroit Love Star Wars DIADetroit is hosting a traveling exhibition of costumes from the popular film series starting May 20 There are a few days left to submit your DIA volunteer application We re seeking Gallery Service Gallery Informat https t co dsLlz3qVER StarWarsatDIA StarWarsCostumes https t co FMVPJkmDjb Join us https t co xxCVYIR1I9 metrotimes sat down with award winning poet <PERSON>Tmillerpoetry</PERSON> who will host The Science of Grief a 14 hour communi https t co J7qWoXuMsG MrsGowersArtist Come see us again soon ccainlms LarsonMS tsdthinkers Thanks for learning with us PontiacArts Great find <ORGANIZATION>RT Local4News Detroit Institute of Arts</ORGANIZATION> to host traveling Star Wars costume exhibit https t co Aodo9DiB49 DIADetroit CityofDetroit Thanks Happy birthday to us https t co C60HQySB7I TONIGHT RackhamChoir performs <PERSON>Richard Einhorn</PERSON> s <ORGANIZATION>Voices of Light</ORGANIZATION> accompanying a screening <PERSON>Carl Th Dreyer</PERSON> s fil https t co ZL6lC2MIFt Don t miss WayneKramer and The Kollaborators TrioReenactment funk4ever DennisCoffeyDET April 13 at the <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> s https t co 3pbtlilQSG JaneHammond is an American artist who creates paintings photographs and mixed media works often based on literatu https t co eqS85FiZLP RT Freep_Film_Fest We just told Chance the Rapper the dog that waynekramer is performing April 13 at DIADetroit s Detroit Film Theatr This year and next you can see DIA exhibitions throughout the state We re organizing two statewide exhibitions of https t co PrhlCOJKSL detroitnews writer LouisAguilar_DN shares his family connection to <PERSON>Diego Rivera</PERSON> s <ORGANIZATION>Detroit Industry</ORGANIZATION> murals whi https t co uL97eAZ9z3 The exhibition coincides with the <ORGANIZATION>Detroit Tigers</ORGANIZATION> 1968 World series championship 50th anniversary It features DIA https t co jFT2FJPs3U RackhamChoir performs <PERSON>Richard Einhorn</PERSON> s <ORGANIZATION>Voices of Light</ORGANIZATION> accompanying a screening <PERSON>Carl Th Dreyer</PERSON> s film The P https t co BTbcoNLObf RT modeld Attn Star Wars fans DIADetroit https t co N6E1iF6I9D RT SalvadorSalort It was my great pleasure to talk to ChicagoBooth students to discuss my tenure DIADetroit and our place in the City o Can t wait to see C 3PO at the <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> beginning May 20 StarWarsatDIA StarWarsCostumes spring https t co S3RnzimyMK Happy spring equinox If you ve visited the <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> s Japanese art galleries recently you ll notice that the tokonoma https t co oBQh9gkq7H Don t miss the Freep_Film_Fest Roaring Twenties Gala which benefits the <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION>Detroit Film Theatre</ORGANIZATION> on Apri https t co 9rVCY9uEsH RT crainsdetroit Tickets for new Star Wars exhibit at the DIADetroit go on sale April 1 https t co UoH2z3ZEnj ViaVisuals We re glad to know that the <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> has had such an impact on your education Thank you for your support RT 1043WOMC The force is strong at the <ORGANIZATION>Detroit Institute of Arts</ORGANIZATION> https t co cFffFz7ioZ Empowered today DIAeveryday DIA347 https t co vAgbeQmlYJ RT SalvadorSalort Enjoyed speaking with members of the <ORGANIZATION>Plymouth Noon Rotary Club</ORGANIZATION> last night Thanks for hosting my Director s Cut talk S <PERSON>Don</PERSON> t miss In <LOCATION>Between Bar Bahar</LOCATION> at our <ORGANIZATION>Detroit Film Theatre</ORGANIZATION> this weeknd In her debut director <PERSON>Maysaloun Hamoud</PERSON> https t co w3HfRdL2JN Painter and art educator AlmaThomas is best known for her mosaic like abstracts which she referred to as <ORGANIZATION>Alma</ORGANIZATION> s https t co DVaw7hexdh DetroitLove https t co g6Q6MWmtTh RT soundbureau313 Our 2 Year anniversary party is coming up on March 30th at DIADetroit with a special performance from matthewdear RT SalvadorSalort Thanks to SouthfieldPL for hosting my Director s Cut talk last night It s always a pleasure to be with you In partnership with SGLabDetroit the <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> presents The Science of Grief a 14 hour community conversation and pe https t co GXoeolKW1C RT techtowndetroit We know there s some <LOCATION>Detroit</LOCATION> Star Wars fans who are counting down the days until this DIADetroit exhibit opens http RT SalvadorSalort DIADetroit members can now reserve their complimentary tickets to our highly anticipated exhibition Star Wars and th RT After5Detroit If you re in town for the tourney here are the Top 10 Things to do in <LOCATION>Detroit</LOCATION> MarchMadness PureMichigan https t co Join us in celebrating the power of cinema at the FreepFilmFest Gala April 14 https t co nMJWp5OvUV Using overhead projectors paper shadow puppets actors on camera and live music Manual Cinema weaves a perfectly https t co KpTnJZMeFv RT SalvadorSalort Thanks to <PERSON>Wayne Oakland</PERSON> and <LOCATION>Macomb</LOCATION> for your millage support For <PERSON>Wayne</PERSON> alone in the past 5 years 739 000 residents r RT SalvadorSalort We re honored to host the 2018 State of the County address DIADetroit This is an exciting time for the <ORGANIZATION>CityofDetroit RT</ORGANIZATION> CountyExecEvans Excited to be at the DIADetroit to discuss the progress we ve made in <LOCATION>Wayne County</LOCATION> and talk about the challenges ahea Check out the 2018 FreepFilmFest lineup The DIA s <ORGANIZATION>Detroit Film Theatre</ORGANIZATION> is one of the host venues See the films A https t co hZdWK031uC You can stream the 2018 State of the County Address happening tonight at the DIA s <ORGANIZATION>Detroit Film Theatre</ORGANIZATION> at https t co csxfZoPy8w Happy 313Day DYK The <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> owns a number of public artworks installed around <LOCATION>Detroit</LOCATION> including Monument to <PERSON>Joe</PERSON> https t co UBT7TOmX5u RT SalvadorSalort I m celebrating my pride for <ORGANIZATION>Detroit</ORGANIZATION> artists like <PERSON>Mario Moore Gilda Snowden Charles McGee Marshall Fredericks Bill Detroit</PERSON> is one of this year s <ORGANIZATION>NCAA</ORGANIZATION> Men s Basketball Tournament host cities and CNNTravel lists the DIA on its https t co 87M1tj2tnH Shop for a good cause <ORGANIZATION>Amazon</ORGANIZATION> is tripling the donation rate on your first https t co OVBa5lqIgG purchase now thr https t co <ORGANIZATION>WRSdf1iArN RT</ORGANIZATION> SalvadorSalort DIADetroit hosted nearly 1 500 MacombCounty students on free field trips in February We hope you enjoyed your visit RT SalvadorSalort Last month DIADetroit welcomed nearly 2 000 <ORGANIZATION>OaklandCounty</ORGANIZATION> students on free field trips Come see us again soon O RT SalvadorSalort In February more than 4 100 <ORGANIZATION>WayneCounty</ORGANIZATION> students visited DIADetroit on free field trips Thanks for learning with us artsydoyle blackriverrats See you again soon The 2018 Freep_Film_Fest lineup will be announced tomorrow Stay tuned FreepFilmFest https t co BZV9LMKZsc Thanks for visiting https t co eHhAYFAsoP The DIA s newest exhibition Play Ball Baseball at the <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> opens just in time for OpeningDay Beginning March 2 https t co RAyjAK1RIs RT GraffonMusic Lots to do in the <LOCATION>Detroit</LOCATION> metro this weekend Check it out in today s TheOaklandPress Go amp amp Do section DetroitSymphon Celebrate the legacy of FridaKahlo and other influential women artists in the DIA Shop You can find a variety of https t co FURPCvZXZ9 We re open until 10 p m on Friday nights In addition to live music we offer guided tours drawing in the galleri https t co YFChgy5cH6 RT DeadlineDetroit DetroitLooksLikeThis Detroitk12 4th graders at the <ORGANIZATION>Fisher Music Center</ORGANIZATION> on Wed for a DetroitSymphony Educational C Channeling ElizabethCatlett s Women of <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> in honor of InternationalWomensDay 5WomenArtists https t co WmYnHqkuu1 RT DetroitSymphony Today we welcomed <ORGANIZATION>Detroit Public Schools Community District</ORGANIZATION> fourth graders to our Educational Concert Series program IAMJustLetitia Great idea Have you heard the news Star Wars and the <ORGANIZATION>Power of Costume</ORGANIZATION> is coming to the <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> May 20 https t co GDR4CgIb6N https t co DjZEeR8hd0 mickalenethomas Something You Can Feel is a favorite among staff and visitors alike at the <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> because of the https t co 7hMxD2Ax2f RT SGLabDetroit Listen and share at The Science of Grief an all night community conversation Hosted by Tmillerpoetry in partnership wi In partnership with SGLabDetroit the <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> presents The Science of Grief a 14 hour community conversation and pe https t co n11iILNuq7 In a rare special event RackhamChoir will perform <PERSON>Richard Einhorn</PERSON> s Voices of Light accompanying a screening https t co YGghiwcUFL theblklovechild Thank you for the glowing review We hope to see you again soon RT MIChronicle <ORGANIZATION>Detroit Institute of Arts Popular Inside Out</ORGANIZATION> program Returns For Its Ninth Year https t co kkh0z41acg goldishfreckles Thanks for the shout out RT WWJ950 The DIADetroit is again installing dozens of artwork reproductions outside in the metro area this summer DIAInsideOut https On March 10 the <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> s <ORGANIZATION>Detroit Film Theatre</ORGANIZATION> presents Rabbit in the Moon the next installment in our Making Home https t co OtzcyR6w39 RT SalvadorSalort In Ancient <LOCATION>Greece</LOCATION> the Olympic games set the stage for the creativity of athletes amp amp artists DIADetroit s upcoming exh Interested in volunteering at the DIA The museum is currently seeking <ORGANIZATION>Gallery Service Gallery Information</ORGANIZATION> and Det https t co ZVGSMGSclA RT SalvadorSalort Excited for my next Director s Cut talk at the <ORGANIZATION>Plymouth Noon Rotary Club</ORGANIZATION> March 16 One of many talks in <LOCATION>Wayne Oakland</LOCATION> RT Freep_Film_Fest One of our fave directors StanleyNelson1 will be at the DIADetroit s <ORGANIZATION>Detroit Film Theatre</ORGANIZATION> at 730 tonight for a In honor of WomensHistoryMonth the <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> offers a variety of events that celebrate the creative contributions of wo https t co ul3WA9STGe Kenyan born ceramicist <PERSON>MagdaleneOdundo</PERSON> is best known for producing hand built pottery using a coiling technique r https t co bhqDrUs5KM RT SalvadorSalort Can you name 5womenartists I m featuring work by <PERSON>LornaSimpson</PERSON> currently on view in MakingHomeDIA We ll be featuri Love it https t co z0XWxUZrhB RT <PERSON>SalvadorSalort Nina</PERSON> s skills and experience will help us achieve one of our most important goals which is to secure DIADetroit s lon Please join us in welcoming <PERSON>Nina Holden</PERSON> CFRE the <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> s new senior vice president and chief development officer H https t co JHkh5WlfLN RT SalvadorSalort I m looking forward to return to the <ORGANIZATION>Southfield Public Library</ORGANIZATION> for my next Director s Cut talk on March 14 Join me at <PERSON>HowardenaPindell</PERSON> said her work Air CS560 relates to all struggles in the world by people who do not wish for the https t co z1qvxJVr1L DIAInsideOut is embarking on its 9th year Today we announced the 2018 communities participating in the program w https t co xD4TfOa8gO Our LunarNewYear celebration continues today Enjoy Korean and Taiwanese cultural activities including music dan https t co J5x7DbNAO1 RT SalvadorSalort This weekend we re exploring the LunarNewYear as celebrated in <LOCATION>Korea</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Taiwan</LOCATION> DIADetroit This festival has me exci Our two day LunarNewYear celebration begins today Enjoy Korean and Taiwanese cultural activities including music https t co TTgKoJQHH2 RT SalvadorSalort Arts and culture are both woven deeply into <LOCATION>Detroit</LOCATION> s fabric <PERSON>Barry Gordy</PERSON> s music and <PERSON>Diego Rivera</PERSON> s murals are two ma DetroitPistons thanks for coming out to celebrate BlackHistoryMonth and the support of <PERSON>Arn</PERSON> and <PERSON>Nancy Tellem</PERSON> with https t co UlcFdfwfHI RT Dexter_Mason3 Some of my favorite things in the CityofDetroit the DetroitPistons and DIADetroit ForTheCulture BlackHistoryMonth RT macombdaily Celebrate Japanese Girl s Day at the DIADetroit https t co qwi5tm7hMf https t co m3gro3R3Fr Welcome to <LOCATION>Detroit</LOCATION> blakegriffin23 PistonsAtDIA DetroitHeart NBABHM BlackHistoryMonth DetroitPistons https t co 5tOnF6PL3b RT SalvadorSalort I had a wonderful time DIADetroit s second annual DetroitPistons team dinner Thanks to the team for coming out to <ORGANIZATION>ce RT DetroitPistons Squad</ORGANIZATION> at DIADetroit PistonsAtDIA NBABHM https t co 6wh33XVoEb DetroitPistons got together at the <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> tonight for the second annual BlackHistoryMonth team dinner https t co PB7Wu6eGtg Join the DIA Studio on March 10 from noon to 4 p m for a cell phone sleeping bag drop in workshop in honor of https t co po3aMX9uof Join DIA Director <PERSON>SalvadorSalort Pons</PERSON> at the <ORGANIZATION>Detroit Policy Conference</ORGANIZATION> next Thursday March 1 <LOCATION>Salvador</LOCATION> will discu https t co OpNwdUAF2a RT SalvadorSalort Today I met with <ORGANIZATION>OakGov Board of Commissioners</ORGANIZATION> to discuss the 2018 highlights of DIADetroit s partnership with <PERSON>Oakla BeaufordDelaney</PERSON> was an African American painter known for his figurative works made in <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> during the 1930s 4 https t co UYMWtrSgEm nelsonsabrina The <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> has installed the recently acquired painting Queen <PERSON>Mother Helen Moore</PERSON> by native <LOCATION>Detroit</LOCATION> artist <PERSON>Mario Mo</PERSON> https t co 4xtG6zpNkE CultureSource sat down with <PERSON>Elliot Wilhelm</PERSON> film curator of the DIA s <ORGANIZATION>Detroit Film Theatre Click</ORGANIZATION> below to read t https t co Plpcu4RgUm The DIA s <PERSON>Valerie Mercer</PERSON> department head <ORGANIZATION>GM Center for African American Art</ORGANIZATION> discusses the ObamaPortraits and th https t co M2kcEP8hnC Hear from the <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> s <PERSON>Valerie Mercer</PERSON> department head <ORGANIZATION>GM Center for African American Art</ORGANIZATION> on the significance of the https t co JrOBDfPcvy Have you seen the 2018 Academy Award Nominated Short Films yet The DIA s <ORGANIZATION>Detroit Film Theatre</ORGANIZATION> is screening them a https t co vw2eZwPIYN Our BlackHistoryMonth celebration continues This weekend catch an artist demonstration with <PERSON>Donald Calloway</PERSON> He https t co P8g3Gqd3JH RT LiteratiBkstore An amazing sold out evening with <PERSON>Patti Smith</PERSON> Thank you DIADetroit thank you all who attended and thank you <PERSON>Patti</PERSON> Explore the LunarNewYear traditions celebrated in <LOCATION>China Taiwan</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Korea</LOCATION> at the DIA February 24 25 during a speci https t co kK9qXlC24I Happy LunarNewYear While 2018 is the year of the dog the lion remains an important symbol of luck in <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> and o https t co T25KQSZa9i RT SalvadorSalort It was a pleasure hosting the <ORGANIZATION>Detroit Fine Arts Breakfast Club</ORGANIZATION> DIADetroit tonight I spoke with old friends made new RT <PERSON>SalvadorSalort Angelo Sherman</PERSON> presenting at the Breakfast Club Today DIADetroit hosts the event Amazing stories of <LOCATION>DETROIT</LOCATION> and its <PERSON>Don</PERSON> t miss artist demonstrations by <PERSON>Donald Calloway</PERSON> this weekend Admission is free for residents of <ORGANIZATION>Wayne Oakland</ORGANIZATION> https t co XxH2MWqSJO Join the DIA in celebrating Hinamatsuri or JapaneseGirlsDay with demonstrations of a tea ceremony ikebana flowe https t co nuVGqRn76J BaseballIsBack We can t wait for <ORGANIZATION>Tigers</ORGANIZATION> OpeningDay and the start of Play Ball Baseball at the DIA next month https t co ebztHWuFRj Congratulations https t co YXioYbJftt A great ValentinesDay read https t co FTjT8HTAdC Hear from DIA contemporary curators <PERSON>Lucy Mensah</PERSON> and <PERSON>Taylor Aldridge</PERSON> on their newest exhibition MakingHomeDIA https t co F96kYV1CCO RT SalvadorSalort Start your DetroitLoveStory DIADetroit DiegoRivera FridaKahlo ValentinesDay https t co uyEtf4Aps2 RT wdet The ObamaPortraits and the History of African American Portraiture Listen here amp gt amp gt https t co U9zOChFVLX DetroitToday DIADe RT wdet DIADetroit African American Art Curator <PERSON>Valerie Mercer</PERSON> speaks with SHDetroit about the <PERSON>Obama</PERSON> portraits unveiled on Monday at t Our DIA Away visit at <LOCATION>Beaumont Family Medicine Center</LOCATION> in <LOCATION>St Clair Shores</LOCATION> planned for Feb 15 17 has been canceled https t co 178NOo5b2t RT SalvadorSalort Nearly 1 100 MacombCounty students visited DIADetroit on free field trips last month Please come see us again soon RT SalvadorSalort In January DIADetroit welcomed over 2 200 <ORGANIZATION>OaklandCounty</ORGANIZATION> students on free field trips Thanks for visiting OakGov RT SalvadorSalort Last month DIADetroit welcomed nearly 2 000 WayneCounty students on free field trips waynecountymi CountyExecEvans There are only a few weeks left to see Monet Framing Life at the <ORGANIZATION>DIA Don</ORGANIZATION> t miss this rare opportunity to see ou https t co hZyZiuv1DD RT SalvadorSalort Enjoyed meeting with MacombBoC for an update on DIADetroit s partnership with <LOCATION>Macomb County</LOCATION> In addition to free mus RT WeAreOneMacomb DIA Away visits <LOCATION>Roseville St Clair Shores</LOCATION> https t co aDQ8FNzIoj RT After5Detroit There s no need to break the bank for date night There s plenty to do in the D that s free Here are some date ideas ev You can see Officer of the Hussars a masterpiece by <PERSON>Kehinde Wiley</PERSON> the artist who painted BarackObama s officia https t co zFLKuh3RmV <ORGANIZATION>NPG</ORGANIZATION> unveils the official portraits of <PERSON>Barack</PERSON> amp amp <PERSON>Michelle Obama</PERSON> which were painted by <PERSON>Amy Sherald</PERSON> and <PERSON>Kehinde Wile</PERSON> https t co vWLpsBU2rr RT GrossePteTimes A smaller version of the DIADetroit is coming to a BeaumontHealth facility in <LOCATION>St Clair Shores</LOCATION> this week Art https The Weekend of <PERSON>J Dilla</PERSON> continues today with the TheWrightMuseum s 7th Annual Dilla Youth Day Learn to how to l https t co KVLDRD0nWH The DIA has resumed regular hours today amp amp is open 10 5 Enjoy a performance of J <PERSON>Dilla</PERSON> s music by <PERSON>Cecelia Sharpe</PERSON> amp amp https t co TUlFoFDCsp RT SalvadorSalort Great conversation last night at my Director s Cut talk I appreciate the feedback i received from my MacombCounty fri RT SalvadorSalort We apologize for any inconvenience Please stay safe and warm https t co nmLoybfpGT DIA <ORGANIZATION>Detroit Film Theatre</ORGANIZATION> goers who purchased tickets for today s screenings can exchange their tickets for another https t co l334omHYXM Due to the continued strength of today s snowstorm the <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> will remain closed for the rest of the day All schedul https t co mVfiTjit2R Due to the inclement weather the <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> will be closed until at least 3 p m today At noon we ll make an announceme https t co L6HWd561Kf RT SalvadorSalort I m uplifted by the students who competed in the DetroitPistons BlackHistoryMonth Scholarship Event with <PERSON>Rick Mahorn Congrats</PERSON> to the winners of the 13th Annual Black History Month Scholarship Event PistonsAtDIA DetroitHeart https t co 2SFZSHmdDw RT DetroitPistons We re live from DIADetroit for our 13th Annual Black History Month Scholarship Event hosted by badboyhorn44 WATCH h <ORGANIZATION>Metro Detroit</ORGANIZATION> students take part in a scavenger hunt of works from the <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> s collection during the DetroitPistons https t co MiBatV8Fxn RT StoriesFromDet 6 things to do in <LOCATION>Detroit</LOCATION> this weekend Feb 9 Feb 11 https t co U5VYacQEiM https t co paJ4firGCS RT AntonArtCenter See you at the <LOCATION>Anton Art Center</LOCATION> tonight for the Director s Cut with <PERSON>SalvadorSalort</PERSON> and the DIADetroit WeAreOneMac RT modeld Be sure to check out the exhibit Making Home at the DIADetroit before it closes in June https t co SCKu1OKn3m RT SalvadorSalort The opening of our gallery DIAOutOfTheCrate sheds light on the process of purchasing art including the very important We re excited to host the DetroitPistons 13th Annual Black History Month Scholarship Event with <PERSON>Rick Mahorn</PERSON> today https t co raPtUNRLHe The Weekend of J <PERSON>Dilla</PERSON> presented by the DIA and the TheWrightMuseum is almost here Enjoy performances honoring https t co HxTHIY0C90 RT SalvadorSalort I m looking forward to seeing you at my next Director s Cut talk hosted by the AntonArtCenter tomorrow Free and open RT WeAreOneMacomb DIADetroit SalvadorSalort Visits MacombCounty and gives updates on exciting upcoming exhibits 2018 program plans an RT MacombBoC The DIADetroit free mobile creativity trailer will be in <LOCATION>RosevilleCity</LOCATION> today through Thursday AND Director SalvadorSalort RT SalvadorSalort Met with <ORGANIZATION>Macomb County Arts Authority</ORGANIZATION> members to discuss DIADetroit s 2018 county programs Can t wait for a community Join us in celebrating <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> s pastime in Play Ball Baseball at the <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> which opens March 30 The exhibition https t co ylM4TcARsS Conceptual artist <PERSON>Willie Cole</PERSON> transforms familiar objects into powerful artworks evoking the African American expe https t co YGCWK1sYYe We had another special DetroitPistons guest appearance today <PERSON>Hooper</PERSON> joined us for <ORGANIZATION>Schroeder Cherry</ORGANIZATION> s Can You Spe https t co e8BYBWNgBp RT SalvadorSalort Congrats to <PERSON>Willie Cole</PERSON> and <PERSON>Jocelyn Rainey</PERSON> recipients of the 2018 national and local Alain Locke Awards presented by The <ORGANIZATION>DetroitPistons Motor City Minis</ORGANIZATION> dance team showed up for a spontaneous performance before our Detroit Film The https t co uF9FlmAnSF RT DeadlineDetroit DetroitLooksLikeThis last night Recording artist <PERSON>Mahoganyjonez</PERSON> at DIADetroit Friday Night Live https t co YpPn Our BlackHistoryMonth celebration continues throughout February This wknd see a showing of <PERSON>Sammy Davis Jr</PERSON> I https t co Hz7HNZuO6M KDnTheD it BlackHistoryDIA RT KDnTheD DIADetroit is on jam tonight In celebration of BlackHistory is our history https t co hS1mNiDer5 Tickets for U S Poet Laureate <PERSON>Tracy K Smith</PERSON> s presentation at the <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> are sold out You can watch her reading and https t co b8G2TspQcC RT wdet U S Poet Laureate <PERSON>Tracy K Smith</PERSON> Joins DetroitToday with SHDetroit Hear her conversation here amp gt amp gt https t co i6R69EAS5b DIA RT SalvadorSalort We want everyone to experience the inspiring way <PERSON>Tracy K Smith</PERSON> believes poetry like art can connect us in difficul RT SalvadorSalort I m so honored to welcome U S Poet Laureate <PERSON>Tracy K Smith</PERSON> DIADetroit today as part of our 17 hour kickoff of <ORGANIZATION>BlackH RT</ORGANIZATION> wdet Right now <ORGANIZATION>U S Poet Laureate Tracy K Smith</ORGANIZATION> joins DetroitToday with SHDetroit She speaks tonight at 7 the DIADetroit Tune i Our 17 hour <ORGANIZATION>Black History Month</ORGANIZATION> kick off begins today at noon See you soon BlackHistoryDIA BlackHistoryMonth https t co AjnOqXWflb JohnnyGHowell Happy anniversary Thanks for your support and for reaching out Unfortunately as part of museum po https t co Nb7bwiR1Uf RT SalvadorSalort Thanks to <PERSON>Arn</PERSON> and <PERSON>Nancy Tellem</PERSON> for continued support of DIADetroit s BlackHistoryMonth programs Their support began <ORGANIZATION>RT After5Detroit Kick off Black History Month</ORGANIZATION> at the DIADetroit for a full day of events on Friday including a reading by U S poet lau Join the <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> s Friends of African and African American Art for a private reception with <ORGANIZATION>U S Poet Laureate Tracy K</ORGANIZATION> https t co m23CUIgZGV RT After5Detroit It s February Need date ideas for your Valentine Here are 25 fun things to do in <LOCATION>Detroit</LOCATION> ValentinesDay https t co Our BlackHistoryMonth kick off celebration gets underway tomorrow Join us for 17 hours of programming honoring th https t co Bx7TDTeTy8 RT SalvadorSalort Thanks to LeaderMacomb for hosting Arts amp amp Culture Day highlighting the beneficial impact art has on our communities RT faaaa_dia Friday Night LIVE BHM Edition DIADetroit start this Friday FEB 2 Museum will be open TIL 2AM Event incl artist demonstr <LOCATION>Detroit</LOCATION> battle rappers Quest MCODY and <PERSON>Marv Won</PERSON> spent their day off at the DIA See them in D Cyphered Portraits https t co Znese0UKa0 RT HistoricDET On this date 124 years ago work began on building an extension to the back of the <LOCATION>Detroit Museum of Art</LOCATION> seen here with Last week students from <ORGANIZATION>Vernor Elementary School</ORGANIZATION> visited the DIA to take part in a STEAM science technology eng https t co 02Hs8oBaXQ RT TheWrightMuseum FRIDAY at DIADetroit Hear from U S Poet Laureate <PERSON>Tracy K Smith</PERSON> author of three books and Pulitzer Prize winner P Join the DIA s <ORGANIZATION>Detroit Film Theatre</ORGANIZATION> for a rare special event March 23 25 RackhamChoir will perform composer <PERSON>Rich</PERSON> https t co xToD9Zo9xJ RT DeadlineDetroit DetroitLooksLikeThis Something You Can Feel a 2008 acrylic and oil painting on wood panels by mickalenethomas of Not to miss Admission is free for residents of <LOCATION>Wayne Oakland</LOCATION> and <ORGANIZATION>Macomb BlackHistoryDIA</ORGANIZATION> https t co YTFp3d0AUg RT AdvancingMacomb This weekend at the DIADetroit https t co f0xjh9Kba1 RT SalvadorSalort Looking forward to DIADetroit s 2018 <LOCATION>Wayne County</LOCATION> programming plan presented at today s Arts Authority meeting which <ORGANIZATION>U S Poet Laureate Tracy K Smith</ORGANIZATION> presents a reading and talk at the DIA s BlackHistoryMonth kick off event this F https t co EvJMFkCZfS BlackHistoryDIA https t co rD1i3i9hzF RT SalvadorSalort Happy birthday to mickalenethomas born onthisday in 1971 Thomas Something You Can Feel is a favorite among staff Explore the story behind the <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> s <ORGANIZATION>Monet</ORGANIZATION> mastesrpiece Rounded Flower Bed and learn how the <LOCATION>Paris</LOCATION> suburb of Argen https t co aNfltwNc7W LiteratiBkstore hosts PattiSmith at the DIA Feb 14 Click below to purchase tickets https t co a8YNy1J73K TheWrightMuseum Thanks for the shout out and happy Friday RT TheWrightMuseum IN 1 WEEK Enjoy a free lecture and reading by U S poet laureate <PERSON>Tracy K Smith</PERSON> at the <ORGANIZATION>DIA Detroit Film Theater Audi RT</ORGANIZATION> AntonArtCenter Jan 31 Join us for a panel discussion on supporting public funding for arts amp amp culture Mixer to follow at O Halloran The DIA s BlackHistoryMonth kick off celebration is almost a week away Make sure to reserve your FREE tickets to https t co 5ieoYRnPzV RT SalvadorSalort Join me for my next Director s Cut talk AntonArtCenter February 8 Free and open to the public See you there https The DFT s Oscar Shorts program begins February 9 Oscars OscarNoms Oscars2018 https t co exbK9eCZ3m Thanks to all who attended our drop in art making workshop on Martin Luther King Jr Day Participants created 160 https t co MK6cbZkBHS juliehinds Yep And the <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> s <ORGANIZATION>Detroit Film Theatre</ORGANIZATION> premiered three other films in <LOCATION>Detroit</LOCATION> that were just nominate https t co ReIGtEwo8d Join the <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> and TheWrightMuseum in honoring the music and legacy of legendary <LOCATION>Detroit</LOCATION> hip hop producer <PERSON>J Dilla</PERSON> F https t co xE9SmcdYTh We love it Thanks for sharing https t co RputeXAV6I Did you know The DIA s Detroit Film Theatre premiered four films in <LOCATION>Detroit</LOCATION> that were just nominated for Oscars https t co 4ic9pxVCF3 Students from <LOCATION>Detroit</LOCATION> s <ORGANIZATION>Earhart Elementary Middle School</ORGANIZATION> visited today to tour highlights of the DIA s collection https t co WhK1uEF0Tw Hear from DIA contemporary art curators <PERSON>Taylor Aldridge</PERSON> and <PERSON>Lucy Mensah</PERSON> on the creation of MakingHomeDIA in today https t co s8T8MRiAqB RT SalvadorSalort Happy birthday to Post Impressionist painter <PERSON>Paul C zanne</PERSON> who was born onthisday in 1839 See his masterpieces DIADe Have you seen MonetFramingLife at the DIA Explore the art historical context of the DIA s <ORGANIZATION>Monet</ORGANIZATION> masterpiece Rou https t co E6suozNipG RT SalvadorSalort I m excited for DIADetroit s programming plans in <LOCATION>Oakland County</LOCATION> this year Stay tuned for a community art project th RT SalvadorSalort Thanks to the <ORGANIZATION>Fischers</ORGANIZATION> for presenting a sneak peek of the 2018 NAIASDetroit Inspiring talk by <ORGANIZATION>GM</ORGANIZATION> s <PERSON>Mark Reuss</PERSON> NAIAS RT NAEAMusEd Mark Your Calendars NAEA and MuseumDirectors invites you to explore results of a 3 year research partnership at The Impa The DIA s <ORGANIZATION>Detroit Film Theatre</ORGANIZATION> presents the 2018 Academy Award nominated short films Feb 9 through March 4 <ORGANIZATION>Ticke</ORGANIZATION> https t co R4rMgdKfUo A wonderful example of self portraiture MuseumSelfieDay MuseumSelfieDay2018 https t co 6EsdGonC6A Post your DIA selfies today in honor of MuseumSelfieDay https t co iF5CfkyNCS RT maryjogibson <PERSON>Martha</PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION>Mary Magdalene Caravaggio 1598 Detroit Institute of Art MuseumSelfieDay DIADetroit</ORGANIZATION> https t co NGxbbd7CuL RT SalvadorSalort Amazing Vermeer show ngadc where DIADetroit great <PERSON>Ter Borch Lady</PERSON> at her <ORGANIZATION>Toilette</ORGANIZATION> is one of the best See the banner <ORGANIZATION>Monet Framing Life</ORGANIZATION> will be closed today through this Thursday Jan 18 to facilitate the de installation of <PERSON>Chu</PERSON> https t co XicO8lXK8K Stop by the <ORGANIZATION>DIA Studio</ORGANIZATION> between 11 and 3 to make a notebook to donate to a local school in honor of the the national https t co IyRdWVXjFg Come check out DIAOutOfTheCrate our newest exhibition curated by DIA Director <PERSON>Salvador Salort Pons</PERSON> https t co VlNXon1kYb On January 20 the <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> invites the public to attend DIA amp amp You A Community Conversation a follow up panel discus https t co YB5BGrDVEr RT SalvadorSalort In December more than 1 300 MacombCounty students visited DIADetroit on free field trips We hope you enjoyed your vi RT SalvadorSalort Last month DIADetroit welcomed more than 1 500 <ORGANIZATION>OaklandCounty</ORGANIZATION> students on free field trips Thanks for learning with u RT SalvadorSalort In December DIADetroit welcomed more than 2 300 WayneCounty students on free field trips See you again soon waynec Celebrate Martin Luther King Jr Day at the DIA The museum will be open from 9 a m to 4 p m on January 15 with https t co aywKBbbPgU <PERSON>Don</PERSON> t miss DIA Away partridgecreek this weekend Channel your creativity and learn how to think like an artist https t co ONfFezOew3 RT SalvadorSalort Excited to see our DIADetroit exhibition Church A Painter s Pilgrimage on freep s list of <LOCATION>Detroit</LOCATION> s best 2017 arts <ORGANIZATION>Monet Framing Life</ORGANIZATION> will be closed Tuesday Jan 16 through Thursday Jan 18 to facilitate the de installation o https t co uFnhRowWj3 RT <PERSON>SalvadorSalort Don</PERSON> t miss this stunning mask and its feathered costume by the Kom and Bamileke cultures respectively of <LOCATION>Cameroon</LOCATION> now <ORGANIZATION>Black History Month Kick Off</ORGANIZATION> 17 Hours Celebrating Black Creativity happening all day on Feb 2 includes a readin https t co OCiUkzOGK0 See Church A Painter s Pilgrimage at the <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> before it closes next Monday Jan 15 PaintersPilgrimage https t co jbglwQBuUD The <PERSON>Aaron Douglas</PERSON> works are on view in the African American galleries Admission is free for residents of <PERSON>Wayne Oa</PERSON> https t co 5SV2QTIwYL Join the <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> and our <ORGANIZATION>Detroit Film Theatre</ORGANIZATION> for Friday Night Live performances by <PERSON>Eszter Balint</PERSON> known for her actin https t co J9310jxEfS There s only one week left to see Church A Painter s Pilgrimage at the DIA Learn more and purchase tickets befo https t co A49sO4PDmQ Can t wait https t co jHvNuzmRtx Thanks for sharing DCyphered https t co b0Mcae0urm RT TheOaklandPress One week left to see Church exhibit at the DIADetroit https t co 17OZSZMkaF https t co XGDoEU2Ndj TODAY Join members of Citywide Poets as they compete head to head for the title of hip hop supremacy Free admissi https t co nmFgs1JS5h RT crainsdetroit a hip hop tournament at the DIADetroit a dancing light display and more ideas for your weekend in metroDetroit https Looking for something to do with the kids this winter Bring them to the <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> s <ORGANIZATION>Detroit Film Theatre</ORGANIZATION> for the Best of https t co IqodS2iGwn RT After5Detroit AwesomeDre313 is at the DIADetroit tonight for Friday Night Live https t co 9xeOOiUNCf Check out one of TylerGreenDC s latest podcasts featuring DIA Church A PaintersPilgrimage curator <PERSON>Kenneth Myers</PERSON> https t co w13jhvOiLx RT ArabAmericanMus Call and Response <PERSON>Leyya Tawil Bayoumi Ibrahim Ghawanmeh</PERSON> Read this and see a clip from the National Arab Orches The DIA s <ORGANIZATION>Detroit Film Theatre</ORGANIZATION> presents Making Home on Film a new series programmed in conjunction with the exhibi https t co cxYUErKcIB We hear there s a museumsnowballfight happening now While we re not affected by <PERSON>BombCyclone</PERSON> we have plenty of s https t co UJak6YZBN4 More on MakingHomeDIA A must see exhibition https t co aMeglATjaC Join us in celebrating MLKDay on January 15 https t co 8cDk8auHKi RT SalvadorSalort Not to be missed the art of A <ORGANIZATION>Douglas Detroit Institute of Arts</ORGANIZATION> displays four loaned paintings by <PERSON>Aaron Douglas</PERSON> ht Kick off the DIA s <ORGANIZATION>Detroit Film Theatre</ORGANIZATION> winter 18 season with Bombshell The <PERSON>Hedy Lamarr Story</PERSON> this weekend <PERSON>Lea</PERSON> https t co 556nYIbnh9 The DIA is on the list of CurbedDetroit s top places to visit this winter along with BelleIsle_Park Pewabic https t co GqiZ96w0VK Spotted today on the DIA s north lawn TuesdayThoughts <LOCATION>Detroit</LOCATION> https t co j8YvklXme7 RT SalvadorSalort Church A Painter s Pilgrimage closes in less than two weeks DIADetroit Explore American master <PERSON>Frederic Church s j Beautiful</PERSON> shot from DIA Director <PERSON>SalvadorSalort</PERSON> s native <LOCATION>Spain</LOCATION> https t co trnRJECvzQ RT DutchCultureUSA Please join the screening of the documentary Five Seasons The Gardens of <PERSON>Piet Oudolf</PERSON> on January 4 at <ORGANIZATION>DIADetroit F RT</ORGANIZATION> SalvadorSalort Hoping 2018 is as spectacular as 2017 Sharing some of my favorite moments from last year DIADetroit Happy NewYear Here s to a joyous 2018 Happy New Year from the DIA Image Dancing at <ORGANIZATION>Jazz Alley Chicago Illinois Roland L</ORGANIZATION> https t co GEkqVvvPUL RT SalvadorSalort Happy birthday to HenryMatisse born OnThisDay in 1869 Did you know that DIADetroit was the first U S museum to ac Happy NewYearsEve A reminder that the <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> is open today from 10 a m to 5 p m The museum will be closed tomorrow https t co F70tK147IJ This holiday weekend bring your family and friends to see Church A Painters Pilgrimage and <ORGANIZATION>Monet Framing Life</ORGANIZATION> https t co eeyZpaGcO2 RT SalvadorSalort DIADetroit Michelangelo drawing is part of this groundbreaking metmuseum show about the master as draftsman amp amp designer RT wdet The DIADetroit s <ORGANIZATION>Detroit Film Theatre Pairs Tea</ORGANIZATION> and Movies for Kids amp gt amp gt https t co bxZGKTRGfx https t co jymslcSbRf TONIGHT The <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> presents a DavidBowie tribute with <PERSON>Dylan Dunbar Jennifer Westwood Paul Randolph Bobby</PERSON> East Th https t co kKLygzO986 RT SalvadorSalort Help us make 2018 as special as 2017 with a year end gift to DIADetroit s Annual Fund Your contribution will let us c RT GraffonMusic Lots to do in the metro <LOCATION>Detroit</LOCATION> on this New Year s weekend Check it out in today s TheOaklandPress Go amp amp Do Weekend c We think <LOCATION>Detroit</LOCATION> is photogenic too CurbedDetroit compiled a list of the city s most popular Instagram spots in 2 https t co p34qaG5BP9 From a distance <ORGANIZATION>Monet</ORGANIZATION> s Rounded Flower Bed Corbeille de fleurs appears completely covered in paint Close up https t co tKIjHJLYBn Spread the word Residents of <LOCATION>Wayne Oakland</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Macomb</LOCATION> counties receive free admission to the <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> https t co rjROcKxirQ RT SalvadorSalort Put <LOCATION>Detroit</LOCATION> s Cultural Center including DIADetroit TheWrightMuseum DHSDetroit mi_sci DetroitLibrary amp amp other A reminder that the <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> is closed today We re open for extended hours beginning tomorrow This week s schedule is https t co 80TDVHXpz6 RT SalvadorSalort I m returning to my curatorial roots Jan 12 with the opening of Out of the Crate New Gifts amp amp Purchases DIADetroit DYK metmuseum s exhibition Michelangelo Divine Draftsman and Designer features a very rare work from the <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> https t co GSAbajsoEr Out of the Crate New Gifts amp amp Purchases a new permanent collection gallery at the <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> opens January 12 https t co HoSbcws1HQ RT TylerGreenDC Holiday book rec The DIADetroit catalogue for its <ORGANIZATION>Frederic Church</ORGANIZATION> in the <LOCATION>Far East</LOCATION> exhib Smart essays richly illustrat The <ORGANIZATION>Garden Club</ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION>Michigan</LOCATION> and the <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> s Friends of the <ORGANIZATION>Detroit Film Theatre</ORGANIZATION> co host a screening of the documentar https t co 78xh5NCRts RT SalvadorSalort We re embracing the power of rhythmic artistry at tonight s Cypher Workshop presented by Inside Out Literary Arts DIAD mizkorona poses next to her DCyphered portrait by <PERSON>JennyRisher</PERSON> See her perform tonight at 7 and 8 30 at the <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> https t co D5TqdxY7px Excited for the release of LastJedi Beginning May 20 you can get an up close look at dozens of original costumes https t co xpNvjgzXU8 RT TheWrightMuseum Happy birthday to Detroiter and Kresge Eminent Artist <PERSON>Charles McGee</PERSON> who was born OTD in 1924 <PERSON>McGee</PERSON> is a trailblazer At age 93 <PERSON>Charles McGee</PERSON> shows no signs of stopping See his works all over <LOCATION>Detroit</LOCATION> including at the <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> https t co dDkRRporzM See performances by mizkorona tonight at the DIA Free for residents of <LOCATION>Wayne Oakland</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Macomb</LOCATION> counties https t co 3vWdfQ5wMI marcgeelhoed We like the sound of that Highly regarded as a top hip hop lyricist <LOCATION>Detroit</LOCATION> rap pioneer AwesomeDre313 has been putting out work for over 2 https t co Cwp6LF7Q6o Thinking of what to do on your snow day Come visit the DIA We re open until 4 and admission is free for resident https t co LWgFyUhxU9 RT SalvadorSalort DIADetroit uses <LOCATION>Lumin</LOCATION> technology to enhance the visitor experience in our galleries https t co zDSBh36DI4 RT GuidiGO_app Using the DIADetroit s <PERSON>Lumin</PERSON> AR app 9 out of 10 users say that DIALumin helps them engage with the art Read more here More holiday gift ideas from the <ORGANIZATION>DIA Shop</ORGANIZATION> https t co gz5Mfydk6k RT SalvadorSalort In November DIADetroit welcomed nearly 1 500 MacombCounty students on free field trips Come see us again soon WeA RT SalvadorSalort Last month DIADetroit welcomed nearly 2 000 <ORGANIZATION>OaklandCounty</ORGANIZATION> students on free field trips We hope you enjoyed your visi Field trips and transportation to the DIA are FREE for schools in <LOCATION>Wayne Oakland</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Macomb</LOCATION> counties https t co <ORGANIZATION>J2b93jS1pA Eric Huck DIA</ORGANIZATION> director of retail operations highlighted his favorite holiday gifts from the DIA Shop You can pur https t co ynrD3RYLdB RT There_is_no_Ty Please check out exhibition Making Home DIADetroit It s the most beautifully considered and brilliantly curated s Thanks to <PERSON>Madonna</PERSON> for the <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> shout out on LiveKellyRyan https t co 6I4kCJAHnJ RT GuidiGO_app Using AR visitors to the DIADetroit can see how an Ancient Middle Eastern cylinder seal would have worked right in fro HeidelbergProj nytimesarts Thanks for the shout out RT HeidelbergProj Congrats to our friends at the DIADetroit for making The nytimesarts list for best art of the year <LOCATION>Detroit</LOCATION> After Da Get 25 off when you Lyft to any of the 2017 Detroit Lyftie Award winners including the DIA Use code DETLYFTIE https t co rggbFpcScI Don t miss performances by mizkorona this Friday Free for residents of <LOCATION>Wayne Oakland</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Macomb</LOCATION> counties https t co gu6Zl8LfLE Are you an amazon shopper Give back to your favorite charitable organizations like the <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> while you shop at https t co z2hnR8HFnC RT SalvadorSalort Taking some time to celebrate the holidays with DIADetroit staff during our annual Winter Solstice Party Thanks to th nytimesarts lists the <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> s <LOCATION>Detroit</LOCATION> After Dark exhibition as one that left a lasting impression in 2017 See th https t co AHsgmdX4J2 Happy birthday to <ORGANIZATION>DiegoRivera Google</ORGANIZATION> googlearts https t co SYCg0MV4Yy RT MidtownDetroit DIA Director <PERSON>Don</PERSON> t let an act of violence keep you from <LOCATION>Detroit</LOCATION> s Midtown https t co 8jFngZuarV via freep Thanks to RT SalvadorSalort A message from <LOCATION>Detroit</LOCATION> s Cultural Center leaders on how we can continue to improve the lives of the communities we are Did today s snowfall inspire you to go outside and paint or photograph your surroundings Even in the winter Clau https t co FyOmNUVKh2 Thanks to <ORGANIZATION>Detroit Lyft</ORGANIZATION> drivers for naming the DIA the top Trending Destination of 2017 https t co 8bc3dj1bki Despite the seemingly simple premise the show packs plenty of surprises starting with a dramatic work that is ne https t co CrCENQJG3q Our thoughts are with our neighbors to the west GettyMuseum and the residents of the surrounding area SkirballFire RT SalvadorSalort Many thanks to local collectors <PERSON>Wilson</PERSON> A and <PERSON>Deborah F Copeland</PERSON> and <PERSON>Lauren</PERSON> F C N Namdi for sharing these treasures New on view at the DIA are four works by renowned painter illustrator muralist and arts educator AaronDouglas w https t co VHaE4534Pq RT SalvadorSalort Enjoying ArtBasel with FMCA_DIA Happy to run into the awe inspiring MarkBradford ArtBasel https t co 21bw8r4hhx RT SalvadorSalort Huge Thxs to <PERSON>Michelle</PERSON> amp amp JasonRubell 4 opening the doors of their amazing home to the DIADetroit FMCA_DIA RubellMi RT SalvadorSalort Gracias josebedia for sharing your art collection of worlds cultures through the keen eye of an artist Hope to see yo Join us for performances by <PERSON>Reg Pettibone</PERSON> a Native American champion dancer from the <ORGANIZATION>Ho Chunk Nation</ORGANIZATION> and his fami https t co HZOXL891xx Through this digital exhibition discover the emergence of the Impressionists and <ORGANIZATION>Post Impressionists</ORGANIZATION> https t co QAvSMiyOpw <PERSON>Guyton</PERSON> s <ORGANIZATION>Rosa Parks Heidelberg Fragment</ORGANIZATION> is a visitor favorite See it on view in MakingHomeDIA https t co 9I18Mw3l7e RT SalvadorSalort We ve decked the halls and planned fun activities for visitors of all ages this holiday season DIADetroit From exhibi See you tonight https t co reSlRtpByu NoelNight MidtownDetroit https t co Ho0D2UyHQb RT SalvadorSalort We were pleased to welcome the future leaders of <LOCATION>Macomb County</LOCATION> DIADetroit last night Come back any time <ORGANIZATION>Macomb County RT</ORGANIZATION> SalvadorSalort DIADetroit is proud to host business and community leaders from <LOCATION>Washtenaw County</LOCATION> who traveled to the museum to promot RT SalvadorSalort We know not only from personal experiences but also from scientific research that having access to the arts has a pos RT SalvadorSalort Consider your own concepts of home in DIADetroit s new contemporary show Making Home Contemporary Art from the DIA Making Home Contemporary Art from the <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> opened today and is on view through June 6 2018 https t co kqEt3fLbR2 museummammy TaylorRAldridge Us too We hope you can stop by to see it RT museummammy Highest praise for <ORGANIZATION>TaylorRAldridge</ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON>Lucy Mensah</PERSON> who just mounted their inaugural show Making Home Contemporary Works Making Home Contemporary Art from the <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> inaugural exhibition of assistant curators <PERSON>Taylor Aldridge</PERSON> and <PERSON>Lucy</PERSON> M https t co xStTBU7kxp RT mizkorona Check me out LIVE diadetroit on 12 15 17 7pm amp amp 8pm FREE Admission for <ORGANIZATION>Oakland Wayne</ORGANIZATION> and https t co ySZanrtwt0 RT LoriAHiggins DIADetroit DetroitSymphony MusicHallCenter DetOperaHouse Detroitk12 freep It s worth noting that most of these inst <LOCATION>Detroit</LOCATION> s cultural institutions including the DIA DetroitSymphony MusicHallCenter and DetOperaHouse are hel https t co uOWdKdtTls RT KDnTheD Shoutout to detroitpolice and our D67project partners DIADetroit collecting toys today outside of the museum If you re in Yum Glad you re enjoying your visit https t co CJ7WYTJO3i RT SalvadorSalort I NoelNight because it brings our communities together <PERSON>Don</PERSON> t miss it this year on Dec 2 MidtownDetroit https t RT CultureSource Making Home Contemporary Works From DIADetroit opens tonight https t co kxAqm3K9jU NoelNight MidtownDetroit s annual community wide holiday celebration is just a few days away Join the <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> and https t co fn7OCmUSVX Tomorrow join FMCA_DIA in celebrating the opening of Making Home Contemporary Works from the DIA the inaugural https t co lhYDqfx421 There s still time left to contribute on GivingTuesday SupportTheDIA and young learners with a gift to the annua https t co HB1S3C78ok Looking for ways to give back to the community SupportTheDIA with a GivingTuesday donation https t co EUsVUN82JO Looking for ways to give back to the community SupportTheDIA with a GivingTuesday donation Thanks https t co EUsVUN82JO SupportTheDIA and provide an art making experience for a disabled adult with a gift of 10 https t co EUsVUN82JO GivingTuesday SupportTheDIA and the next <ORGANIZATION>Picasso</ORGANIZATION> 25 gives a visitor supplies and instruction to draw in the galleries https t co EUsVUN82JO SupportTheDIA with a GivingTuesday donation and demonstrate the value of your museum to our region https t co EUsVUN82JO Does your employer match donations Double your impact when you SupportTheDIA https t co EUsVUN82JO GivingTuesday Your GivingTuesday donation will help fund art making programs for veterans https t co EUsVUN82JO SupportTheDIA https t co 7AfWKNsknR Remember your DIA field trips SupportTheDIA and help today s kids find personal meaning in art https t co TIzItKe9hp Your SupportTheDIA donation helps fund bedside art projects at Children s Hospital and more https t co EUsVUN82JO GivingTuesday SupportTheDIA with a donation of 10 to help fund engaging gallery games for families https t co EUsVUN82JO Your GivingTuesday donation helps fund school field trips educator workshops and more https t co EUsVUN82JO SupportTheDIA RT SalvadorSalort SupportTheDIA with an annual fund gift to keep DIADetroit open forever https t co Vgv3NnguRO GivingTuesday RT SalvadorSalort SupportTheDIA to ensure that future generations of students will find personal meaning in art https t co GaPQl4A341 RT buddyspizza RT Great organizations to follow and support on GivingTuesday thehenryford mhumane DIADetroit detroitpublic Today is GivingTuesday Your donation to the <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> will support field trips family gallery games art making for ve https t co MTJqpJwj1M Happy CyberMonday We re offering 20 off on new DIA memberships TODAY ONLY A DIA membership makes a perfect gift https t co ntra7OqCaC RT SalvadorSalort Celebrate MuseumStoreSunday by shopping at https t co J8b1j7ab4Y You ll find a wide selection of artful gifts for e RT CultureSource Keeping it Local Holiday Shopping 2017 on SmallBusinessSaturday https t co wks0KmM68A https t co uNpPQRgvNn The DIA s Thanksgiving weekend festivities continue Bring your family to see <ORGANIZATION>Monet Framing Life Church</ORGANIZATION> A Pa https t co CYMqW38mT5 DIADetroit is your holiday town square From art to puppet shows to films amp amp more we have something for everyone https t co KsyEM12ne5 RT SalvadorSalort Back at it with my Distinguished Clowns at the DetroitParade Gathering DIADetroit before bringing smiles to many fac Happy Thanksgiving from the DIA Pictured here Poultry Yard by <PERSON>Melchior de Hondecoeter</PERSON> c 1668 https t co 8FG3S0g90Z The DIA will be closed tomorrow Thursday Nov 23 for Thanksgiving The museum will resume regular hours on Frida https t co 4JZBiDGxDJ Reserved senior groups 25 can visit <ORGANIZATION>Monet Framing Life amp amp Church</ORGANIZATION> A Painter s Pilgrimage FREE in December A https t co gYKCK8WlLo Closing out the day with a Catsgiving tweet because why not Adding <PERSON>Oskar Kokoschka</PERSON> s The Cat to the mix https t co bde0V7UnBu RT DeadlineDetroit DetroitLooksLikeThis Hip hop recording artist and actor mizkorona performs Friday with a band at <ORGANIZATION>DIADetroit Kresge</ORGANIZATION> GivingTuesday is November 28 Your donation to the <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> will support field trips family gallery games art making https t co G9FOWGe08X RT OakGovMeisner Seniors from <ORGANIZATION>OaklandCounty</ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON>Wayne</PERSON> amp amp <LOCATION>Macomb</LOCATION> can get door to door service to the DIADetroit every Thursday Groups Join us Friday Dec 15 for Friday Night Live performances with DetroitHipHop artist mizkorona Then see her phot https t co cTdgWIx8JK RT CultureLabDET <LOCATION>Detroit</LOCATION> is featured in <PERSON>Wendy Vogel</PERSON> s City Report for frieze_magazine today covering CultureLabDetroit DIADetroit M aaronschey <PERSON>SalvadorSalort JennyRisher KahnSantori NickSpeedEnt</PERSON> https t co e7f6yvOGvw We re offering specials for seniors this December https t co aAkw4YZjg7 RT HistoryLivesDet On this day in 1983 <LOCATION>Detroit</LOCATION> s Cultural Center which includes DIADetroit DetroitLibrary and <PERSON>Horace H Rackham</PERSON> buil pvtannie Unfortunately the <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> is closed on Mondays The museum is open T Th 9 a m 4 p m F 9 a m 10 p m a https t co XTYhEdFusq Don t forget Residents of <LOCATION>Oakland Macomb</LOCATION> and <PERSON>Wayne</PERSON> counties receive free DIA admission Come see us https t co x8FiLUvdrX DYK FredericChurch painted this scene of the <LOCATION>Parthenon</LOCATION> at night during his trip to the <LOCATION>Middle East</LOCATION> amp amp <ORGANIZATION>Mediterranea</ORGANIZATION> https t co FHfnN6SyDp RT SalvadorSalort Fascinating talk by DCyphered artist <PERSON>JennyRisher</PERSON> with <PERSON>KahnSantori NickSpeedEnt</PERSON> amp amp <PERSON>Nancy Barr</PERSON> The catalog is beauti NewUSCitizen Congratulations to the <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> s two newest U S citizens https t co CKyFL2OjiL RT DevonAkmon Discussing the live scoring of the historic silent films of <PERSON>Mohamed Bayoumi</PERSON> w <PERSON>Mohannad Ghawanmeh</PERSON> amp amp <PERSON>Michael Ibrahim</PERSON> MOVE RT mosaicdetroit Get your tickets today to see Woodward Wonderland December 8 10th at the diadetroit https t co AdeFbj4IxF This Saturday join a convo with DCyphered artist <PERSON>Jenny Risher Detroit</PERSON> hip hop expert KahnSantori https t co uioV3e0z8k RT DevonAkmon Over 500 RSVPs already for the opening of ArabAmericanMus commission of <ORGANIZATION>National Arab Orchestra</ORGANIZATION> w partner DIADetroit G The <ORGANIZATION>Community Group Show</ORGANIZATION> is on view at the <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> through December 31 Come see it Free for residents of <PERSON>Wayne Oakla</PERSON> https t co acySOEtoXw Not to miss https t co b3kidgKahr RT SalvadorSalort HBD <ORGANIZATION>Monet On Facebook MonetFramingLife</ORGANIZATION> curator <PERSON>Jill Shaw</PERSON> discusses the research that led to the renaming of our Mon RT MatinWindsor L exposition MonetFramingLife les d buts impressionnistes de Monet DIADetroit amp amp les oeuvres de Frederic Church Paint HBD ClaudeMonet Tune in to the <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> s Facebook page today at 4 p m for a live interview with MonetFramingLife cu https t co OjxJMxhvd8 RT SalvadorSalort Thanks to the <ORGANIZATION>Plymouth Men s Book Club</ORGANIZATION> for inviting me to give a Director s Cut talk Come see us DIADetroit Free for RT SalvadorSalort Happy birthday to my wife <PERSON>Alex May</PERSON> who shares a birthday with ClaudeMonet Te amo axmay13 https t co e32EgU0K8d Happy birthday to artist BennyAndrews born onthisday in 1930 <PERSON>Andrews</PERSON> was a socially minded artist and an advoca https t co SOGkC3bjqh Join the DIAofrendas2017 artists for a free talk about their work this Sunday https t co JGU5uEd72s DIADetroit s AndreaMontielS talks DIALumin best practices MuseumCN MCN2017 musetech AugmentedReality https t co T9JYaPHxaJ RT GuidiGO_app AR in museums should facilitate an experience with the real objects AndreaMontielS mcn2017 t33 ar DIADetroit https Only a few days left for DIAmembers to save 20 in store amp amp online Double Discount Days end 11 12 Start shopping https t co pNDCUZoGoh RT SalvadorSalort Explore the meaning of home in Making Home Contemporary Art from the <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> opening December 1 Curated by lkmens amp amp <PERSON>Don</PERSON> t miss Ai Weiwei s Human Flow at the <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> s <ORGANIZATION>Detroit Film Theatre</ORGANIZATION> this weekend https t co SBsfeuEllB aiww https t co 01iyqQKFYp Spend your Thanksgiving weekend at the DIA Enjoy puppet performances live music art making films amp amp more https t co QTux1iaMDi RT SalvadorSalort Thanks for the invite from the <ORGANIZATION>Plymouth Men s Book Club</ORGANIZATION> for my Nov 13 Director s Cut talk Looking forward to it The DIA s new Japanese art gallery opens today Celebrate the opening this weekend with activities for all ages https t co XKjZF4zla5 RT SalvadorSalort I can t wait to share DIADetroit s new <LOCATION>Japan</LOCATION> gallery a project that began in 2015 with you amp amp my family tmrw More htt We designed the interactive tea table with tellart Come check it out beginning tomorrow https t co Q7fOCMf0mh RT SalvadorSalort Many thanks to the <ORGANIZATION>Japanese Business Society of Detroit amp amp</ORGANIZATION> others for their generous support of DIADetroit s new <LOCATION>Japan</LOCATION> Some DIA galleries and public spaces will be closed Nov 8 12 We apologize for any inconvenience Details at https t co k3xeoaGkOS RT SalvadorSalort Getting a head start on holiday shopping at the DIADetroit Shop s Members Shopping Event Visit https t co 3pAKzgSv See nearly 4 000 objects spanning about 3 000 years by artists from <LOCATION>North Central and South America</LOCATION> in our collect https t co T5WoFWj9iK DCyphered is free for residents of <LOCATION>Wayne Oakland</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Macomb</LOCATION> counties The exhibition is on view through Feb 18 https t co WVqtr0JRp5 RT 313libraries First library given away from DIADetroit to <LOCATION>Highland Park Tx</LOCATION> to <PERSON>Michael Lisieski</PERSON> for stewarding https t co St6J37fkX0 <PERSON>Tomoko Konno</PERSON> s work will be on view in the <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> s newly renovated Japanese art gallery which opens this weekend https t co PcCF7ayAgW RT SalvadorSalort Get spooked with DIALumin this Halloween DIADetroit AugmentedReality musetech projecttango GuidiGO_app https Happy Halloween from the DIA Sharing <PERSON>Paul</PERSON> C zanne s The Three Skulls https t co 6NTTIToU8P Celebrate the opening of the DIA s reinstalled Japanese art gallery November 4 5 with exciting events for all ages https t co u6mN9KYvzn DYK FredericChurch was the most popular amp amp financially successful U S painter in the mid 1800s https t co OwuO2bEJ2C Presenting world premiere of live score by <PERSON>Michael Ibrahim</PERSON> accompanying Egyptian silent films with ArabAmericanMus https t co HvZHqKFeWW RT SalvadorSalort Ever leading never following Happy birthday to Cubism co founder <PERSON>PabloPicasso</PERSON> who was born onthisday in 1881 http RT DDFRtv Check out behindthescenes photos from new <ORGANIZATION>TVShow Family Pictures USA</ORGANIZATION> visit to DIADetroit Genealogy amp amp travel https t c Get spooked Hallo weekend at the DIA The <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> s <ORGANIZATION>Detroit Film Theatre</ORGANIZATION> is offering a frightening lineup of films https t co hy34OO3Ozv The DIA s <PERSON>Eve Straussman Pflanzer</PERSON> discusses the work of <PERSON>Carlo Dolci</PERSON> https t co zlU18mwzoh DIAmembers are invited to an exclusive after hours museum shopping event Nov 1 Save 20 on all purchases https t co yxbPzGKGAA RT EnglishGardens English Gardens is so excited to be a sponsor of the DIADetroit Monet Framing Life Exhibit https t co iLh41tLrTX RT DeadlineDetroit DetroitLooksLikeThis MonetFramingLife at DIADetroit looks at his work in <LOCATION>Argenteuil</LOCATION> near <LOCATION>Paris</LOCATION> from 1871 78 ht Shana_Was_Here VisitDetroit Thanks for stopping by Hope to see you again soon mb5938 Thanks for visiting Glad you enjoyed the exhibitions RT DeadlineDetroit DetroitLooksLikeThis <PERSON>Claude Monet</PERSON> s Rounded Flower Bed unframed is part of MonetFramingLife at <ORGANIZATION>DIADetroit Su RT</ORGANIZATION> SalvadorSalort Thanks to the generous individual amp amp corporate sponsors who made Church A PaintersPilgrimage amp amp MonetFramingLife pos RT SalvadorSalort Travel back in time to the late 19th century and see the world through these artists eyes Enjoy PaintersPilgrimage The DIA s newest exhibitions Church A Painter s Pilgrimage and <ORGANIZATION>Monet Framing Life</ORGANIZATION> are now open https t co 4QBy9tfdZ0 RT SalvadorSalort Celebrating the partnership between DIADetroit and <PERSON>Wayne Oakland</PERSON> amp amp <LOCATION>Macomb</LOCATION> counties Thank you for your continued supp Checkmate MarkHackel How d you fare against the <ORGANIZATION>Detroit City Chess Club</ORGANIZATION> stars Thanks for stopping by our County https t co bT0SD6SkF4 Thanks for visiting tonight https t co c4AKub3m75 Celebrate the closing of ArtofRebellion with this free performance in <LOCATION>Rivera Court</LOCATION> https t co JWooIvOe4y Eight contemporary <LOCATION>Detroit</LOCATION> artists close out ArtofRebellion with a FREE performance in <LOCATION>Rivera Court</LOCATION> Saturday https t co rksfTWuzOm Great shot https t co 4PGTRkNC3y RT SalvadorSalort Thanks to <PERSON>MarkBradford</PERSON> for an exhilarating talk Your work demonstrates the power of art to inspire social change FMC Free admission for residents of <LOCATION>Wayne Oakland</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Macomb</LOCATION> counties https t co Y4z5nXv5uH Not to miss Learn more and purchase tickets at https t co k3xeoaXWds https t co hytkcSnlOI Church A Painter s Pilgrimage opens this Sunday Oct 22 in conjunction with Monet Framing Life https t co 84YtyhmiL9 MImuseums2017 https t co HzoGE1ctF0 Check them out this weekend at our <ORGANIZATION>Detroit Film Theatre</ORGANIZATION> https t co xiUuMFIXot Join us for a free talk with <PERSON>Mark Bradford</PERSON> tomorrow Click below to RSVP https t co NNme8CXQ6r Please join us in welcoming <PERSON>Clare Rogan</PERSON> the <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> s new curator of prints and drawings She begins December 4 https t co M1uPp2CMWP We re proud to be on this list for our Bitter Sweet Coffee Tea amp amp Chocolate exhibition sipthestory https t co qxXJTnLU4I Join the Ofrendas Celebrating el D a de Muertos artists November 12 for a talk about their work https t co W5q09mPKE3 They look great https t co BTijcjkwbj Our Ofrendas Celebrating el D a de Muertos opening weekend celebration continues Join us https t co fSEVSrH4nc RT SalvadorSalort Thanks to DIADetroit s <ORGANIZATION>Women s Committee</ORGANIZATION> for your endowment support helping us to keep the museum open forever Gratis para residentes de los municipios de <ORGANIZATION>Wayne Oakland</ORGANIZATION> y Macomb DIAOfrendas2017 https t co gTtOPixh7P The ofrendas will be on view through Sunday November 12 Free for residents of <LOCATION>Wayne Oakland</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Macomb</LOCATION> counties https t co CZ2cpYy7BO Tickets are free for residents of <LOCATION>Wayne Oakland</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Macomb</LOCATION> counties https t co Qj2Gl9UL3D RT CultureSource Check out Step Afrika s The Migration Reflections on <PERSON>Jacob Lawrence</PERSON> DIADetroit https t co tYyQScxKHs Beautiful https t co ZWhASjCMaF RT GuidiGO_app With DIALumin you can get directions through the museum in augmented reality Try it at DIADetroit https t co Gh7zMG Admission is free for residents of <LOCATION>Macomb Oakland</LOCATION> and <PERSON>Wayne</PERSON> counties https t co AFESYGJkpW RT StepAfrikaHQ Learn to step w <PERSON>StepAfrika</PERSON> at our FREE workshop on 10 12 at DIADetroit https t co FJybUMrG10 <LOCATION>Detroit</LOCATION> stepping Happy DayoftheGirl ElizabethCatlett https t co D1UG2PSyeN DIA Program Coordinator <PERSON>Michael Hill</PERSON> sat down with SHendersonFreep on amblackjournal to talk StepAfrikaHQ https t co dFZONGO8bj TheWrightMuseum Thanks for the shout out RT CultureSource Only a few days left to catch Art of Rebellion Black Art of the <ORGANIZATION>Civil Rights Movement</ORGANIZATION> DIADetroit https t co rBguhihh RT SalvadorSalort Join FMCA_DIA for a free talk with critically acclaimed artist <PERSON>Mark Bradford</PERSON> DIADetroit Oct 19 https t co 9t7Ne3j RT wdet Tune in to WDET for your chance to win tickets to see LovingVincent at the DIADetroit s <ORGANIZATION>Detroit Film Theatre</ORGANIZATION> amp gt amp gt https t co <ORGANIZATION>E7 RT DeadlineDetroit DetroitLooksLikeThis Detroit City Chess Club</ORGANIZATION> at DIADetroit Photo by <PERSON>Patricia Lay Dorsey</PERSON> https t co 4tVKmQ3eqq ArtofRebellion closes Oct 22 Not to miss Free for residents of <LOCATION>Wayne Oakland</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Macomb</LOCATION> counties https t co QLjKmDtdVj RT SalvadorSalort Join us in celebrating the opening of DIADetroit s new Japanese art gallery with exciting events Nov 4 5 https t co We our DIAvolunteers https t co oXwLirRZpE Come see us again soon https t co IkWcU2hlLE Hosting our first Wiki Edit A <PERSON>Thon</PERSON> to provide additional amp amp concurrent info on the 1967 <LOCATION>Detroit</LOCATION> rebellion <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> https t co dVSKmQnV4a RT SalvadorSalort OnThisDay in 1927 the <ORGANIZATION>Detroit Institute of Arts</ORGANIZATION> opened in its current location on Woodward Ave The building was desi RT SalvadorSalort <PERSON>Bonnie Larson</PERSON> s leadership as a board member amp amp volunteer inspires all who cherish DIADetroit We thank you for your en Can t wait for tomorrow https t co mr92osHYzg Hurry there are only two weeks left to see ArtofRebellion at the DIA Free admission for tri county residents https t co 8wJrWLnnft RT ZipporahFilms ExLibris now screening at filmcenter mfaboston <LOCATION>Belcourt</LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION>OKCMOA</ORGANIZATION> DenverFilm DIADetroit jbfc_ny more https RT SalvadorSalort Thanks to DIADetroit s <ORGANIZATION>European Paintings Council</ORGANIZATION> amp amp <PERSON>Bonnie Larson</PERSON> for endowment support which helps fund exhibits lik RT StepAfrikaHQ Tune into wrcjfm909 this week amp amp next for a chance to win 2 tix to our 10 13 <LOCATION>Detroit</LOCATION> performance at DIADetroit https Happy WorldTeachersDay DYK The <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> offers free field trips amp amp transportation to schools in <LOCATION>Wayne Oakland</LOCATION> amp amp Macom https t co cugIvBwEiY Thrilled to host <LOCATION>Detroit</LOCATION> native amp amp doc expert thompowers amp amp others this wknd at our <ORGANIZATION>Detroit Film Theatre</ORGANIZATION> freep https t co ya8rG0yuih RT SalvadorSalort Congrats again to <PERSON>Gene Gargaro</PERSON> DIADetroit chairman of the board for being honored as one of the 2017 <ORGANIZATION>Neal Shine Awar RT</ORGANIZATION> juliehinds <PERSON>Thom Powers</PERSON> watched docs as a teen at DIADetroit Now he s bringing some of best documentary filmmakers there https t c RT thompowers Detroit Documentary All Stars come to DIADetroit on Sat Oct 7 MorganSpurlock barbarakopple shannoncason https t co Great advice from yokoono https t co 5a97PIXq8B Spend your Hallo weekend at the <ORGANIZATION>DIA Our Detroit Film Theatre</ORGANIZATION> is offering a frightening lineup of films Oct 27 29 https t co vEBiyp93LK Join the <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> s Detroit Film Theatre in celebrating Italian cinema October 19 22 https t co yClLVBYRZu https t co sIRCVQWSLt RT SalvadorSalort Tickets for Church A Painter s Pilgrimage and <ORGANIZATION>Monet Framing Life</ORGANIZATION> are now on sale I can t wait for you to see bot Church A Painter s Pilgrimage amp amp <ORGANIZATION>Monet Framing Life</ORGANIZATION> tickets are on sale https t co Ztm0Qe9ATX https t co RQYLbUxTn0 RT SalvadorSalort Join TaylorRAldridge DIADetroit contemporary curator for our first Wiki Edit A Thon Oct 8 https t co HEllLggOmh In October 1874 Monet moved into this <LOCATION>Argenteuil</LOCATION> home where he painted his newly renamed masterpiece Rounded Flow https t co LgAMietOQ6 Our weekend of Taiwanese shadow puppets continues https t co SXy9FBwoUJ RT SalvadorSalort Cheers to our neighbor the scarabclub celebrating 110 years of being a driving force in the artistic community Here Spend the weekend learning about creating and watching Taiwanese shadow puppets https t co SXy9FBwoUJ The DIA s newly re installed Japanese art gallery will open to the public Nov 4 5 https t co 0oy45hVBJM RT DeadlineDetroit DetroitLooksLikeThis tonight at DIADetroit 7 amp amp 8 30 p m performances by 18 SphinxMusic alumni https t co UTc RT SalvadorSalort Celebrating the premiere of The D with the incredible AlleeWillis The city comes together DIADetroit WeAreTheD h RT AlleeWillis DETROITERS C u 2night DIADetroit 4 THED premiere 3000 peeps expected so make sure you have FREE tix https t co Wiq Great shot See you there https t co Q6J8lpgAlD See you tonight to celebrate the premiere of The D AlleeWillis <LOCATION>Detroit</LOCATION> anthem https t co xhXl4MMYDK Join FMCA_DIA for a free talk with critically acclaimed artist MarkBradford on Thursday Oct 19 https t co ZsppZl4TuN tripsavvy_tips named DIAInsideOut one of the top 10 <LOCATION>US</LOCATION> museum events worth the trip https t co cMKrHWGLWt https t co q9sUYuYK0T Don t miss an evening with documentary all stars at our Detroit Film Theatre including <LOCATION>Detroit</LOCATION> native Thom Powers https t co aJtWwdCicL RT SalvadorSalort The 2017 Arts amp amp Health Symposium brought leaders of both industries together Let s continue to improve patient outcome RT AlleeWillis My massive party salute to <LOCATION>Detroit</LOCATION> THIS THURS nite DIADetroit https t co bXhzNch5RW Free tix https t co WiqPAPLmd7 Today the <ORGANIZATION>DIA Volunteer Council</ORGANIZATION> celebrated its 55th anniversary Thank you for your countless hours of service amp amp de https t co VATZcc1atg RT SalvadorSalort StarkweatherArt hosts my Oct 10 Director s Cut talk Join us to discuss my vision for DIADetroit https t co zIfZj RT dbusiness Get ready DIADetroit will host a StarWars exhibition beginning next May https t co zIJ6k3zsFB The internationally renowned <ORGANIZATION>Sphinx Virtuosi</ORGANIZATION> perform live this Friday at the DIA Free for tri county https t co Lxebyio2RL SphinxMusic RT SphinxMusic <LOCATION>Sphinx Virtuosi</LOCATION> at the DIADetroit one week from today Free performance https t co 8Vdx9pRl0x Tickets are still available for the second annual Arts and Health Symposium tomorrow at the <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> https t co NFBtlWAQmF ArtsHealthDET RT SalvadorSalort RashaadNewsome s acclaimed Shade Composition was a spectacular and satisfying ending to DLECTRICTIY DIADetroit B Could not get enough of RashaadNewsome s King of Arms Parade last night DLECTRICITY DLECTRICITY <LOCATION>Detroit</LOCATION> https t co 4oeSO9UPwG DLECTRICITY continues tonight <PERSON>Don</PERSON> t miss RashaadNewsome s acclaimed Shade Composition at 8 p m https t co hbP3oEYsVn DLECTRICITY RT SalvadorSalort DLECTRICITY lights up DIADetroit amp amp electrifies our city A celebration of light amp amp art brings our community together RT detroitnews StarWars costume exhibit coming to DIADetroit in 2018 https t co H2Y4feC4Bz https t co 53iyCtvfDT The force is with <LOCATION>Detroit</LOCATION> as Star Wars and the <ORGANIZATION>Power of Costume</ORGANIZATION> comes to the <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> May 20 Sept 30 2018 StarWars https t co 2Q7RnG5Ig4 Happy to host the <ORGANIZATION>Sistine Chapel Choir</ORGANIZATION> from <LOCATION>Rome</LOCATION> aka the Pope s Choir during a visit before their first ever pe https t co ifczfH3KYL Happy FirstDayofFall https t co BO4OT1DeB2 DLECTRICITY is here See light based projects at the <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> amp amp throughout MidtownDetroit Festivities begin at 7 https t co r1rZsPcMQU Can t wait https t co mXZfJFNIbU RT crainsdetroit Longtime board member <PERSON>Bonnie Ann Larson</PERSON> gifts 5 million to DIADetroit https t co 7Aj0pfMh1p <LOCATION>Detroit</LOCATION> In recognition of her gift the <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> has established the <PERSON>Bonnie Ann Larson</PERSON> Modern European Masters Series supportin https t co ZZ3UtuPldp RT wdet <LOCATION>Detroit</LOCATION> Songwriter AlleeWillis Brings Her Micro Documentary The D to the DIADetroit amp gt amp gt https t co GJ5AuQqHK7 https t co l Amazing https t co 8QPt9z73XJ REMINDER To better serve the museum s nearly 700 000 annual visitors the <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> will be closed to the public today for a staff enrichment Join us this Sunday at 2 https t co hR4nXsY5cb REMINDER To better serve the museum s nearly 700 000 annual visitors the <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> will be closed to the public tomorrow for a staff enrichment Not to miss DLECTRICITY https t co I5BIhua129 RT TheFIA While <ORGANIZATION>FIA</ORGANIZATION> is closed 7 31 9 16 <ORGANIZATION>FIA</ORGANIZATION> members get free gen admission up to 4 adults DIADetroit View exhibitions https t c RT SalvadorSalort Join us in celebrating National HispanicHeritageMonth with our D a de Muertos exhibit amp amp programs https t co <ORGANIZATION>BgzHTex RT</ORGANIZATION> SalvadorSalort DetroitHomecoming is about connecting w each other amp amp DIADetroit we bring ppl together Let s continue to advance the RT SalvadorSalort Thanks to the <ORGANIZATION>William Davidson Foundation</ORGANIZATION> for this DLECTRICITY sneak peek DIADetroit DetroitHomecoming dethomecomi RT SalvadorSalort DIADetroit partnered w Bmooralliance LifeRemodeled amp amp Live6Detroit to show the importance of art in public spaces f RT SalvadorSalort Among many industry leaders with strong <LOCATION>Detroit</LOCATION> roots at the iconic <LOCATION>Michigan Central Train Station</LOCATION> for DetroitHomecom LilyTomlin we heard you were a fan of <PERSON>Bruegel</PERSON> s The Wedding Dance Come on over and see it DetroitHomecoming https t co ubtoKqJOXx That s a wrap on our AskACurator Day coverage Thanks for your questions TaylorRAldridge lkmens AskACurator danmcknight <ORGANIZATION>Michigan Central Train Depot Canada Customs</ORGANIZATION> and Immigrations by <PERSON>Russ Marshall</PERSON> By <PERSON>Russ Marshall</PERSON> https t co YQlQwCugvF danmcknight It s a sparse image shot in black and white that invites the viewer to think about the history of t https t co o1AeFVCbJd danmcknight I do a photograph by American artist <PERSON>Russ Marshall</PERSON> titled <ORGANIZATION>Michigan Central Train Deport Canada Cust</ORGANIZATION> https t co eyRdSMMGRX AyList cont d see art talk to artists and do plenty more Every day is different and this is a good challenge AskACurator AyList cont d challenging part of being curator is that I wear so many different hats I write research give talks AskACurator AyList cont d I learn so much during studio visits and feel so inspired afterwards What is probably the most AskACurator AyList One of the most rewarding parts of being a curator is the ability to talk to and work with artists AskACurator quinsyg TaylorRAldridge distantdark lkmens AskACurator cont d of all backgrounds and how these contribut https t co do0uCOzeXB quinsyg TaylorRAldridge distantdark lkmens AskACurator cont d we are interested in internationalizing ou https t co XCG5cmFWxS quinsyg TaylorRAldridge distantdark lkmens AskACurator cont d including African Oceania African Ameri https t co fSaPWCTIMA quinsyg TaylorRAldridge distantdark lkmens AskACurator There are about 13 000 works by European artists and ov https t co t5Lw2aOqsU KaceyArnold3 cont d attending as many gallery openings and events as possible AskACurator KaceyArnold3 cont d I try to remain on the pulse of the arts and other communities by reading local publications and AskACurator KaceyArnold3 I m from the City of <LOCATION>Detroit</LOCATION> so I have been engaged with this vibrant community here for a long time Now AskACurator stuartandco_ cont d Is one of the most difficult objects to de install amp amp install due to the heavy impasto on https t co VxpAa4bFLK stuartandco_ Haven t had any major difficulties with install yet but from what I have learned the <PERSON>Anselm Kiefer</PERSON> D https t co cgufbCKiSV N_du_Time AskACurator lkmens TaylorRAldridge cont d We then propose works to our board of directors for a https t co kplEq6hBbf N_du_Time AskACurator lkmens TaylorRAldridge cont d To do so we visit galleries and artists studios arou https t co 97O0WqXzgR N_du_Time AskACurator lkmens TaylorRAldridge As contemporary curators we conduct thorough research on artworks https t co Oaa5NRXdto Dansplaining TaylorRAldridge lkmens AskACurator FYI this is one of our most favorite questions so far AskACurator Dansplaining TaylorRAldridge lkmens AskACurator cont d and could be quite powerful if it came to life AskACurator Dansplaining TaylorRAldridge lkmens AskACurator Great question I d say TonySmith s <PERSON>Gracehoper</PERSON> would definitel https t co YHhi5Gp7jk SilviaMansoor AskACurator We have reproductions of prints and works on paper by artists but no replicas of works AskACurator distantdark TaylorRAldridge lkmens AskACurator cont d Which is currently on view in the ArtofRebellion exhibition AskACurator distantdark TaylorRAldridge lkmens AskACurator The DIA is constantly acquiring new works We recently acquired https t co dBpI24WfpT saradoxical cont d Birds snakes wild amp amp tame animals are included in the piece along with a real insect adhe https t co H7H2TOoOHE saradoxical cont d In it he recalls his childhood experience of growing up in the American south in nature https t co D00wONLyYP saradoxical Ah It s so difficult to choose one of many favorites is <PERSON>Noah</PERSON> s Ark Genesis 1984 by Detroiter Ch https t co jFw6amcmgW saradoxical cont d I knew from my earlier visits to the museum that I wanted to work in one to preserve and https t co deX7fECJMq saradoxical cont d I became completely enamored by this massive place filled with beautiful objects AskACurator saradoxical My first introduction to art was actually at the DIA My mother would bring me here as a child and AskACurator distantdark TaylorRAldridge lkmens AskACurator No official ranking but the <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> s collection is generally consi https t co NlFdGUL5pj RT SalvadorSalort It s AskACurator Day Contemporary art curators <PERSON>Taylor Aldridge</PERSON> and <PERSON>Lucy Mensah</PERSON> will take your questions DIADetroit It s AskACurator Day DIA contemporary curator <PERSON>TaylorRAldridge</PERSON> will take your questions here 10 1 lkmens takes over 1 4 AskACurator Tomorrow is AskACurator Day DIA contemporary art curators lkmens and <PERSON>TaylorRAldridge</PERSON> will be taking your questi https t co 4tZVfhziE7 See DiegoRivera s <ORGANIZATION>Detroit Industry</ORGANIZATION> frescoes in exquisite detail HispanicHeritageMonth <LOCATION>Detroit</LOCATION> https t co a7m3vr3f9s RT SalvadorSalort DIADetroit and <PERSON>Nicole Eisenberg</PERSON> DIA gala co chair wish to thank <PERSON>Barbara Gucfa</PERSON> and AlixPartnersLLP for their genero RT dbusiness The DIADetroit will be hosting two major exhibitions next month https t co ZT1LDsCfco RT SalvadorSalort Happy to meet with waynecountymi to report on DIADetroit s contributions for the first half of 2017 Thank you for yo Can t wait https t co xZd6cLYOkX RT SalvadorSalort From Detroitk12 to nytimes The <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> continues to inspire with arts education Spotlight on Detroiter <PERSON>Mario Moore</PERSON> htt RT TheWrightMuseum During this event <PERSON>Erin Falker</PERSON> assistant curator at The <LOCATION>Wright Museum</LOCATION> will present an overview of the SayItLoud exh Join us for the Detroit67 Wiki Edit A Thon October 8 at the DIA Register here https t co OHMSR6N1Sa NowEditingDetroit67 Join us for a second series of free panel discussions related to the ArtofRebellion exhibition next Friday Sept https t co 97SsBYY6vy The <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> opens two major exhibitions on Oct 22 Church APaintersPilgrimage and MonetFramingLife More https t co SIrTRYWcLD CityofDetroit Thanks for coming Get an up close look at DiegoRivera s <ORGANIZATION>Detroit Industry</ORGANIZATION> frescoes at the <ORGANIZATION>DIA</ORGANIZATION> using <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> s powerful Gigapixel t https t co Q7GSXi05Rr RT faaaa_dia If you missed HotInHavana diadetroit hosted by faaaa_dia YOU MISSED an AMAZING Experience https t co xjjskhZ2gc RT SalvadorSalort Congrats to faaaa_dia on a successful night celebrating Afro Cuban culture Thank 