<ner>Zoomorphic weights were widespread in the ancient world Weights in the shape of frogs and toads were rare in the N https t co 7YjKAv7JpW Winter Scene in Moonlight <PERSON>Henry Farrer</PERSON> s earliest known watercolor landscape probably represents a site in <LOCATION>Broo</LOCATION> https t co tsa94CFbgV On Friday June 1 at 7pm The <ORGANIZATION>Aizuri Quartet</ORGANIZATION> will continue its Met residency performing an exploration of music i https t co 7fItPoN6Ey Before On After <PERSON>William Wegman</PERSON> and <LOCATION>California</LOCATION> Conceptualism surveys Conceptual art as it developed in Southern C https t co 3AdCmvGqbh Playing with Fire European Terracotta Models 1740 1840 offers the first comprehensive overview of Neoclassical https t co IOXH0tDHOo <PERSON>Ernst Ludwig Kirchner</PERSON> was born this day in 1880 This Portrait of <PERSON>David</PERSON> M ller is a woodcut from Kirchers Bauha https t co MkGMC8Bacm RT etammykim Just two weeks left to see the astounding exhibit of Mt Geumgang paintings at metmuseum many on loan from <LOCATION>Korea</LOCATION> and just This exhibition showcases more than 120 Chinese landscape paintings in four rotations offering insights into the t https t co 9LFT6hxmd7 Today at 2pm visit The Met Fifth Avenue for a free lecture on Painted in <LOCATION>Mexico</LOCATION> 1700 1790 Pinxit Mexici and e https t co JlVPGSHioU Tomorrow is The <ORGANIZATION>MetGala</ORGANIZATION> and the <LOCATION>Met Fifth Avenue</LOCATION> will be closed The MetBreuer normally closed on Mondays will https t co jU2UD1wkb6 Unearthed in the <LOCATION>Eastern Highlands</LOCATION> of <LOCATION>New Guinea</LOCATION> this ancient stone image may represent the head of the cassowary https t co 1OvHX1PQ0I The breastplate of this gusoku armor is inscribed inside with the armorer s name My chin Munesuke While the hel https t co v37tsqsdRV The latest Selections from the Department of Drawings and Prints include representations and designs for palaces https t co XcY2MCdpdE This blog post explores how women are represented in The MetLibrary s collection of twentieth century American and https t co x20kx4R9gF <PERSON>William Eggleston</PERSON> <LOCATION>Los Alamos</LOCATION> presents the artist s most notable portfolio which includes seventy five dye trans https t co LUObhCkoO4 How do you create a you are there audio experience when the there in question is a palace in an entirely diffe https t co BONGBHtUaL This Instagram account gives you a behind the scenes glimpse into special events at The Met https t co Uf0QJPji2N Happy CincoDeMayo May 5th marks <LOCATION>Mexico</LOCATION> s victory at the Battle of <LOCATION>Puebla</LOCATION> the same region where this pedestal bow https t co mrOX5LqZel Learn how conservators lifted the grey veil from final commission by the Renaissance artist <PERSON>Moretto</PERSON> da <ORGANIZATION>Brescia</ORGANIZATION> https t co gChdhhhvQF This painting belongs to a series illustrating the Rasamanjari a fifteenth century Sanskrit love poem by <PERSON>Bhanudatt</PERSON> https t co JwW5chLOHg The legend of Saint <PERSON>Anthony Abbot</PERSON> a fourth century Egyptian hermit tells of the saint s heroic resistance to the https t co Hc6Rbqo9HT <PERSON>Charles Honor Lannuier</PERSON> was a talented b niste cabinetmaker who migrated to <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> from <LOCATION>Paris</LOCATION> at the age of tw https t co GKLanUQWN3 Spirited Creatures Animal Representations in Chinese Silk and Lacquer explores how real and mythical animals suc https t co FrkLqneAUj Los poderosos gobernantes de <LOCATION>Palenque</LOCATION> un sitio maya ubicado en <LOCATION>Chiapas</LOCATION> M xico fueron enterrados con indumentaria https t co FELozhvkYv The great rulers of <LOCATION>Palenque</LOCATION> a Maya site nestled in the misty hills of <LOCATION>Chiapas Mexico</LOCATION> were buried with elaborate https t co d1tZqrQuQw <PERSON>Frederic Edwin Church</PERSON> was born on this day in 1826 This picture was inspired by <ORGANIZATION>Church</ORGANIZATION> s second trip to South Amer https t co pzAbfMiONT South Italian vases are ceramics mostly decorated in the red figure technique that were produced by Greek colonis https t co xbjBxFfLR0 Watch artist <PERSON>Katerina Jebb</PERSON> scan objects from <ORGANIZATION>MetHeavenlyBodies</ORGANIZATION> to create photo collages for the exhibition catalog https t co 5BxZ2n67Ee In this blog post <ORGANIZATION>Wikimedia Foundation</ORGANIZATION> Executive Director krmaher and Met Chief Digital Officer LoicTallon disc https t co iUoGk56e7S This morning at 10 am join our current fellows as they present brief papers on their research Some of today s top https t co uYT8uuCFzm This mask by <PERSON>Muneakira</PERSON> was already famous when it was first published in 1763 It represents Jikokuten guardian of https t co uwtupiYclC Pre Islamic forms can be seen in bracelets such as this one found in <LOCATION>Gorgan Iran</LOCATION> indicating traditionalism in t https t co Mob2d6uLbR RT JimMoske View of main hall of metmuseum in 1882 drawn by <PERSON>George Gibson</PERSON> for an illustrated guidebook published that year https t co Sunday at 2pm explore the vibrancy of 18th century Mexican painting with <PERSON>Ronda Kasl</PERSON> The Met s Curator of Latin Am https t co hNTfTRy86u For just 10 days starting on May 4 The <ORGANIZATION>MetStore Mezzanine Gallery</ORGANIZATION> will have an extensive selection of kilim rugs https t co vDw8dhKbc5 Save the date On Monday May 21 Members with Evening Hours Members with Opening Nights and Patrons are invited t https t co 7slIX51h8l This <LOCATION>Pinterest</LOCATION> board celebrates the dog as an Emblem performer and friend with works from The Met s collection https t co V6WajWblNC This exhibition closing on Monday May 7 highlights 19 distinctly patterned examples of woven bags from nomadic c https t co xCKujsyc7H For Europeans access to newly discovered parts of the world produced a culture that marked the unfamiliar and fore https t co GQ98UTpsWc Closing soon <PERSON>Thomas Cole</PERSON> s <LOCATION>Journey Atlantic Crossings</LOCATION> celebrates one of <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> s preeminent landscape painters https t co Ol70rZFLED This sculpture belongs to a series of diorite statues commissioned by <PERSON>Gudea</PERSON> who devoted his energies to rebuilding https t co hf0EmuCMUE Learn why several authors to connect this brilliant bronze figure of a boy with a fountain constructed in the garde https t co 0dvpxYE6p0 Learn about the art and architecture of The MetCloisters in this book available to read for free online https t co LRAkkjnFCi MetKids fun fact tapestries were hung not only for decoration but also to keep out the cold like a beautiful coa https t co E7QoJGMiRc RT JamesDoyleMet Curator <PERSON>JoannePillsbury</PERSON> discusses Moche metallurgical innovations with students from <ORGANIZATION>Yale</ORGANIZATION> in GoldenKingdoms metmuseu See what s happening in May at The MetBreuer Highlights include family tours and gallimdance and MetLiveArts n https t co lBOcqk75im In the nineteenth century <LOCATION>Italy</LOCATION> became an important destination for photographers because of the peninsula s disti https t co 1x1qWPLVdl RT m2m Get a sneak peek at the metmuseum s annual <ORGANIZATION>Costume Institute</ORGANIZATION> exhibition https t co ktWffyJsEa https t co 2b4okqWPiH We re less than a week away from the MetGala In preparation for MetHeavenlyBodies milliner <PERSON>Philip Treacy</PERSON> visite https t co PUT1VqBaj3 Join us on the CantorRoof this Spring for stunning park views and <PERSON>Huma Bhabha</PERSON> s site specific work We Come in Pe https t co CDX0PuOWRx MetLikeLife at The MetBreuer examines seven hundred years of sculptural practice and representations of the hum https t co dv0NrWtGRu This canvas of Mrs <PERSON>Hugh Hammersley</PERSON> is among the first of a series of ravishing images of glamorous English women https t co fn6pivBnig Military style decoration was recapitulated in civilian clothing as seen in the front closure shoulders and cuff https t co kyFvV6Ob7C With just six days left to go until the 2018 <ORGANIZATION>MetGala CostumeInstitute</ORGANIZATION> Chief Communications Officer <PERSON>Nancy Chilton</PERSON> https t co 9v1b8Odd6e <PERSON>George Inness</PERSON> was born this day in 1825 Inness who began his career painting in the <LOCATION>Hudson River School</LOCATION> mode emb https t co W1ZzRSJzPV The single most potent symbol of Buddhist ritual as performed in <LOCATION>Nepal</LOCATION> is the <LOCATION>Vajracarya</LOCATION> priest s crown This exhib https t co zkRdB7DwFu Dangerous Beauty Medusa in Classical Art explores the connection between beauty and horror https t co 6vnng2Tg3C The VisitorstoVersailles exhibition features The Met s first in gallery 3 D audio experience Learn more about ho https t co blgOnXqejr RT lizdahlem Making history More on the monumental summit between leaders of North and South Korean and the painting between them We sp Celebrate the first day of May with this 1899 lithograph by <PERSON>Edward Penfield</PERSON> https t co 4PWkjNN1PN https t co ucANvv319z On this episode of TheArtNewspaper s podcast a curator and conservator at the <ORGANIZATION>Metropolitan Museum of Art</ORGANIZATION> discuss https t co UJF77HjFYB Curator <PERSON>Soyoung Lee</PERSON> highlights two paintings on view in <ORGANIZATION>Diamond Mountains Travel</ORGANIZATION> and Nostalgia in Korean Art by https t co GyThcd4ZCC Curator <PERSON>Soyoung Lee</PERSON> highlights two paintings on view in <ORGANIZATION>Diamond Mountains Travel</ORGANIZATION> and Nostalgia in Korean Art by https t co hCY1hezZy4 This 19th century Japanese sword guard tsuba features a design of bamboo amid rock https t co 3lwcOeAjwa https t co pYsd0AGBp4 The overall form of the pitcher is based on English models yet the relief decoration of thistles appears to be uni https t co RxiHTktqE4 This book available to read in full online explores the traditions of Japanese storytelling in art through the le https t co 2gsqnl6NRZ hyperallergic visits the newly reopened MetMusic galleries Read their review https t co GBOgmYzeoP https t co o3vILXkxEo The museum s mission is to collect preserve and study works of art If someone is making an AR experience out of https t co uCabBdzZFe Painted in <LOCATION>Mexico</LOCATION> 1700 1790 Pinxit Mexici explores a period of pictorial splendor in <LOCATION>Mexico</LOCATION> as local schools of https t co kOc4SrZpIA Today is InternationalJazzDay When the saxophone was patented in 1846 the wind family lacked a robust lower voic https t co CcinO4hkXK Opening July 17 this exhibition will highlight how drawing shaped Eug ne <PERSON>Delacroix</PERSON> s formation throughout his care https t co gujI00EMTW This depiction of the Annunciation by <PERSON>Botticelli</PERSON> unfolds in a classicizing architectural interior rendered with one https t co gG13svuIUz Probably made for <PERSON>Henry II</PERSON> of <LOCATION>France</LOCATION> reigned 1547 59 the helmet passed as a diplomatic gift to the Medici court https t co KPrlJYH2z8 Este poporo en forma de jaguar utilizado para recoger el polvo de cal testimonia la excelencia art stica precolom https t co IlVFuChQ1s This feline shaped container used to hold powered lime is a purr fect example of the masterful artistry of the https t co W1SNphng3c This exhibition focuses on the work of <PERSON>William Wegman</PERSON> one of the pioneers of Conceptual art as it developed in Sou https t co m6FqZs11Ez Alongside the monumental terrifying Gigantomachy II <PERSON>Leon Golub</PERSON> Raw Nerve features paintings from the artist https t co GUvPIywh37 Just how perfectly should figurative sculpture resemble the human body This exhibition explores representations o https t co zqReCDUrR2 The first brass instrument the vernacular Western term for any wind instrument sounded by buzzing the lips into https t co hq7F9Ka765 Today at 2pm join curators historians and landscape architects as they discuss the ongoing significance and evolu https t co rvkLJaPZt0 Scientists in The <ORGANIZATION>Met s Department of Scientific Research</ORGANIZATION> use their research skills to investigate works of art in https t co UaqJdHd4pG The tone and volume of this <LOCATION>Tanggu</LOCATION> can be varied depending on the location of the strike Used in theatrical perfor https t co 7ti0HkiHYN Mountain Stream is one of <PERSON>John Singer Sargent</PERSON> s most dazzling images based on the theme of flowing water https t co O7qbKR98Y7 This copy of Nature by <PERSON>Ralph Waldo Emerson</PERSON> was printed in 1905 and resides in The Met s collections MetLibrary https t co ooXMiDMiPj In this blog post curator <PERSON>Stephanie Herdrich</PERSON> talks about the exhibition American Painters in <LOCATION>Italy</LOCATION> From Copley t https t co KvyPB7eNVf This exhibition centers around the celebration of the natural world and the intertwined relationship between poetry https t co pvkntqPfNb Here s a photo series by The MetCloisters gardeners with their bulb display of potted Hyacinths Grape Hyacinths https t co RSo1iMoj9x This Sunday at 2pm discover the ongoing significance and evolution of urban parks from 19th century <LOCATION>Paris</LOCATION> to prese https t co P8MfiQEzQl Thomas Cole s abiding passion for the American wilderness resulted in his fervent visual warning in his paintings t https t co MatkPE4qb8 The NewYorker calls MetLikeLife mindblowing Plan you visit to the MetBreuer to see it yourself https t co k1K05QpAj7 RT m2m In a brand new Art of Style premiering May 2nd the metmuseum s CostumeInstitute curator takes us inside the museum s stunning f En este Diadegato GoldenKingdoms les presenta una cuenta con atributos felinos fosas nasales en forma de espira https t co DCTMXaxmg4 The cat s out of the bag GoldenKingdoms on view at the <LOCATION>Met Fifth Avenue</LOCATION> until May 28 features many objects with https t co F3HIvUPWRi <PERSON>Julia M Cameron</PERSON> s portrait of <PERSON>Philip Worsley</PERSON> vividly conveys the intensity of his intellectual life and something https t co K79RF9awqT Spectacular large pattern silks were favored materials for luxury garments among the courtly elite of sixteenth ce https t co 4NnwAkYZTz Explore our map jump in a time machine and watch videos made exclusively for MetKids https t co VsancDyxSY https t co 9uNKZIdzh3 Possibly the last royal armor made in <LOCATION>Europe</LOCATION> this is believed to have been presented to the five year old <PERSON>Infante</PERSON> https t co zyku5QsrOy This large oval plate representing the Destruction of the Hosts of Pharaoh as described in Exodus 13 15 is a supe https t co kiFLPvix8v This exhibition explores the connection between beauty and horror embodied above all in the figure of <LOCATION>Medusa</LOCATION> https t co xbEKp2mFH3 This exhibition features more than six hundred works of art and writings by <LOCATION>New York City</LOCATION> teens who received the h https t co betzYnur7I It s the last weekend to see this rotation of Selections from the Department of Drawings and Prints which include https t co NH61KgsfsV Children s classes at The Met are taught by experienced educators and teaching artists who use the entire Museum fr https t co VLodzbhIgL <LOCATION>Khafre</LOCATION> built his own pyramid the Second Pyramid at <LOCATION>Giza</LOCATION> just to the south of his father s Great Pyramid This fra https t co wJGETlSFam American painter ornithologist and naturalist <PERSON>John James Audubon</PERSON> was born on this day in 1785 https t co vb7dEILuqW Join us tomorrow for Drop In Drawing Experience The Met collection through creative drawing challenges in the gall https t co zbtEd09ehE Eug ne <PERSON>Delacroix</PERSON> was born this day in 1798 Poet and critic <PERSON>Charles Baudelaire</PERSON> once wrote <PERSON>Delacroix</PERSON> was passiona https t co rzzcbWewAs Julie L Assistant Museum Librarian oversees The <ORGANIZATION>Costume Institute s Irene Lewisohn Costume Reference Library</ORGANIZATION> as https t co 0UqN7qtEKD As a curator in the Dept of Arms amp amp Armor I study interpret publish and promote our collection grow it throug https t co 0yNvvFoaKr <PERSON>Darcy</PERSON> and <PERSON>Jeary</PERSON> work on engaging young people with the museum s collection through various public programs and inte https t co MxNL0negT6 For MuseumWeek we ll be introducing staff from around The Met to learn a bit about what they do at the Museum https t co iWC5nNVjXx The chasuble s embroidered decoration seminaturalistic flowers curving leaves and scrolls is an excellent e https t co VMSpoSbuyS In the Directoire revival the waistline was raised in the manner of a century earlier Perhaps even more important https t co gdiJdurboV World Make Way matches leading poets with their favorite works from The Met Collection The result is delightful https t co 7xkMBftcLz hyperallergic explores how The Met uses Facebook Live to give tours in American Sign Language https t co H7m65ctGN8 Musical instruments have played an important role in the military of many cultures for thousands of years Learn ab https t co 6HsgG1Q6CV Learn about the conservation of The Goddess Kurukulla a beautifully constructed appliqu d thangka in The Met col https t co fRu3nvuceD RT artandwriting Gold Key art and writing from NYC s most creative teens are on display metmuseum Visit the <ORGANIZATION>Metropolitan Museum of Art The New York Dutch Room</ORGANIZATION> in the American Wing is presented as a decorative arts gallery rather than furnished as a p https t co uYhTMh9Ua3 RT m2m Andrew <PERSON>Bolton</PERSON> Head Curator of the metmuseum s <ORGANIZATION>Costume Institute</ORGANIZATION> takes us inside the museum s fashion archives ahead of this yea To a great extent conservation is the study of materials how they re created and how they change over time <PERSON>Lea</PERSON> https t co aX8Z3qB1xu Read about how <LOCATION>Ethiopia</LOCATION> s heritage demonstrates <LOCATION>Africa</LOCATION> s longstanding ties to the world at large and the resilience https t co QznKKJAS3r Following in the footsteps of nineteenth century artists who celebrated the out of doors as a place of leisure ren https t co HBZ0q8uPCb In this seventeenth century jacket floral and vegetal motifs are accounted for with scientific clarity but assembl https t co sx6T24qHvH Over six hundred bronze griffins heads from cauldrons are known today most have been found at the sanctuary of Ze https t co c9tV4RIkfd This book which accompanied the exhibition Art and the <LOCATION>Empire City</LOCATION> focused on the complex story of the prolife https t co EBCFh0hxPF In this interview Curator <PERSON>Kelly Baum</PERSON> talks about toxic masculinity as it relates to the exhibition <PERSON>Leon Golub</PERSON> R https t co dVEkQdhoIf RT GillianSuss We have a bunch of MetMusic objects that have roots in here NYC including archtop guitars by <PERSON>James D Aquisto</PERSON> played by N <PERSON>Thomas Hart Benton</PERSON> s <ORGANIZATION>America Today</ORGANIZATION> showcases American life in cities in each of the nation s four corners to port https t co ty6gEM4n1G By around 3200 B C the largest settlement in southern <LOCATION>Mesopotamia</LOCATION> if not the world was Uruk a true city Learn https t co wa3QcmjQCU The <LOCATION>Flatiron Building</LOCATION> photographed here by <PERSON>Berenice Abbott</PERSON> was completed in 1902 and was the tallest building in https t co B7P7v81wV4 RT gomezpickering Acompa e a la Secretaria mcristina_gc durante la inauguraci n de la maravillosa exhibici n PaintedInMexico en el met <LOCATION>Public Parks Private Gardens Paris</LOCATION> to <LOCATION>Provence</LOCATION> features work that explores horticultural developments that resh https t co 2uacJaSDSF RT JamesDoyleMet It s a great time to see art from the <LOCATION>Americas</LOCATION> at metmuseum Come see GoldenKingdoms and PINXITMEXICI now open http Painted in <LOCATION>Mexico</LOCATION> 1700 170 Pinxit Mexici opens to the public today The exhibition focuses on the vitality and i https t co uAfHaCRarC The traditional East Asian lunar calendar consists of a repeating twelve year cycle Celebrate this year The Year https t co hGLuMXq6bf Imagery from <LOCATION>Ilkhanid</LOCATION> and later period painting reveals that necklaces sharing some details with the jewelry elemen https t co Cxerpiie4m <PERSON>Andrea Palladio</PERSON> s palazzi villas and churches are among the unforgettable monuments of <LOCATION>Venice</LOCATION> and the <LOCATION>Veneto</LOCATION> but https t co OxmASYqkHK In this blog post <ORGANIZATION>Wikimedia Foundation</ORGANIZATION> Executive Director krmaher and Met Chief Digital Officer LoicTallon disc https t co qesRAjWrxX Learn how conservators lifted the grey veil from final commission by the Renaissance artist <PERSON>Moretto</PERSON> da <ORGANIZATION>Brescia</ORGANIZATION> https t co JT60QGpVjr Learn how designer <PERSON>Elsa Schiaparelli</PERSON> got inventive when buttons were in short supply during World War II https t co OQt3NLTmRM In this video artist <PERSON>Huma Bhabha</PERSON> and curator <PERSON>Shanay Jhaveri</PERSON> discuss her sculpture We Come in Peace which is now o https t co uoTZDaCNNe This blog post looks at The Red Queen as part of the GoldenKingdoms exhibition and reveals thrilling discoveries o https t co mTV5FQTDII RT GillianSuss Did you know that the MetMusic collection was spear headed by the work of <PERSON>Mary Elizabeth Crosby Brown</PERSON> AND that that its f For seven decades <LOCATION>Georgia</LOCATION> O <PERSON>Keeffe</PERSON> was a major figure in American art Learn about her life and work in this https t co QunJayM17a It s MuseumWeek Today we are exploring achievements by women throughout our collection View this tobacco bag by https t co NyyEyBQhis Most have not been seen outside of <LOCATION>Mexico</LOCATION> and nearly half have been newly conserved <PERSON>Ronda Kasl</PERSON> Curator The Am https t co zlYpqxjdhp Painted in <LOCATION>Mexico</LOCATION> 1700 1790 Pinxit Mexici opens to the public tomorrow Tuesday April 24 https t co bXTFtE1kux Painted in <LOCATION>Mexico</LOCATION> 1700 1790 unfolds in seven major chronological and thematic sections including Master Storyte https t co Vzh84utn6T If the names of these painters are unfamiliar it s largely because the arts of the time have been under studied a https t co wIBrxFZSkn As you ll soon discover the time has come for a new appreciation of the art from this period unique to this pa https t co BUPDeSAFS7 The volume of work produced by the four generations of Mexican painters that spanned the 18th century is nearly unm https t co ztuKaPCeUQ Painted in <LOCATION>Mexico</LOCATION> 1700 1790 is the first major exhibition devoted to this neglected topic The exhibition featur https t co bPId0ygINT The Latin phrase pinxit Mexici sometimes included in signatures on artwork means painted in <LOCATION>Mexico</LOCATION> https t co HGmb2nIlH4 The eighteenth century ushered in a period of pictorial splendor in <LOCATION>Mexico</LOCATION> as local schools of painting were consol https t co rmCZQTpuvL Painted in <LOCATION>Mexico</LOCATION> 1700 1790 Pinxit Mexici focuses on vitality and inventiveness of artists in eighteenth centur https t co Fn7oc2A20L Join us for a first look at The Met s presentation of Painted in <LOCATION>Mexico</LOCATION> 1700 1790 Pinxit Mexici which travels https t co 0O0gkytcSC RT GettyMuseum Getty curator <PERSON>Davide Gasparotto</PERSON> and metmuseum s <PERSON>Keith Christiansen</PERSON> visit the <PERSON>Getty</PERSON> s exhibition <ORGANIZATION>Giovanni Bellini Landsc RT Wikimedia Wikimedia</ORGANIZATION> and MetMuseum A shared digital vision https t co QWRpBRatIT The size and delicate decoration of this bottle are remarkable few such large or painterly examples of enameled gl https t co CtRiozGH5e This is the allegorical figure of Earth who holds a cornucopia and has child or putto holding a sickle in his hand https t co 5LnrK6LFz8 The popularity of Indian textiles is evidenced in the number of words that have made their way into English calico https t co qhdYW2NUWE Juan Mart nez <PERSON>Monta</PERSON> s was one of the greatest spanish sculptors of the first half of the 17th century This statue https t co SN88FiyFVD PoetryofNature explores works from the Edo period a time when painting blossomed in <LOCATION>Japan</LOCATION> and artists daringly ex https t co 4rfNlNbZs5 Before On After <PERSON>William Wegman</PERSON> and <LOCATION>California</LOCATION> Conceptualism at <ORGANIZATION>The Met Fifth Avenue</ORGANIZATION> surveys Conceptual art as it https t co AWA17mNQ9q This installation features a selection of drawings called Portraits and States presents a diverse approaches to https t co KGOkj1otyy Read about how the MetLibrary uses object cataloging software and databases to keep track of loaned books and manu https t co JBWRebHCKa Happy EarthDay This ThomasCole exhibition looks at the artists abiding passion for the American wilderness and h https t co 9au9UzNCLf Happy EarthDay This ThomasCole exhibition looks at the artists abiding passion for the American wilderness and h https t co <PERSON>LcTPqyYqwt ParksandGardens</PERSON> presents 19th century artists who celebrated the out of doors as a place of leisure renewal and https t co g0z0hdGVrh Poet calligrapher and <ORGANIZATION>Chan Zen Buddhist</ORGANIZATION> adept <PERSON>Huang Tingjian</PERSON> believed that calligraphy should be spontaneous a https t co wnlkhg3ws3 Often called earspools these ornaments from Moche culture would have been worn by a high status individual Moche https t co DHuU1xD5W9 <PERSON>Vasily Kandinsky</PERSON> theorized a new form of artistic expression that would reject the materialist world in favor of em https t co 7WACysujWj By the middle of the third millennium B C cuneiform primarily written on clay tablets was used for a vast array o https t co wcYGznMbF1 In this blog post <ORGANIZATION>Wikimedia Foundation</ORGANIZATION> Executive Director krmaher and Met Chief Digital Officer LoicTallon disc https t co GPzfFo06Fq The diamond daisy pattern in this amethyst colored pocket flask was probably made by <PERSON>Henry William Stiegel</PERSON> who was https t co yYzItFrMFI The sheer wealth on display in this show of pre Columbian luxury goods is jaw dropping you can understand why the https t co lLDzh6gVF8 <PERSON>Odilon Redon</PERSON> was born this day in 1840 Between 1908 and 1914 <PERSON>Redon</PERSON> repeatedly depicted beautiful women from class https t co m6HoV4NgNF GoldenKingdoms is a landmark exhibition of luxury arts of the Incas the <ORGANIZATION>Aztecs</ORGANIZATION> and their predecessors traces the https t co aj32eK86m1 TheBrooklynRail s podcast Rail Tracks talks with <PERSON>Jaykerrdobney</PERSON> one of the curators of the Museum s reopened g https t co NPwGbPWsTs Today at 6pm join art historian <PERSON>Joan Kee</PERSON> and artist <PERSON>Kimsooja</PERSON> as they discuss Korean visual art and identity This https t co K8GeGCCdee Streams and <LOCATION>Mountains</LOCATION> without End Landscape Traditions of <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> features more than 120 Chinese landscape paintin https t co jBgaZ3SSh8 This small silver bull clothed in a robe decorated with a stepped pattern and holding a spouted vessel shows a cu https t co y13o4wfeO6 This head was probably part of a ceremonial boat of hard stone that stood in a temple sanctuary Boats with antelop https t co MjIxmsoYtd Tsesah crests by Bamileke artists stand out for their monumental scale and bold interpretations of the head In cel https t co e58A0Ku57t This exhibition of works from the Museum s collection features watercolors drawings and sketchbooks by eighteen A https t co jSiJ9BsgJr This Friday April 20 The <ORGANIZATION>MetStore</ORGANIZATION> will host a special viewing and sale of limited edition prints by a celebrated https t co ujzBPhcdos Join art historian <PERSON>Joan Kee</PERSON> and artist <PERSON>Kimsooja</PERSON> moderated by Met curator <PERSON>Soyoung Lee</PERSON> as they discuss Korean visua https t co FMP6Socy6i Algunas de las obras precolombinas m s antiguas en oro fueron encontradas en los <LOCATION>Andes</LOCATION> peruanos precisamente en el https t co fU2e85h3ES Some of the earliest works in gold from the ancient <LOCATION>Americas</LOCATION> were found in the Peruvian Andes most notably at the https t co PP4W8YHJPg RT JamesDoyleMet One of my favorite things to see in the metmuseum galleries are NYC school groups These bright young minds are learnin Today at 1 30 pm instructor <PERSON>Beverly Hashimoto</PERSON> will demonstrate how to prepare a Japanese <LOCATION>Ikebana</LOCATION> flower arrangeme https t co Eu7XL581no Fascination with the moon ran high among the German Romantics This is the third version of one of <PERSON>Friedrich</PERSON> s most https t co y0anuijVOy Snake thread is a term used by modern scholars to describe the distinctive type of trailed decoration that is found https t co tMyX660QgW In this episode of The Modern Art Notes Podcast TylerGreenDC interviews <PERSON>Colta Ives</PERSON> curator and author of https t co Gp4hqOznuX RT PSIS18_NYC Our 4th graders recently visited the metmuseum to learn more about teepee models and transformation masks All part of inf Nepalese religious painting whether for Hindu or Buddhist patrons is conservative in technique style and iconog https t co E37AYTHpF6 RT JamesDoyleMet This shows a figure from a Mixtec mosaic shield made of over 14 000 tesserae of turquoise On loan from <ORGANIZATION>SmithsonianNMAI RT</ORGANIZATION> MsAndersonHNMCS A sunny morning in NYC metmuseum with our HNMCS travellers https t co h0oqycKrvV ncartmuseum We ll be tuning in to your tour RT ethelcentral Hey NYC ETHEL returns to the <LOCATION>Balcony Bar</LOCATION> at the metmuseum this Friday and Saturday night from 5 8pm ETHELandFriends ht MetLikeLife at The MetBreuer explores narratives of sculpture in which artists have sought to replicate the liter https t co tysSmCNTFA RT flynn_catherine <PERSON>Lee Bennett Hopkins</PERSON> s gorgeous new anthology seen in the wild at metmuseum this morning NationalPoetryMonth https RT CentralParkNYC Lots of magnolia trees are in bloom between the metmuseum and the Great Lawn CentralParkBloomWatch https t co x ThomasCole s Journey Atlantic Crossings explores Cole s abiding passion for the American wilderness and his fer https t co czKe5B9Ert This Friday April 20 The <ORGANIZATION>MetStore Mezzanine Gallery</ORGANIZATION> will host a special viewing and sale of limited edition prin https t co 6ASR5MCtvB <PERSON>Paul Revere Jr</PERSON> known from his midnight ride on April 18 1775 was also <ORGANIZATION>Boston</ORGANIZATION> s most famous patriot silversmith https t co Sc2SDeajrV This poetic depiction of a star streaked sky combines the long broken brushstrokes of <ORGANIZATION>Henri Edmond Cross</ORGANIZATION> s late wor https t co IyrZnz3fi8 Luxuriously woven in fine wool and silk with silver and gilded threads the seven individual hangings known as The https t co CeHVFDlaoP Saturday at 7pm early music vocal group TENETnyc and the Grammy nominated new music group metroensemble come tog https t co BLqxLfRlrf There s still time to vote for MetKids in the youth category of this year s TheWebbyAwards People s Voice Awards https t co pZvKCc4P8S On Saturday April 21 at 1 pm teens are invited to participate in this sculpture studio The event is free requir https t co NpN38QZgta This interview with curator <PERSON>Soyoung Lee</PERSON> looks at the landmark exhibition <ORGANIZATION>Diamond Mountains Travel</ORGANIZATION> and Nostalgia i https t co IBlj0u1Jle RT Scholastic If you re in <LOCATION>New York City</LOCATION> check out some award winning art by Scholastic artandwriting Award recipients at the metmuse Scholastic Art amp amp Writing Awards New York City Regional Exhibition features more than 600 works of art and writin https t co 111kyIJVnB <PERSON>Huma Bhabha</PERSON> s site specific piece We Come in Peace is now open on The CantorRoof https t co ENLll8Iw8i https t co D6R4iI6cCo According to the Roman writer <PERSON>Pliny</PERSON> the decorative device of the Herakles knot on this sumptuous armband could cur https t co xl8svMpcaX The mistress of the harim <PERSON>Tiye</PERSON> wears the voluminous wig and clinging dress of her time Her necklace is made of g https t co oiZcw0d9tL MuseumDirectors sandrajd Go <PERSON>Sandra</PERSON> go Thursday April 19 at 1 30 pm instructor <PERSON>Beverly Hashimoto</PERSON> will demonstrate how to prepare a Japanese <LOCATION>Ikebana</LOCATION> flo https t co EVfNmzWZe1 RT TylerGreenDC The spectacular French parks and gardens painted by the impressionists et al were themselves influenced by earlier Frenc We d like to thank <ORGANIZATION>Atout France US_FranceFR</ORGANIZATION> and its partners the <ORGANIZATION>Paris Region Tourist Board</ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION>Lafayette Trave</ORGANIZATION> https t co vG1MnAx04T RT masha_tee One of the best projects I ever created metmuseum with children from around the globe who taught me and metmuseum so much Meet <PERSON>Joan Elrich</PERSON> the volunteer who responds to kids s letters to the Museum https t co uBzGepe3NB MetKids https t co qdQr0SsNJm <PERSON>Huma Bhabha</PERSON> s We Come in Peace will be on view on the CantorRoof from April 17 through October 28 2018 https t co O4OpVNa6x1 They are not simply monumental forms they are monuments <ORGANIZATION>Shanay Jhaveri</ORGANIZATION> Assistant Curator of South Asian Art T https t co woeWLxdIfu I want to thank <PERSON>Huma Bhabha</PERSON> who s thoughtfulness dedication consideration and humor sustained and reassured ever https t co d7cvt6tLqx We Come in Peace asks visitors to explore and interrogate the piece and confront issues of violence social uphea https t co UplnlwFZtW jaydotkaydot Try lifting pulling out just the back disc Let us know if that works The Roof Garden Commission Huma Bhabha We Come in Peace is the sixth in a series of site specific commissions f https t co ZQYL7LEqPc Bhabha uses materials and the detritus of everyday life she creates haunting human figures that hover between abst https t co ogB0bFGsNP Born in 1962 in <LOCATION>Karachi Pakistan</LOCATION> <PERSON>Huma Bhabha</PERSON> pictured at right lives and works in <LOCATION>Poughkeepsie New York</LOCATION> Her w https t co kwv3EHG2em This morning we re on the CantorRoof to get a peek at <PERSON>Huma Bhabha</PERSON> s new work We Come in Peace https t co ChcNLyIJVs RT JamesDoyleMet This life size burial mask made of copper alloy sheet amp amp inlaid with shell stone eyes illustrates the Moche mastery of By 1904 <PERSON>William Glackenshad</PERSON> given up illustration for painting Yet his talent for quick characterization gesture https t co 6E0vhdEPJ2 This is one of a small group of distinctive vessels from the <LOCATION>Central Piedmont</LOCATION> region of <LOCATION>North Carolina</LOCATION> With its ex https t co VrKtDVeWcF The Cesnola Collection of antiquities preserves <LOCATION>Cyprus</LOCATION> s artistic traditions from prehistoric through Roman times a https t co tnxkAg0ZRi There is still time left to vote for MetKids in this years People s Voice awards with TheWebbyAwards https t co JOwsMGe9c2 This exhibition explores the important role of parks and gardens in French life richly illustrated by paintings d https t co l5haAHg8Lx In this episode of MetArtistProject feminist artist <PERSON>Carolee Schneemann</PERSON> explores gender politics and body language https t co mGlNMdsT5F Today at 2pm at The <LOCATION>Met Fifth Avenue</LOCATION> scholars and artists discuss <PERSON>Thomas Cole</PERSON> s relationship with environmentali https t co 0uZkBNHXJX Today is the last day to visit Birds of a Feather <PERSON>Joseph Cornell</PERSON> s Homage to Juan Gris The exhibition reunites https t co jrO1ClhLB2 Frogs are frequently depicted in the goldwork of <LOCATION>Costa Rica</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Panama</LOCATION> In this tropical region numerous species ab https t co BXecIyikFv Among the many momentous social transformations generated by photography s invention was the possibility of self re https t co Dlclvg35Kc The organ employs one or more keyboards to operate valves that admit air into a series of individual pipes which m https t co ildCEbHNXt MetLikeLife at The MetBreuer juxtaposes well known masterpieces with surprising and little seen works along with https t co XFoH6NskMQ This interview with <PERSON>Kelly Baum Cynthia Hazen Polsky</PERSON> and <PERSON>Leon Polsky</PERSON> Curator of Contemporary Art critiques power a https t co jU5T0DnqeW On TheCut watch our conservators give the famous Degas ballerina The Little Fourteen Year Old Dancer a tutu m https t co GsyOcCqOME Join us today starting at 10 30 am for a symposium on Like Life Sculpture Color and the Body Scholars and c https t co 8eWsmcNcL0 <PERSON>Don</PERSON> t miss the chance to double the impact of your donation to The Met For a limited time an anonymous donor will https t co ySDVPZiFBV This o daiko usually played in temples theater orchestras and at festivals was never sounded Instead the drum i https t co AQ4g28Dqov This vase of cream colored earthenware by <PERSON>John Bennett</PERSON> features underglaze decoration of pink and white dogwood blo https t co MeGdHTg5lm <PERSON>Don</PERSON> t miss the chance to double the impact of your donation to The Met For a limited time an anonymous donor will https t co gdNjY56Vao Support our legacy and celebrate with us by donating to the <ORGANIZATION>Museum s Annual Appeal Join</ORGANIZATION> our Matching Gift Challeng https t co cMSHBbSCbb Sir <PERSON>Thomas Lawrence</PERSON> was born this day in 1769 The composition of this portrait by <PERSON>Lawrence</PERSON> is elegant and the pain https t co sr1i5Bywh1 Few of <ORGANIZATION>Winslow Homer</ORGANIZATION> s watercolors rival this one for its effects of simmering sunlight and steamy atmosphere achi https t co v0KnKfZazj It s our 148th birthday celebrate with us The Museum s role as a cultural epicenter of the arts is a testament t https t co <PERSON>JXK4m0htoW ThomasJefferson</PERSON> was born this day in in 1743 This portrait by <PERSON>John Trumbull</PERSON> copied from the <ORGANIZATION>Yale</ORGANIZATION> picture was pa https t co LBgBCFmXEU Today is FridayThe13th Explore our most wicked works including depictions of witches ghosts bats and skulls in https t co <ORGANIZATION>N16AWOHSdk RT JamesDoyleMet Watch Teresitafz</ORGANIZATION> and JoannePillsbury speak about the importance of <ORGANIZATION>GoldenKingdoms</ORGANIZATION> and broader implications of coloni On this day in 1870 the <ORGANIZATION>Legislature</ORGANIZATION> of the State of <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> granted an act of incorporation that formally establi https t co 132qJp08BX On April 14 attend a symposium on Like Life Sculpture Color and the Body Scholars and creative voices consid https t co jdjwOGnThN If you love the videos interactive maps and online resources from MetKids vote for the site for this year s <PERSON>Webb</PERSON> https t co DPWmSfniG8 This MetMusic Pinterest board features pins from JayKerrDobney Associate Curator and Administrator Department https t co KLMqPb845O Explore new MetTimeline essays from the Department of Egyptian Art on the use of turquoise in ancient <LOCATION>Egypt</LOCATION> as wel https t co LGCxK8Ghky ThomasCole s Journey marks the two hundredth anniversary of Cole s first <LOCATION>Atlantic</LOCATION> crossing His seminal works ar https t co xkxh7pgzvM GoldenKingdoms traces the emergence and florescence of goldworking in the ancient <LOCATION>Americas</LOCATION> from its earliest appe https t co PnOsk8TWLR RT Teresitafz Looking forward to speaking tonight at metmuseum about contemporary art and GoldenKingdoms with <PERSON>JoannePillsbury</PERSON> and sa MetKids is nominated for TheWebbyAwards Vote for MetKids in this year s People s <ORGANIZATION>Voice</ORGANIZATION> awards https t co HZ5z29aDcc Today at 6 30 pm attend Artists on Artworks and join contemporary artist <PERSON>Teresita Fern</PERSON> ndez to explore the art a https t co s9FiH4NWuL This elaborately carved flywhisk handle was once owned by the Tahitian royal family In the late 17th century it l https t co Mog3Rm3HxW This exhibition explores the connection between beauty and horror embodied above all in the figure of Medusa who b https t co ykcyFfK1Rt Here is a glimpse of this year s CantorRoof commission <PERSON>Huma Bhabha</PERSON> s We Come in Peace The roof garden will ope https t co Bk4Kt2xseN Indian sculptor <PERSON>Ranjani Shettar</PERSON> combines natural and industrial materials in her large scale installations For Se https t co bCoyN0ycJ3 Tomorrow April 12 at 6 30 pm explore the art and culture of the Incas the <ORGANIZATION>Aztecs</ORGANIZATION> and their predecessors through https t co t6q4GaaMOD RT nytimes The <ORGANIZATION>Metropolitan Museum of Art</ORGANIZATION> has reached beyond its doors for a director for the first time in 60 years choosing the <LOCATION>Vienna</LOCATION> TheCut takes a look at what conservators did when The Little Fourteen Year Old Dancer a sculpture created by E https t co DvhsPovPpd Happy NationalPetDay This exhibition celebrates the dog as one of the earliest domesticated animals and a symbol https t co uBCGY7quOr RT JamesDoyleMet No puedes llegar al metmuseum antes del 28 de mayo para ver a <ORGANIZATION>GoldenKingdoms Toma</ORGANIZATION> el recorrido virtual conmigo en Fac From <LOCATION>India</LOCATION> to <LOCATION>Italy</LOCATION> and beyond arms and armor have taken diverse forms and decoration This <LOCATION>Pinterest</LOCATION> board highl https t co 1hf1L2rHrc Formes et couleurs by <PERSON>Auguste H Thomas</PERSON> is an album of sixty seven decorative motifs printed in vivid colors using https t co i6LiCCPKoQ Painted by <PERSON>Gustav Klimt M da Primavesi</PERSON> s expression and posture convey a remarkable degree of confidence for a nin https t co tw75Ywa8Lv Lithography was invented around 1796 in <LOCATION>Germany</LOCATION> by an otherwise unknown playwright who accidentally discovered that https t co R2WPqqm44Y RT majindat Cheering for metmuseum in 5th place in Webby People s <ORGANIZATION>Voice RT</ORGANIZATION> VOTE https t co OG4u8DzU5r Thursday April 12 at 6 30 pm explore the art and culture of the Incas the <ORGANIZATION>Aztecs</ORGANIZATION> and their predecessors through https t co 7j8gJlAPFW RT rpogrebin BREAKING The <ORGANIZATION>Met Museum</ORGANIZATION> has chosen a new director <PERSON>Max Hollein</PERSON> the <LOCATION>Vienna</LOCATION> born director of <LOCATION>San Francisco</LOCATION> s Fine Arts <PERSON>Museu Max Hollein</PERSON> has been elected the tenth Director of The <ORGANIZATION>Metropolitan Museum of Art</ORGANIZATION> https t co aGO5JyEGDp RT artandwriting Visit The <LOCATION>Metropolitan Museum of Art</LOCATION> to see art and writing from talented NYC teens The NYC Scholastic Awards exhibitio Support MetKids and vote for them in TheWebbyAwards https t co PN2maoyAmS TheWebbys https t co wyzFKPeHt0 Friday April 13 at 11 am join acclaimed novelist <PERSON>Francine Prose</PERSON> and Met curator <PERSON>Jeff Rosenheim</PERSON> for a dynamic expl https t co PH0YLFDmG8 RT VogueRunway Take a first look at the catalogue of the <ORGANIZATION>MetMuseum</ORGANIZATION> s Upcoming Heavenly Bodies Fashion and the Catholic Imagination sh Watch artist <PERSON>Katerina Jebb</PERSON> scan objects from <ORGANIZATION>MetHeavenlyBodies</ORGANIZATION> to create photo collages that show new details of e https t co YnUqhfBApV This exhibition explores how real and mythical animals such as the dragon unicorn phoenix lion ox and butterfl https t co GcTpc5dMY5 Heavenly Bodies Fashion and the <ORGANIZATION>Catholic Imagination</ORGANIZATION> opens in one month at The Met Fifth Avenue and The https t co en5y2c6B47 RT LordProvostGCC Fabulous time metmuseum NYC touring Islamic Galleries with curator Dr <PERSON>Sheila Canby</PERSON> amp amp Director burrellcollect <ORGANIZATION>James RT</ORGANIZATION> GlasgowCC Lord Provost excited to be promoting <LOCATION>Glasgow</LOCATION> amp amp burrellcollect abroad The stunning WagnerGardenCarpet soon to go on displ Many of the known examples of huqqa bases from the seventeenth and eighteenth centuries were made in the Deccan and https t co k2gWBw7fnz This helmet was found in near Tr voux <LOCATION>France</LOCATION> The quality of the helmets and their diverse find sites suggest that https t co vEQONFbdRo Ceramics such as this bowl made by Iraqi potters are among the first examples to incorporate calligraphy as the mai https t co 8P982si1zh MetMusic fun fact the audio guide for our galleries is available on your phone and it has lots of music examples https t co 4vv5qKSiqN This Tibetan style long trumpet or dung chen is one the instruments associated with Buddhism The dung chen is play https t co x85VimGkFP RT jeannewmanglock What was it like to be an 18th century Visitor To Versailles From <PERSON>Ben Franklin</PERSON> to everyday travelers a great new RT ZakMartellucci Apparently it s NationalUnicornDay can you spot the unicorn horn on display at the metmuseum Hint it s also a wal RT didihoffman4 Don t miss this exhibit metbreuer Seven hundred years of sculptural practice from fourteenth century <LOCATION>Europe</LOCATION> to the glo VisitorsToVersailles opens to the public next Monday April 16 https t co Kd7Lpmc4hK https t co aRyI62mPI2 Visitors to the exhibition can experience an immersive audio experience for free Using high quality headphones pr https t co jgBElAfSE6 Highlights of the exhibition also include a custom robe la fran aise and a fashionable French hunting costume an https t co 8thmrGecD1 VisitorsToVersailles was designed to evoke the grandeur and opulence of <LOCATION>Versailles</LOCATION> The exhibition includes galler https t co mPotx3FIkh We decided on a special atmospheric 3D soundscape to let the 17th and 18th century visitors speak for themselves https t co p66PeZe56X In planning this exhibition we realized we would have to work at lot harder here at The Met than at CVersailles https t co GqVmtVvola Despite the vast literature the topic of the visitor experience has never before been explored in an exhibition https t co 2WKSVfeq7k A number of Americans journeyed to <LOCATION>Versailles</LOCATION> either as tourists or diplomats including <PERSON>Benjamin Franklin</PERSON> who fir https t co NWO1W7lKe3 VisitorstoVersailles brings together works from <ORGANIZATION>The Met CVersailles</ORGANIZATION> and over 50 lenders to highlight the experi https t co 2Zi1jU1zxb The palace of <LOCATION>Versailles</LOCATION> and its gardens have attracted travelers ever since it was transformed under the direction https t co 5rUJ4WxWcl Follow along for a preview of Visitors to <LOCATION>Versailles</LOCATION> 1682 1789 at The Met Fifth Avenue https t co bVfiaFD4Ux https t co U0KrTakxOW Birds of a <ORGANIZATION>Feather Joseph Cornell</ORGANIZATION> s Homage to <PERSON>Juan Gris</PERSON> reunites nearly a dozen boxes from <ORGANIZATION>Cornell</ORGANIZATION> s Gris series https t co QEroXnNgZj The importance of incense in the religion of southwestern <LOCATION>Arabia</LOCATION> is reflected in this bronze incense burner the ib https t co fnJs9l206a Stone blades of various types and sizes were produced in the <LOCATION>Americas</LOCATION> as early as people arrived including project https t co SSJ6m0W0tB Today is the last day to see Provocations <PERSON>Anselm Kiefer</PERSON> at The MetBreuer The exhibition focuses on the German https t co gtorQepWLR Last chance today is the final day of <ORGANIZATION>Quicksilver Brilliance Adolf de Meyer Photographs</ORGANIZATION> at The Met Fifth Avenue https t co XJQcNXvHCL Today at 2pm Pop Art trailblazer <PERSON>Ed Ruscha</PERSON> will be in conversation with novelist <PERSON>Tom McCarthy</PERSON> to discuss the influ https t co 2jQIXHFJHU <PERSON>Tara</PERSON> who worked primarily during the reign of <PERSON>Sarup Singh</PERSON> maharana of Mewar often employed formal perspectival d https t co jw9RSlO1LO This book explores the museum as it was in 1972 Read Guide to The <ORGANIZATION>Metropolitan Museum of Art</ORGANIZATION> in full and for fre https t co tKeXrDJkrx It s NationalBeerDay This brush and ink work by <PERSON>F Droimer</PERSON> was drawn in 1912 https t co FAfdC9nsNt https t co Kcj4Veb4Lz In this blog post learn about how the newly acquired The Crucifixion was attributed to <PERSON>Stefano da Verona</PERSON> one of https t co hg0w3XsGnV This exhibition which showcases more than 120 Chinese landscape paintings in four rotations offers insights into https t co tgcwr9EBd7 <PERSON>Gerrit Dou</PERSON> was born on this day in 1613 <PERSON>Dou</PERSON> was the leading figure among the <LOCATION>Leiden</LOCATION> fijnschilders fine painters https t co odkQihJbUp MetKids is nominated for TheWebbyAwards Help them win by casting your vote https t co PN2maoyAmS https t co vDtWecHGo7 This exhibition features more than six hundred works of art and writings by <LOCATION>New York City</LOCATION> teens who received the h https t co Ngji9jyFPy This exhibition focuses on The <LOCATION>Diamond Mountains</LOCATION> perhaps the most famous and emotionally resonant site on the <LOCATION>Korea</LOCATION> https t co hVZFPdwFmw This remarkable vase was found during the Museum s excavations of the palace of Amenhotep III at <LOCATION>Malqata</LOCATION> in western https t co O2xCRiBKpV <PERSON>Jean Jacques Rousseau</PERSON> based the exotic vegetation of his many jungle pictures such as this work on studies that h https t co ZjJjTk4Mbn The newly renovated MetMusic galleries are now open to the public The new galleries feature dynamic kiosks and a https t co BZcaaU6EIr RT <ORGANIZATION>JamesDoyleMet Start</ORGANIZATION> your weekend off with a Maya GameofThrones New blog post on <LOCATION>Calakmul</LOCATION> vs <LOCATION>Palenque</LOCATION> and the competition of their r Saturday April 14 attend a symposium on MetLikeLife Scholars and creative voices will discuss aspects of figura https t co tI0PrxCCc3 RT voguemagazine Heavenly Bodies Fashion and the <ORGANIZATION>Catholic Imagination</ORGANIZATION> will take the viewer through some 26 galleries between the metm <PERSON>William Eggleston</PERSON> <LOCATION>Los Alamos</LOCATION> consists of seventy five dye transfer prints from color negatives made between 1965 https t co 6hPKdmFfvy RT TheCut <PERSON>Edgar Degas</PERSON> s dancer received a new tutu https t co Ge09tWBurk The NYTimes visited <PERSON>Keith Christiansen</PERSON> the chairman of the European paintings department to discuss the replacem https t co WFuBO6n2uJ ParksandGardens features some 150 works by more than 70 artists Anchored by Impressionist scenes of outdoor leisu https t co xFvFXw3b70 Hear curators and other experts illuminate the history and details of spectacular luxury arts including exciting n https t co hVdSmEqI9b This rare marble shell imitates a pelican s foot shell which is common to the Mediterranean They must have been m https t co m0z0gQWm5j During the Renaissance and Baroque eras amber a fossilized tree resin known as the gold of the <LOCATION>Baltic Sea</LOCATION> was https t co PJiF8ffCfR Met Curators <PERSON>Luke Syson</PERSON> and <PERSON>Sheena Wagstaff</PERSON> share an introduction to themes explored in the exhibition MetLikeLife https t co vYsKNiqtbh TandCmag calls the exhibition catalogue for Visitors to <LOCATION>Versailles</LOCATION> the best coffee table book to read this Apri https t co QjwtlbD6ag dantmaldo museummammy littlelenore Thanks for asking <PERSON>Dan</PERSON> This is an event for our Members and Patrons you can https t co nBMuJFF6Pp In the seventeenth and eighteenth centuries the Central African interior witnessed the florescence of three large https t co BROrV7cOVG During yesterday s MetKids Animation Lab our group began animating This animation was inspired by the composite https t co hHnSSKYkyk World Make Way New Poems Inspired by Art from the <ORGANIZATION>Metropolitan Museum of Art</ORGANIZATION> is a new volume of poetry which fe https t co OPi3REzuNe MetKids has been nominated for TheWebbyAwards Vote for MetKids in the Youth category https t co PN2maoyAmS https t co FtT52VMbqE a mind blowing show The NewYorker on Like Life Sculpture Color and the Body 1300 Now at The MetBreuer https t co 4kVxmFwWz1 Jean Honor <PERSON>Fragonard</PERSON> was born this day in 1732 In the work of <ORGANIZATION>Fragonard</ORGANIZATION> finish is a relative term Here over a https t co OW1Keik4k5 As avatars of royal power and authority in <LOCATION>Western Cameroon</LOCATION> tsesah crests by Bamileke artists stand out for their https t co c76b9iJi1B This work featuring meticulously rendered beech and basswood trees illustrates a new trend in the work of the Huds https t co AexO19l7xu These meltingly carved busts of father and son are surely the finest examples of the portrait style of G B <PERSON>Foggin</PERSON> https t co rm1D7W58pe This exhibition looks at artist <PERSON>Anselm Kiefer</PERSON> and his nearly fifty year career where he has never been afraid to wr https t co ZRfHAi5UeV Degas 1834 1917 available to read for free in full online is the catalogue of the first large scale retrospect https t co LjqO3NxkTB Although turquoise is closely linked with Egyptian culture in scholarly and popular perceptions it was in fact a https t co UD3S29Nmy0 RT artandwriting Stop by The <ORGANIZATION>Metropolitan Museum of Art</ORGANIZATION> to view works from NYC teens Art and writing from the 2018 NYC Scholastic Awards <PERSON>Edward Hicks</PERSON> was born this day in 1870 The Quaker minister and painter <PERSON>Edward Hicks</PERSON> is best known for his Peaceab https t co AzknATCVBy Quicksilver Brilliance is the first museum exhibition devoted to <PERSON>Baron Adolf de Meyer</PERSON> and his photographs in more https t co mAXuNcGzGh Los poderosos gobernantes de <LOCATION>Palenque</LOCATION> un sitio maya ubicado en <LOCATION>Chiapas</LOCATION> M xico fueron enterrados con indumentaria https t co bM8SOFIFb0 The great rulers of <LOCATION>Palenque</LOCATION> a Maya site nestled in the misty hills of <LOCATION>Chiapas Mexico</LOCATION> were buried with elaborate https t co A7lSl2vWt4 During the second day of the MetKids Animation Lab our guests began working on story development for their final https t co 3i92fV2R1s The artist <PERSON>Riza yi Abbasi</PERSON> revolutionized Persian painting and drawing with his inventive use of calligraphic line https t co T5bHr8ErMQ Spaniards arriving in sixteenth century <LOCATION>South America</LOCATION> encountered a rich and complex indigenous tradition of gold w https t co lOcy5tuLQM This <LOCATION>Pinterest</LOCATION> board explores the splendors of Spring and works from the collection that celebrate the season https t co sG7qcXE2BU Revel in the splendors of Spring and explore seasonal works from The Met s collection in this <LOCATION>Pinterest</LOCATION> board https t co 52XsEkOB1f Birds of a Feather <PERSON>Joseph Cornell</PERSON> s Homage to <PERSON>Juan Gris</PERSON> reunites for the first time nearly a dozen boxes from Co https t co DDaI4Pm2sL On Sunday April 8 join Pop Art trailblazer <PERSON>Ed Ruscha</PERSON> in conversation with novelist <PERSON>Tom McCarthy</PERSON> as they discuss th https t co vZIkZjXD62 Explore what s on at The MetBreuer this month including MetLikeLife American Sign Language tours and a sculptur https t co ZAJ8hOible Thomas Cole s Journey marks the two hundredth anniversary of Cole s first <LOCATION>Atlantic</LOCATION> crossing when he emigrated from https t co zAwc1518HV On April 19th experience all The Met has to offer at The Grand Tour where current Members and Patrons can wander https t co GnDg9UlTWi Copied in a minute naskh script the finely written calligraphy of this tiny Qur an is rivaled only by its exuberan https t co 5RKoFnjiL4 In <LOCATION>Harihara</LOCATION> imagery <ORGANIZATION>Shiva</ORGANIZATION> is represented as the right half of the deity his vertical third eye lightly incised i https t co 5sR3kfyfDB This tall bottle with its well preserved surface paint is said to come from northern <LOCATION>Peru</LOCATION> The feline association https t co Vp326c6LHc MetMusic fun fact the world s oldest piano is in metmuseum s collection It was made by <PERSON>Bartolomeo Cristofori</PERSON> in https t co IF7WK8k3kh This rotation of Selections from the Department of Drawings and Prints features a selection of drawings that pres https t co P9IjvIcLmN The CostumeInstitute s permanent collection of shoes is comprised of more than 5 000 examples and forms a large p https t co Uo3ZffjCeI The 2018 MetKids Animation Lab begins today Twenty young artists are excited to create stories inspired by compos https t co sfgl4dSDUR In eighteenth century dress the torso was encased by layers of quilted linen and boning that constitute an exagger https t co rqJl7gRXis Follow The CostumeInstitute on Instagram for updates on exhibitions conservation and the world s most comprehensi https t co mtVH7c5SCV This exhibition presents a selection of jade works that represent the sophisticated art of Chinese lapidaries durin https t co rOJ2FnhaW4 Check out classes workshops and special events designed especially for teens and connect with art ideas and oth https t co VYOLbyPruf Peter <PERSON>Carl Faberg</PERSON> was a visionary and talented artisan and jeweler with a devoted clientele that included members https t co ALgMEvCymn This painting by <PERSON>Giovanni di Paolo</PERSON> shows the universe as a celestial globe with the earth at the center surrounded https t co 5MhIyvANie Popularized in the <LOCATION>Netherlands</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Northern Europe</LOCATION> wineglasses with fantastic dragon stems sometimes known as s https t co LLqnrSuCnw <PERSON>John La Farge</PERSON> was born this day in 1835 When <ORGANIZATION>La Farge</ORGANIZATION> painted flowers during the 1860s he preferred to capture th https t co aMC5FRXaVc This blog post focuses on the specific pigments that artist <PERSON>Thomas Cole</PERSON> selected to create the richly beautiful and https t co 2IikENgNTO Some of the most potent political art of the past 25 years The <ORGANIZATION>WSJ</ORGANIZATION> on <PERSON>Leon Golub</PERSON> Raw Nerve https t co M68teq6RUo Although today we think of bathing as a private activity the public bath or hammam was a vital social institutio https t co mjLWJ8q0Si GoldenKingdoms reveals the distinctive ways ancient Americans used not only metals but also jade shell and feat https t co MmN7V8WttQ En este Diadegato le hacemos honor a una vasija que representa un ser mitol gico con garras colmillos y manchas d https t co 0ugxxEeWfE This Caturday we celebrate a vessel depicting a mythological creature with the claws fangs and spots of a felin https t co R8mvQhn63l The EiffelTower opened on this day in 1889 This Albumen silver print of the <LOCATION>Eiffel Tower</LOCATION> was taken by an unknown https t co gt411xa9ya This extraordinary French doublet is one of only two surviving examples of its type from the 1620s Made of luxurio https t co l0Wo01aHlZ Study of a Young Woman may be one of the three paintings by <PERSON>Johannes Vermeer</PERSON> that were described in an <LOCATION>Amsterdam</LOCATION> https t co 1BRXoQQ4YQ In this exhibition more than 40 examples of <PERSON>Edo</PERSON> period paintings help trace the development of the major schools a https t co oGYt1fKe8u Celebrate the art of music and the reopening of the MetMusic galleries with this <LOCATION>Pinterest</LOCATION> board https t co 7B49VlDHzX Today is <PERSON>Vincent van Gogh</PERSON> s 165th birthday In Irises on view at <PERSON>ParksandGardens Van Gogh</PERSON> sought a soft effect https t co 1DwLC2Fxty RT Badermasaker Today in NYC we at miskartinst signed a partnership agreement with metmuseum to empower Saudi Artists in many ways RT Scholastic If you re in <LOCATION>New York City</LOCATION> check out some award winning art by Scholastic artandwriting Award recipients at the metmuse LikeLife Sculpture Color and the Body 1300 Now at The MetBreuer explores narratives of sculpture in which https t co h6Ii8ssUnE Today is <PERSON>Vincent van Gogh</PERSON> s 165th birthday In Irises on view at <PERSON>ParksandGardens Van Gogh</PERSON> sought a soft effect https t co vifyn2Oqir Today is <PERSON>Vincent van Gogh</PERSON> s 165th birthday In Irises on view at <PERSON>ParksandGardens Van Gogh</PERSON> sought a soft effect https t co tVExNLP89A Tomorrow at 2pm award winning poet and performer <PERSON>DeniceFrohman</PERSON> joins the Aizuri Quartet for The Seven Last Words https t co 6lQsG0sVAO <PERSON>Goya</PERSON> was born this day in 1746 The Spanish master produced this print using burnished aquatint to achieve subtle e https t co vzkW0d0HQn RT vangoghmuseum Happy birthday Vincent Today we celebrate <PERSON>Van Gogh</PERSON> s 165th birthday with friends from all over the world Share your RT JamesDoyleMet Detail of the miniature double strung owl necklace adorning the warrior on the Lord of Sip n s earspool Spot t In The Crucifixion <PERSON>Pietro Lorenzetti</PERSON> imbued a familiar biblical subject with a new sense of pathos and dramatic https t co UW7tShIMLj RT TylerGreenDC <PERSON>Sanford Gifford</PERSON> 30 looking suave in a little 1853 self portrait metmuseum https t co i7fxOShIp0 This example of military headgear is elaborately decorated with three figures on the front It would have been worn https t co NxcPFV7PMI Dionysos god of wine and divine intoxication wears a panther skin over his short chiton and his high sandals with https t co R6hwD7pTZH Throughout his nearly fifty year career the German artist <PERSON>Anselm Kiefer</PERSON> has never been afraid to wrestle with the https t co B1xo1u9Klq Spirited Creatures explores how real and mythical animals such as the dragon unicorn phoenix lion ox and but https t co cWkx6bVYDx Tomorrow March 30 at 6 30 pm learn how to investigate a work of art through close looking and discussion No pre https t co i1SzWiC09f The exhibition <PERSON>William Eggleston</PERSON> <LOCATION>Los Alamos</LOCATION> features a landmark gift to The Met of <PERSON>Eggleston</PERSON> s most notable port https t co Vo93fPiYGP This book available to read in full online explores American advertisements of the 1890s and the subsequent revol https t co sNBigGZcFI cntraveller names all three locations of The Met as part of their 25 Best Things to Do In <LOCATION>New York City</LOCATION> list https t co lEQ6UPtola Today at noon join a Great Paintings tour and visit masterworks across different time periods and cultures to ge https t co OCSulZCAKZ And we re live Tune in here https t co eFTMoDmzgW https t co uSArufHfuZ <PERSON>Childe Hassam</PERSON> s summer sojourns on the <LOCATION>Isles</LOCATION> of Shoals ten miles east of <LOCATION>Portsmouth New Hampshire</LOCATION> were among the https t co TAh9lUU0F6 Popular at nineteenth century Indian courts this bowed lute borrows features of other Indian stringed instruments https t co nfx5PvTK7J Curator <PERSON>Keith Christiansen</PERSON> gives readers a behind the scenes view of how <PERSON>Raphael</PERSON> s <PERSON>Madonna</PERSON> and Child Enthroned wit https t co Gb26bjE9Rq Why were prints made Who bought them Read online or download a PDF of Prints and <ORGANIZATION>People A Social History of Pri</ORGANIZATION> https t co PPIJwwLSWU a thundering show NYTimes on The Face of Dynasty Royal Crests from <LOCATION>Western Cameroon</LOCATION> on view at The Met https t co fJHeAzTjCp This Saturday at 2pm Aizuri Quartet The Met s Quartet in residence will be joined by Award winning poet and perf https t co vg4ELwBy3a The MetStore is delighted to share their new text World Make Way featuring new poems by 18 poets inspired by art https t co Av4zgHQjzu RT JamesDoyleMet Detail of the headdress of the <PERSON>Se ora de Cao</PERSON> on loan to metmuseum for GoldenKingdoms Can t make it Take a gallery Explore sculptural masterworks dating from ancient times to the present during our one hour long Great Sculpture https t co i4ofEwG9Lx The exhibition Japanese Arms and Armor from the Collection of <PERSON>Etsuko</PERSON> and <PERSON>John Morris</PERSON> features several important p https t co AMPgQTYZ0W The fur the alms bowl the flute and the trance like meditative state identify this figure as a dervish or a suf https t co 2smRXXfDiu The Futurists celebrated the fast pace and mechanical power of the modern world <PERSON>Umberto Boccioni</PERSON> s figure s march https t co bbzKcByjJc It s WomensHistoryMonth Celebrate with this essay on 18th century women painters in <LOCATION>France</LOCATION> https t co WbP0t5gGGd The nytimes selected Thomas Cole s <LOCATION>Journey Atlantic Crossings</LOCATION> as one of their Critics Picks https t co slL31zykyd The expert craftsmen at Across the Puddle created a line of jewelry inspired by the exhibition <PERSON>GoldenKingdoms Lu</PERSON> https t co L8CTlKegej <ORGANIZATION>Artnet</ORGANIZATION> shares their favorite breathtakingly odd works of art on view in Like Life Sculpture Color and the B https t co NFGDDJLyko This year s Scholastic ArtandWriting Awards exhibition features more than six hundred works of art and writings https t co u1XqluQSrg In this blog for MetKids a curatorial intern writes about body ornaments from the ancient <LOCATION>Americas</LOCATION> https t co 2IWbOgVHWh Saint <PERSON>Catherine</PERSON> depicted in the delicately jeweled statuette was seen to embody the power of Christian erudition https t co SnWDe615bP Marble statues of lions were sometimes used as tomb monuments or as guardians at both ends of a large tomb facade https t co c5Po1hyPhK They re who you want to be but maybe you can t be because you re too stuffy Artist <PERSON>Ann Agee</PERSON> on the Villeroy Ha https t co ziIYa3qucU RT ItalyinUS <LOCATION>Italy</LOCATION> through the eyes of American painters What an amazing opportunity to explore our country one masterpiece af RT JamesDoyleMet Check out the Forests of Jade Sunday at the Met event held in conjunction with GoldenKingdoms Video available on th RT museummammy UMM STOP DE PRESSES paging all boriquas denicefrohman is going to be at metmuseum this weekend https t co TcfArQ9U RT Scholastic Last Friday Scholastic artandwriting Award recipients debuted their winning art at the metmuseum in NYC You can check RT erbenorgan A view from the exhibit Fanfare at the metmuseum The stops on the <PERSON>Erben</PERSON> include Cornopean and Clarion which are now In this blog post <PERSON>Dan Lipcan</PERSON> shares a dispatch from the ARLIS_NA s ARLISNA2018 convening for librarians https t co O9T8Kme3zc RT Vilavaite Cat Watching a Spider ide T k <LOCATION>Japan</LOCATION> 1841 1905 metmuseum https t co 8lDr0pjHrB Opulent jewels in the Fatimid period were worn by both men and women and likely served more than just an ornamenta https t co im2hQMdQ6y MetMusic fun fact the smallest instrument in the newly installed <ORGANIZATION>Musical Instruments</ORGANIZATION> galleries is this tiny Panam https t co frGEbftntr RT <PERSON>JimMoske Eva Kot</PERSON> tkov collage installation now showing in metmuseum Gallery 914 includes found altered library imagery https t co Gorgeous a razzle dazzle show Forbes on <LOCATION>Public Parks Private Gardens Paris</LOCATION> to <LOCATION>Provence</LOCATION> on view at https t co vrASPeArrq MetKids fun fact This large jar gets its name from its shape and color it reminds people of a full moon https t co V3wPzzkHg6 RT girlswritenow Congratulations to all of our incredible mentees whose work has been recognized by the Scholastic Art amp amp Writing Awards a The small exhibition <ORGANIZATION>Public Service Announcement</ORGANIZATION> presenting three exemplary works from The Met collection by Czec https t co xmqUOQ5Y4m Few examples of medieval Islamic jewelry survive leaving scholars to rely on depictions of jewelry in manuscript p https t co jNlZfUqgez In the eighteenth century formal dress was so closely associated with <LOCATION>Versailles</LOCATION> and the French court that it was https t co 1WqU4OqFTa In this video <PERSON>Dongsok Shin</PERSON> performs the Sonata in D minor K 9 by <PERSON>Domenico Scarlatti</PERSON> on the earliest known survi https t co aIwV6mTm5c Who knew sculpture had such a colorful history Listen to curators explore a few of the questions and conflicts sur https t co cplQd7oTxc A luohan arhat in Sanskrit is a Buddhist sage who has achieved enlightenment View this object in A Passion fo https t co QM0yjDtE9c American Painters in <LOCATION>Italy</LOCATION> explores how American painters have celebrated the art ancient ruins and picturesque https t co iy7tsyfaeO Digital Analyst elenustika explores the impact <ORGANIZATION>MetOpenAccess</ORGANIZATION> has had on engagement with the Museum s collection o https t co yczPsBIJSZ The MetApolloCircle is a community of young supporters of The Met interested in establishing a deeper connection w https t co G4WEp9UDBT <PERSON>Jean Antoine Houdon</PERSON> the preeminent sculptor of the French Enlightenment was born on this day in 1741 https t co SP6IGVX2Rv A self taught artist from <LOCATION>Pennsylvania Horace Pippin</LOCATION> only started making art at the age of thirty seven and later https t co agihdIUBE0 Watch a video featuring time lapse photography of the installation of the exhibition ThomasCole s Journey Atlant https t co 4DR2TDNVAx Assistant Curator <PERSON>JamesDoyleMet</PERSON> explores the artistry of a selection of blades on view in the GoldenKingdoms exhi https t co MRbaIpf2Qi The Bulletin for Dangerous Beauty Medusa in Classical Art explores the ways in which Medusa and other hybrid cre https t co 8vjC9WYfp9 The English textile designer and activist <PERSON>William Morris</PERSON> was born on this day in 1834 https t co 1j4mbDpPQc https t co iUHink9Th0 Objects on view in Crowns of the Vajra Masters Ritual Art of <LOCATION>Nepal</LOCATION> are a splendid example of the virtuosic skill https t co gSnnu2q0ij In celebration of the fiftieth episode of MetCollects the team that produces each episode shares some of their fa https t co Y1zzV3jJoP Join us tonight at 7pm for Women s Voice at The Met featuring three of today s most creative and expressive singers https t co OnW0sx4ghh The cat was the sacred animal of the goddess Bastet a great and benevolent Egyptian goddess https t co CuGQidLSAm This lute an extraordinary example of musical exchange between <LOCATION>East</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>West</LOCATION> is similar to instruments played by https t co qdkbsFQ2hb With the reopening of several MetMusic galleries this MetTimeline essay will help you prepare and learn musical https t co oQnOamSBvq This exhibition features some 30 works from the <ORGANIZATION>Kharga Oasis</ORGANIZATION> grouped according to the archaeological context in wh https t co R2ik9azpYW RT NYCDisabilities The Met seeks excellence and diversity is excellence <PERSON>Alison Rutledge Parisi</PERSON> from the metmuseum speaking on the im <PERSON>Juan Gris</PERSON> was born this day in 1887 The exhibition Birds of a <ORGANIZATION>Feather Joseph Cornell</ORGANIZATION> s Homage to <PERSON>Juan Gris</PERSON> pays https t co 1cukEGjPcM A curatorial intern takes readers behind the scenes of GoldenKingdoms as teams from across the Museum prepare for https t co 1tEdibeMcE Portable Storage Tribal Weavings from the Collection of <PERSON>William</PERSON> and <PERSON>Inger Ginsberg</PERSON> highlights 19 distinctly patt https t co gw4DTQXk5r Thank you for following along during my MetMusic takeover Tweet to me gilliansuss with any questions and make su https t co MRC1mzQtiT My favorite objects in the new MetMusic galleries are the mounts that disappear into the instruments they re hol https t co cvhgb9Nfno The audio guide for the new MetMusic galleries can be accessed on your mobile device or tablet Visit this link t https t co kRXjE9p1YY In an effort to re think the MetMusic story we borrowed artworks and artifacts from within the Museum that were https t co mPXtadaO1a As you ll see in the new MetMusic galleries there are several loans from other departments in the Museum includi https t co fo4h6QnE3w In our new MetMusic galleries we tell the story of music chronologically through time starting thousands of years https t co 4Qv4uIYmKi In our new MetMusic galleries we re re telling the history of music using musical instruments and other objects https t co lPLObXDHti Two years ago we closed the MetMusic galleries for their first renovation since the 1970s We ripped up all the https t co FUBEuaEonj RT walkergallery One of our most famous sculptures has gone stateside <PERSON>John Gibson</PERSON> s Tinted Venus is on show at the <LOCATION>Met Breuer New York</LOCATION> Good morning I m Gillian Suss Collections Management Assistant for The Met s Musical Instrument Dept I m taking https t co 2qX6plldEm The size of this core formed glass jug is exceptional The vast majority of surviving examples are relatively small https t co TowfkkbF3a This masterpiece of Egyptian wood carving was discovered in a hidden chamber at the side of the passage leading int https t co 0I1ViTDXEq The Royal Women of <LOCATION>Amarna</LOCATION> available to read in full and for free online explores images of beauty in Ancient Eg https t co x5O3tQMhz1 Provocations <PERSON>Anselm Kiefer</PERSON> at The MetBreuer explores the nearly fifty year career of the German artist <PERSON>Anselm</PERSON> K https t co z77v4rQUQA It s almost like if you could rewind the film and a second later he d be alive again <PERSON>Cornelia Parker</PERSON> examines R https t co DpmBBp1w6l GoldenKingdoms traces goldworking in the ancient <LOCATION>Americas</LOCATION> from its earliest appearance in the <LOCATION>Andes</LOCATION> to its later https t co ySytUxNH8W RT JoannePillsbury Sometimes we like bugs in museums Check out these wonderful critters from <ORGANIZATION>Sitio Conte Panama</ORGANIZATION> The one on the right h RT JamesDoyleMet Join us on Sunday March 25 for a chat about the Forests of Jade among the GoldenKingdoms metmuseum JoannePillsbur RT GillianSuss A look at our newly reopened MetMusic galleries metmuseum bigchanges gorgeous https t co RlWHLflmPS Read an interview with Curator <PERSON>Soyoung Lee</PERSON> to learn about her work on the landmark exhibition <ORGANIZATION>Diamond Mountains T</ORGANIZATION> https t co hoBDFYXpy2 <PERSON>Anthony van Dyck</PERSON> was born this day in 1599 The picture s warm humanity and elegantly rhythmic composition reflect https t co YRdD1w10j7 RT artandwriting You re invited to the opening reception for the NYC Scholastic Awards Regional Exhibition at The <ORGANIZATION>Metropolitan Museum of RT JayKerrDobney Today</ORGANIZATION> is the day Welcome to the newly renovated <ORGANIZATION>Andr Mertens Galleries for Musical Instruments</ORGANIZATION> metmuseum MetMusic ht This image from <LOCATION>Bijapur</LOCATION> made for the last of its rulers <PERSON>Sikandar</PERSON> shown here as a young boy brings together all n https t co Iy6p4eBNI2 The subject of this intensely Romantic work is derived from canto XXXIII of <PERSON>Dante</PERSON> s Inferno which describes how th https t co HyJgwNH6SE RT JayKerrDobney My favorite memory of the old musical instruments galleries metmuseum was hosting <PERSON>Ringo Starr</PERSON> and <PERSON>Ben Harper</PERSON> I m looki This <LOCATION>Pinterest</LOCATION> board features depictions of athletes and athletic endeavors across time and cultures https t co dgL99NNoQT Learn about <PERSON>Thomas Cole</PERSON> s love for panoramas These huge circular paintings created a completely convincing illusio https t co wDQWEfBAbE This exhibition presents 20 textiles and 50 lacquers spanning several hundred years all exploring how real and myt https t co rp9t6yzomn Saturday March 24 at 7pm three of today s most creative and expressive singers and songwriters from Muslim regio https t co MSIf7MYMJF PoetryofNature features more than 40 examples of <PERSON>Edo</PERSON> period paintings The celebration of the natural world serves https t co mihYibaHx9 En este Diadegato GoldenKingdoms les presenta una cuenta con atributos felinos fosas nasales en forma de espira https t co ZVCOIeuAMq The cat s out of the bag GoldenKingdoms on view at the <LOCATION>Met Fifth Avenue</LOCATION> through May 28 features many objects wit https t co HqVSWHBXxg It s WorldPoetryDay This tile panel titled Reciting Poetry in a Garden features a lush landscape as the setting https t co jPVVFgenKr Like the Achaemenid gold vessel decorated with the forepart of a lion also in the Museum s collection this ornamen https t co wgODvgbB6a This page from an anthology of Persian poetry illustrates a poem about the moon as it enters the houses of all twel https t co TScNjhcdWP In antiquity clothing was usually homemade and the same piece of homespun fabric could serve as a garment shroud https t co VVDPlXgunM Learn about the ancient Persian festival of Nauruz celebrating the start of spring https t co 38BUzVEeoJ https t co sJiEPjoxeF With its five simple yet powerful hand motifs which symbolize friendship this Osage woman s wearing blanket is a https t co m0EzBxptmj RT JayKerrDobney The new musical instruments galleries metmuseum open on Thursday A favorite memory in the old galleries was the day S Thomas Cole s Journey marks the 200th anniversary of Cole s first <LOCATION>Atlantic</LOCATION> crossing when he emigrated from <LOCATION>Engla</LOCATION> https t co Sl60ox48sv susavestheworld I m so sorry to hear that Please follow us so we can DM you and help solve this issue With its five simple yet powerful hand motifs which symbolize friendship this Osage woman s wearing blanket is a https t co jeJSJrYpNT With its five simple yet powerful hand motifs which symbolize friendship this Osage woman s wearing blanket is a https t co vmXgV1reC6 The exhibition Birds of a <ORGANIZATION>Feather Joseph Cornell</ORGANIZATION> s Homage to <PERSON>Juan Gris</PERSON> reunites for the first time nearly a doze https t co NvBdM0vBpn Today marks the first day of Spring In this allegory of Spring from a series of the four seasons a young woman sta https t co Pvivn9dMfA This book based on the Almagest of the Greek astronomer <PERSON>Ptolemy</PERSON> concerns the forty eight constellations known as https t co uQitwex25m In summer 1872 <PERSON>John F Kensett</PERSON> painted exclusively from and around the island he owned in <LOCATION>Long Island</LOCATION> Sound He ex https t co bPLdJtM0vY The current rotation of Selections from the Department of Drawings and Prints focuses on portraiture and diverse https t co tFvA7RWpi0 In the GoldenKingdoms audio guide hear curators and other experts illuminate the history and details of spectacul https t co QWPx1ltewU This exhibition explores tsesah crests by Bamileke artists as avatars of royal power and authority in Western Camer https t co nePlL8YbfN Like Life Sculpture Color and the Body 1300 Now opens to the public on Wednesday March 21 at The MetBreuer https t co kUk5o9t2WU Attributed to the cabinetmaker <PERSON>Martin Carlin</PERSON> who was known for his graceful furniture mounted with Sevres porcelai https t co jvIwajJqw6 The works in <ORGANIZATION>MetLikeLife</ORGANIZATION> will highlight the continuing anxieties and pleasures attendant upon the three dimensiona https t co rvF3NVhvd9 Without the challenge of thinking about how we might work together on how to make the juxtaposition of history tru https t co HUPcYwXWH7 The works display dramatically shifting views of gender race class sexuality and religion over 700 years Sh https t co 8yncEaeBn1 Since the dawn of history people have been fascinated by the challenge of creating a life like rendition of the h https t co hI2YAKlyMC MetLikeLife examines seven hundred years of sculptural practice from 14th century <LOCATION>Europe</LOCATION> to the global present https t co Mtoev9OmdD Join us for a preview of Like Life Sculpture Color and the Body 1300 Now at The MetBreuer https t co drsZ0s85SX Today at 2pm join The <PERSON>Charles K Wilkinson</PERSON> Lecture Series and learn about ancient gardens with experts from The De https t co wYqhjuaHgS Bacchante and Infant Faun epitomizes the dramatic French Beaux Arts style that dominated American sculpture durin https t co eDSPk4buVh Look inside <ORGANIZATION>Diamond Mountains Travel</ORGANIZATION> and Nostalgia in Korean Art the first book in English to explore the picto https t co 3bmSWT5zGh artsy visited The <LOCATION>Met Fifth Avenue</LOCATION> to learn about our copyist program which welcomes a selection artist to set up https t co oq7bDkp3Yv RT JayKerrDobney This Thursday we open renovated galleries for musical instruments metmuseum Here are a few of my favorite memories in t Celebrate AsiaWeekNY by visiting <ORGANIZATION>Diamond Mountains Travel</ORGANIZATION> and Nostalgia in Korean Art at The Met Fifth Avenue https t co OTQl8O9C75 GoldenKingdoms traces the emergence and florescence of goldworking in the ancient <LOCATION>Americas</LOCATION> from its earliest appe https t co wrZCMeWflZ Short on time Join one of these tours and in 30 minutes engage with great works of art connected by a shared them https t co iOODbTxYb0 This exhibition features some 30 works from the peoples of the <ORGANIZATION>Kharga Oasis</ORGANIZATION> https t co rMXnQB93wK https t co Ren4lYaW8S Today at 2pm curators <PERSON>John Carpenter</PERSON> and <PERSON>Soyoung Lee</PERSON> along with Professor <PERSON>Robert E Harrist Jr</PERSON> will discuss tra https t co 1sxSX2j2Py This chalice is one of an ensemble containing some of the elements needed for the celebration of the Eucharist the https t co RBABBYmjLD Created in the <LOCATION>Tehuacan Valley</LOCATION> of the southeast corner of modern day <LOCATION>Puebla</LOCATION> this effigy censer depicts a seated de https t co bFyFhODPaY Happy StPatricksDay This Urn from the Irish factory <LOCATION>Belleek</LOCATION> features wildflowers among a trail of shamrocks https t co xaN2i4kvFe This interview with curator <PERSON>Soyoung Lee</PERSON> centers around the landmark exhibition <ORGANIZATION>Diamond Mountains Travel</ORGANIZATION> and Nostal https t co f1wLwNd0Bz This exhibition explores the relative value systems in the Renaissance era by examining and comparing 62 masterpiec https t co dfqtoWpWs0 <PERSON>Leon Golub Raw Nerve</PERSON> at The MetBreuer survey s the artist s devotion to the figure his embrace of expressionis https t co XkwLEjrbeP Tomorrow at 1pm join a family workshop at The MetCloisters and learn about medieval artists and the materials and https t co 8JTezjtn4o <PERSON>Alexander McQueen</PERSON> born on this day in 1969 has been hailed for his challenging perceptions of the role of fashion https t co 5F8dfoQWFR During tomorrow s SundayatTheMet program curators and art historians will discuss traditions of depicting East As https t co tYdoXXJ4Hv This unconventional teapot by <PERSON>George E Ohr</PERSON> exhibits sophisticated sculptural qualities its punched in sides creat https t co W4ApNHthIb With precious metal tracery applied to expensive ebony this miniature triptych s hinged wooden doors invite handli https t co azXnKmM7gZ In this episode of the MetArtistProject <ORGANIZATION>Petah Coyne</ORGANIZATION> examines a Japanese outer robe depicting <LOCATION>Mount</LOCATION> H rai https t co BBzExxILEb This rotation of The <ORGANIZATION>Secret Life of Textiles</ORGANIZATION> celebrates textile scholar <PERSON>Milton Sonday</PERSON> one of the world s foremos https t co j7SC5GgYPa RT BloombergDotOrg Going beyond the use of traditional media artist <PERSON>Huma Bhabha</PERSON> s sculptures create a visceral reaction You can experie RT JimMoske 1846 ledger of <LOCATION>Paris</LOCATION> architects <PERSON>Lachaise</PERSON> et Gourdet documents interior decoration projects On view in metmuseum ParksandG French artist <PERSON>Rosa Bonheur</PERSON> was born this day in 1822 This <PERSON>Bonheur</PERSON> s best known painting shows the horse market h https t co zB9OMX9niM Dresses coats hats and full ensembles by the late <PERSON>Hubert de Givenchy</PERSON> are well represented in The https t co wrS2VzedFv The sound of the conch gave its player a powerful superhuman voice and the ability to communicate Learn about the https t co z6h1MbBtLB The American photographer <PERSON>WilliamEggleston</PERSON> emerged in the early 1960s as a pioneer of modern color photography No https t co 4s0PvofMR0 Today is the last day of our IDNYC pop up at The Met Fifth Avenue Cardholders are eligible to redeem a free 1 yea https t co CoGHe4Gwvv MetKids fun fact tapestries were hung not only for decoration but also to keep out the cold like a beautiful coa https t co j80C6KXvW6 This vase given to the Museum in 1896 was the first American glass to enter the Museum s collection The shapes https t co 6y7FT4wi91 Power figures were collaborative creations of Kongo sculptors and ritual specialists This example belongs to the m https t co ww2peqph21 Crowns of the Vajra Masters Ritual Art of <LOCATION>Nepal</LOCATION> is occasioned by the recent acquisition of a superb early Vajrac https t co fGHLAqthxP Beyond Representation available to read in full online surveys Chinese painting and calligraphy from the eighth https t co pQsJ3sFDZw This Sunday at 2pm join curators and art historians as they discuss traditions of depicting East Asian landscapes https t co hOlyxRE8YZ Popular in <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> between 1845 and 1865 furniture in this Rococo Revival style such as this t te t te that ho https t co H4UIbbATx4 The exhibition A Passion for Jade presents a selection of the most refined works from the Bishop collection of ja https t co 2vtnewAFta The centerfield of this carpet presents a geometrical design of a pointed arch above an octagonal motif The arch e https t co r395mftWa3 Superbly crafted in the shape of a serpent ready to strike this labret is a rare surviving example of the Aztec go https t co WMXHwrglIU RT latinainmuseums Not an exhibition review more like an exhibition reflection goldenkingdoms Golden Kingdoms at The Metropolitan Muse Tomorrow March 16 at 4 30 pm attend the Annual Distinguished Lecture on the Arts of South and <LOCATION>Southeast Asia</LOCATION> wi https t co 16kiHpXr5g RT yaleARTbooks It s almost spring we re thinking flowers Here s a fun floral themed quiz from MetMuseum that aligns your gardening p Dreaming of Spring in bloom Browse The MetStore s Spring eCatalog https t co LHq89CFQFU https t co rb3VD2zef8 One great strength of the exhibition lies in showing the art Cole saw in <LOCATION>England</LOCATION> both old and new https t co 492n9V7tH9 I think a lot of people panic and it s not just the claustrophobia it is the intensity of that experience Sar https t co 037Bpo8bOW This exhibition surveys Conceptual art as it developed in <LOCATION>Southern California</LOCATION> in the 1970s through the lens of Will https t co MLkyVLN9xk Here at The Met the people who take care of the musical instruments are called conservators Recently they worked https t co g6q8ojyTU2 Friday is the last day of the our IDNYC pop up at The Met Fifth Avenue Cardholders are eligible to redeem a free https t co lPngwfus43 RT JimMoske Always inspiring to share MonumentsMen field notebooks of <PERSON>James Rorimer</PERSON> for research projects in metmuseum Archives https <PERSON>Thomas Cole</PERSON> s Journey brings to prominence the dialogue between American and European artists in the mid 19th cen https t co MO8M8fzI16 In 1885 <PERSON>James McNeill Whistler</PERSON> captured a busy market square The result was one of his most delightful and comple https t co H5B0EaljFo This globe once rotated charting the constellations A unique object uniting extraordinarily complex mechanical te https t co 1DPxziWWo4 Now open Ranjani Shettar Seven ponds and a few raindrops features a new work suspended from the ceiling castin https t co CKvDAUUZAK Fine gemstones have been perceived as objects of value and appreciated for their beauty and rarity since antiquity https t co OCOGKVNOgO RT JimMoske Telegrams sent in 1915 by art collector <PERSON>Robert Lehman</PERSON> about pictures for sale in <LOCATION>Europe</LOCATION> From metmuseum <ORGANIZATION>Lehman</ORGANIZATION> papers https The Metropolitan Museum of Art welcomes all visitors and affirms its commitment to offering programs and services t https t co 0NmLOyUZS5 Join us tomorrow Wednesday 14 at 1 30pm for a Tea Ceremony demonstration in Gallery 227 at The Met Fifth Ave https t co E13qm6K04Q The sexual energy with which this painting is charged is rarely equalled in Tibetan art learn about a newly ac https t co v7EACKFljY RT IDNYC Friday is the last day of our metmuseum pop up site IDNYC cardholders are eligible to redeem a FREE 1 year membership to the <ORGANIZATION>M RT</ORGANIZATION> JamesDoyleMet The britishmuseum <ORGANIZATION>Codex Tepetlaoztoc</ORGANIZATION> on view in GoldenKingdoms documents indigenous sovereignty and its demise after c If you are eager for spring and summer to bloom then you ll swoon aplenty over the gorgeous new Public Parks Pr https t co tLlnvnTtmP Painting blossomed in <LOCATION>Japan</LOCATION> during the Edo period 1615 1868 as artists daringly experimented with conventional st https t co yQgrQ2LVbp This impressive polychrome bottle has a modeled feline head at the neck and a flattened canteenlike chamber Read m https t co G8zx2YIDdM RT wwd <ORGANIZATION>Yu Holdings</ORGANIZATION> establishes endowment for curator in charge at The <ORGANIZATION>Costume Institute</ORGANIZATION> https t co w7Y8JCylE7 https t co bf9NLk5JJy By 1915 <PERSON>Paul Klee</PERSON> had devised the unique style of abstracted forms and symbols that characterized much of his later https t co r0lJ3ZGI4o <PERSON>Adolf de Meyer</PERSON> was a pioneering photographer known for creating works that transformed reality into a beautiful fa https t co m3TJQUiyy6 The text Adorning the World Art of the <LOCATION>Marquesas Islands</LOCATION> available to read in full online for free explores th https t co oF88CCHaJE This selective survey of <PERSON>Leon Golub</PERSON> s work at The MetBreuer examines <PERSON>Golub</PERSON> s devotion to the figure his embrace o https t co GvjRsA3WuZ Can you name 5womenartists Celebrate WomensHistoryMonth by learning about the artistic contributions of women th https t co WpWvrpgbyS <PERSON>Anton Raphael Mengs</PERSON> was born on this day in 1728 <PERSON>Mengs</PERSON> born in <LOCATION>Bohemia</LOCATION> was for the most part trained in <LOCATION>Rome</LOCATION> wh https t co SbPsJNESrc Opening today <LOCATION>Public Parks Private Gardens Paris</LOCATION> to <LOCATION>Provence</LOCATION> explores horticultural developments that reshaped https t co Dci2M7AITi The composition of this picture is splendidly orchestrated with a striking effect of unity and emphasis that did n https t co XQo0NBdm6W Emily de Forest rightly considered this Mexican mid 17th century basin decorated with a bold pattern of cobalt bl https t co 9hkloSqyA1 The <ORGANIZATION>Department of Drawings amp amp Prints</ORGANIZATION> boasts more than one million drawings prints and illustrated books made in Eu https t co pJpjwLFBX7 In this episode of The MetArtistProject <PERSON>Annabeth Rosen</PERSON> examines ceramic deer figurines in The American Wing s vis https t co UPubP0YPkt Inside The Met s <LOCATION>Appleton</LOCATION> organ there are over 800 pipes Each pipe needs to be tuned regularly just like a guitar https t co sru3fvYsyb Get a behind the scenes look at The Met s Department of Objects Conservation on Instagram https t co xYl4QKm4Gx https t co JK9O074Be3 Spring is around the corner celebrate with blossoming works on this <LOCATION>Pinterest</LOCATION> board https t co b6fUqeDpTI https t co ZDJhLPmtl5 Join today and be a part of what makes The Met so extraordinary Members receive free express admission and compli https t co nevCtSqrWS This exhibition Portable Storage highlights 19 distinctly patterned examples of woven bags from nomadic cultures https t co N71YQZVpkp In the eighteenth century porcelain figures depicting characters from the Italian commedia dell arte were extremel https t co CsYbaa2pmz This picture was made by <PERSON>Jean</PERSON> L on G r me after he returned to <LOCATION>Paris</LOCATION> from a twelve week journey to the <LOCATION>Near East</LOCATION> in https t co 7ChNLzSUzP Curator <PERSON>Joanne Pillsbury</PERSON> takes a look at some of the women of power from the ancient <LOCATION>Americas</LOCATION> featured in the https t co umD6Vv7iMd This exhibition focuses on The <LOCATION>Diamond Mountains</LOCATION> perhaps the most famous and emotionally resonant site on the <LOCATION>Korea</LOCATION> https t co l9PGctx3Wm Provocations <PERSON>Anselm Kiefer</PERSON> at The MetBreuer includes works by the artist that remain a visceral and poetic cons https t co OLXYR4LFxJ On Friday March 16 at 4 30pm attend the Annual Distinguished Lecture on the Arts of South and <LOCATION>Southeast Asia</LOCATION> an https t co fljEEGnghi Valuing the presence of personality in a work more than mere technical skill the Ming scholar painter aimed for ma https t co Bw1otApH2U Since July of last year The <ORGANIZATION>MetLibrary</ORGANIZATION> has added over eight hundred titles just over twenty three thousand pages https t co 1iVuJ8TCZX Tonight at 7pm attend the <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> Premiere of The <ORGANIZATION>House Is Black Media Project</ORGANIZATION> a mesmerizing multimedia tribu https t co UCum0cZwEG Vel zquez painted some of his most vibrant and animated portraits while in <LOCATION>Italy</LOCATION> from 1649 to 1650 This one was mo https t co QI85lxNOaO Between 1939 and 1942 <PERSON>Marsden Hartley</PERSON> created more than eighteen bold paintings of <LOCATION>Maine</LOCATION> s highest peak <LOCATION>Mount Kat</LOCATION> https t co iiEWxTuzED These meltingly carved busts of father and son are surely the finest examples of the portrait style of G B <PERSON>Foggin</PERSON> https t co XK0xwn3vkG Associated with royalty and symbolizing beauty immortality and exoticism the peacock has long been a favorite mot https t co 9jWDSKcPC1 Bringing together masterpieces of 16th century northern European art this exhibition revolves around questions of https t co xB4hPwatAV <PERSON>Leon Golub Raw Nerve</PERSON> at The MetBreuer explores <PERSON>Golub</PERSON> s incisive perspective on the catastrophes that afflict hu https t co qN4deDx4wi RT BMacJ Dare I say sphinx sie Visits are never long enough at the metmuseum themet museum arts https t co 3gzIbI9m7D RT JamesDoyleMet The Se ora de Cao a powerful Moche ruler had 44 gold and silver nose ornaments in her funerary bundle ca AD 400 All RT <ORGANIZATION>LACMA</ORGANIZATION> Don t miss the chance to see Painted in <LOCATION>Mexico</LOCATION> 1700 1790 Pinxit Mexici which the latimes described as one of the most mem <LOCATION>Egypt</LOCATION> s Third Intermediate Period laid the foundation for many changes that are observable in art and culture throu https t co blEarmCtHS Tonight at 6pm join artist <PERSON>SHONIBARESTUDIO</PERSON> as he discusses a career committed to exploring contemporary African i https t co vqcNr5d0ib In this interview <PERSON>Kathryn Galley Galitz</PERSON> kcgalitz author of MasterpiecePaintings at The Metropolitan Museum o https t co BvLw4mK7Va The Met Fifth Avenue will serve as a registration site for IDNYC from March 5 9 and March 12 16 Visit our website https t co zLmsRhqs6b The massive black trunk of an ancient plum tree with bending twisting branches spans nearly sixteen feet across fo https t co iwMH7vY70E By the mid 1880s crazy quilts were so popular that enterprising manufacturers offered them in ready to sew kits w https t co LN0fzfJ1Vr Sojourner Truth sits for one of the war s most iconic portraits in an anonymous photographer s studio likely in De https t co a4FJEPaiED <PERSON>Mary Cassatt</PERSON> painted this self portrait a year after <PERSON>Edgar Degas</PERSON> invited her to exhibit with the Impressionists https t co 6kFlCFxS5y Beginning in the fifth century B C <PERSON>Medusa</PERSON> became increasingly anthropomorphic and feminine This exhibition explo https t co sbyGztnmHx This woodblock print is from the Edo period and was printed in 1793 Year of the Goat It depicts a woman young wo https t co ZAQ7gC3hP2 In celebration of InternationalWomensDay curator <PERSON>JoannePillsbury</PERSON> takes a look at some of the women of power from https t co 3kwj5ABPAW This monumental head gives an impression of sovereign calm and power She was worshiped as an Egyptian goddess in a https t co KJLk80JK2G On this pictorial quilt appliqu d vignettes depict soldiers who fought in the American Civil War assuredly still https t co YJchD61tmG Since founding Comme <PERSON>des Gar</PERSON> ons like some boys in 1969 the <LOCATION>Tokyo</LOCATION> based designer <PERSON>Rei Kawakubo</PERSON> has consistently https t co lbjgC6jwhW From 1857 <PERSON>Emily Mary Osborn</PERSON> was active in feminist causes joining the newly established <ORGANIZATION>Society of Female Artists</ORGANIZATION> https t co PIvg9d56kK Friday at 6 30 pm join British Nigerian artist <PERSON>Yinka Shonibare</PERSON> as he discusses a career committed to exploring con https t co 4JhOJ09UMT In this blog post learn how the exhibition ThomasCole s <ORGANIZATION>Journey Atlantic Crossings</ORGANIZATION> and its catalogue re examin https t co Ww2NmHgLoH Saturday March 10 at 7pm the creative visions of two of <LOCATION>Iran</LOCATION> s most fiercely creative female artists converge on https t co zSSvdrctRj The Met Fifth Avenue will serve as a registration site for IDNYC from March 5 9 and March 12 16 Visit our website https t co iIQceWnXFJ In the GoldenKingdoms audio guide hear curators and other experts illuminate the history and details of spectacul https t co UFV0Dliexa <PERSON>Piet Mondrian</PERSON> was born this day in 1872 This is an early example of the geometric mode of painting that <PERSON>Mondrian</PERSON> https t co syyMaeRt5I RT kcgalitz <PERSON>Gustave Courbet</PERSON> Bouquet of Flowers 1862 63 A much needed burst of spring as seen in <LOCATION>Parksandgardens</LOCATION> now open metmuseum The great Indian fruit bat Pteropus giganteus is frontally displayed with one wing out stretched The body is sho https t co 9pkoQMLV6o This domed cup supported by the figure of a bearded <PERSON>Turk</PERSON> is richly decorated in many precious materials worked in a https t co Apm7XkFPvU This drawing by <PERSON>Hendrik Meijer</PERSON> titled March was done in varying chalks inks and watercolor https t co Di8E67bF8o Just in time for spring explore the latest catalogue from The MetStore https t co LHq89CFQFU https t co o7MWw23e6G The development of plastics from the mid nineteenth century to the present has profoundly changed the materials of https t co tFTCyPMjl0 GoldenKingdoms es una destacada exposici n del arte suntuario en la Am rica precolombina Alfonx habla con la cur https t co GsYTb3HHQ7 There s less than a week left to see Silver Caesars an exhibition dedicated to the extraordinary set of 12 silver https t co Fce9zZW88j RT openculture The Artist Project Reveals What 127 Influential Artists See When They Look at Art An Acclaimed Video Series from The MetKids Fun Fact This dress is made of silk a fabric that co