<ner>RT camdiary <LOCATION>Cambridge</LOCATION> on a SundayMorning 6 May 2018 https t co IBC8XgAStW The greatest director in the world right now <PERSON>Lucrecia Martel</PERSON> is this year s filmmaker in residence at https t co tqJdqMWB5T Methane is a greenhouse gas at least twenty five times more potent than carbon dioxide https t co auG9uaCPjt Look what we found in theUL Tower while working on the ulTallTales exhibition it s only a mint first edition https t co iDI9da14QF RT Kings_College There are still places left for our BME Open Day on 25th June Registration info here https t co sRqAMP4f5r BB_STE Flourishing reed beds created by changing climates could threaten to double the already significant methane product https t co 9QudVzK94a RT ChuArchives OnThisDay in 1979 <PERSON>Margaret Thatcher</PERSON> arrived in <LOCATION>Downing Street</LOCATION> and recited an adaption of the prayer of <PERSON>St Francis</PERSON> of <PERSON>Assi</PERSON> The star rower whose research examines teachers perceptions of intelligence https t co 9d4rz4JH8e https t co mIojR12Yp9 Professor <PERSON>Lynn Gladden</PERSON> has been selected to be the next Executive Chair of EPSRC the <LOCATION>UK</LOCATION> s main funder for researc https t co rqRw0nZLWJ RT Cambridge_Eng Our outstanding performance in research amp amp development has been recognised by <ORGANIZATION>Boeing</ORGANIZATION> in its 2017 Supplier of the Year RT d_spiegel Have up to 270 women died by missing a breast screening appointment letter My doubts here https t co 7aOmTYXOkp 17 storeys high and home to nearly one million banished books the Tower theUL is a national treasure that tells https t co akZE9vXgxJ I have never been a fan of the multiverse <PERSON>Stephen Hawking</PERSON> s final paper published https t co UovHfTz8v4 Taming the multiverse <PERSON>Stephen Hawking</PERSON> s final theory about the big bang https t co UovHfTz8v4 Tall Tales Secrets of the Tower is now officially OPEN theUL If you simply can t wait to visit you can take a sn https t co vjb2eWfRJT RT cu_mat Congratulations to the GaN group team of <PERSON>Humphreys Thomas</PERSON> and <PERSON>Guiney</PERSON> in raising 2 9M in VC funds for their spin out <PERSON>Paragra Stephen Hawking</PERSON> s final academic paper submitted before his death earlier this year has now been published https t co UovHfTQJTE Celebrating 10 years of helping to strengthen research capacity and scholarship in African universities and researc https t co 5Z67DoiR2b RT CamUniLibrarian Hundreds of years of British history through 1000s of books stacked high into the sky a glimpse of the secrets of Cam RT BBCBreakfast A tower of books opening to the public and also dispelling certain myths theUL https t co mbmOCtx1r2 RT camdiary A tribute to all the <LOCATION>Cambridge</LOCATION> gardeners Thank you for making the city so beautiful https t co rBcy1HYYSo RT theUL The Simplicity of Rearing Chickens The author <PERSON>Mrs Woodrow</PERSON> of Harrow notes that rearing chickens is one of the least expensiv Researchers from scottpolar and ucsc are leading a project studying the margins of the ThwaitesGlacier https t co <ORGANIZATION>LZXFpzNEtb RT</ORGANIZATION> NERCscience <LOCATION>UK</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>USA</LOCATION> join forces to understand how quickly a massive Antarctic glacier could collapse https t co TZCOCNHZIO Thwai In the wake of <LOCATION>Iraq</LOCATION> the position that <ORGANIZATION>Whitehall</ORGANIZATION> knows best is constitutionally untenable says VeronikaFikfak https t co jzYmffEY87 RT kettlesyard This weekend is your last chance to see RanaBegumStudio s installation in the church as part of <ORGANIZATION>ACTIONSkettlesyard Don Cambridge</ORGANIZATION> has received 10 million in funding for a new AI supercomputer CambridgeAI https t co i7nStEIKwx Researchers from <ORGANIZATION>FacultyMaths</ORGANIZATION> and nyuniversity are using candy to determine how landscapes forget or remember https t co UhWJjk27Lo RT liamsims Another classic from the tower theUL ulTallTales opens next Wednesday https t co 7d4S165GCX Super satellite which features extra stars in focus GaiaDR2 https t co Ko45xlnjAb RT theUL Happy WorldIPDay Did you know that theUL is entitled to receive a copy of every book published in the <LOCATION>UK</LOCATION> to preserve for all This will be the definitive stellar catalogue for the foreseeable future GaiaDR2 https t co Ko45xlnjAb https t co vqTIpKUMWf In March <PERSON>Stephen</PERSON> died and the world lost an incredible individual Meet <PERSON>Peter Benie</PERSON> the man who helped to prese https t co NSCoV8gLry They are 40cm tall made of white plastic and don t look like your average students Meet the robot avatars helpin https t co HXy6qASvCI Could low alcohol drinks actually encourage us to drink more New research from BHRUCambridge https t co 8elANCywWT RT TPpodcast_ NEW EPISODE The Attention Economy How can we fight back against the endless pull of the phone in our pocket What is it RT ProfKAArmstrong Now is not the time for a least worst Brexit it s time for a referendum on Brexit itself https t co NtFC8juMcU h RT scottpolar Happy WorldPenguinDay Why not celebrate by taking part in some CitizenScience style penguin spotting https t co Rl4zLJ Gaia s galactic map is coming into sharper focus GaiaDR2 https t co Ko45xlnjAb RT theUL The first ever Mr Men book Mr Tickle was inspired by <PERSON>Hargreaves</PERSON> s son who asked him what a tickle looked like In 1971 he di We need the majority groups to think about representation otherwise minority voices will continue to be drowned o https t co sgRMNXWkp5 There is hardly a branch of astrophysics which will not be revolutionised by <PERSON>Gaia</PERSON> data GaiaDR2 https t co Ko45xlnjAb I hope that as more studies on anxiety come out more people will start talking about this condition and will see https t co u5ZFJLaK6s RT CamDigLib Our latest update https t co zw7T3SfH53 2 new collections Schroder collection from Kings_College containing writings amp amp RT stjohnscam If you just can t get enough of our fab UniversityChallenge team you can check out our interview with them https t co A new home for cebcambridge was officially opened today https t co difZykTLTJ This new video from <ORGANIZATION>Fermilab</ORGANIZATION> features <PERSON>Mark Thomson</PERSON> from DeptofPhysics neutrino https t co CZgOUBbv7R Women who feel in control of their lives and who find purpose and meaning in life are less likely to have anxiety https t co aqXkqUudJi RT stjohnscam Congratulations to <PERSON>James Devine Stoneman John Clark Levine Rosie McKeown</PERSON> and <PERSON>Matt Hazell</PERSON> for becoming the first <ORGANIZATION>St John RT</ORGANIZATION> theUL Happy WorldBookNight Towers are magical T H White s The Sword in the Stone from 1938 was brought to life by disney in 1963 RT stjohnscam Tonight s the night of the <ORGANIZATION>University Challenge</ORGANIZATION> final so here s your last warm up question Tune in to <ORGANIZATION>BBC</ORGANIZATION> 2 at 8 30pm ton RT theUL What do theUL tower and a red telephone box have in common They were both designed by Sir <PERSON>Giles Gilbert Scott</PERSON> Those windows l RT Cambridge_Eng The IfMCambridge part of the <ORGANIZATION>Department of Engineering</ORGANIZATION> has been selected to help enhance the <ORGANIZATION>InternetofThings IoT RT</ORGANIZATION> camdiary <ORGANIZATION>Cambridge</ORGANIZATION> 22 April 2018 https t co Jzk0AdlVmR How your thinking style may have influenced whether you voted for Brexit or not https t co Vl6HaXhMU7 cognition RT theUL The first edition of Ian Fleming s Casino Royale is among the hidden books of the tower It s the only one to feature his artwor RT stjohnscam Professor <PERSON>Eske Willerslev</PERSON> a fellow of St John s is part of an international research team that recently discovered geneti RT MeredithCrowle1 Can the Commonwealth replace the <LOCATION>EU</LOCATION> in post Brexit trade relations Interesting program last night on bbcradio4 http RT camdiary Cambridge 8 50am 19 April 2018 https t co nELd4dPgwW RT camdiary <ORGANIZATION>Cambridge</ORGANIZATION> 19 April 2018 https t co X5VcoVe269 RT induswaliarch This is a great series of short videos highlighting some of the most fascinating Indian objects from the different CamU Loneliness can be a real problem for newcomers People have often left established careers to follow their partner https t co NNzP1sHyBb Our new <ORGANIZATION>CysticFibrosis Innovation Hub</ORGANIZATION> supported by cftrust aims to take a moon shot at treating the condition https t co MvnRP2Y0Ho RT inthelongrunuk Now online <PERSON>Josh Platzky Miller</PERSON> on Radical Democracy and Educational Experiments in <LOCATION>Brazil</LOCATION> and Rojava northern <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> RT camdiary <LOCATION>Cambridge</LOCATION> 8 18pm 18 April 2018 https t co Sk0HnUtVBm RT DianeCoyle1859 The <ORGANIZATION>BennettInst</ORGANIZATION> launched here Cambridge_Uni this week Here are <PERSON>Lindsay Aqui</PERSON> s reflections on the day https t co RT camdiary <ORGANIZATION>Cambridge</ORGANIZATION> 11 46am 18 April 2018 https t co rLGbiu0tes RT WhippleMuseum It seems Professor <PERSON>Dumbledore</PERSON> not affiliated with Cambridge_Uni in any way has taken significant inspiration from our RT cu_mat Many congratulations to the teams from cu_mat GlasgowChem <ORGANIZATION>Manchester Sheffield</ORGANIZATION> and <LOCATION>Strathclyde</LOCATION> on securing a 5 54m EPSR RT TanyaFiler How can we build a sustainable GovTech sector that balances efficiency with democratic accountability My WiredUK op ed G RT paulcoxon Today I helped wind the Trinity clock hughhunt does an ace job bringing modern tech tweaks to keep the ancient mechanism r Combining superconductivity and spin could lead to a revolution in high performance computing https t co 3ncJbCgdAi RT TanyaFiler We need to massively upskill our legislators amp amp policymakers <PERSON>Marthalanefox</PERSON> on policy amp amp technology at our launch We Ben RT georgiecannon Excited to see DianeCoyle1859 speak for the first time at the launch of the new BennettInst policycam https t co I3 RT EarthSciCam Hot warm or cold New research reveals how cooling magma cracks to form geometric columns such as the famous basalt colu The BennettInst will tackle policy challenges in our age of disruption https t co dB2BfpH1xt https t co LhYkZpWuyI RT BoeingUK Our 2017 Supplier of the Year winners have been revealed Congrats to Cambridge_Uni for winning the Innovation Award for out RT UCamEnterprise Delighted that <ORGANIZATION>Ceres Agritech Knowledge Exchange Partnership</ORGANIZATION> in conjunction with uniofeastanglia UniofHerts unilinc RT camdiary Sunset in <LOCATION>Cambridge</LOCATION> 14 April 2018 https t co sLhKq9LjVB https t co 0Ty0etB97E Statement from the <ORGANIZATION>University s Head of the School of Arts amp amp Humanities</ORGANIZATION> on Dr <PERSON>Priya Gopal</PERSON> https t co gP1xViE5EI RT ChurchillCol https t co W0oAp1PTJW RT ChurchillCol Statement from the Master AtheneDonald in response to the article in the <ORGANIZATION>Daily Mail</ORGANIZATION> regarding Churchill Fellow Priyamva International amp amp constitutional law experts VeronikaFikfak and hayleyjhooper on why theresa_may should turn to https t co l1YNeP6CIL It s an icon of the <LOCATION>Cambridge</LOCATION> skyline that has inspired authors from CS <PERSON>Lewis</PERSON> to stephenfry Now the treasures of https t co wLHuij25rn How does someone who is almost blind study the tiny world of the scuttle fly <ORGANIZATION>Meet Henry Disney</ORGANIZATION> a world expert in https t co rgPO94Q8cC Introducing the Gates_Cambridge class of 2018 Congratulations to all our Scholars Elect https t co sLnL2alNzF https t co Gfo3V1eKk3 PriyamvadaGopal We ve emailed you RT AndyNeely <LOCATION>Cambridge</LOCATION> young entrepreneurs recognised by <ORGANIZATION>Forbes</ORGANIZATION> 30 Under 30 list https t co uspbdMUMfM via Cambridge_Eng RT theUL Coming soon Secrets Myths Banished books An exhibition to uncover the secrets of <LOCATION>Cambridge</LOCATION> s remarkable Library Tower Tall Little robots behind the scenes at one of the <LOCATION>UK</LOCATION> s leading academy schools https t co HHrZwhlpSC edchat ukedchat education There is nothing more exciting than examining actual Tasmanian devils in the wild they are truly majestic animal https t co pYZ2WauUTp Tasmanian devils are facing extinction because of a transmissible cancer New research from tcgcambridge offers ho https t co Bjpx68PNAs RT stjohnscam Congratulations to our students <PERSON>James Devine Stoneman John Clark Levin Rosie McKeown</PERSON> and <PERSON>Matt Hazell</PERSON> for qualifying for t How do you go from being the <LOCATION>UK</LOCATION> s first bomb disposal officer to the only woman ever to be in charge of https t co YiklW5teqR RT Dept_of_POLIS The recording of the 2018 Antcliffe Lecture given by Lord <PERSON>Peter Hennessy</PERSON> is now available to watch on our website https When I turned 50 I decided to challenge myself every year with an activity that took me out of my comfort zone I https t co FKp67NNnAM Are you a careless typist or an attentive error free typist There s one way to find out https t co EOpc8Y1mgE RT cambtweetcusu A reminder that we will be holding a Q amp amp A hour this Sunday 8 April at 8pm A great opportunity to ask current <ORGANIZATION>Cambridg RT</ORGANIZATION> MeredithCrowle1 Tune in to <ORGANIZATION>BBC Radio</ORGANIZATION> 4 tonight at 8 00 GMT to hear me discuss what the <LOCATION>US China</LOCATION> TradeWar means for the <LOCATION>UK</LOCATION> and <ORGANIZATION>Brexit RT</ORGANIZATION> TrinCollLibCam What a difference a month makes Do you prefer the <LOCATION>Wren Library</LOCATION> in the snow or in the sunshine We are free t RT TrinityHall_SLO <ORGANIZATION>Trinity Hall</ORGANIZATION> is taking part in the Cambridge_Uni FacultyMaths Open Day 5 May 2018 You can spend the morning at T How fast can you type Take the test and find out https t co uMCcomYIgp RT GlobalFood_Camb Interacting with farmers is one of the most important learning exercises <PERSON>Lisanne Meulendijks</PERSON> is off to meet smallh Infrared sensors and a marshmallow offer researchers a new way to monitor and assess social interaction https t co WruoxnTot5 An online test can measure how likely you are to fall victim to internet scams https t co FCxcKBS3Go RT stjohnscam greghassall has made a fantastic documentary for AustralianStory on Dr <PERSON>Justin Yerbury</PERSON> s quest to understand MND He s be RT yourscambridge Leading science for health policy think tank PHGFoundation joins Cambridge_Uni following philanthropic gift from the What might make a person more vulnerable to internet scams https t co FCxcKC9F4Y RT camdiary <PERSON>Stephen Hawking</PERSON> s funeral in <LOCATION>Cambridge</LOCATION> 31 March 2018 Thank you for following the coverage https t co mawCrOfnWB RT CaiusCollege A Service of Thanksgiving for the life of StephenHawking Fellow of <PERSON>Caius</PERSON> for 52 years will be held wabbey on Friday Professor <PERSON>Stephen Hawking</PERSON> s funeral on Saturday will be a private service A Condolence Book may be found at https t co TJoD6Wvv0L RT M_N_Guenther PhD thesis submitted And even took the obligatory jump in front of the red door picture Thanks DidierQueloz and The mini organs helping scientists understand our biology and how they could open up the fields of personalised https t co vnjbgNQxfg I ve always done different things in parallel things that on the face of it appear unconnected I lack focus an https t co OVgtNiuAvI A year after the HE sector was urged to reforms its support and protection of sexual misconduct victims Professor https t co aZq0LKIQLu RT UKandEU CSBarnard24 and Emilija Leinarte Cambridge_Uni discuss The future of <LOCATION>EU UK</LOCATION> trade partnership what is the <ORGANIZATION>EU</ORGANIZATION> offering ht RT VarsityMatch BREAKING NEWS The Varsity Match extends <LOCATION>Twickenham Stadium</LOCATION> agreement with EnglandRugby for 4 more years ahead of 10 New Cambridge_Eng centre for smart city research to be established in the city of <LOCATION>Nanjing</LOCATION> https t co j4coZl1Qex RT camdiary <ORGANIZATION>Cambridge</ORGANIZATION> 27 March 2018 ZoologyMuseum s <LOCATION>Whale Hall</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Mammal Gallery</LOCATION> now open https t co h2CtGg98RE https t co Y8ot RT GreatStMarys Professor <PERSON>Stephen Hawking</PERSON> s funeral on Saturday will be a private service conducted by <ORGANIZATION>CaiusCollege</ORGANIZATION> We apologize that w RT emmanuelaccess Has Spring finally sprung at EmmaCambridge the sun stays with us https t co <ORGANIZATION>GkglydhFfj RT</ORGANIZATION> ChuArchives otd in 1964 the first dinner took place in <ORGANIZATION>ChurchillCol Dining Hall</ORGANIZATION> https t co qPl9xkmsqu https t co QB2srw46gT RT BBCSport Women s Boat Race <ORGANIZATION>Cambridge Men s Boat Race Cambridge Bragging</ORGANIZATION> rights <ORGANIZATION>Cambridge Watch</ORGANIZATION> highlights https t co 85 Four victories for <LOCATION>Cambridge</LOCATION> crews in the Boat Race Go lightblues Great racing from <LOCATION>Cambridge</LOCATION> and <ORGANIZATION>Oxford</ORGANIZATION> crews t https t co gBqz1WOp5k RT EarthSciCam Observing deep carbon with an Icelandic volcano read about how fayalite08 amp amp co estimate mantle CO2 content using rocks How many could be infected in the next flu pandemic Find out from our researchers tonight at 9pm on BBCFOUR https t co veD2cGlmJY RT AdamJKucharski The simulation model in tonight s BBCPandemic show was created by petrakle <PERSON>StephenKissler</PERSON> and <PERSON>Julia Gog</PERSON> who did an The results of the biggest citizen science project of its kind will be announced tonight at 9pm on BBCFOUR https t co TTGPtZrcL9 RT TPpodcast_ NEW EPISODE We ask what really happened in <LOCATION>Salisbury</LOCATION> what is <PERSON>Putin</PERSON> s master plan and is he succeeding in his goal of s Solar cells based on perovskites can be made more efficient just add potassium https t co XetlwUobia Human Rights podcast DeclarationsPod from CGHR_Cambridge is now available to stream on Anchor Tune in and leave https t co CALoH2lp7n In <LOCATION>Cambridge</LOCATION> alone there are groups growing mini livers brains oesophaguses bile ducts lungs intestines womb https t co XdDkpjNMnS RT InterACEcyber Listen in to Professor <PERSON>Frank Stajano</PERSON> of InterACE speaking to JonnyDymond BBCRadio4 on the <LOCATION>UK</LOCATION> s cybersecurity threats Memories of the largest lava flood in the history of <LOCATION>Iceland</LOCATION> recorded in an apocalyptic medieval poem were used t https t co tJuDuyV3ma RT camdiary End of term cambridgefaces https t co EQ7x15WXy9 The future of <LOCATION>UK</LOCATION> universities our Vice Chancellor s latest blog post https t co 3tQociSgPr https t co HuFnuqmNX9 Our Vice Chancellor Prof <PERSON>Stephen Toope</PERSON> on the future of <LOCATION>UK</LOCATION> universities https t co 3tQociSgPr https t co GdCEcWw2Ux Prof <PERSON>Stephen Toope</PERSON> our Vice Chancellor on USSstrikes students as consumers and the future of <LOCATION>UK</LOCATION> universities https t co j5ouaU6gwv What makes <LOCATION>Cambridge</LOCATION> a hotbed for AI amp amp machine learning start ups In my experience <LOCATION>Silicon Valley</LOCATION> is 10 tech https t co jHwe50kRQL A chain reaction of fast draining lakes poses new risk for the <LOCATION>Greenland</LOCATION> Ice Sheet https t co MIVosestmI https t co m1kxuy7KSj A growing network of lakes on the <LOCATION>Greenland</LOCATION> Ice Sheet is threatening its stability climatechange https t co 5kfi13VYLx RT paulcoxon If you d like to read more about <PERSON>Stephen Hawking</PERSON> s contributions to physics nature APSphysics amp amp royalsociety have collec Men get eating disorders too I remember a doctor saying You re a bloke surely you don t want to look like th https t co iLRv8taNzV kedikebba CaiusCollege Apologies corrected link here https t co dKrEzZwfcY RT CaiusCollege We ve opened an online book of condolence for those who can t come to College to pay tribute Please fill in the form her RT BarackObama Have fun out there among the stars https t co S285MTwGtp RT FacultyMaths Professor <PERSON>Stephen</PERSON> Hawking 1942 2018 https t co AvOGSMeSoK https t co <ORGANIZATION>EvZIKOcNcv RT NASA</ORGANIZATION> Remembering <PERSON>Stephen</PERSON> Hawking a renowned physicist and ambassador of science His theories unlocked a universe of possibilities th RT ProfBrianCox Sad to hear about <PERSON>Stephen</PERSON> Hawking What a remarkable life His contributions to science will be used as long as there are Thinkersact Now fixed sorry about that <PERSON>Stephen Hawking</PERSON> an appreciation by Lord <PERSON>Martin Rees</PERSON> https t co Awup1QKpVw RT CaiusCollege The College flag is flying at half mast today in tribute to Professor Hawking A book of condolence will be opened in th Professor <PERSON>Stephen</PERSON> Hawking 1942 2018 a video tribute https t co DzwjZII2RL Look up at the stars and not down at your feet Professor <PERSON>Stephen</PERSON> Hawking 1942 2018 https t co h8uWznhEpb https t co RVeQx2BTxP josephinecumbo We can confirm that there is an ongoing incident at the university of <LOCATION>Cambridge</LOCATION> s Old Schools site https t co NBgF4E8eSP A Stray Sumerian Tablet Unravelling the story behind the oldest written object 4 200 years old theUL https t co Vhtrt6u0lM We also welcome agreement to convene an independent expert valuation group We welcome as we called for today a commitment to meaningful discussions for the future of the USS from 2020 We welcome this transitional benefit arrangement that maintains a level of defined benefit for all scheme members We welcome news of an agreement between UniversitiesUK and UCU to protect defined benefits pensions for 3 years and increase contributions Tonight s statement on USS and industrial action from Cambridge_Uni VC https t co 20nnekUJYA In <LOCATION>Cambridge</LOCATION> people are not just thinking about what can be done to address the problems of today they are antic https t co oPJu5mpb3t One in ten stroke survivors need more help with taking medication https t co U5w9dqUHNH Empathy isn t just a result of our upbringing and experience it s also partly a result of our genes https t co gLk0eLbCa6 Over 60 000 people are employed in the <LOCATION>Cambridge</LOCATION> cluster of companies Its 4 733 knowledge intensive firms genera https t co Uja29rcjtI RT BlueSciPod The BlueSci podcast is now available on iTunes just in time for camscience starting today Cambridge_Uni For more info RT camscience So what is on today Take your pick from all these amazing events https t co pvCnn0RBW6 We ve kept a few spaces back at RT CamArtsHums We hear you should be listening via newsoveraudio to andymartinink in Independent on the joys of listening over readi The Cambridge Science Festival camscience starts today More than 320 mostly free events for all ages Check out https t co wnDqRoouTf RT BlueSci The first episode of our new podcast is out science podcast sciencepodcast muchexcitment https t co mKljx4Bztj RT pembroke1347 Pembroke is saddened to learn of the death of Sir <PERSON>John Sulston</PERSON> CH FRS 1960 alumnus and Honorary Fellow In 2002 Sir J RT CamDigLib New today manuscript draft of <PERSON>Isaac Newton</PERSON> s Principia with annotations by <PERSON>Edmond Halley</PERSON> and <PERSON>Newton</PERSON> himself from the coll RT HelenHet20 Thoughts on what the Italian election says about the problem of consent in European politics https t co n8i4MOxgcX The female scientists taking their fields by storm and using IWD2018 to encourage others to do the same https t co wIRbbDCSqr <PERSON>Dame Athene Donald</PERSON> professor of experimental physics and master of <ORGANIZATION>Churchill College ChurchillCol</ORGANIZATION> on how women ca https t co TWLcvaydq5 RT JuliePCGould Happy IWD2018 Here s a new sciencemamas podcast with the fantastic <PERSON>Dame AtheneDonald</PERSON> a super sciencemama with a gre We all need to press for progress in science and beyond IWD2018 womeninSTEMM https t co 0pHVLAggRc RT EarthSciCam Join us as we celebrate InternationalWomensDay by meeting nine of our Cambridge_Uni Earth Scientists Follow this week s To celebrate IWD2018 CambridgeUP has made a collection of inspirational work written by or about leading acade https t co 6NMd5vKDXl <PERSON>Melissa Wilson</PERSON> had never picked up an oar before goingtoCambridge now she s an Olympic hopeful with her sights s https t co oUMZ6kxDFa RT camscience Join realdocmartin and see if you can help her make a diagnosis in her on stage GP surgery You ll see real life patients Growing up I benefited from tremendous freedom which gave me the courage to try new things and speak out for mys https t co BSX7u5ZNbb RT stjohnscam For IWD2018 we meet 9 Johnians who are breaking new ground in the world today https t co TmNjagNzCo StJohnsCam Since RT UCamArchaeology From researchers to technicians lecturers to professional staff here s to the phenomenal women who make up the Depar Celebrating IWD2018 with a message from one of cambridge_uni s leading scientists who has a lyrical take on the https t co PN6k8Pyilz RT CUWBCPresident Throughout my life I ve been surrounded by strong powerful women who ve taught me resilience and stubborn determination RT Cambridge_Eng Visit our YouTube channel today amp amp meet some of our inspiring amp amp go getting students amp amp alumni https t co eMPG4gjnyW RT PaulineMRose On international women s day IWD2018 all power to the girls and women of camfed for the amazing work they do to promot New TPpodcast_ <LOCATION>Italy Germany</LOCATION> and the Future of <LOCATION>Europe</LOCATION> with <PERSON>Chris Clark</PERSON> HelenHet20 and cjbickerton https t co Fj39rgQN9Q RT TPpodcast_ NEW EPISODE <LOCATION>Italy Germany</LOCATION> and the Future of <LOCATION>Europe</LOCATION> Why is social democracy is such trouble everywhere Can <PERSON>Merkel</PERSON> s On IWD2018 VC pledges equality of opportunity for women Cambridge_Uni and reward and recognition for their ex https t co MNclApZZ0I Celebrating IWD2018 at the <ORGANIZATION>University of Cambridge</ORGANIZATION> which numbers writer <PERSON>Zadie Smith</PERSON> chemist <PERSON>Rosalind Franklin</PERSON> and https t co 9gIH2jEd5t RT CambridgeJBS The business case for <ORGANIZATION>GenderDiversity Read</ORGANIZATION> about the new study co authored at CambridgeJBS in advance of Internation A re post from last year in advance of IWD2018 First study to actually compare prehistoric female bones to those https t co xa0RQVxRgJ RT GlobalFood_Camb Dietary changes in <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> are indirectly affecting deforestation in <LOCATION>Brazil</LOCATION> Meet Dr <PERSON>Pablo Salas</PERSON> CambridgeLandEc Cam RT Impulse_Maxwell Extended deadline Impulse2018 Cambridge_Uni until 19 March Accept the challenge and make your idea a reality Made Congratulations to Prof <PERSON>Michel Goedert</PERSON> from MRC_LMB and CamNeuro for being awarded TheBrainPrize for research in https t co m1wHsgPseV RT EarthSciCam It s InternationalWomensDay on Thursday 8 March All week we will be focussing on the women who work at <ORGANIZATION>EarthSciCam Fol RT</ORGANIZATION> EPSRC On today s Life Scientific on BBCRadio4 EPSRC supported Cambridge_Uni chemist Professor <PERSON>Clare Grey</PERSON> discusses the Big Battery RT CamArtsHums Fascinating read on the BeastFromTheEast from andymartinink on our need to give a name and an identity to obscure forces A <LOCATION>Cambridge</LOCATION> technology which could lead to better medicines has been licensed to spinout TeraView https t co 04B9MxMvyu What causes molecules to crystallise and how can the answer lead to better medicines https t co 04B9MxuUGW Researchers from cebcambridge have developed a method to predict the stability of new drugs https t co 04B9MxuUGW It s Oscars night and metoo is back in the spotlight but how do you call timesup when someone crosses the line https t co ptva2S6JVP People on the front lines trying to change the culture surrounding sexual misconduct share their tips on standing u https t co 7rH77txYDA How do you step out of your comfort zone to stop someone being harassed Staff and students share their stories at https t co h7FrQlcMbZ Our hardy lentbumps crews won t let the beastfromtheeast put them off their strokes Can you spot your crew https t co 4u0z3e3GEU It s not about being a have a go hero so just how do you save someone in danger without putting yourself at ris https t co Ed5KpRGDWu Look out for the <ORGANIZATION>CRUKCambridge Early Detection Programme</ORGANIZATION> on BBCLookEast tonight Here s our article on the moving https t co RWZFhq82FO RT camdiary Peterhouse <LOCATION>Cambridge</LOCATION> uksnow https t co m1AqkC1AKW The new kettlesyard is a space for calm in a world of chaos If you haven t visited yet take a look at what you https t co 33inYS0aM5 RT EarthSciCam The evolution of land plants transformed sedimentation on Earth new study of mud preservation on the continents by Will What do you do when you see a stranger being sexually harassed Learn expert techniques for intervention at https t co c02ccepEPy Today the Vice Chancellor of cambridge_uni says there has to be compromise to bring industrial action to an end https t co Zu5JYrbFxl If you want to find out about historic events from volcanic eruptions and pandemics to the rise and fall of civil https t co IUpHHf1vwQ My wife and I joke that our hobby is moving countries Meet Egyptian geneticist <PERSON>Ahmed Balboula</PERSON> https t co GnHo5Lfv6f <LOCATION>Cambridge</LOCATION> is running a course on stepping in when you see someone in danger Find out what they re teaching at https t co DfqTAc4Hpu It s snowing outside but inside the rainbows are out for LGBT history month at UniCamPrimSch LGBTHM18 https t co YaACLZsgrm It s a place of ideas it s a place of imagination it s a place of inspiration kettlesyard is back and bette https t co aK6BLj7X7D Have you been following our focus on CambridgeAI research Our experts have been sharing their views on the hopes https t co T6BnB2kKeG Most days I m like the other birds Other days though I m not And I have to be very brave Avery the little bi https t co HO8702n214 Trust and transparency in ArtificialIntelligence systems Join us at camscience as adrian_weller discusses ho https t co p1pPXdbcOp If we are to give general intelligence to machines we ll need to give them moral authority too That means a rad https t co ol4Px6Yrhi Opioids hijack the brain s natural painkilling system which is why they work so well But what if there was an alt https t co 4fxMfWMjVe RT CamArtsHums Understand Inspire Change the aspiration of the <ORGANIZATION>Humanities amp amp Social Change Foundation</ORGANIZATION> based CRASSHlive launched tod RT JustisTogether Brilliant students and colleagues from across Cambridge_Uni have been collecting books to enhance develop on wing libr RT Channel4News JonSnowc4 on the robotic avatar helping new mothers learn genomics from home https t co aB79sHg9Y4 Could your brain kill pain as effectively as opioids https t co q5HNnpQ735 Would you think twice about your food order if the menu told you how many calories it contained New evidence from https t co 4nSl23qR4k Researchers have pinpointed the brain s natural painkilling system which could lead to the development of alternat https t co 5i6VhkM5YM ArtificialIntelligence could help police make difficult custody decisions CambridgeAI https t co 95sKUV6xRd RT GreatStMarys Watching the snow fall onto Kings_College from atop the tower of <ORGANIZATION>GreatStMarys Cambridge Have</ORGANIZATION> you climbed our tower y RT ProfKAArmstrong A <ORGANIZATION>Customs Union</ORGANIZATION> Without a Single Market Is <PERSON>Corbyn</PERSON> s Position Credible https t co ggXyWrA6Ao https t co YNlWPpzW RT CorpusCambridge Snow has arrived CorpusCambridge snowfall snow BeastFromTheEast https t co yyyWmUKSPy In tech we trust But do we place too much faith in algorithms to make the right decisions And what happens when https t co WjGwLm9Qh7 Today the Cambridge_Uni Vice Chancellor calls for new talks with UCU https t co oHSkVlCtkd Meet wellcometrust funded researcher Dr <PERSON>Luca Peruzzotti Jametti</PERSON> who hopes that using a patient s reprogrammed c https t co wfVJKwF767 Study in mice suggests personalised stem cell treatment may offer relief for progressive MultipleSclerosis https t co IYI2BZdDic It may not be considered by some to be the most glamorous research but what we are trying to do is make a big imp https t co 4d0bHh7P4Q A message from the Vice Chancellor of cambridge_uni on industrial action https t co sCsBPshNFK If we are aiming for human like technology should robots also have our rights Meet BVLSingler the scifi https t co LxykkHx9LY <LOCATION>Cambridge</LOCATION> and Indian partners launch TIGR2ESS a collaboration that aims to transform <LOCATION>India</LOCATION> s Green Revolution https t co AXBsWJH8Fj RT BVLSingler IT S ME The sci fi geek urging us to question our relationships with intelligent machines by Cambridge_Uni https t c Stroke survivors and caregivers feel abandoned by health services study finds https t co 1TnRMJZ6Mr RT UCamArchaeology Ancient DNA reveals impact of the Beaker Phenomenon on prehistoric Europeans Large multi institutional team reveal <ORGANIZATION>RT</ORGANIZATION> TPpodcast_ NEW EPISODE <PERSON>Jeremy Corbyn</PERSON> In the week he s been forced to answer questions about what he did in the Cold War we ask wher A study of more than 1 000 workers finds that many employees who are highly engaged in their work are also exhauste https t co BL66p6QpYw RT CamDigLib From shelf to screen a behind the scenes glimpse at <ORGANIZATION>Cambridge Digital Library</ORGANIZATION> digitisation digitalhumanities with D For many decades hype outstripped fact in terms of AI and machine learning No longer 26 experts forecast the https t co bwqw63rmYg Could you grow paint https t co NEjL5jKi5z We live in a world that could become fraught with day to day hazards from the misuse of AI 26 global experts co https t co 6nyrNF2lL5 Researchers from VignoliniLab have unlocked the genetic code behind some of the brightest colours in nature https t co NEjL5jKi5z The <ORGANIZATION>University</ORGANIZATION> and support services will be open as usual during the upcoming strikes We are committed to minimisi https t co 6lAGwIhjjH Ever wanted to become a master of propaganda Now you can do it for science FakeNews https t co Y0Rgckt7ko Excess levels of calcium in the brain may lead to Parkinsons disease https t co NC8E2Eef3U RT ProfKAArmstrong Does the Validity of the Article 50 Letter Depend Upon the Existence of a Formal Decision https t co aKPLNPua8Y h RT SCICambridge Why do people need blood transfusions Dr C dric Ghevaert s research group are answering your questions about lab grown b Planning permission has been granted for a new home for DeptofPhysics https t co KtJyX6FtU3 RT CaiusCollege Imagine not being able to frequent backstreet taverns or having to speak solely in Latin around College Unthinkable no Wondering what to have for lunch A Mediterranean diet could lower your risk of heart disease CBCHeart https t co huX9m0sBct Can you spot the cuttlefish These sea creatures have a remarkable ability to hide behind a 3D invisibility cloak https t co JnTHiZr70i Social media is awash with extreme judgements Simplistic and polarised judgments abound and extreme negativity https t co 4aROQVJaGX RT Refugees Treating refugees as a sub group of irregular migrants risks obscuring their distinct status and rights in international l RT hollykrieger An important reminder for the day love is chaos valentines math https t co BYSg8DDpy1 The uncertain unicycle that taught itself and how it s helping AI make good decisions CambridgeAI https t co y0pQZu5LTr RT slcuplants <PERSON>Patrick Dickinson</PERSON> has discovered that there is a signal sent from the chloroplast in response to light which activates gen RT scottpolar Happy ValentinesDay One of the more unusual items in our collection is a piece of Captain <PERSON>Scott</PERSON> s wedding cake As you mi Complications in pregnancy could increase the risk of heart disease not just for your children but maybe even your https t co Q8dnomqL1p Around 4 000 people visited kettlesyard for its grand reopening at the weekend If you weren t one of the lucky on https t co MSpHt60QfZ RT camscience Your senses aren t as simple as they seem GinnyFBSmith gives us a fast paced tour of the human brain as part of csf201 RT Raff_Danna For those who missed it the podcast of our session on the last crisis of social democracy is out EuroBriefing and cjbic RT RoyceInstitute The <LOCATION>Cambridge Royce</LOCATION> will be holding an opening event on Mon 26 Feb Speakers will include Professor <PERSON>Stephen Toope</PERSON> Vice In my experience <LOCATION>Silicon Valley</LOCATION> is 10 tech and 90 hype but <LOCATION>Cambridge</LOCATION> is just the opposite https t co N4Esxxc6x2 RT CamUnivMuseums Twilight at the Museums is today Grab your torch wrap up warm amp amp prepare for adventure amp amp don t forget to bring the ki RT camscience Oh my goodness over 5500 tickets booked in the first hour Plenty still available book online at https t co dzTnjAb7 RT EarthSciCam The shape of blue mussel shells is a powerful indicator of changes in environmental conditions New openaccess research b Our researchers are unearthing new discoveries about truffles with the help of a 170 year old living laboratory a https t co UgI4xlvORZ On his 68th birthday <PERSON>Charles Darwin</PERSON> was sent a rather unusual gift two albums featuring portrait photographs of h https t co iAmrGiAXrB Congratulations to RoyalPapworth celebrating its centenary today RoyalPapworth100 https t co MBa5d815KI Join SanjaySinhaUK and <PERSON>Thomas Krieg</PERSON> on 13 February to discuss how to mend a broken heart CBCHeart Free tickets https t co D6zQzhIFCk How do you mend a broken heart Stem cell patches could help repair damaged tissue after a heart attack https t co HxNcHjVbh5 Nurse <PERSON>Jan</PERSON> reveals her personal journey towards breakingthesilence She now runs training to help people to stop ha https t co uAX6OnEX3Q Best of luck to camawise co chair CathySorbara who sets off on the homewardbound16 expedition to <LOCATION>Antarctica</LOCATION> this week womeninstem <PERSON>Ada Lovelace</PERSON> created the world s first computer programme Which other female scientists do you admire FindingAda WomeninSTEM Women scientists have built our world it s time to support and invest in them <ORGANIZATION>UN</ORGANIZATION> Secretary General Ant nio Gute https t co ryeoOUhIOi Today is the InternationalDayofWomenandGirlsinScience Retweet to spread the word and help us fight for gender equ https t co sAkemCyHAz Today is WomenScienceDay Hear from some of the <LOCATION>Cambridge</LOCATION> women campaigning for gender equality in science https t co X3GrFxcObQ Join the thousands of <LOCATION>Cambridge</LOCATION> people helping to keep our city safe by learning how to safely intervene in situati https t co er2iQZTNo7 After a two year closure for redevelopment kettlesyard opened its doors to the public this morning If you don t https t co Uwu824W9ZX Nurse <PERSON>Jan Brighting</PERSON> explains how she s training students to step in and speak up as part of breakingthesilence https t co 26m0rcc6jk What happened when <ORGANIZATION>Cambridge</ORGANIZATION> students were taught how to tackle harassment https t co IUtVHRng8z https t co FeQH6tpINW RT CambridgeHPS <PERSON>Simon Schaffer</PERSON> wins the prestigious DanDavidPrize https t co ggyqm3KoA4 RT AtheneDonald Science is for the endlessly curious and then we need to pass the excitement of what we learn on to others The world n RT ChurchillCol No dream too high Churchill student <ORGANIZATION>NikkiHari</ORGANIZATION> wants to tell young girls to not allow societal stereotypes to stop them Join the students who are breakingthesilence at https t co tMrAj56h2h ItsNotOK https t co rbulRq2ELc RT pembroke1347 February 11th is International Day of Women and Girls in Science Next week we ll be sharing a series of interviews with Tomorrow kettlesyard will be open to the public again for the first time in two years following a multi million https t co iqscOWIev0 How do we improve the way in which robots and humans understand one another in a social setting CambridgeAI https t co vGOynzlh7h To end sexual harassment on campus we need to listen harder to student voices says <PERSON>Aoife Hogan</PERSON> https t co PC2O2SZKAl RT Cambridge_Eng We ve just heard that <PERSON>NikkiHari</PERSON> amp amp alumnus Bily_Boyle will speak TEDxCambridgeUK on 17 March https t co vCEOQYr4Ps RT DarwinLectures Not much longer to wait before RefugeesChief arrives to give his talk on Refugees and Migration https t co C4UejXQj RT CamUnivMuseums It s the tiny object that made big headlines and you can see it now MAACambridge We caught up with curator jodypat RT CambridgeCDBB Read In his first blog for the CambridgeCDBB AndyNeely introduces the Centre and its task of driving the next phase o It does not take many people to change what is thought of as normal and acceptable breakingthesilence itsnotok https t co GP9VEnvduV I ve found no conflict between science and the Bible Scientists and Christians are both seekers after truth <PERSON>Mee</PERSON> https t co oKq2GbzLCG Intervention can help potential victims and potential perpetrators breakingthesilence itsnotok2018 itsnotok https t co sRtllg5Klf Congratulations to adrian_weller of Cambridge_Eng CambridgeAI https t co k1jzZjKkEz Congratulations to <PERSON>Shaun Fitzgerald</PERSON> of Cambridge_Eng the new director of Ri_Science https t co n3TcuZOdbd RT TPpodcast_ NEW EPISODE Why have British governments never fixed the housing crisis What does the state of the American economy mean <PERSON>Tori McKee</PERSON> on ancient and modern ways of being a man and how male allies help with breakingthesilence https t co <ORGANIZATION>9KwKtaiuom University of Cambridge</ORGANIZATION> to seek <ORGANIZATION>Real Living Wage</ORGANIZATION> accreditation https t co GHWefHvJmI We re leading a consortium of all Unis amp amp FE colleges in EastAnglia working with schools to help teens from under https t co AYs1rDRVyB Why don t we step in when we see someone in trouble A psychologist explains the tricks our minds play to prevent u https t co CTZxqMyKKk New image guidelines developed by <ORGANIZATION>InclDesignTools</ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION>Unilever</ORGANIZATION> will make shopping on mobiles faster and easier https t co Hi5hnDUBJu RT theIHpodcast NEW EPISODE F_Waldmann talked to us about forgeries discoveries and the Enlightenment in intellectual history htt As we celebrate the 100th anniversary of women gaining the vote in the <LOCATION>UK</LOCATION> today the fight for equality feels far f https t co bLZZ1WKQdQ Perhaps we want to build systems that fill the gaps that humans cannot reach whether it s AI that thinks in no https t co HqYIyUqDNz Women s suffrage centenary is a rallying call for us all to take action on sexual harassment https t co m35KHePx6n To be a female suffrage activist of any kind was a militant act https t co c58yQplIRx Suffrage100 Vote100 https t co 644becu7o5 RT Hughes_Hall Dear World A woman s place is wherever she likes Yours <PERSON>Elizabeth Marking</PERSON> 100years since women first got the vote on RT Newnham_College <PERSON>Millicent Fawcett</PERSON> co founder of <LOCATION>Newnham</LOCATION> was a leading suffragist who campaigned tirelessly for women s right to vote RT pjsloman Is the next financial crisis about to hit A very timely piece from <PERSON>Jack Owens</PERSON> over at Dept_of_POLIS Cambridge_Uni blog In libertyruth From July 2015 to July 2016 there were two formal reports of student to student misconduct From 2011 https t co WHmzjOBCB3 <ORGANIZATION>Cambridge University</ORGANIZATION> received 173 anonymous reports of sexual misconduct in nine months <PERSON>Graham Virgo</PERSON> explains how https t co cc0HgJ94n0 RT CamZoology We are delighted to announce the launch of <LOCATION>Cambridge</LOCATION> ZooCasts A series of short videos about life as a postgrad in the dep Today marks the start of Sexual Abuse and Sexual Violence Awareness Week itsnotok2018 Throughout the week we will https t co yNddppSPKt Huge increase in sexual misconduct reports shows our new anonymous reporting system has given survivors a voice It https t co Aer4t0IROZ RT UCamEnterprise Registration is now open for this year s Research Commercialisation Open Programme The course will run from 10 14 Sept RT scottpolar How do you safely store 110 year old blackboards with cartoon penguins chalked on them Especially when they were drawn by Japanese men are becoming cool The suit and tie salaryman remodels himself with beauty treatments Loyal company s https t co EuoeNJBYlj A rare and beautiful 7th century cross found buried with the body of an Anglo Saxon teenage girl has gone on disp https t co qKUIHtfKrn RT Selwyn1882 The college is deeply proud that its former Master <PERSON>Owen Chadwick</PERSON> is now commemorated in <ORGANIZATION>Westminster Abbey</ORGANIZATION> along with his br RT HomertonCollege 4th year <ORGANIZATION>MML</ORGANIZATION> student from <ORGANIZATION>HomertonCollege</ORGANIZATION> and drag performer with Dragtime Cambridge <PERSON>Ben Hetherington</PERSON> featured by What we ve seen of AI so far is only the leading edge of the evolution to come Today we launch a month long spot https t co AQHBMAjp2C Our weapon is public opinion posters of the women s suffrage movement theUL https t co c58yQplIRx https t co SZdNMp0Ctt RT JesusCollegeCam The Rainbow Flag is flying today over College to mark the start of LGBTHM18 LGBTHMUK It was raised by <PERSON>Ed</PERSON> and <PERSON>Holly</PERSON> f RT GirtonCollege We are celebrating the first day of LGBTHM by flying the flag universityofcambridge LGBTHistoryMonth lgbthm htt RT LucyCavColl We are flying our LGBTQ flag to celebrate the start of LGBTHistoryMonth Lots of events planned at the <ORGANIZATION>University</ORGANIZATION> and in RT Newnham_College It is February 1 and that means we are flying the flag to mark LGBTHistoryMonth https t co GD4alPU4HG RT WolfsonCam Proudly flying the LGBTQ flag at <LOCATION>Wolfson</LOCATION> today LGBTHistoryMonth LGBTHMUK https t co J3ZAAcNxZK RT Selwyn1882 The rainbow flag is flying over <PERSON>Selwyn</PERSON> today to mark the start of LGBTHM18 https t co 164cHiFbHw RT takanocraig I ve been surprised amp amp flattered by how many people have told me I am a role model for them of a woman in science To mar RT pembroke1347 We re flying the flag today for the start of LGBTHM18 There are a lot of events in <LOCATION>Cambridge</LOCATION> this month and we re exci RT magdalenealumni The Rainbow Flag is flying over College to mark the start of LGBT History month LGBTHM18 https t co z4pklkAXOC RT StEdmundsCamb In observance of LGBT History Month NoOrdinaryCollege is flying the rainbow flag today diversity inclusivity LGBTH RT Catz_Cambridge Blue skies and blustery wind Perfect conditions for flying the rainbow flag to mark the start of LGBTHM18 https t c RT CaiusCollege The sun is shining and the rainbow flag is flying proudly over <PERSON>Caius</PERSON> today to mark the start of LGBTHistoryMonth The RT MeredithCrowle1 My thoughts on the leaked government Brexit analysis <LOCATION>UK</LOCATION> in a changing <LOCATION>Europe</LOCATION> https t co GUOgsaPdrc I ve been surprised amp amp flattered by how many people have told me I am a role model for them of a woman in science https t co Gktm7Z3Z5l RT christs_college Flying the flag https t co nbb1Ek3F8K RT Kings_College To mark the beginning of LGBTHistoryMonth King s proudly flies the rainbow flag https t co KlxWB1rk4T RT Hughes_Hall We are proudly flying the rainbow flag today to mark the beginning of <ORGANIZATION>LGBT History Month Hughes Hall</ORGANIZATION> will also be celebr RT <ORGANIZATION>CamVetSchool Veterinary Medicine</ORGANIZATION> supporting LGBT cusulgbt https t co GRCcqkXh7C RT theUL This morning we raised the rainbow flag on our iconic tower to mark the start of and show our support for LGBT History Month Our city and university are places where people can be themselves without fear of discrimination LGBTHistoryMonth https t co lyjBJlFL9u RT TPpodcast_ NEW EPISODE <PERSON>David</PERSON> and <PERSON>Helen</PERSON> discuss how vulnerable is Theresa May What is <PERSON>Philip Hammond</PERSON> playing at What would be the RT RobGMacfarlane Word of the day Imbolc in the Celtic calendar the midpoint between winter solstice amp amp spring equinox marking the Graphene has lots of potential uses on solid ground but now it s going into space https t co KnzXqhhubb RT UCamEnterprise What s the most efficient amp amp beneficial way to get the research from lab to the public <PERSON>Ji</PERSON> writes about his experience RT HomertonCollege Dr <PERSON>Shery Huang</PERSON> Biointerface_CU Cambridge_Eng Cambridge_Uni will be presenting at our ActionStations event on th The <ORGANIZATION>University</ORGANIZATION> s primary school is to become a CharteredColl regional teaching hub helping teachers share researc https t co E2NcsE7mHl RT ProfMarkElliott The <ORGANIZATION>Lords Constitution Committee</ORGANIZATION> has today published a major report on the <ORGANIZATION>EU Withdrawal Bill Here</ORGANIZATION> s a short blog RT Cambridge_Eng LEGO amp amp robotics fan We hosted FLLUK regional final Young people competed in missions with robots they designed bu RT NakedScientists Scientists from Cambridge_Uni discover a toothpaste ingredient that helps fight malaria https t co O0yL6y80gA People are often amused by the earliest known illustration of Stonehenge According to the text <PERSON>Merlin</PERSON> flew the https t co nPUxhXgr8x On the second anniversary of his disappearance we remember <PERSON>Giulio Regeni</PERSON> <LOCATION>Cambridge</LOCATION> scholar colleague and friend https t co 5FbKtzk3Xa The extraordinary tale of the raising of the whale https t co WocsbbuMml ZoologyMuseum CamUnivMuseums https t co 9XhR9iQgHU This is a major departure from media reports claiming that shadowy kingpins monopolise certain routes https t co L3UepS3U7h RT CamEdFac Our Cambridge_Uni PGCE open day is taking place a week today on Fri 26 <PERSON>Jan Don</PERSON> t forget to register for your ticket via ev Congratulations to <PERSON>Mark Thomson</PERSON> of DeptofPhysics who has been named Executive Chair of STFC_Matters https t co xTq1HN9AO8 RT STFC_Matters STFC welcomes the announcement of Professor <PERSON>Mark Thomson Cambridge_Uni</PERSON> who will be our new Executive Chair from April 2 RT pembroke1347 Students are raising funds for the <PERSON>Jo Cox</PERSON> studentship by rowing 120km Donate through JustGiving https t co tOnwFOwQdR RT inthelongrunuk An idea whose time has come The return of Universal BasicIncome https t co t3FqsUw4XK polisci ukpoli https t c RT Dept_of_POLIS <PERSON>David Runciman</PERSON> on Fire and Fury could a book bring down a president https t co 7VBe2cXAko DavidLammy Happy to discuss this important issue we will be in touch to arrange a meeting RT CambridgeJBS Join us on 27 March for InnoFrugalUK the <LOCATION>UK</LOCATION> s first conference dedicated to the subject of FrugalInnovation co hosted PREVIOUSLY at the <ORGANIZATION>University of Cambridge</ORGANIZATION> https t co 4IbsnXPHsL The new season has just started Here s to an unstoppable 2018 Something my mum once said is imprinted on my brain It was However big a leap you take into the plunge pool yo https t co TMT4pKILN2 RT js_simons <LOCATION>Cambridge</LOCATION> people The MemoryLab at CambPsych is looking for volunteers to take part in paid computerised and or MRI studie AI robot scientist finds that toothpaste ingredient may help fight drug resistant malaria https t co WFYiyEbKD1 https t co IXN6YYwYdQ A message from the <ORGANIZATION>University of Cambridge</ORGANIZATION> about the death of <PERSON>Giulio Regeni</PERSON> https t co H4X5fjkQHm https t co mtG1hfH3Ko RT QAdmissions Good work <ORGANIZATION>Verity Bradford</ORGANIZATION> youngsters urged to apply to country s top universities https t co x9bzklPcdC RT UCamEnterprise Know an academic entrepreneur deserving for work in 2017 or over their whole career Enter them in BusinessWeekly RT CamUnivMuseums Turn on the torches crack out the glowsticks Twilight at the Museums is back across 14 venues 13 Feb 4 30 7 30 Researchers MRC_MBU discover how incurable mitochondrial diseases might strike previously unaffected families https t co D7h7dIh6Ff RT libertyruth Want to discover the world s tastiest insects I m not sure I ve done quite that but either way this piece i wrote fo Bop on An introduction to the quintessential College entertainment https t co CKh76GjLm7 RT ClimateSeries The competition opens today In our collab with ClimateTracking we are asking young people to write an article based RT SouthmoorAc We welcomed students from Cambridge_Uni who held discussions with Year 9 amp amp 10 students about what to expect from higher e RT RAEngNews The Year of Engineering is here Find out how you can get involved at https t co wFBMRiOaH5 YoE inspireanengineer https <PERSON>Duncan Maskell</PERSON> never really had a career plan but went from a comprehensive school to one of <LOCATION>Cambridge</LOCATION> s top posi https t co XryF86kQ7X RT CRASSHlive Black holes are simpler than forests and science has its limits <ORGANIZATION>Astronomer Royal Martin Rees</ORGANIZATION> https t co UbzSp4vhGz ht RT michaelkenny_ Happy to announce new studentship funding for our M <PERSON>Phil</PERSON> in Public Policy https t co tQvr3dkDdp need to apply soon Our Vice Chancellor has launched HEPlusProject in StokeonTrent to prepare more students for top uni places Thank https t co a6IHNaM5Y4 Newborn galaxies in the early Universe spun like the Milky Way https t co BizCVXvbNC RT TheCIMR Excellent session at the Clinical School today on BreakingTheSilence campaign Cambridge_Uni to promote zero tolerance of sex Astronomers have detected movement in some of the first galaxies in the Universe look familiar https t co BiYUjjScxw Greener fuel cells move a step closer to reality as researchers design more efficient and potentially more cost e https t co tUBWwY9CXz RT TrinCollCam Whilst I was kicked out of school <PERSON>Lewis</PERSON> is fighting back against a culture of low expectations professorgreen Cambr Congratulations to everyone receiving their offers this week https t co kYVHKPlG3s GoingToCambridge RT cambridge_astro Tonight is the first public open evening of 2018 Come along to the <ORGANIZATION>Institute of Astronomy</ORGANIZATION> to hear <PERSON>Craig Mackay</PERSON> talk a Last summer professorgreen dropped by with an inspiring 6th former his mum amp amp a camera crew To find out why watc https t co 6rHxZYJ9BD JamesAALongman This was tweeted by mistake by a member of staff so has now been deleted the tweet not the member of staff RT CaiusCollege We wish a very happybirthday to Professor <PERSON>StephenHawking</PERSON> 76 today and a Fellow of <PERSON>Caius</PERSON> for 53 years in 2018 The cos Advances in brain imaging have helped settle the debate over how tau a key protein in Alzheimers disease spreads https t co o8Y23FrPZl Researchers from CamZoology and stjohnscam have identified direct genetic traces of the earliest Native Americans https t co zRWWV9Jx1D RT TrinCollCam White Working Class Men a new series Channel4 presented by professorgreen starts 9 Jan 10pm Features the lives of six Humans first arrived in the <LOCATION>Americas</LOCATION> in a single migratory wave perhaps more than 20 000 years ago a new study su https t co dm6aqYFlTm RT BeCambridge Start the new year by booking your place at one of eight <ORGANIZATION>Oxford</ORGANIZATION> and Cambridge Student Conferences taking place around the RT magdalenealumni Bookings are now open for the 2018 <ORGANIZATION>Oxford amp amp Cambridge Student Conferences</ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION>Glasgow Swansea Birmingham Merseys</LOCATION> The bones of a child who lived 11 500 years ago hold possible answers to a series of questions about how humans fir https t co BXAffLTXhG Researchers from DeptofPhysics have suggested that quantum particles can be tracked when no one s looking https t co <ORGANIZATION>NvX2zIWjFE RT</ORGANIZATION> camscience Researcher Cambridge_Uni planning publicengagement in 2018 Deadline for applications to our <ORGANIZATION>Rising Stars Public Engageme RT</ORGANIZATION> d_spiegel Pleased to do a bit on coincidences on Radiolab starts around 24 00 https t co wXxdm9HpOZ https t co 9bl9rliVRG A new technique for mapping the wiring of the brain has found a link between IQ and how well connected brain region https t co En18nWPXKT 24 If your New Year resolution is to lose weight it might be more difficult than you think 24CamThings https t co TsbB0pwi6w 23 We love climate change now it means we can grow black truffles in the <LOCATION>UK</LOCATION> 24CamThings https t co zPgBlVtZHL https t co VAQZOo93Nc 22 This is what a 700 year old <LOCATION>Cambridge</LOCATION> man looks like 24CamThings https t co TKzi5iow9r https t co ShZ6IJDV6B 21 Ey up Is that t Rex 24CamThings https t co N7oB4S4k2C https t co N7oB4S4k2C Image rjan Hoyd V llestad https t co 8PjQR5Fkk6 20 <PERSON>Margaret Thatcher</PERSON> was for turning And reversing 24CamThings https t co pYphaXN4t0 https t co cWssSEHOTo 19 You and your baby are literally on the same wavelength 24CamThings https t co AhzbjHZj2H https t co UTblxMffGM 18 The <PERSON>Vikings</PERSON> loved their cod 24CamThings https t co ZBj9EdmNVr Image <PERSON>Frank Meffert</PERSON> https t co uKmFZWahAa 17 Caterpillars love plastic bags 24CamThings https t co OY3zBpwSrf Image USGS Bee Inventory and Monitoring L https t co IqqUgRo9Ue 16 Elephants are not so dumbo after all 24CamThings https t co 3KEXxYCdcP Image Tontan Travel https t co K3q2Wbbh8l 15 We do like a glass of wine And a very big one at that 24CamThings https t co JDfVfLh4a4 https t co qVR0g40Rn0 14 Our earliest prehistoric ancestors had a mouth and anus in the same hole 24CamThings https t co hwIMOLYSHu https t co VYCHi6q5y0 13 This is what the last lost Liszt sounds like 24CamThings https t co 0Gccy38erL https t co hzjH4zBVtP 12 Before long robots will be our lords and masters 24CamThings https t co VGWMZLF1Q1 Image Rog01 https t co Kmp981W92h Happy Christmas https t co CIq2ORcRZk What s it like singing in Kings_College Chapel on ChristmasEve Meet ChoirOfKingsCam Baritone <PERSON>Steve Whitford</PERSON> pa https t co hcynhUx2HI 11 There s a robot crime wave coming our way 24CamThings https t co Eu3j1uI9Na Image <PERSON>Doug Waldron</PERSON> https t co OMTqvwB1zb 10 Honest people give a 24CamThings https t co Htb8pDrYKD https t co 2xfDVcvboN 9 Our female ancestors were totally ripped 24CamThings https t co vEYllUlMq3 https t co 7UqxgFlJ2w 8 Forget <PERSON>Tom Cruise</PERSON> the real Top Gun is the robber fly 24CamThings https t co LjiFe4ShZi https t co S3ns3hmoA4 Ineffective governance is the strongest predictor of declining species numbers more so than economic growth clim https t co WYuOKUa0YL 7 Astronomers found the little star that twinkles 24CamThings https t co uXTxSvfQEv https t co <ORGANIZATION>mJ1H315Uda RT</ORGANIZATION> camdiary <ORGANIZATION>Cambridge</ORGANIZATION> 21 December 2017 There s no Christmas without the arrival of the <ORGANIZATION>BBC</ORGANIZATION> radio broadcast trucks for 9LC live servic Singing is strenuous almost like a sport Meet Choral Scholar <PERSON>Steve Whitford</PERSON> who will be singing with https t co 1H6itcTl7W RT yourscambridge Campaign reaches 1 billion mark here s just one example of how gifts are enabling Cambridge_Uni to respond to the wo RT SCICambridge REGISTRATION IS OPEN If you fancy a trip to <LOCATION>Cambridge</LOCATION> in September 2018 for some outstanding stem cell science networki 6 The TRUTH behind the FAKE moon landings 24CamThings https t co 6QzAejk988 https t co xvJcXxBgOv Habitable planets could exist around pulsars according to new research from cambridge_astro https t co y3ksVgOQcy RT yourscambridge Campaign reaches 1 billion mark here s an example of how gifts enable Cambridge_Uni to respond to the world s challe RT EarthSciCam Interested in a CambridgeESS Earth Sciences PhD at Cambridge_Uni There are just a couple of weeks until the 2018 deadli 5 There s a vaccine against fake news 24CamThings https t co jrqfFQsLle Image The <ORGANIZATION>Public Domain Review</ORGANIZATION> https t co dStzzxx2ZS 4 Celebrity Twitter accounts behave a bit like bots 24CamThings https t co Gf1i8G70HG Image <PERSON>Gage Skidmore</PERSON> https t co ZHl4P84fNs Welcome to the 18th century <ORGANIZATION>Starbucks</ORGANIZATION> https t co AAC2vA6S7B Calf s foot jelly with your flat white https t co AAC2vzPhg3 RT yourscambridge Campaign reaches 1 billion mark here s an example of how gifts are enabling Cambridge_Uni to respond to the world s 3 We found out who gave us herpes 24CamThings https t co 5oLz8S08NO https t co m3NK8RFz9w in https t co bjjT7QgwlG RT michaelkenny_ An introduction to the new public policy institute at <LOCATION>Cambridge</LOCATION> we ll be launching in the new year https t co 4R1 2 Sheep can recognise <PERSON>Barack Obaa</PERSON> ma We apologise for the terrible puns this story unleashed on the world https t co 1xT3MPWJYi Do you find exam times stressful Mindfulness could help you cope New study from MSSatUoC https t co nEVSryH8Cb https t co uQkfhbkmJV 1 <PERSON>Stephen</PERSON> Hawking s PhD thesis almost broke the internet when it became available online 24CamThings https t co 3vyOaXvI8h Dodgy robots fake news and smart sheep here are 24 things we learned in 2017 What were your highlights https t co QZypmUafil Congratulations to EnvalLtd a spinout from cebcambridge https t co ZunJBo2MFk I experienced first hand what happens when a university chooses the path of openness and diversification The Vic https t co Ewxg3MDVE9 Ancient Greek reveals intestinal parasites described in Hippocratic texts https t co smOJa0CACW Talking to people at <PERSON>Jimmy</PERSON> s puts your student worries into perspective <ORGANIZATION>Meet Cat Somerville</ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON>Niamh Buckingham</PERSON> https t co NElFktDsa8 Mistletoe and a large Wine There s been a seven fold increase in wine glass size over the past 300 years Is thi https t co gQSZFLSxjH RT Hughes_Hall Our Nurse <PERSON>Maria</PERSON> welcomes the opportunity to destigmatise conversation around sexual harrassment or misconduct breakingthe RT CamPolicyInst What are the difficult choices to be made in public policy The audio of our public policy lecture with PJTheEconomist RT ProfMarkElliott New post In the preliminary Withdrawal Agreement the <LOCATION>UK</LOCATION> promises to confer a very high degree of legal protection o How to cut through post truth political polarisation over climate change https t co ykXjPQMNWz <PERSON>Kate Gross</PERSON> was just 36 years old when she died of cancer CRUKCambridge researchers including her husband are https t co A7buZJMVCk In the shadow of king coal negative emotions persist in <LOCATION>UK</LOCATION> s former industrial heartlands https t co PUvCKNKPP4 RT BBCRadio4 Are you a published writer You could win 15 000 and have your short story read on Radio 4 It s the <ORGANIZATION>National Short Story RT</ORGANIZATION> DiSpeirs Hey writers We are open for submissions for the bbcnssa 2018 and thrilled to have such an eminent and talented judging pa Could these high tech and low tech pills on a string help us catch oesophageal cancer early https t co nxTjdmANRg RT camdiary Snow Newnham_College 10 December 2017 https t co gx9dzx5fRI RT TPpodcast_ <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> is both incredibly democratic and incredibly autocratic <PERSON>David Runciman</PERSON> on the real power of social media Hear Good morning https t co 0g7aYIATXx RT TPpodcast_ NEW EPISODE Nothing Lasts Forever When is Democracy s sell by date polis CUPAcademic Cambridge_Uni <ORGANIZATION>LRB</ORGANIZATION> https t Vice Chancellor s blog Prof <PERSON>Stephen Toope</PERSON> reflects on his first term in office and on how <LOCATION>Cambridge</LOCATION> puts openness https t co lyZLKcB5lp All this cancer talk is new to me but I do know there isn t a stage five How one woman s tragic story is helpin https t co SrPq03BpSk RT UCamArchaeology Downing Site Cambridge_Uni this morning What amazing light https t co hJqrp6SmUW RT CamUniSport And that s it <LOCATION>Cambridge</LOCATION> win 20 10 What superb day for cambridgesport Well don t to Official_CURUFC representing Camb Director of Admissions Dr <PERSON>Sam Lucy</PERSON> explains what it is like to apply to <LOCATION>Cambridge</LOCATION> https t co GcsPCxNKfJ RT CamUniSport Cambridge_Uni CURUFCW cambridgesport varsity winners https t co gNGMY3lCft RT HomertonCollege And that s the curtain down CAMBRIDGE FOR THE WIN Congratulations to the Cambridge_Uni team and especially to P We need <LOCATION>West Africa</LOCATION> s early career researchers to engage with the archaeology of their own region amp amp tell its stori https t co Y1vVj0osVS RT HomertonCollege Love that the <ORGANIZATION>Cambridge_Uni Womens</ORGANIZATION> team have their RainbowLaces on today Representing the sportforall campaign to 20 years of lessons from CleanEnergy funding distilled into 6 guiding principles for future investment https t co xC2km8OAz8 The new <ORGANIZATION>Cavendish Laboratory</ORGANIZATION> will be a facility for the nation DeptofPhysics https t co 19sEF3tz0q https t co Q3r6AwGoLB The 85 million gift from the Dolby family is the largest ever donation to <LOCATION>UK</LOCATION> science https t co 19sEF3bXBQ https t co NGs4K2v4lt An 85 million gift from the Dolby family will transform <LOCATION>UK</LOCATION> science https t co 19sEF3bXBQ https t co 5YDUJT5MFY Our series of films about OCD won the Award for Website or Use of New Media at last night s ConcordatOpenness Awa https t co F5Rjzidpzi RT pembroke1347 Good luck to everyone coming for interviews this week Our student volunteers are ready to welcome you to <LOCATION>Pembroke</LOCATION> https RT Peterhouse_SLO Our interview helpers <ORGANIZATION>Bec</ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON>Jonny</PERSON> say think out loud and don t be afraid if you don t know the answer often there i RT CaiusCollege Our fantastic student helper team out in force at the gate to welcome candidates or admissions interviews Cambridge_Un RT EarthSciCam Dr <PERSON>Owen Weller</PERSON> recently joined the NakedScientists for an early Earth Q amp amp A Listen now on bbc5live https t co epQ9o5rHS He s not one of the greatest scientists who ever lived he s a very naughty boy <PERSON>Isaac Newton</PERSON> s sins for 1662 inclu https t co 3R7wbDsN2w RT NewnhamSLO 3 days until the first applicants arrive Newnham_College If you have an interview at <ORGANIZATION>Newnham</ORGANIZATION> you may meet JCR Access Off RT CaiusCollege Coming to Cambridge_Uni for interview Here at <ORGANIZATION>Caius</ORGANIZATION> our admissions team including Dr <PERSON>Sarah Houghton Walker</PERSON> has care Sir <PERSON>Isaac Newton</PERSON> s most important papers on gravity calculus and the cost of white wine as a Cambridge_Uni unde https t co L3hrRSAPFy Today even in resource poor settings HIV infected women are able to breastfeed safely <ORGANIZATION>Meet Florence Nabwire</ORGANIZATION> w https t co c65r53zbbI RT Cambridge_Eng Gov announcement new <ORGANIZATION>Centre for Digital Built Britain</ORGANIZATION> CambridgeCDBB based Cambridge_Uni https t co w659nIxw89 We relate to horses in a unique way not quite as pets not quite as permanent family members not quite as workin https t co ybLp7SdECp By interpreting women s bones in a female specific context we can start to see how intensive variable and laborio https t co uSQdfl5dSa RT CUWBC Fascinating research from UCamArchaeology Not sure about the title though https t co YJur3q3S4r Great to see so many of our recent graduates becoming novelists poets and playwrights Congratulations <PERSON>Kiran</PERSON> https t co 4h1EXu7ILA RT theIHpodcast NEW EPISODE <PERSON>Ben Slingo</PERSON> talked to us about earlymodern scholastic visions of power republicanism and the value of t RT CSERCambridge Check out this great new video an overview of our work on existential risk https t co eRuAf5VLpD RT CamPolicyInst Do you have a world changing idea What if you could suggest new policy We are looking for Cambridge_Uni students to j Making eye contact with your baby when you re talking to them or singing nursery rhymes helps your brainwaves get i https t co 96kekXUwWE The more we understand the physics the closer we are to understanding gravity and what dark energy and dark matt https t co GIv9nLvgIi RT HomertonCollege It s GivingTuesday A single day of giving following the shopping frenzy of BlackFriday amp amp CyberMonday We invite yo RT GirtonCollege To celebrate GivingTuesday we asked <PERSON>Girton</PERSON> students how gifts from alumni have enabled them to study here You can RT ChurchillCol Today is GivingTuesday It s our goal to be able to house all of our grad students in College so that everyone can exper RT WolfsonCam Listen to <PERSON>Abigail Jenny</PERSON> and <PERSON>Matt</PERSON> talk about how their Alumni in the City bursaries helped them at Wolfson givingtuesday RT stjohnscam To mark GivingTuesday2017 five current undergraduates told us about what the College Studentship Scheme funded entirely b RT cambridgelaw Have you been called up for a cambridgeinterview <PERSON>Don</PERSON> t worry the admissions team are looking forward to meeting you T RT MECCambridge Today marks 50 years since our alumna and Honorary Fellow <PERSON>Dame Jocelyn Bell Burnell</PERSON> discovered the <ORGANIZATION>first radio pulsar Co RT</ORGANIZATION> paulcoxon 50 years ago today in a cold field outside <LOCATION>Cambridge</LOCATION> PhD student <PERSON>Jocelyn Bell Burnell</PERSON> found signals from the first radio p RT NewnhamSLO Dr <PERSON>Sam Lucy</PERSON> is Admissions Tutor Newnham_College amp amp Director of Admissions Cambridge_Uni and she ll be interviewing 84 ap Gravity is a mystery We know what it does but we don t know what it is https t co 2ZCbGdR4DQ DeptofPhysics https t co YRqAv5ROuc RT CaiusCollege Coming for an admissions interview Cambridge_Uni <PERSON>Chris</PERSON> one of our first year English students at <ORGANIZATION>Caius</ORGANIZATION> offers some New agreement with sciencespo builds on strong existing relationships between our universities at a time when https t co CQL6xbllah RT NewnhamSLO One week to go for Newnham_College interviews For Music student <PERSON>Hannah the Cambridge_Uni</PERSON> interview was the first oppo RT EarthSciCam Dr <PERSON>Owen Weller</PERSON> travelled to <LOCATION>Baffin Island</LOCATION> for fieldwork this summer He s featured in the UKinArctic campaign which high A box full of diamonds volcanic rock from <LOCATION>Mount Vesuvius</LOCATION> and the geology guide that <PERSON>Darwin</PERSON> packed for his epic vo https t co DBAfHeTQiK RT HTempestPhoto Reminder to all Cambridge_Uni graduates we are your official graduation photographers our studios will be located in RT Hughes_Hall The <ORGANIZATION>MCR</ORGANIZATION> Hughes_Hall supports breakingthesilence against sexual misconduct Cambridge_Uni https t co IXDd1ajA2T RT TrinCollCam Students TrinCollCam support Cambridge_Uni BreakingTheSilence against all sexual misconduct https t co owepEkjeAh htt PriyamvadaGopal The next slide in the externally provided training makes clear this is not <LOCATION>Cambridge</LOCATION> s view https t co oZ7mmNxc70 I m full of admiration for university staff who come here from overseas Their commitment is inspiring https t co gui6RicbEd RT UCamArchaeology Our Thanksgiving dinner was finished quite some time ago HappyThanksgiving from the zooarchaeology lab https RT CamUniSport Today during This Bucs Girl Can Week we are taking a closer look at what it takes to be an Athlete A big thank you to C To let people know about our BreakingTheSilence campaign we ve been out distributing drinks coasters around the U https t co 2Iboo0W9mj Meet g_a_ross who helps to get those tricky visa applications right the first time ThisCambridgeLife https t co iooB3GjsaK RT TPpodcast_ NEW EPISODE DMiliband explains what the refugee crisis tells us about the state of world politics and why it is both so No judgement for asking what the point of such a question might be But the solution has some interesting connectio https t co nRwvD4NdNn RT CUBotanicGarden Excitement behind the scenes in the Glasshouse Potting Shed this morning as the <ORGANIZATION>CUBG</ORGANIZATION> staff get a lesson on TitanArum One for the mathematically inclined gardeners out there what shape lawn has the best chance of retaining a grassho https t co UkTcembYMX RT DpmmsCambridge What kind of work of being done in the Stats Lab and why is it important See <PERSON>Richard Samworth</PERSON> the new Director of the In biology this long running debate has teeth https t co 8gDXXNjMLK Synthetic biology and bioengineering friend or foe https t co KxWxdwZUKz Evidence provided by REAL_Centre for cross party report calls for significant spending on early years education https t co DOe8xo8cAB Prof <PERSON>Diane Reay CambridgeEdFac</PERSON> discusses her new book on inequality in education and working class experiences wit https t co 2kP5qimMRQ It s mesmerising but what is it Find out at https t co gA1C8MtN0D https t co 9zGRD3M80x <PERSON>James Riley</PERSON> from englishunicam discusses CharlesManson and the nature of celebrity for ConversationUK https t co xg5bQXPPoF RT EarthSciCam Enhancing the growth of plants on inhospitable land using a biological fertiliser CUBotanicGarden Cambridge_Uni https That s one colourful tiger See more from this year s Cambridge_Eng photo competition at https t co gA1C8MLnSb https t co ilEIP9yCVZ RT GayTimesMag Dr <PERSON>Rachael Padman</PERSON> is the recipient of the <ORGANIZATION>Barbara Burford Gay Times</ORGANIZATION> Honour GayTimesHonours https t co UTR8NKYz1V Crystal tigers metal peacock feathers and a nano man are just some of the striking images in the Cambridge_Eng https t co Z00XPTc6Ta RT TrinityHallCamb Wonderful new poem Wake about <ORGANIZATION>Trinity Hall</ORGANIZATION> becomes visible on a flag stone in <ORGANIZATION>Front Court</ORGANIZATION> when wet Written by alumn RT Queens_Lib Manuscript waste used as spine guard in this edition of Harmonia evangelistarum emendullata <PERSON>Jena</PERSON> 1653 with frontispiec RT BTGroup We ve announced a new five year initiative with <ORGANIZATION>Huawei</ORGANIZATION> which aims to establish a joint research and collaboration group at <ORGANIZATION>RT</ORGANIZATION> camdiary <ORGANIZATION>Cambridge</ORGANIZATION> 17 Nov 2017 https t co EaPN71aOK5 https t co mduWU5HVJm RT Astro_Jenni Hey Cambridge_Eng <PERSON>Kayla</PERSON> and I want to say hello thanks for the support https t co DhYzDETNhc I first saw a baby with HIV in 2010 It was a huge shock to see babies who were just skin and bones Meet https t co Nnkzw9rcJT RT deBritish Got a question for Cambridge_Uni s <PERSON>Zoubin Ghahramani</PERSON> about artificial intelligence Share it with us for a chance to receiv Mini liver tumours grown in lab could play an important role in developing personalised medicine for patients s https t co tM49o1fAVH RT AtheneDonald Flexible reduced hours working just as important in academia and can be done Cambridge_Uni has professorial examples ht RT Cambridge_Eng The Seduction of Curves PrincetonUPress by AllanMcRobie Reader in Engineering Cambridge_Eng travels across the art TrentSixthForm downingcollege TrentCollege Well done and good luck Companies only need one <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> like to effectively target potential customers https t co BxupT0t5CQ RT AnnieThwaite Hey twitterstorians Check out the latest issue of Cambridge_Uni s Research Horizons which spotlights materialcultu josephjoecastle Why thank you https t co EGE7nAJ1SJ josephjoecastle Hi have a look at https t co SwbOS6lff6 for scholarships Information on applying can be found https t co HYfQry086i lachlanmoir Now how will you handle your new found fame https t co ZT09KC15Hw New report from nsingal14 CamEdFac suggests children with disabilities are being denied equal education opportuni https t co pb5kpLZZMC sldecrausaz UCamArchaeology CamBioanth Don t you mean minds as bright as your jacket LSimmons_Coard Hi We are afraid there is no online learning option for degree courses but we do offer part time https t co x4AE0q3bUa On November 3rd we held our Postgraduate Open Day Watch our video below to see what went on from college tours to https t co Xx0AANNU2z What makes the <LOCATION>Cambridge</LOCATION> cluster special AndyNeely explains https t co EmR2CNVo4O codiiclaus RT camdiary <ORGANIZATION>Cambridge</ORGANIZATION> 10 Nov 2017 https t co EaPN71aOK5 https t co 8fR3QkW0M9 RT ProfKAArmstrong Exit Day What Does it Mean for a Transitional Deal https t co uFYC2juxMn RT ahrcpress The winner of the RIFA2017 Best Research Film is BVLSingler for Pain In The Machine Huge congratulations https t co Good Lad facilitator <PERSON>Ben</PERSON> explains why GLInitiative is an important part of harassment amp amp sexual misconduct campaign https t co 0wheJaFjKb SimonKnight100 SchoolsWeek jonathansimons Drop me an email fred lewsey admin cam ac uk <PERSON>Robert Mair</PERSON> from CSIC_IKC and Cambridge_Eng is the new President of ICE_engineers https t co Tiwl2du2ql Human behaviour is fascinating and underpins all financial markets Meet <PERSON>Raghu Rau</PERSON> co founder of https t co gYvqdgsB7l RT theUL A chance discovery Guest post by <PERSON>Jason Scott Warren</PERSON> https t co SyyDz97vYq https t co q1MM97dxCL RT EPSRC Congratulations to Prof Lord <PERSON>Robert Mair</PERSON> CBE CSIC new President ICE_engineers https t co VBrB7AqD70 https t co pqpYC6g4iT Our CamClassics researchers have found a 2 000 year old intact Roman sundial And we think we know whose it was https t co TqCYmeUx0B A brief history of body size over 4 million years of evolution https t co mvkrddtiCE Washable stretchable and breathable electronic circuits can be printed directly onto your t shirt https t co 1awQxtAeqX Is that <PERSON>Barack Obaa</PERSON> ma Sheep are able to recognise human faces from photographs https t co 5D3DhG886E https t co ctMndXmIf5 Outrage at harassment must be channelled into change breakingthesilence https t co 4uMF0MhkjK UniversitiesUK Changing The Culture empowered unis to tackle harassment A year on GrahamVirgo reviews its impact https t co 4uMF0MhkjK Universities must continue to change to be safe places for everyone says GrahamVirgo https t co 4uMF0MhkjK UUK changingtheculture RT Dept_of_POLIS Choices in public policy evidence fairness and the art of the possible a lecture with <PERSON>Paul Johnson</PERSON> https t co ju3u Menon_Cambridge jointly leads an international push to reduce the global burden of traumatic brain injury https t co LEy7jYeFHU RT conspiratCRASSH Listen to our researchers TanyaFiler NayanikaM HDrochon discuss populism and truth at this years camideasfest ht RT camideasfest An excellent public engagement training opportunity for postgraduates post docs and early career academics at <ORGANIZATION>Cambridge RT</ORGANIZATION> takanocraig We re looking for LGBT researchers to speak at PrideinSTEM public event CambSciFest 2018 If you re interested please Foodies rejoice The black truffle has been cultivated in the <LOCATION>UK</LOCATION> for the first time https t co zPgBlVtZHL RT TrinCollCam Tutors TrinCollCam support Cambridge_Uni BreakingTheSilence against all sexual misconduct https t co owepEkjeAh https RT CambPsych All at CambPsych support the <ORGANIZATION>University</ORGANIZATION> s campaign to prevent harassment and sexual misconduct https t co N0RCKMgd5U bre We have 10 000 postgrad students from 250 countries working in countless subject areas Say hello to some of them https t co bXTvLCG4jR Scientists have identified a key chemical in the brain s memory region that helps us suppress unwanted thoughts https t co RQHfxuScyD RT stjohnslibcam Silver rain and singed eyebrows a new SpecialCollections Spotlight on 17th C fireworks https t co 39dRjp69ys Hap CaiusCollege Happy birthday For many students managing a disability comes as an extra pressure <PERSON>Rachel Demery</PERSON> Cambridge_DRC is there to hel https t co 3bgXiPzuJX RT TrinCollCam Senior Tutor CSBarnard24 TrinCollCam supports Cambridge_Uni BreakingTheSilence against sexual misconduct https t co RT Cambridge_Uni Tomorrow is postgraduate Open Day so here s PhD historian <PERSON>Eleanor</PERSON> on food amp amp eating in Reformation <LOCATION>England</LOCATION> amp amp <LOCATION>Italy</LOCATION> http RT CamUniSport Some close results but a good week overall for the sports teams representing Cambridge_Uni lightblues cambridgesport c Tomorrow is postgraduate Open Day so here s PhD historian <PERSON>Eleanor</PERSON> on food amp amp eating in Reformation <LOCATION>England</LOCATION> amp amp <LOCATION>Italy</LOCATION> https t co tI2PvBCX3Q RT TPpodcast_ NEW EPISODE The latest on Brexit negotiations being a leaver in a remainer university With cjbickerton https t RT NewnhamSLO GoodLuck to all Newnham_College amp amp Cambridge_Uni applicants sitting a pre interview assessment today https t co ZxmWUx RT stjohnscam We re very excited to announce a special performance of KeplerOpera at the V_and_A on Nov 9th Book tickets now https RT TrinityHall_SLO Good luck to the Cambridge_Uni applicants taking a pre interview assessment today https t co fbBpwbB1fd RT HDrochon I wrote a piece for guardian on how conspiracytheories help explain Brexit based on <PERSON>YouGov</PERSON> surveys CRASSHlive https t RT TrinCollCam Tutors TrinCollCam support Cambridge_Uni BreakingTheSilence against sexual misconduct https t co FzP96huv0h https t The CambridgeUP investigates the HarryPotter impact on our language Which <PERSON>Potter</PERSON> words have entered your lexicon https t co q0LWZNdy0F RT CaiusConnect Coming to Cambridge_Uni for postgraduate open day CamGradEvents on Friday Watch our film amp amp drop in at <LOCATION>Caius</LOCATION> https How the galaxy is like a peach DarkMatterDay https t co XmPLs5a3mS Dwarf galaxies in orbit around the Milky Way could hold the key to understanding dark matter DarkMatterDay https t co K0cw1zaMq2 RT chiefrabbi CR met today with the Vice Chancellor of Cambridge_Uni amp amp received assurances that any instances of antisemitism are comple While we do not yet understand what dark matter is formed of we know that it is everywhere DarkMatterDay https t co fCluwq6FI9 The city of <LOCATION>Cambridge</LOCATION> was deeply affected by the Reformation Learn more at a new online exhibition https t co DTYWZaRYzM Fri Postgraduate Open Day Join students like <PERSON>Yesim</PERSON> who is researching political violence truth amp amp reconciliatio https t co EMSg0ekjkv RT TrinCollCam Tutors TrinCollCam support Cambridge_Uni BreakingTheSilence against sexual misconduct https t co FzP96huv0h https t A new online exhibition marks Reformation500 https t co DTYWZaRYzM The world s first search engine https t co 7ISDxPOck0 An eclipse mentioned in the bible has helped date the Egyptian pharaohs https t co fr6pItIMvU The oldest recorded eclipse took place on October 30th 1207 BC In the afternoon in case you were wondering https t co fr6pItrb7k RT scottpolar Listen to the NaturePodcast for our researcher DrMattWise on traces of Antarctic instability https t co DWPI19teHI ht The oldest recorded eclipse took place OnThisDay 3224 years ago https t co fr6pItIMvU RT cambtweetmedic Timelapse view from the EmmaCambridge library CambTweet https t co zyOqwZAumc RT camdiary <LOCATION>Cambridge</LOCATION> on a SundayMorning 29 Oct 2017 clockswentback https t co eUEgmDu25u RT TPpodcast_ Very pleased and humbled to spot TP in today s Observer s Best Podcasts 2017 supplement worth grabbing for other podcast RT pembroke1347 Senior Tutor <PERSON>Dan Tucker</PERSON> on the Cambridge_Uni BreakingTheSilence campaign https t co dPFMK1Ua2l https t co vbF2M7sitz RT pembroke1347 Our Graduate Parlour President on the crucial work of BreakingTheSilence https t co dPFMK1Ua2l https t co EspApLINwQ RT pembroke1347 College Nurse <PERSON>Jan Brighting</PERSON> is running the Bystander intervention initiative in Pembroke We re BreakingTheSilence https RT pembroke1347 <PERSON>Evie Aspinall</PERSON> on seizing the opportunity to empower meaningful long term change by BreakingTheSilence https t co dPFM RT pembroke1347 Sophia GP Women s Officer on making BreakingTheSilence a College wide campaign https t co dPFMK1Ua2l https t co jD RT pembroke1347 <PERSON>Evie Aspinall</PERSON> on seizing the opportunity to empower meaningful long term change by BreakingTheSilence https t co C Thanks to the 100s of thousands who viewed the HawkingThesis or tried to Here s a sound clip by the man himself https t co 6jmhCJAHnV We invite you to explore the amazing collection of FitzMuseum_UK Which amazing objects have you discovered there https t co kG4E0Uma2l RT pembroke1347 Pembroke supports Cambridge_Uni s BreakingTheSilence campaign to promote zero tolerance of sexual misconduct https t RT TrinCollCam Strong support TrinCollCam Hon Fellow amp amp VC <PERSON>Stephen Toope</PERSON> breakingthesilence campaign against sexual misconduct https t 3 Nov is Postgraduate Open Day Join students like Dra ko who is helping bilingual and autistic children https t co LWTgaiypmk <LOCATION>Rwanda</LOCATION> s first international cricket stadium co designed by <LOCATION>Cambridge</LOCATION> architects to open tomorrow https t co RpnSbN7W7U We need to start deploying <ORGANIZATION>CCS</ORGANIZATION> now carbon climatechange https t co Ze0Lh0MK61 RT AtheneDonald Tonight s post on harassment have things changed in unis It s time to break the silence https t co Wym4i4Z16a RT DufourGeraldine If you work at Cambridge_Uni or one of its Colleges you can attend our staff training sessions https t co qz5YzQ Scars left by icebergs record <LOCATION>West Antarctic</LOCATION> ice retreat climatechange https t co u9zy7E1kTV https t co 5i0Y3eFWy5 RT BBCWomansHour We spoke to <ORGANIZATION>CUSUWO</ORGANIZATION> about unknowingly becoming the face of a campaign to decolonise Cambridge_Uni curriculum https t How a trip to <LOCATION>Cambridge</LOCATION> in 2000 led Indian teen siddhartha_kar to become expert in cancer genomics IndiaUnboxed https t co Hjz2r8Uu8q RT EarthSciCam Interested in a PhD in Earth Sciences at Cambridge_Uni Our projects for 2018 are now online For more info visit https RT GreatOrmondSt I m so excited GOSH patient <PERSON>Alycia</PERSON> has just started at Cambridge_Uni against the odds https t co 6mWoDD7wp1 Phot Rangeenkhail ukinpakistan Hi information on the application requirements can be found here https t co t8gNwuPNTY Rapid retreat of <LOCATION>Antarctic</LOCATION> ice could cause sea levels to rise even faster than currently predicted ClimateChange https t co u9zy7E1kTV RT TheGingerSci I m a PhD student working in cancer research Cambridge_Uni This is what InvisiblyDisabledLooksLike https t co fHWksK 3 Nov is Postgraduate Open Day Join brilliant students like <PERSON>Sarah</PERSON> who investigates embryonic stem cells https t co GCL5QXPP7z <PERSON>Norah Al Ani CambRapeCrisis</PERSON> Director on the impact of harassment Find help and advice at https t co tMrAj56h2h https t co <ORGANIZATION>Gp26bNW8Tv University of Cambridge</ORGANIZATION> Vice Chancellor promotes zero tolerance approach to harassment as part of https t co C8ElBxJheG Statement from <ORGANIZATION>University of Cambridge</ORGANIZATION> in support of <PERSON>Lola Olufemi CUSUWO</PERSON> in reaction to today s media coverage https t co 2Q53sjQZNj <PERSON>Lola Olufemi</PERSON> women s officer CUSUonline makes her BreakingTheSilence statement about sexual misconduct https t co RtCD9p7wA8 RT FitzwilliamColl Fellow Dr <PERSON>Rogier Kievit</PERSON> on his support for Cambridge_Uni BreakingTheSilence campaign against sexualharassment https Professor <PERSON>Graham Virgo</PERSON> Pro Vice Chancellor talks about BreakingTheSilence around sexual misconduct https t co 2Unh4Socaz RT JackieAshley Important initiative at <LOCATION>Cambridge</LOCATION> uni has strong support from <PERSON>Lucy Cavendish</PERSON> college No better time https t co gtbr8Y Can your printer do this https t co 0ylYdlroKV How <PERSON>Elvis Presley</PERSON> helped in the fight against polio WorldPolioDay endpolio https t co <ORGANIZATION>JrZ3mWG1tQ RT HomertonCollege Homerton College</ORGANIZATION> supports the Cambridge_Uni BreakingtheSilence campaign promoting zero tolerance of sexual misconduc RT CFR32 Are you a new or expectant parent Join for honest conversations with an expert panel on the 4th Nov esrcfestival https t co RT MECCambridge <PERSON>Dame Barbara Stocking</PERSON> supports new BreakingTheSilence campaign against sexual harrassment Cambridge_Uni Read more http RT FitzwilliamColl Our Master Professor <PERSON>Nicola Padfield</PERSON> lending her support to the new Cambridge_Uni BreakingTheSilence campaign http RT rogermosey I strongly support Cambridge_Uni s BreakingTheSilence initiative amp amp the part played by Selwyn1882 s <PERSON>Lola Olufemi</PERSON> https Professor <PERSON>Eil</PERSON> s Ferran Pro Vice Chancellor speaks about our BreakingTheSilence campaign https t co tMrAj56h2h https t co jsX7bYm1YA Daydream network helps your brain get on with the job https t co nNpEBcI5dN RT CaiusCollege Our Master elect PippaRoge lending her support to new Cambridge_Uni breakingthesilence campaign against sexualharas RT EqualityCam Honoured to work with <ORGANIZATION>Cambridge Rape Crisis Centre</ORGANIZATION> on our campaign of zero tolerance to sexual harassment BreakingTheSile The clock is ticking for <LOCATION>UK</LOCATION> research funded by the <ORGANIZATION>EU</ORGANIZATION> says Prof AtheneDonald https t co FVhUuzaACm ChurchillCol camideasfest <ORGANIZATION>Brexit RT</ORGANIZATION> CaiusAlumni Our students on why they re backing Cambridge_Uni breakingthesilence campaign against sexual harassment https t co <ORGANIZATION>OGA RT</ORGANIZATION> CaiusConnect Master of Caius Professor Sir <PERSON>AlanFersht</PERSON> on his support for Cambridge_Uni breakingthesilence campaign against sexual h 72 new genetic variants that contribute to the risk of developing BreastCancer have been identified https t co yh8ZN8e7Zw RT VarsityUK Today marks the start of the new Cambridge_Uni campaign against sexual harassment BreakingTheSilence Read more https t Today we launch our BreakingTheSilence campaign to promote zero tolerance of sexual harassment https t co DxOnGJrsKx RT NewnhamSLO What s ADayInTheLife like Cambridge_Uni Follow 5 Newnham_College students on instagram this week to find out https Fancy a bit of light reading We ve put StephenHawking s 1966 PhD thesis online to celebrate openaccessweek https t co bakmB4kRtl MachineLearning used to predict earthquakes https t co C51VtrJeee When your noggin hogs the juice https t co shj0Cs7hqz Halo is it bee you re looking for https t co E3ksq69jo3 My first word was spider Meet cuckoo expert and behavioural ecologist <PERSON>Jenny York</PERSON> https t co k8LIQLZGZm https t co pxRFXxbNhC I can never rescue them but I can rescue their story Uncovering the horrors of Nazi persecution on British soil https t co zyUj9rO7mn Bees see floral halo of blue made by messy petal grooves https t co <ORGANIZATION>9Kx4zFyRTL RT GirtonCollege News Swirles Court Girton College</ORGANIZATION> The Official Opening Read more here https t co TpbWMBvrJM Cambridge_Uni NWCamb RT bhask286 <LOCATION>Cambridge</LOCATION> exhibition focuses on water crisis in <LOCATION>Himalaya</LOCATION> PrasunSonwalkar htTweets https t co 8Swo0L3TG7 Cambridge_Uni F A fashion for feathers and a fading lobster our latest issue of researchhorizons materialculture https t co aghfwBoHj1 A <LOCATION>Cambridge</LOCATION> undergrad armed with coloured pens truly is a force to be reckoned with CambTweet is a great resource https t co 5owHXG2Zep RT cambridgelaw Faculty s ACLudlow and cambridgecrim talk learningtogether JustisTogether on education in prisons https t co vvC 3 Nov is Postgraduate Open Day Join brilliant students like <PERSON>Himansha</PERSON> a Pharmacologist striking fear into bacteri https t co ONvQAFU6Nl RT Gates_Cambridge <PERSON>Shefali Mehta</PERSON> on her time at <LOCATION>Cambridge</LOCATION> and starting her own agriculture consultancy https t co ELFX487wyt shefal First detection of <PERSON>GravitationalWaves</PERSON> and light from colliding neutron stars https t co knlvwiMgsz Big announcement from the <ORGANIZATION>LIGO</ORGANIZATION> team this afternoon Watch live here https t co ICmo5yKDYb GravitationalWaves Nanobots could soon be patrolling our bodies making repairs as they go FutureofMedicine https t co FgmUGqJBKF https t co DivtR0GBak Restless legs syndrome is surprisingly common but we know little about what causes it and how to treat it https t co HqoHbxpkQZ RT NewnhamSLO ApplyingToCambridge over the next 3 days Check out these application tips Remember the deadline is 6pm <LOCATION>UK</LOCATION> time on 15th O Bobby_Seagull cambtweetmedic emmanuelaccess EmmaCambridge pembroke1347 TrinCollCam We were rather hoping for eternal glory cambtweetmedic Bobby_Seagull emmanuelaccess EmmaCambridge The chapel pembroke1347 amp amp the <LOCATION>Wren Library</LOCATION> clue is https t co wWvahiQL3N RT CamDigLib As we settle into the new academic year <PERSON>Isaac Newton</PERSON> s thoughts On Educating Youth in the Universities https t co hRBMR RT vnbateman <ORGANIZATION>BBC</ORGANIZATION> article on gendergap amp amp sexism in economics amp amp our annual WomenInEconomicsDay CaiusCollege Cambridge_Uni https t Look Look again Every object in the MAACambridge tells not one but many stories https t co WCOqBN5orY RT mel_rosina Now it s official https t co <ORGANIZATION>NSG7bEie7q RT</ORGANIZATION> TPpodcast_ Latest books by TP contributor <PERSON>Brendan Simms</PERSON> from Cambridge_Uni Listen to him on this week s ep https t co S43kSJOrjO Remember to apply this Sunday If you have questions please look at https t co hYPu7T23JA or contact BeCambridge https t co 1JljPp0g8P The Future of Medicine a world of nanobots killer immune cells and artificial organs https t co FgmUGqs0T7 https t co h9UJND2cPO Ed made a last minute application Now he s doing his dream job looking after 1 2 million insects https t co iLRaVElW03 There can t be many people with a 20 year old exotic newt living in the kitchen <ORGANIZATION>Meet Ed Turner</ORGANIZATION> from ZoologyMuseum https t co XsZq14pCkO RT BeCambridge Important reminder 15 October 18 00 <LOCATION>UK</LOCATION> time <ORGANIZATION>UCAS</ORGANIZATION> application closing date and pre interview assessment registration RT ChuArchives We hold the collections of two pioneering women scientists <PERSON>Lise Meitner</PERSON> and <PERSON>Rosalind Franklin</PERSON> dayofthegirl womeninscien RT NakedScientists What can DNA tell us about our past present and future Also what DNA do we find in a sausage https t co S9f2QfU6 RT camideasfest Who believes in conspiracy theories HDrochon talks about his event on 21 October https t co SDEHhXVqZK conspiratCRA Experts led by RDuschinsky express concerns over infant mental health assessment https t co cSkOhO03n5 https t co fOXQgfZpPw RT IfMCambridge Professor <PERSON>Tim Minshall</PERSON> appointed head of the <ORGANIZATION>Institute for Manufacturing</ORGANIZATION> https t co KNYWhqQstt https t co NGZ0MyIzA8 RT UKandEU Read our latest explainer on Article 218 the new Article50 CSBarnard24 Cambridge_Uni https t co zCjagwu0Jr https t co Remember to apply those of you goingtocambridge in future https t co KeJWEXOMAC Lady <PERSON>Thatcher</PERSON> s closest allies begged her not to fight another election newly opened papers for 1987 have revealed https t co xHL3U9pBWu RT WhippleMuseum Here s the Difference Engine that inspired friendship between mathematicians <PERSON>Ada Lovelace</PERSON> amp amp <ORGANIZATION>Babbage</ORGANIZATION> AdaLovelaceDay htt The size of conservationists own environmental footprints might surprise you https t co jewaMP0Ydn RT camdiary <ORGANIZATION>Cambridge</ORGANIZATION> 10 Oct 2017 https t co EaPN71aOK5 https t co T5DvFBXh9n RT paftersnu So the new academic year has started Are you REALLY ready https t co 6BmQ0nFbNu RT EarthSciCam This term we ll be following our Part IIs 3rd years as they work on their independent mapping projects with an update e OCD can ruin lives our researchers are trying to better understand it amp amp develop more effective treatments OCDWeek https t co l2FxRv3Mu5 RT AllegreHadida Do popular or acclaimed movie stars shine brighter at the box office Find out in our new JAMS_updates article https RT scottpolar Mind the gap brilliant shot from our recently submitted PhD student tjy511 taken on fieldwork in <LOCATION>Greenland</LOCATION> this sum RT CUWBC A huge thanks to Professor Sir <PERSON>Leszek Borysiewicz</PERSON> for supporting us so well during his 7 years as Vice Chancellor WeAreCambrid We are now coming to the end of CambridgeFreshers 2017 What was the best moment of your week freshersweek https t co VY6Ea1a8vw Early humans seem to have recognised the dangers of inbreeding at least 34 000 years ago https t co dOMkRXP9xv RT cambtweetecon Taster session for <ORGANIZATION>Sidney Sussex Boat Club</ORGANIZATION> earlier today rowing CambTweet https t co utVUdftHp8 senji Hi would you mind letting UniCamIT know Thanks RT camideasfest What are the prospects for <LOCATION>UK</LOCATION> research after <ORGANIZATION>Brexit AtheneDonald</ORGANIZATION> discusses on 23 October https t co Fs96YHeFKP Chur fiorebosso84 Hi fiorebosso you could try asking cambtweetlaw Meet the <LOCATION>Caribbean</LOCATION> PhD student getting to grips with protein folding https t co wwOjOR1FfC https t co cRiRZZ27Tl RT bhask286 What is the future of the <LOCATION>UK</LOCATION> countryside post Brexit Look at the opinion of some key thinkers on our site https t co u7GCu RT turinginst We re delighted to announce Professor <PERSON>Frank Kelly</PERSON> has joined turinginst Board as Trustee for Cambridge_Uni https t co Could we build a BladeRunner style replicant <PERSON>Fumiya Iida</PERSON> from Cambridge_Eng lays out what it would take https t co VfZnjX7Yat Lectures started Looking for a place to study In May students shared their top study spots check them out here https t co nUV1mQjxts RT KavliFoundation Q amp amp A <PERSON>John Richer Cambridge_Uni</PERSON> on the massive challenge of building almaobs at 5000m in <LOCATION>Earth</LOCATION> s driest desert ht RT Gates_Cambridge <PERSON>Kavita Ramakrishnan</PERSON> to speak at camideasfest in panel on technology and nationalism in <LOCATION>India</LOCATION> https t co <ORGANIZATION>IvLHDFwcl RT</ORGANIZATION> hknbgc NobelPrize celebrations have started at MRC_LMB with <PERSON>Richard Henderson</PERSON> s speech NobelPrize Cambridge_Uni https t co XQZUw These transit instruments from the WhippleMuseum helped keep 