<ner>Mindfulness based meditation may help those experiencing depression https t co fVqtBm6FR6 <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> scientists reveal the genetic roadmap to building an entire organism from a single cell https t co xiYEXra479 Adopting these 5 habits may increase your lifespan https t co bcKvWmllh7 The President s Innovation Challenge recognized three student ventures STEMgem OZ and PionEar https t co Q5TaRjfj0V Assistant professor of history and African and African American Studies <PERSON>Elizabeth Hinton</PERSON> was named a 2018 Carnegie https t co pEUPQPbsRg In a new study researchers uncovered one explanation for why exercise might be beneficial It stimulates the heart https t co QNOXZwvks6 Iconic 90s album Jagged Little Pill adapted into americanrep show written by <PERSON>Diablo Cody</PERSON> https t co JOBx7yxLwf <PERSON>Benjamin Grimm</PERSON> 18 only laughs at the coincidences that have shaped his <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> career Harvard18 https t co W85xbNtFxQ A new public art installation is coming to the RadInstitute <LOCATION>Wallach Garden</LOCATION> https t co zkhNxXE8Md https t co AktYR15pVK As their days as an undergrad draw to a close students reflect on their experience at <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> in this Senior Talk https t co a7Uh48BDOX 5 healthy habits to live by from <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> researchers https t co bcKvWmllh7 The setting of her childhood <LOCATION>Virginia</LOCATION> s <LOCATION>Shenandoah Valley</LOCATION> instilled in Drew Faust a dual passion for history an https t co ShczQNUm4r RT hseas A multi layered structure allows robots to create and eliminate joints and to rapidly change their stiffness damping and dynam The recently released 2017 Harvard Sustainability Report shows the <ORGANIZATION>University</ORGANIZATION> s progress to a healthier fossil fue https t co SOVUQE9lhr There are not clear lines between the private and the public life in this job You re always president of <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> https t co OrVMNM05Mc <PERSON>Casey Khang Moore</PERSON> 18 found new roles to explore at <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> including singer politician and archaeologist https t co TC1TbnPbvk RT HarvardArchives At <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> historic <LOCATION>Massachusetts Hall</LOCATION> stands the test of time with a little help https t co P1N0R0UkTW via Harva This new microscope captures 3 D images and videos of cells inside living organisms https t co bl9moKMdpz https t co oKFj2Rsi9u <ORGANIZATION>Harvard Arts Medalist Colson Whitehead</ORGANIZATION> discussed the journey behind his Pulitzer Prize winning novel The Undergro https t co Da1TtMkmli From your friends at <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> MayThe4thBeWithYou Happy Star Wars Day https t co Z6LufsFLMT <PERSON>James Earl Jones</PERSON> told <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> graduates May the Force be with you at our Harvard17 Commencement StarWarsDay https t co KG9G7S0IxT <PERSON>John McCain</PERSON> has announced this will be his final term in the <ORGANIZATION>Senate Harvard</ORGANIZATION> experts discuss his legacy https t co 9QdImtVVC4 Professor <PERSON>CassSunstein</PERSON> said Star Wars was a seminal source of inspiration in his life and career https t co 6QLlASwE80 Is lasting peace between North and <LOCATION>South Korea</LOCATION> realistic https t co 1DytVmsLoO A portrait of S <PERSON>Allen</PERSON> Counter founding director of harvfoun was recently unveiled at <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> s <LOCATION>Annenberg Hall</LOCATION> https t co FBFCBQBnm7 Family history and the 1960s all helped to shape President <PERSON>Drew Faust</PERSON> but it was illness that urged her forward https t co B0tYKdxiLl How can mindfulness meditation help reduce stress and anxiety https t co oW5UVwRSI6 RT HarvardChanSPH During a conversation with <PERSON>HarvardChanDean BillGates</PERSON> says he takes a two pronged approach to funding big ideas looki A symposium on traffic safety around the globe was hosted by HarvardGH https t co K7LyxXSj7I <PERSON>Lindsay D Amato</PERSON> took a circuitous route from <LOCATION>Missouri</LOCATION> to the <ORGANIZATION>Harvard School of Dental Medicine</ORGANIZATION> via graduate school https t co Nlpv2gpS08 Can you love the art but hate the artist Alum <PERSON>Alex Ross</PERSON> explores if and how it is possible to separate a controver https t co X83BaXsnk3 A study by <PERSON>DrMANowak</PERSON> explores what social conditions help cooperation thrive https t co MjYKCnnzHL Award winning author <PERSON>Chimamanda Ngozi Adichie</PERSON> will speak at <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> s Class Day Harvard18 https t co wMGMUnKoSp <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> experts say these 5 healthy habits may add more than a decade to your life https t co bcKvWmllh7 https t co QGV09jaJJx At a RadInstitute panel <ORGANIZATION>Hall of Fame</ORGANIZATION> pitcher <PERSON>Pedro Martinez</PERSON> and others discussed the <ORGANIZATION>RedSox</ORGANIZATION> s responsibilities t https t co HcwN54bTpv Discovery from hseas has the potential of increasing the capacity of wireless communications https t co q6mBz7H7WB <PERSON>Elizabeth Hinton</PERSON> assistant professor of history and of African and African American Studies has been named a 2018 https t co 2RWgbp1cnk RT innovationlab Congrats to all of our winners It s been a long and fruitful journey and we couldn t be more proud of you https t co The HarvardGH partnered with the <ORGANIZATION>Safe Life Foundation</ORGANIZATION> in an effort to combat global traffic deaths https t co K7LyxXSj7I RT hgse BREAKING HGSE s <PERSON>Bridget Terry Long</PERSON> bterrylong will become the next dean of the <ORGANIZATION>Harvard Graduate School of Education Please</ORGANIZATION> j Thanks for joining us at ARTSFIRST https t co tVkzPTkCGV RT HoughtonLib Now open our new exhibition Passports Lives in Transit In addition to drawing on our collections it features an art in RT MittalInstitute Our latest podcast The distinguished psychiatrist Professor <PERSON>Vikram Patel</PERSON> harvardmed is one of the speakers at How is an entire organism built from a single cell <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> scientists are revealing the genetic roadmap https t co VmXlYrNmc1 RT HarvardAlumni WBW the Class of 1965 busting a move at their HarvardReunion linedancevibes dancingshoes https t co rLJJzaekcY <PERSON>Bridget Terry Long</PERSON> a leading economist and internationally recognized scholar on the economics of higher education https t co gRE5Njq6rN In 1958 <PERSON>Constance Kite</PERSON> was featured in a HarvardMuseum of Natural History postcard with this 42 foot long prehisto https t co PJHwDli4fU RT harvardmed A new discovery could help scientists better understand how the brain forms memories https t co <ORGANIZATION>S1DgWQv7qz Harvard</ORGANIZATION> analysts discuss the legacy <PERSON>John McCain</PERSON> https t co 9QdImtVVC4 Good morning https t co 2EsaunR72O RT Kennedy_School <PERSON>Sheila Jasanoff</PERSON> asks Would we let people control aspects of our lives the same way we let technology https t co 3r7 On a recent visit to <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> BillGates viewed demonstrations of cutting edge research at hseas https t co peN3Nzc8Q3 RT niemanfdn ICYMI We announced the Nieman class of 2019 today These 27 journalists are going to light up <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> with their many crea The 2017 Harvard Sustainability Report released by <ORGANIZATION>GreenHarvard</ORGANIZATION> documents the <ORGANIZATION>University</ORGANIZATION> s transformation to a hea https t co Oy0EaIeXJA RT HarvardHealth A blood test to screen for cancer may be just around the corner https t co ub3N41qPBe HarvardHealth https t co TYj Exercise stimulates the heart to make new muscle cells helping keep your heart younger https t co a8as2cYaUj Following the historic announcement of their intent to sign a peace treaty BelferCenter s <PERSON>John Park</PERSON> discusses the https t co JJAkce9DPp At <ORGANIZATION>RadInstitute Pedro Mart nez</ORGANIZATION> and fellow panelists discussed the RedSox s work off the field including efforts https t co 9GXm6nuM73 These 5 healthy habits may add more than a decade to your life https t co bcKvWmllh7 https t co uMtVxKTnij Under what social conditions does cooperation thrive This latest study takes a look https t co MjYKCnFb6l <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> received a spotlight award which recognize businesses colleges and universities that encourage the use o https t co ZyMG3SP8mJ <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> scientists reveal the genetic roadmap to building an entire organism from a single cell https t co bGIdHvQNF6 Do curiosity driven fundamental research programs lead to the discovery of more medicines https t co Q9Emxu9Q2h President <PERSON>Faust</PERSON> recommends reading Philosophy Prepared Me for a Career in Finance and Government by <PERSON>Robert E Rub</PERSON> https t co 0O35gM4EuT A Kennedy_School panel on progress and challenges featured former leaders of <LOCATION>Tanzania Nigeria</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Cape Verde</LOCATION> https t co LEXNdZBoDY <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> Professor <PERSON>Michael Sandel</PERSON> recently spoke about ethics markets and democracy to 1 500 people in <LOCATION>Moscow</LOCATION> s Ma https t co v6bIzszIev Obstacles turned into stepping stones for senior <PERSON>Casey Khang Moore</PERSON> Harvard18 https t co hPpJWIIIL4 RT harvardmed A one time treatment with a new gene therapy reduced or eliminated the need for blood transfusions in 22 patients with a se <ORGANIZATION>Harvard Arts Medalist</ORGANIZATION> colsonwhitehead recalled the journey behind his Pulitzer Prize winning novel https t co vaczzu4HO3 Five healthy habits to live by from <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> researchers https t co bcKvWmllh7 Healthy diets and exercise have helped but longer lives also mean more cases of dementia https t co n158AmU7pa Tonight at 6 30pm EDT Antigone the ancient Greek drama by <PERSON>Sophocles</PERSON> will be performed in <ORGANIZATION>Harvard Stadium</ORGANIZATION> https t co gfgXt7qcUC This feat is one of the most remarkable in the natural world and despite decades of study a complete understandin https t co uw1ukUbMsV Former leaders of <LOCATION>Tanzania Nigeria</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Cape Verde</LOCATION> were welcomed to Kennedy_School for a panel on progress and ch https t co kfUdkK7YjO Leading historian on law and society tbrownnagin has been named dean of <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> s RadInstitute https t co oQwMDxgGsh A new microscope is capable of capturing in unprecedented detail 3 D images and videos of cells inside living org https t co yGXnKme8Pb While a single sleepless night is probably harmless the cumulative effects of sleep deprivation may be more danger https t co TkSJvQvIEK Mindfulness meditation can help reduce stress and anxiety https t co oW5UVwRSI6 <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> scientists are revealing how one cell builds an entire organism https t co xhXfsDyxTU https t co Yakp8ooBQO RT HarvardLocal The ARTSFIRST Performance Fair is today on the <LOCATION>Science Center Plaza</LOCATION> next to <ORGANIZATION>Harvard Yard With</ORGANIZATION> 11 stages and more than Award winning author <PERSON>Chimamanda Ngozi Adichie</PERSON> is the Harvard18 Class Day speaker https t co wMGMUnKoSp RT harvardarts ARTS FIRST SATURDAY Join us for our daylong FREE festival of the arts at <ORGANIZATION>Harvard All</ORGANIZATION> the arts For all ages All are we RT cs50 This is CS with davidjmalan at Visitas2018 at harvard https t co xyki5T1olK WelcomeToHarvard Harvard2022 Under what social conditions does cooperation thrive DrMANowak s latest study takes a look https t co MjYKCnFb6l RT DanaFarber Two years after being given six months to live <PERSON>Michael Mullan</PERSON> s cancer is still at bay because of immunotherapy and targe On Thursday BillGates toured campus visited hseas and wyssinstitute labs and spoke with students https t co 1oh8CMsk5w How can we set the stage for the discovery of more medicines https t co Q9Emxu9Q2h Antigone the ancient Greek drama by <PERSON>Sophocles</PERSON> will be performed in <ORGANIZATION>Harvard Stadium</ORGANIZATION> Sunday at 6 30pm as part of https t co dEVgpCaG8v Thomas Sheehan Associate University Organist and Choirmaster in MemChurch talks about his introduction to music https t co WqMvdosUFP RT HarvardLibrary More than 300 000 newly digitized pages from Colonial era North American life are viewable on the new Colonial North Am Last night Pulitzer Prize winning author colsonwhitehead 91 received the <ORGANIZATION>Harvard Arts Medal</ORGANIZATION> during a ceremony ho https t co ad9FO73NeH Professor <PERSON>Albert Hofman</PERSON> spoke at <ORGANIZATION>RadInstitute</ORGANIZATION> about the dementia epidemic https t co n158AmU7pa This weekend s ARTS FIRST festival features performances exhibitions installations and events of every musical a https t co xhoFYsHSUs A portrait of S <PERSON>Allen Counter</PERSON> founding director of harvfoun who died last summer was unveiled at <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> s <PERSON>Anne</PERSON> https t co R7VvDs4Su2 This new technology opens up an entirely new approach to personalized medicine https t co I4ujz0ssnA The work here is taking robotics in many dimensions and in different realms BillGates said during a Q amp amp A session https t co OBgubkQkHX It is almost like going from seeing a few stars to seeing the entire universe https t co xhXfsDyxTU The new dean of <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> s RadInstitute is tbrownnagin https t co oQwMDxgGsh A new microscope can capture 3 D images and videos of cells inside living organisms https t co bl9moKMdpz https t co D5J1699dVo We loved having BillGates back on campus today He toured through several robotics labs to see the latest faculty https t co ltmBAgSsNV Racial integration of American businesses hasn t improved much despite 40 years of trying <PERSON>Rembrand Koning</PERSON> of https t co gipman6nqX Fundamental research may be the best route for the generation of new medicines https t co pIPPRu9iGp RT marty_walsh I m looking forward to helping the <ORGANIZATION>Harvard Allston Partnership Fund</ORGANIZATION> celebrate its 10th year and 1 million in grants in A Pulitzer Prize winning author colsonwhitehead 91 will receive the <ORGANIZATION>Harvard Arts Medal</ORGANIZATION> tonight kicking off <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> https t co LeNtFyKgOo Watch a live Q amp amp A with BillGates happening now at <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> https t co hvniZvbqHW RT GreenHarvard How did we do in 2017 Check out our annual Harvard Sustainability Report https t co 9CJTW8NvjZ https t co wXihTKEifS Arts First Harvard s annual spring festival makes its debut in <LOCATION>Allston</LOCATION> this year https t co NdxakmFZO3 Join us today for a Q amp amp A with BillGates hosted by Provost <PERSON>Alan Garber</PERSON> and <PERSON>Dean Frank Doyle Watch</PERSON> live at 2pm EDT https t co hvniZvbqHW Using patients unique genetic variation profiles this new method enables personalized medicine https t co I4ujz0ssnA Professor tbrownnagin has been named dean of <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> s RadInstitute https t co oQwMDxgGsh A <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> conference on Afro Brazilian issues will honor the memory of activist <PERSON>Marielle Franco</PERSON> who was gunned dow https t co sT5yoPm25n RT HarvardAsh NEWS Introducing a New Repository of Government Data Visualizations and Maps Learn more about <PERSON>DataSmartCities Solutio Malia Clark</PERSON> 21 reflects on her first year at <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> https t co v2gzWsizF6 RT GreenHarvard Transparency is a key ingredient for accountability and continual improvement We re visualizing and presenting our data RT harvardmed Researchers have discovered how a gene that regulates brain size may have had a hand in the evolutionary development of the RT GreenHarvard 2017 <ORGANIZATION>Harvard Sustainability Report</ORGANIZATION> highlights 129 LEED certified projects Side guards on large trucks to protect cy Researchers find that exercise stimulates the heart to make new muscle cells cc MassGeneralNews https t co ggVnQ424tJ Would prioritizing curiosity driven fundamental research programs over shovel ready science set the stage for th https t co oeChzUs00u The Transcript Project focuses on the idea that college is a time of curiosity driven intellectual journeys https t co hJ9pc82TMp RT HarvardLocal A strong partnership between the <LOCATION>Allston Brighton</LOCATION> community <ORGANIZATION>CityOfBoston</ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION>Harvard the Harvard Allston Partnership</ORGANIZATION> At a RadInstitute talk about the dementia epidemic Professor <PERSON>Albert Hofman</PERSON> said most Alzheimer s cases are likel https t co Ax6kI4w1ch RT GreenHarvard Released today <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> s 2017 Sustainability Report details our path to a healthier fossil fuel free future https t c Happy birthday to <PERSON>Ella Fitzgerald</PERSON> who received an honorary degree from <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> in 1990 https t co vdxqg9T15c RT wyssinstitute A new technique uses patients unique genetic variation profiles to aid in personalized medicine https t co oKk1IeMCR A new microscope is capable of capturing in unprecedented detail 3 D images and videos of cells inside living org https t co aFPuFJAOtd RT HarvardChanSPH A new study shows that vaccines have enormous impact not just on health but on keeping people out of poverty Vaccine The U S lags far behind other countries in terms of maternal and parental leave But the remedies are complex https t co hWRcJlI6ti The 15 finalists for the 2018 President s Innovation Challenge were drawn from an entry pool more than double the s https t co IflVzyJ4sV RT HarvardIOP 70 of young Americans likely to vote in the 2018 midterm elections believe that gun control laws in the U S should be mor Can you love the art but hate the artist At <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> alum <PERSON>Alex Ross</PERSON> discussed the influence of German composer <PERSON>Ric</PERSON> https t co FvujarjjXR The Emancipation Proclamation was on display at HarvardHBS s <LOCATION>Baker Library</LOCATION> last week as part of the library s cele https t co NHmt40BYxK Provost <PERSON>Alan Garber</PERSON> discusses a recent neuroscience symposium at <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION>University</ORGANIZATION> s evolving scientific l https t co TcfaPJAJnM RT HarvardAlumni Harvard18 Commencement is a month from today Ready for that pomp and circumstance https t co I9R8ucduZj RT HarvardChanDean I recommend this profile of <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> s <PERSON>Tania Fabo</PERSON> who views basic science through the lens of health disparities I sp Poor design of some sponsorship programs can hinder rather than help women in the workplace https t co iypNjwSrA5 via <ORGANIZATION>HarvardHBS RT</ORGANIZATION> HarvardLocal From Stone Age target practice to gallery talks get an inside look at some of <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> s public events and programs held RT hseas These applied mathematicians are modeling ventilation in termite mounds hoping to find inspiration for more energy efficient bui The <ORGANIZATION>Science Research Mentoring Program</ORGANIZATION> provides high school students with real life research experience coupled wi https t co SQoPtSqJ4w Junior <PERSON>Lance Oppenheim</PERSON> has a film premiering at the Tribeca Film Festival https t co THmkMGYPFz Senior <PERSON>Elizabeth Keto</PERSON> designed a harvartmuseums gallery tour where she encourages her group to ask questions and https t co azNmlcR8FG RT harvardmed The 2018 Bertarelli Symposium showcased the latest efforts to bring gene therapy to the treatment of sensory disorders http <PERSON>Tania Fabo</PERSON> 18 aspires to reduce health inequalities among minorities https t co rNf0k6Rc5r RT hseas <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> s new Science and Engineering Complex features novel environmentally friendly features https t co 72ncffWtV9 EarthDa RT HarvardChanSPH Tomorrow April 24 <ORGANIZATION>Noon ET Harvard</ORGANIZATION> president <PERSON>Drew Faust</PERSON> joins VoicesHSPH and HarvardChanDean to discuss her decade Can termites teach us how to build more energy efficient buildings https t co zcTLcYJQ7h https t co RM6OldatQg RT HarvardAlumni The ArtsFirst Performance Fair features comedy a cappella dance music of all kinds drama and more https t co ckR Something fun to start your week Can you spot the <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> locations in this video https t co 78jHGlqLrA RT Kennedy_School Watch live tonight <PERSON>Benjamin Crump Lezley McSpadden Jason Pollock Jasmine Rand Ashley Spillane</PERSON> and <PERSON>Khalil Muhammad</PERSON> In honor of <ORGANIZATION>WorldBookDay</ORGANIZATION> hear <PERSON>John Lithgow</PERSON> 67 read <PERSON>Charles Simic</PERSON> s In the Library a love letter to libraries https t co SQWNyFQysv <PERSON>Pierre Berasta</PERSON> n <PERSON>Ojeda</PERSON> 10 M Div 14 has been appointed director of <ORGANIZATION>Harvard s Office of Sexual Assault Preventio</ORGANIZATION> https t co ClO5tlaZA0 On <PERSON>William Shakespeare</PERSON> s birthday take a look at a rare copy of his Third Folio part of the <ORGANIZATION>Harry Elkins Widener</ORGANIZATION> https t co hLWFq9gfRS RT HarvardAlumni How teens view the job market can derail their academic engagement but supportive adults can temper that effect https Researchers at <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> study how neurons control aspects of parenting behavior in mice https t co tuCMEe1EBr <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> student <PERSON>Lance Oppenheim</PERSON> s film The Happiest Guy in the World a documentary about a man who has lived abo https t co vqKDlSAcjN RT harvardmed <ORGANIZATION>Research</ORGANIZATION> suggests that regular practice of mindfulness and meditation may change certain brain regions linked to memory se This winning RadInstitute Public Art Competition design will be installed in the <LOCATION>Wallach Garden</LOCATION> rotating public ar https t co szDLts30VS RT applytoharvard For live updates from Visitas2018 and to hear from current students follow us on Snapchat DiscoverHarvard Instagra The Sustainability Program at HarvardEXT has seen rapid growth in the last decade as climatechange becomes a grea https t co <ORGANIZATION>EHIYoD7nkz Happy EarthDay Harvard</ORGANIZATION> is committed to creating a healthier fossil fuel free future Explore greenharvard s c https t co nfqtV0EDXk A group of former governors discussed the OpioidEpidemic at a HarvardChanSPH forum https t co M1jOsHvelE RT HarvardAlumni Harvard2022 admits are in the 02138 this weekend for Visitas2018 Let them know why YOU chose <ORGANIZATION>Harvard WelcometoHa RT</ORGANIZATION> PoliteFlorencia To the Classof2022 WelcomeToHarvard You are entering such an exciting time in your lives with endless opportunitie <ORGANIZATION>Boston Globe</ORGANIZATION> Spotlight team journalists talked about their landmark December 2017 series on <LOCATION>Boston</LOCATION> s difficult hist https t co DJKepWrB4m Scholars from MottHallBridges learned how to beatbox at <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> https t co AHnC0MYJIp It s Visitas2018 We re excited to welcome Harvard2022 to campus this weekend WelcomeToHarvard https t co oQIgT4QE8O From the more than 400 teams that entered business plans in the President s Innovation Challenge 15 have been sele https t co jAaNp2Mm3F <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> s <PERSON>Sunn</PERSON> m <PERSON>Cheaux</PERSON> taught 7th graders the origin of the Gullah language https t co SDQqcZAlVs Award winning author <PERSON>Chimamanda Ngozi Adichie</PERSON> will address Harvard18 graduating seniors at Class Day on May 23 https t co wMGMUnKoSp At <PERSON>Harvard_Law Liu Zhenya</PERSON> the former head of <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> s electric grid spoke about the potential and need for a wor https t co mkQJUHVNtK Research by <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> s <PERSON>DulacLab</PERSON> sheds light on how parents operate https t co tuCMEe1EBr RT GreenHarvard HarvardEXT s Sustainability Program has seen rapid growth in the last decade as climatechange becomes a greater threat Mindfulness techniques can help with stress and anxiety https t co oW5UVwRSI6 The Happiest Guy in the World a film by junior <PERSON>Lance Oppenheim</PERSON> will premiere at the <ORGANIZATION>Tribeca Film Festival</ORGANIZATION> https t co THmkMGYPFz RT GreenHarvard We celebrated EarthDay early Here are some scenes from today s event which featured a Freecycle electronics recycling Senior <PERSON>Elizabeth Keto</PERSON> s self designed gallery tour is intended to prompt reflection and conversations https t co dyh2IpvgiV RT harvardmed Adapting a technique used by astronomers researchers have developed a microscope capable of capturing cells in unprecedent The <ORGANIZATION>American Academy of Arts and Sciences</ORGANIZATION> announced the election of 213 new members including 11 <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> faculty https t co kcmlpK0AAI The projects from the 15 finalists offer solutions to real world issues and obstacles from ear infections and cont https t co C3iNLTQASd <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> s new interdisciplinary research effort aims to increase scientific understanding of biological systems https t co lFhrSTxyRd RT applytoharvard Harvard2022 are you ready for <ORGANIZATION>Visitas Sarah</ORGANIZATION> shares her tips for making the most of your visit to <LOCATION>Cambridge</LOCATION> https RT HarvardAlumni This is so sweet Visitas2018 Harvard2022 https t co wUPyMFv0oW Journalists from the BostonGlobe whose December series examining race in <LOCATION>Boston</LOCATION> was a finalist for the Pulitzer P https t co SXll2GzlYc During an address at Harvard_Law <LOCATION>Beijing</LOCATION> s longest serving ambassador <PERSON>Cui Tiankai</PERSON> said what s souring relations b https t co uH9yUxP4Ue RT harvardmed Can price shopping transform American health care https t co x3KdznYlGa Even with a world of information at their fingertips consumers routinely make bad decisions Can science help https t co V7HpTbvy6N For a growing segment of the world s population economic inequality has become deadly Nobel Prize winning economi https t co yU928HUnT7 RT harvardphysics <ORGANIZATION>Upcoming Lee Historical Lecture</ORGANIZATION> <PERSON>Rainer Weiss</PERSON> MIT The Remarkable Gamble the <ORGANIZATION>National Science Foundation Took</ORGANIZATION> with L Award winning author <PERSON>Chimamanda Ngozi Adichie</PERSON> has been selected as <ORGANIZATION>Harvard College</ORGANIZATION> s Class Day speaker https t co wMGMUnKoSp Harvard18 RT GreenHarvard Our new climate action plan clears an ambitious path forward to shift campus operations away from fossil fuels https t <PERSON>Elizabeth Keto</PERSON> 18 has designed a harvartmuseums gallery tour that s intended to prompt reflection and conversatio https t co 0iTeNFs80l The system will enable researchers to peer into previously unseen biological processes https t co LLLa8f2wfZ Those who learn mindfulness techniques often say they feel less stress and think more clearly https t co oW5UVwRSI6 Taking first prize at the <LOCATION>Paris</LOCATION> Talents2024 competition this mobile hygiene unit for refugee camps was created by https t co QBM1KVz6yK Charged with keeping the crew and equipment safe coxswains make all of the decisions on the water https t co jj1MV3J3YL RT HarvardCCHANGE We re back with a new name and mission Under leadership of <ORGANIZATION>Fmr EPA</ORGANIZATION> Administrator <PERSON>Gina McCarthy</PERSON> HarvardChanSPH s C As part of <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> s Project Teach a group of middle school students had the chance to learn how to beatbox https t co XkI60HgJSk What can termites teach us about designing green buildings https t co zcTLcYJQ7h RT harvardmed Research unmasks hundreds of cancer driving genes that are invisible to gene sequencing https t co KvgVL5jVjj To increase scientific understanding of biological systems <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> is launching an interdisciplinary research effo https t co YOiygtOM1s Studies say that 8 in 10 Americans experience stress in their daily lives Mindfulness meditation can help https t co oW5UVwRSI6 At the HarvardChanSPH Nobel laureate <PERSON>Angus Deaton</PERSON> and epidemiologist <PERSON>Michael Marmot</PERSON> discussed how socio economic https t co ZAW6WzaQFj Meet <PERSON>Jennie Kunes</PERSON> coxswain for <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> men s heavyweight crew https t co bLPLc9KhnM https t co Li2sNM2cJl Faculty from HarvardHBS set out to understand better when and why people use backhanded compliments https t co OdVQ05nsfW Solving the opioid crisis will require a sustained and comprehensive approach a group of former governors said at https t co UrkJV1OXGJ RT harvardmed A new artificial intelligence based approach to medical imaging yields higher quality images from less data https t co VA A <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> instructor is introducing 7th graders to the world of Gullah https t co SDQqcZAlVs RT harvardmed The first year HMS and HSDM students have released their annual music video parody ReadyNotReady https t co fAVYa2P459 RT Harvard_Law How generations of <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> professors and their students shaped American law and legal education https t co EcD8Kwoiyx RT GreenHarvard Last week we celebrated ten years of the <ORGANIZATION>Office for Sustainability</ORGANIZATION> and honored President <PERSON>Drew Faust</PERSON> s commitment to susta For the first time <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> researchers have combined two atoms into what they call a dipolar molecule https t co 5fMwmdyFYh The winning design A Pine in the Sand will be installed in <ORGANIZATION>RadInstitute</ORGANIZATION> s <LOCATION>Wallach Garden</LOCATION> next year https t co M0brUT5Fzk RT HarvardChanSPH In the future climate change is forecast to be the number one threat to public health Learn how our changing environm Flattery can help you win friends and influence people but a HarvardHBS working paper concludes that offering a b https t co zeCOSe8ISw Local residents got help with their taxes thanks to students at Harvard_Law https t co W9h84LO7x5 TaxDay At <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> former Governors <PERSON>Steve__Beshear</PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION>Kentucky Jim Douglas</ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION>Vermont</LOCATION> <PERSON>Jack Markell</PERSON> of <LOCATION>Delaware</LOCATION> https t co x5v5E9MVsa As part of <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> s Project Teach program <PERSON>Sunn</PERSON> m <PERSON>Cheaux</PERSON> worked with 7th graders to teach them the origin of the G https t co zY111xmhEL RT HarvardEXT Today at 5 pm EDT tune in to an interactive interview with Dean huntlambert from the asugsvsummit https t co 2qbnxORN BubbleBox created by <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> students is a mobile hygiene unit that can be used in refugee camps https t co KjVYDkkIjG RT HarvardChanSPH Mental health issues are on the rise among college students and a serious gap exists in campus services to help them Check out the winning design for the RadInstitute Public Art Competition which will live in the <LOCATION>Wallach Garden</LOCATION> ro https t co FC9dxCDgX1 Could mindful meditation help those with depression <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> researcher GaelleDesbordes is researching https t co <ORGANIZATION>KN8pRjUp6j Harvard</ORGANIZATION> researchers have combined two atoms for the first time which could hold great promise for the future of qu https t co CrSLYl8uLe Good luck to everyone participating in today s BostonMarathon Finish strong Boston2018 https t co C3AdDTKzLm <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> s <PERSON>Daniel Lieberman</PERSON> who has studied the role of running in human survival runs his 8th <ORGANIZATION>Boston Marathon</ORGANIZATION> tod https t co YyPDrPCreY RT HarvardChanSPH Some of the most prevalent diseases in the world are oral diseases At the same time they are the most neglected <ORGANIZATION>RT HarvardWHockey Harvard</ORGANIZATION> women s hockey gave back to the community tonight volunteering its time to make sandwiches for the hundreds of We must strive to make the dream of American citizenship possible to those who have so very much to offer us all https t co aXOkhDrMjl Researchers say the discovery holds great promise for the future of quantum computing https t co tAdrH8kONb <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> s <PERSON>Daniel Lieberman</PERSON> who will run his 8th BostonMarathon tomorrow talks about <PERSON>Bannister</PERSON> s 4 minute mile h https t co 7WlQHiyPV6 1907 <ORGANIZATION>Harvard College</ORGANIZATION> graduate <PERSON>Harry Elkins Widener</PERSON> was aboard the Titanic as it sank on this day in 1912 He perish https t co qyNfWYo39t A <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> professor reflects on the canonization of Salvadoran Archbishop scar <PERSON>Romero</PERSON> https t co c7Rg3jUvxH On OneBostonDay we join our community in celebrating the spirit of <LOCATION>Boston</LOCATION> through acts of kindness and service https t co ARJgNT7k1R Renovations are planned for <ORGANIZATION>Adams House</ORGANIZATION> https t co 0HZYhN2yBp https t co 3aj8VQ4bwd RT HarvardLocal On April 25 join <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON>Drew Gilpin Faust</PERSON> amp amp City of <LOCATION>Boston</LOCATION> Mayor marty_walsh to celebrate the 10th annual H Photographer <PERSON>Rosamond Purcell</PERSON> has shot hundreds of photos from crocodiles and monkeys to toads and chameleons at Ha https t co UJJOkz6QdF How can meditation help those with depression <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> researcher GaelleDesbordes is exploring https t co KN8pRjUp6j <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> s <PERSON>Daniel Lieberman</PERSON> has researched the role of running in human survival He ll run his 8th BostonMarathon https t co Jyp2Nv5dul Do Democratic and Republican doctors treat patients differently at the end of life Researchers at harvardmed exp https t co oeSDtvPKdu RT HarvardChanSPH Members of the <ORGANIZATION>Harvard Chan</ORGANIZATION> community will be among those standing up for research and evidence based policy at the <ORGANIZATION>Mar RT HarvardBaseball Harvard</ORGANIZATION> s <PERSON>Noah Zavolas</PERSON> throws a complete game and NO HITTER the <ORGANIZATION>Crimson</ORGANIZATION> s first since 2001 in a 4 0 defeat of Ivy ri Created by <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> students a mobile hygiene unit for use in refugee camps won first prize at the <LOCATION>Paris</LOCATION> https t co oiuFgENq6R RT HarvardChanSPH In our latest podcast Billions of dollars in global health aid are distributed around the world each year But <PERSON>JesseB Jennifer Kotler</PERSON> a doctoral candidate in HarvardGSAS developed severe ADHD at age 8 but has learned to use her d https t co pn83m4TxRY How fast can we run Ahead of the <ORGANIZATION>BostonMarathon Harvard</ORGANIZATION> s <PERSON>Daniel Lieberman</PERSON> discusses the past present and futu https t co zsdZNR5UnX In terms of size this may be the smallest scientific breakthrough ever made at <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> https t co 5fMwmdyFYh RT Kennedy_School Studies have estimated that anywhere from 9 15 of active Twitter accounts are bots and that there may be as many as 6 Take a walk through the ArnoldArboretum https t co vB5Wu7cydY https t co TLnzUYrNKd Researchers at harvardmed explored whether a doctor s political beliefs make a difference in end of life care trea https t co GrM2kLoeHM This mystical creature has haunted <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> s peabodymuseum for more than 100 years https t co OMeH53dFPp https t co Em3zFV7WHg Renovations are planned for <ORGANIZATION>Adams House</ORGANIZATION> but its pool theater elliptical stairs and the <LOCATION>FDR Suite</LOCATION> where President https t co cl67Wkgzkk <ORGANIZATION>Navy SEAL</ORGANIZATION> veteran and HarvardDivinity student <PERSON>Daniel Cnossen</PERSON> won six medals in the 2018 Winter Paralympic Games in https t co <ORGANIZATION>H9ZZcy0qMS Jhumpa Lahiri</ORGANIZATION> and pronounced_ing discussed immigrant identity at <ORGANIZATION>RadInstitute</ORGANIZATION> s annual conference on gender https t co RKYIJaLweN <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> researchers have combined two atoms for the first time into what researchers call a dipolar molecule https t co 5fMwmdh4zH A team led by two <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> students won first prize at <LOCATION>Paris</LOCATION> Talents2024 for BubbleBox a mobile hygiene unit that https t co lvNFuAAmjV The health risks faced by flight attendants who work outside standard health and safety protections piqued the in https t co 8taT5VWBA7 The first thing <PERSON>Rosamond Purcell</PERSON> photographed at <ORGANIZATION>Harvard s Museum of Comparative Zoology</ORGANIZATION> back in the 1980s was a pa https t co tiW6SFw3cf Renovations will start next year for <ORGANIZATION>Adams House</ORGANIZATION> a beloved quirky complex part of which predates the Revolution https t co ByRJb6u7ya Today 4 12 at 11 30am ET join us for a <ORGANIZATION>Facebook Live</ORGANIZATION> with wyssinstitute researchers creating artificial muscles https t co seV3dTXbKa More 18 to 29 year olds plan to vote in the fall a <ORGANIZATION>HarvardIOP</ORGANIZATION> survey finds https t co M2Daqc2KnC <PERSON>Dan Cnossen</PERSON> M P A 16 M T S 18 is a former <ORGANIZATION>Navy SEAL</ORGANIZATION> and paralympic skier who won six medals in the 2018 Wint https t co iO2G3XwKZJ Could cancer be transformed from a disease that threatens our lives to one we can live with Biologist https t co mmQYM4Jedp What a beautiful gesture Thank you <ORGANIZATION>MIT</ORGANIZATION> https t co SRFcmPNomI RT HarvardIOP Here s how <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> s 18 to 29 year olds view President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> s performance their outlook amp amp intended participation in the m Could mindfulness based meditation help those with depression https t co fVqtBlP4sw Have social networks unwittingly become complicit in amplifying fake news https t co eEVwClMn9k RT harvardmed Scientists at HMS and BrighamWomens have developed a flare responsive gel to treat inflammatory arthritis https t co yTd Research from HarvardChanSPH finds that monounsaturated fatty acids from plant based foods like olive oil and nu https t co B6UIXc5wt9 While an occasional sleepless night is probably harmless the cumulative effects of sleep deprivation may be more d https t co EQBhShvjnn RT harvardmed On NationalPetDay we are celebrating the HMSCountway therapy dogs who help the <ORGANIZATION>Harvard Longwood</ORGANIZATION> community relax and de s A new HarvardIOP poll finds that young adults have little faith in public institutions or big tech companies and https t co YWRQLIB1M2 Beginning next year <ORGANIZATION>Adams House</ORGANIZATION> will undergo a series of renovations that while preserving its history and notabl https t co uVgGHanv01 Students visit with dogs at HMSCountway to help reduce stress and anxiety NationalPetDay https t co rPOkctMDHQ RT hseas Undergrads talked about their experiences in STEM with local high school girls during the annual SET in the City science and <ORGANIZATION>Athena Aktipis ASU</ORGANIZATION> biologist believes an evolutionary approach to understanding and treating cancer can transfo https t co mwbzA1mqhq Can mindfulness based meditation help those experiencing depression https t co fVqtBm6FR6 Using new technology and techniques scholars seek answers for the violent Partition of British <LOCATION>India</LOCATION> in 1947 https t co aVxOLwFlZv Professor <PERSON>Joseph Connors</PERSON> took listeners on a virtual tour of two of <LOCATION>Rome</LOCATION> s most iconic spaces the <PERSON>Piazza Navona</PERSON> an https t co FMR88s6fOc Tonight prominent Mexican archaeologist <PERSON>Eduardo Matos Moctezuma</PERSON> will deliver the first lecture in the series that b https t co faMfYLBudm <ORGANIZATION>Harvard TaxHelp</ORGANIZATION> is a Harvard_Law student run organization that offers local residents help with their taxes free https t co Do86Rqsxji Giving the keynote at a symposium on Martin Luther King Jr Professor <PERSON>Danielle Allen</PERSON> said Civil Rights progress is https t co hTB1NZPDsi On NationalSiblingsDay meet these pairs of <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> twins https t co 56wxmFFX3w https t co tyUpzafk71 A new study argues that social networks have unwittingly become complicit in amplifying fake news https t co SQnbSEaJ3P <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> researcher GaelleDesbordes is exploring the effect of meditation on the brains of clinically depressed pat https t co El3wcB5c08 RT harvardmed Construction is nearing completion on a new HMS student study center and society office space https t co l1xGiU77Yn RT Kennedy_School How to fight climate change from your kitchen https t co 0RDpmWe3mj At an annual dinner <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> welcomed our newest American citizens https t co w1LRepUJZr <ORGANIZATION>Harvard s South Asia Institute</ORGANIZATION> is examining the ramifications of the violent Partition of British <LOCATION>India</LOCATION> in 1947 https t co ZifyhQKprA Prominent Mexican archaeologist <PERSON>Eduardo Matos Moctezuma</PERSON> whose work unveiled major aspects of Aztec religion life https t co 25Fso3HYy0 Follow four <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> undergrads as they discuss their motivation for pursuing a concentration in the Humanities https t co SxJnJhKUCt On April 9 1912 the first game ever played in <LOCATION>Fenway Park</LOCATION> was a matchup between the RedSox and the 1912 <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> https t co Ar9tyYSrkF RT VoicesHSPH Seats are now open for our event with <ORGANIZATION>Drew Faust President of Harvard</ORGANIZATION> For your chance to be in the live studio audience A Nieman Fellow recounts how he and a partner broke the <LOCATION>Panama</LOCATION> Papers scandal two years ago https t co <ORGANIZATION>WWAwBRQzyp RT</ORGANIZATION> harvardmed By analyzing fish DNA HMS postdoc <PERSON>Molly Schumer</PERSON> hopes to better understand the evolutionary forces that shape our genes New findings from HarvardChanSPH show monounsaturated fatty acids from plant based foods like olive oil and nuts https t co wsE9HbJxow RT harvardmed Findings may help inform new treatment strategies for disorders involving interneuron dysfunction such as schizophrenia an A new study urges a multidisciplinary effort to reduce the spread of fake news and to address the underlying patho https t co lY3AzaFkWs At Sanders Theatre R_Denhollander the first victim to come forward in the <PERSON>Nassar</PERSON> sexual abuse case spoke about https t co crRCKD9n8W With the April 17 deadline approaching Harvard_Law students are offering tax help to local residents https t co L4Go0sm8JU A new study argues that social networks have unwittingly become complicit in amplifying fake news and that a multi https t co ctC4CwitgH Could an evolutionary approach to understanding and treating cancer transform it from a disease that threatens our https t co QHrjlDhXBa <PERSON>Richard Martinez</PERSON> III a national <ORGANIZATION>Greco Roman</ORGANIZATION> wrestling champion in high school and <ORGANIZATION>Army</ORGANIZATION> veteran talks about his fr https t co P5aBkpCGQs Marine biologist and RadInstitute s jellyfish guy <PERSON>David Gruber</PERSON> says jellyfish are miraculous with lots of cha https t co vDdMXmgMdh The new hydrogel is designed to respond during arthritis flares releasing the drug as symptoms worsen https t co lkv4XlfRoo RT Harvard One in five <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> undergraduates comes from a family earning less than 65 000 a year and the families pay nothing toward t RT harvard_data The ruse of fake news <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> researchers want to use science to combat techniques that can make the true seem false RT HarvardChanSPH On WorldHealthDay we highlight three countries that have successfully implemented universal health coverage HealthFo RT harvardonline Quality in healthcare matters Learn how to measure and improve healthcare for yourself for your institutions or for <PERSON>Nelson Cardena Urquijo</PERSON> arrived from <LOCATION>Colombia</LOCATION> in 2011 and is now a crew chief for <ORGANIZATION>Facilities Maintenance Operations</ORGANIZATION> https t co naCvEiVG1j Biologist AthenaAktipis of <ORGANIZATION>ASU</ORGANIZATION> believes an evolutionary approach to understanding and treating cancer can transfo https t co 1U8U3kPgBK Price transparency in health care can turn be surprisingly complicated A new report from harvardmed delves into t https t co Lz5hQpP0kB These photos capture the wonder of a walk through the ArnoldArboretum https t co vB5Wu7cydY https t co rULBN4S6c9 While a favorite <PERSON>Vincent van Gogh</PERSON> painting is on loan to the vangoghmuseum in <LOCATION>Amsterdam</LOCATION> these other works will be https t co Xa6IPlAaDf <ORGANIZATION>Harvard TaxHelp</ORGANIZATION> is a Harvard_Law student run organization that offers local residents help with their taxes free https t co zeTdd33Bqv Nieman Fellow f_obermaier recounts how he and another reporter broke the <LOCATION>Panama</LOCATION> Papers scandal two years ago https t co qsmCwyYL9Y Why do fruit flies continue to attract so much scientific interest even as research tools have grown more sophisti https t co 1tW8kdDiSy RT harvardmed Researchers at HMS and MassEyeAndEar have identified a promising candidate for treating an intracranial tumor that causes Reporter <PERSON>Frederik Obermaier</PERSON> a current Nieman Fellow led the effort to break the <LOCATION>Panama</LOCATION> Papers scandal two years a https t co AXdXPWvtKV Evolutionary biologist <PERSON>Athena Aktipis</PERSON> told a <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> audience she sees promise in efforts to control if not eradic https t co teglXOx7gl A new study argues that social networks have unwittingly become complicit in amplifying fake news https t co SQnbSEsjVn <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> graduate <PERSON>Leslie Jamison</PERSON> talks about her new book The Recovering https t co 0ptchZGIZe FridayReads RT harvardmed A new discovery could pave the way for therapies that disarm harmful bacteria by disrupting proteins that build their prote The lawsuit was brought to trial with the help of the <ORGANIZATION>International Human Rights Clinic</ORGANIZATION> the practice arm of the Hu https t co UNEejgoqWC Astronomers have discovered enormous weather systems that are millions of light years in extent and older than th https t co 2o0FONJSOq This tax season Harvard_Law students are helping local residents do their taxes https t co <ORGANIZATION>InffpSmzvy Informed</ORGANIZATION> by recent findings physician and mother drClaire explains why and when formula feeding can help both par https t co Takbqvlwk6 Investigators at <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> affiliated BrighamWomens are working to treat inflammatory arthritis with hydrogel https t co e5hAXgEhwY RT PolicyCast New pod <PERSON>Thomas Piketty</PERSON> joins the show to discuss the findings of the 2018 World Inequality Report and offer his policy re Reducing blame may help reduce obesity https t co y92yV0v4fB RT HarvardTechXfer What does it mean to be well Not just not ill but really thriving A collaborative multi year study by researcher RT GreenHarvard Our new <ORGANIZATION>Green Labs Certification</ORGANIZATION> program for <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> s <ORGANIZATION>Longwood Campus</ORGANIZATION> aims to encourage researchers and lab staff to cre A group of <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> scholars reflect on the life death and legacy of <PERSON>Martin Luther King Jr</PERSON> https t co 7fSuDv2VDf MLK50 While a favorite <PERSON>Vincent van Gogh</PERSON> painting is on loan to the vangoghmuseum in <LOCATION>Amsterdam</LOCATION> a <ORGANIZATION>Picasso</ORGANIZATION> and another van https t co XQkY0O3H5p Professors <PERSON>Brandon Terry</PERSON> and <PERSON>Tommie Shelby</PERSON> co edited a book on the legacy of <PERSON>Martin Luther King Jr</PERSON> s political tho https t co Cd7cW9pP92 While a single sleepless night is probably harmless the cumulative effects of sleep deprivation may be more danger https t co BL21YUXLdH Last week famed political activist and scholar <PERSON>Angela Davis</PERSON> visited <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> https t co GygdVVeKwT In 1968 <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> students invited <PERSON>Martin Luther King Jr</PERSON> to be their Class Day speaker <PERSON>Coretta Scott King</PERSON> agreed to https t co WdPt02irdU Arts and Sciences Professorships were recently awarded to <PERSON>Catherine Dulac Jennifer Lewis Louis Menand</PERSON> and <PERSON>Mary</PERSON> C https t co IkRTHA4wHS RT HarvardChanDean Dr <PERSON>Martin Luther King Jr</PERSON> once said Of all the forms of inequality injustice in health is the most shocking and i On the 50th anniversary of his assassination <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> scholars reflect on <PERSON>Martin Luther King</PERSON> s life death and leg https t co TA0DdNvP3A RT harvardmed Researchers have developed a road map of interneuron function offering unprecedented insight into the biology of these cel This finding by <ORGANIZATION>HarvardChanSPH Northeastern</ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION>MIT</ORGANIZATION> researchers provides insight into the healing of wounds o https t co uPW1eAI0sg Gorgeous photos capture the wonder of a walk through ArnoldArboretum https t co SQlxIsY2ET https t co xnFtsUz20b <PERSON>Vincent van Gogh</PERSON> s Self Portrait Dedicated to <PERSON>Paul Gaugin</PERSON> one of harvartmuseums most beloved works is on loan https t co <ORGANIZATION>z78Dojua4v Dental School</ORGANIZATION> students traveled to <LOCATION>Costa Rica</LOCATION> as part of the Principles of Oral Health course https t co ScQQfAc1id RT hseas With a novel steel framework and other environmentally friendly features <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> s new <ORGANIZATION>Science and Engineering Complex</ORGANIZATION> will be RT HarvardChanSPH When cooking meats chicken or fish it may be better to avoid high temperature cooking methods including grilling or RT BKCHarvard Learn more about thistimeitsmimi a <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> based artist and researcher who creates art that helps expand the conversatio One in five <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> undergraduates comes from a family earning less than 65 000 a year and the families pay nothi https t co o1M4xSA2Zc <PERSON>Vincent van Gogh</PERSON> s 1890 Snow Covered Field with a Harrow after <PERSON>Millet</PERSON> will be on view at harvartmuseums this s https t co KXFVju1rD4 RT Kennedy_School E O <PERSON>Wilson</PERSON> envisions a massive conservation effort to stem extinction https t co YE8qeiBmUF According to new findings from HarvardChanSPH monounsaturated fatty acids from plant based foods such as olive oi https t co fNvKlN3Yj4 Known by his RadInstitute colleagues as the jellyfish guy marine biologist <PERSON>David Gruber</PERSON> says jellyfish are cha https t co 0yZtvds5P5 RT hseas Before coming to <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> freshman shaandsingh studied how computer vision and machine learning could be used to diagnose auti At <ORGANIZATION>Harvard HamiltonMusical</ORGANIZATION> creator Lin_Manuel encouraged Latino students and leaders to make their voices heard https t co FsMxSCeCU1 <PERSON>Nora D Volkow</PERSON> director of the <ORGANIZATION>National Institute on Drug Abuse</ORGANIZATION> spoke at RadInstitute on the harmful effects of https t co WyMTqSgYq1 RT harvardmed Could reversing aging in blood vessels hold the key to restoring youthful vitality https t co IiUUs1ANPv How can we reduce obesity An expert says take the blame out of it https t co lrUJLtbrZm RT hgse Yes education is the key to success but application is the ignition and we must merge the two for the vehicle to be able to A wyssinstitute team devised a CRISPR Cas9 based mutation prevention system to remove cells with mutations such a https t co zQvXtIasQu <ORGANIZATION>Harvard School of Dental Medicine</ORGANIZATION> students traveled to <LOCATION>Costa Rica</LOCATION> as part of the Principles of Oral Health course https t co sHMTSuX43o RT hseas Inspired by the wings of a butterfly researchers are developing new tunable catalytic systems for clean air technologies http RT HarvardLibrary AprilFools throwback to when the HarvardArchives hosted an exhibition of the harvardlampoon memorabilia in honor of Current and former <ORGANIZATION>NFL</ORGANIZATION> players MalcolmJenkins AnquanBoldin demario__davis and <PERSON>McCourtyTwins</PERSON> came to https t co tu3qucyPKC With a record applicant pool <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> has admitted 1 962 students to the Class of Harvard2022 https t co ODPGknva57 The Microbial Life exhibit at the HarvardMuseum of Natural History explores the beauty of the microscopic univer https t co PsNsDkdYgD Students from Harvard_Law traveled to <LOCATION>Puerto Rico</LOCATION> over spring break to offer legal aid to residents and help rebui https t co 31ZPHZYFHa At <ORGANIZATION>Kennedy_School Hamilton</ORGANIZATION> creator <PERSON>Lin_Manuel</PERSON> told Latino students and leaders to make their voices heard https t co dI33CheMZC RT HarvardHBS Leaders have to agitate innovate and orchestrate if they want to push for corporate social responsibility julie_battila Two <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> grads brought to campus the opera company they helped to found https t co TFxFrsTB7D cc HarvardAlumni Graduate students and postdoctoral fellows at the <ORGANIZATION>Harvard Smithsonian Center for Astrophysics</ORGANIZATION> will play key roles i https t co OoUJS0Zt0u Species extinction is a global threat on par with climate change but one that has a solution renowned biologist E https t co kjQQdAdwgU RT harvardmed On NationalDoctorsDay we thank all present and future physicians for their dedication and leadership in alleviating human A group of Harvard_Law students traveled to <LOCATION>Puerto Rico</LOCATION> over spring break to lend a hand to local residents strugg https t co sX6AWN7fO1 RT HarvardChanSPH We often think of aging as an inevitable physical decline But what if that wasn t the case What if we could change ho Congrats to senior <PERSON>Vikram Sundar</PERSON> who was recently awarded a prestigious Churchill Scholarship and is headed to the https t co qkmt5YIZiK RT harvardmed <ORGANIZATION>HMS Fatima Cody Stanford</ORGANIZATION> discusses the complex forces behind weight regulation and how weight shaming in adolescence can Explore the beauty of the microscopic universe around us https t co b1xiWvufec cc socialmicrobes https t co y0KIis00qY Students from Harvard_Law traveled to <LOCATION>Puerto Rico</LOCATION> over spring break offering legal aid to residents and helping r https t co RgOUSJi7w7 Members of the <ORGANIZATION>American Modern Opera Company</ORGANIZATION> spent 9 days on campus during Run <ORGANIZATION>AMOC</ORGANIZATION> participating in more than https t co Ck80wdBUiP Current and former <ORGANIZATION>NFL</ORGANIZATION> players <PERSON>MalcolmJenkins AnquanBoldin</PERSON> and <PERSON>McCourtyTwins</PERSON> came to Harvard_Law as part of th https t co c5DDmgdSaB <PERSON>Fatima Cody Stanford</PERSON> of harvardmed discusses the complex forces behind weight gain https t co NHr5c8BAxR A group of a <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> dental students traveled to <LOCATION>Costa Rica</LOCATION> to learn about global health and disease https t co sHMTSuX43o A CRISPR Cas9 mutation prevention system could help prevent and fight disease in the future https t co MjwJtoQpfj cc wyssinstitute Today 3 29 at 2 30pm EDT join us for a <ORGANIZATION>Facebook Live</ORGANIZATION> from the Microbial Life exhibit at the HarvardMuseum Harv https t co 5lKmTw00PO One in five <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> undergraduates comes from a family earning less than 65 000 a year and the families pay nothi https t co Oo8HPRjZkv Increased awareness by physicians and other providers can help members of the LGBTQ community who often experience https t co T0pJ6Xw2mm Are e cigarettes a good way to help you quit smoking https t co XfY23FcDY7 <PERSON>Dasha Bough</PERSON> 21 who came to <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> from <LOCATION>Montana</LOCATION> by way of <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> is a self taught sand artist https t co UcKrapnTIg RT harvardmed Research unmasks hundreds of cancer driving genes that are invisible to gene sequencing https t co WhYO4idJYu More than half of <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> students receive financial aid and the <ORGANIZATION>College</ORGANIZATION> expects to spend more than 195 million on https t co FImxFRXZv3 <ORGANIZATION>Harvard s Presidential Task Force</ORGANIZATION> on Inclusion and Belonging issued its final report including 8 recommendations a https t co CgScR92DLi With a record applicant pool <ORGANIZATION>Harvard College</ORGANIZATION> has admitted 1 962 students to the Class of 2022 Congratulations https t co XSnawyk8QR RT applytoharvard Congratulations to the <ORGANIZATION>Harvard College Class</ORGANIZATION> of 2022 Welcome to <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> Harvard2022 https t co vQknquMID3 RT HarvardChanSPH Researchers from harvardmed have identified the key cellular mechanisms behind vascular aging and its effects on muscl This class pairs students with indigenous and tribal organizations to work on projects with the communities https t co 13pg8zL5TH The cancer vaccine created by wyssinstitute and hseas works by reprogramming the immune system to reject cancer c https t co ZLVwbOLW3u <PERSON>John Silvanus Wilson</PERSON> reflects on the goals of the new inclusion and belonging report and discusses why they matter https t co xe10YOZrdy The microbial world lives all around us on our skin in our bodies and in our homes and now you can see it in https t co A7Eq2krCDd RT HVClub After serving in the <ORGANIZATION>Army</ORGANIZATION> and completing a tour of duty in <LOCATION>Iraq</LOCATION> <PERSON>Richard Martinez III</PERSON> enrolled at <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> and found a new band RT HarvardChanSPH Chia seeds are often marketed as a superfood but do they really offer health benefits HSPHnutrition reviews the evid The new method opens up an entirely new way to think about disease prevention in the future https t co MjwJtoQpfj Students from Parkland visited <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> and discussed their dedication to reducing gun deaths https t co NhpdQJEHY8 Three <ORGANIZATION>HarvardDivinity Ministry Innovation Fellows</ORGANIZATION> diagnose what ails <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> s soul https t co MEenrjnTyV Before coming to <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> freshman <PERSON>Richard Martinez III</PERSON> was deployed to <LOCATION>Iraq</LOCATION> as a paratrooper https t co OKPTqUABJh President <PERSON>Drew Faust</PERSON> announced today that she has appointed <PERSON>John Silvanus Wilson</PERSON> as senior adviser and strategist o https t co wURDW55kNt Cancer vaccine technology developed at hseas and wyssinstitute will be commercialized by NovartisScience https t co HemScll8TR Professor <PERSON>Rafael Di Tella</PERSON> discusses how many Americans looked to <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> as a president who would put American worker https t co zlUTeKVtWJ Can e cigarettes help those looking to stop smoking https t co uujvMP1MOv In a message to the community President <PERSON>Faust</PERSON> shared her gratitude for the work of the <ORGANIZATION>Presidential Task Force</ORGANIZATION> on https t co wb0WNCO4mm <ORGANIZATION>Harvard s Presidential Task Force</ORGANIZATION> on Inclusion and Belonging issued its final report today and President <PERSON>Faust</PERSON> ann https t co 372NXrk8pG RT HarvardChanSPH A recent HarvardORP poll found that discrimination and harassment prevents many LGBTQ Americans from seeking medical c Fellows at HarvardDivinity found loneliness isolation and division across the country https t co 9Q3X8IgVjt Two <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> scientists are leading a mission to increase the understanding that microbes not only were the evolutio https t co b8pl0tmow7 The Native Americans in the 21st Century Nation Building II class pairs students with indigenous and tribal orga https t co EM5CFRhrd8 RT HarvardHBS Take a listen to our new podcast to hear what professors Youngme Moon Felix Oberholser Gee and desaimihira really want t Couples in supportive marriages appear less likely to gain weight and become obese in middle age according to a ne https t co p8GEnUDQvY Although many people borrow a family member s pain medicine they shouldn t https t co mS494xCOaB The new Microbial Life A Universe at the Edge of Sight exhibit shows the beauty of the microscopic universe arou https t co JNlFPEO86C We re in the dark on dietary supplements but <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> epidemiologist <PERSON>JoAnn Manson</PERSON> is working to change that https t co eqVc0DdziQ Could reversing the aging of blood vessels hold the key to restoring youth harvardmed researchers are investigati https t co gvHlx3YRvr RT HarvardChanSPH New research suggests a possible connection between high heat meat cooking and type 2 diabetes https t co MMw9p2legq On his birthday take a look at <PERSON>Robert Frost</PERSON> s signature in the pages of the <ORGANIZATION>Morris Gray</ORGANIZATION> signature book in the Harv https t co aDHbFqdjAi More than half of <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> students receive financial aid and the <ORGANIZATION>College</ORGANIZATION> expects to spend more than 195 million on https t co BpqLduQlQU A significant number of <ORGANIZATION>LGBTQ</ORGANIZATION> patients experience discrimination in the health care system A HarvardChanSPH panel https t co Cymndypy5N Analysis from HarvardChanSPH shows a resurgence of mumps in the U S is due to the waning of vaccine induced immun https t co zAcEf1EJAY Academic freedom is an important pillar of open societies but panelists at <ORGANIZATION>HarvardWCFIA</ORGANIZATION> worry that it is being ta https t co amAy7Vd3BZ RT hseas Cancer vaccine technology developed at hseas and wyssinstitute to be commercialized by NovartisScience https t co i4riayEq A <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> analyst says the mining of users data on <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> diminishes the public s trust https t co eYPI4KBGqr At <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> students from <ORGANIZATION>Parkland</ORGANIZATION> explained their dedication to reducing gun deaths and outlined their plans to ke https t co 9XyZ7gDwso Hundreds of <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> students joined others from around <LOCATION>New England</LOCATION> at <ORGANIZATION>MarchForOurLives</ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION>Boston</LOCATION> yesterday Freshm https t co RrFJm1cfcP Happy birthday Aretha Franklin Before receiving an honorary degree at our 2014 Commencement the legendary musi https t co 9t6Gr8zxuA The <ORGANIZATION>Private Collegiate Instruction for Women in Cambridge</ORGANIZATION> known as the <ORGANIZATION>Harvard Annex</ORGANIZATION> began around 1880 In 1894 https t co q93yNuHjRf How effective are dietary supplements <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> epidemiologist <PERSON>JoAnn Manson</PERSON> is researching https t co njLkM7CdXt RT HarvardChanSPH Children in the U S are 18 times more likely to be murdered with a gun than children in other developed countries Wound dressings created by researchers at hseas and wyssinstitute promote healing and regrow tissue using protein https t co f8yVdNwQg4 RT cs50 This is CS50x 2018 <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> s introduction to the intellectual enterprises of computer science and the art of programming on e Though the <LOCATION>Earth</LOCATION> s seas have risen and fallen many times the man made changes occurring now and the larger ones an https t co APbAzYZ6hL The wyssinstitute s cancer vaccine works by reprogramming the immune system to reject cancer cells https t co YSqajK4Ylq <PERSON>Douglas Johnson</PERSON> of the Kennedy_School explains what it takes to turn protest into policy https t co 2aQ8sJCxAH MarchForOurLives Parkland students shared how they have tried to transform the pain and tragedy they experienced in the attack into https t co As0nrGcOWD Having kids exercise an hour each day before school has been shown to lower BMI and encourage academic engagement https t co mzmPGReRKV Transplant rejection may be influenced by the sex of the donor https t co iYP7pvacHq Scholars voiced their opinions on the Insidious Threats to Academic Freedom in the U S and Abroad at a recent https t co BlkP5CZl8r A resurgence of mumps in the U S among vaccinated young adults appears to be due to waning of vaccine induced immu https t co 6338s49Rhd RT Harvard_Law <PERSON>Malcolm Jenkins Devin McCourty</PERSON> and members of the <ORGANIZATION>Players Coalition</ORGANIZATION> visit <ORGANIZATION>HLS</ORGANIZATION> for a day of conversations about criminal j RT Harvard_Law At <ORGANIZATION>HLS</ORGANIZATION> emilybazelon <PERSON>MalcolmJenkins McCourtyTwins AnquanBoldin</PERSON> demario__davis discuss how <ORGANIZATION>NFL</ORGANIZATION> players are using thei Two original members of the <ORGANIZATION>Harvard Extension Alumni Association</ORGANIZATION> look back https t co q4YnO1gAvi The wyssinstitute and hseas announced Tuesday that <ORGANIZATION>Novartis</ORGANIZATION> will have access to commercially develop their cance https t co 61z45pQIMv Maha and <PERSON>Amala Mahadevan</PERSON> faculty deans at <ORGANIZATION>Mather House</ORGANIZATION> say their black <PERSON>Labrador Cheetah</PERSON> is a puppy at heart w https t co GbBRyo5YDQ Freshman Dasha Bough s creations in sand are inspired by her experiences in <LOCATION>Russia Montana</LOCATION> and at <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> https t co tk4GTFD36l Parkland students visited <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> and discussed their dedication to reducing gun deaths and their plans to keep pus https t co tAFNPTqixb The first women graduates of Harvard_Law Class of 1953 by <ORGANIZATION>Melvin Robbins 1988 Harvard Law School Library</ORGANIZATION> His https t co tMTjWC84ul Images captured by <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> researchers often blur the boundary between art and science https t co LQRexat5NR https t co re27d84KED Analyst vivekdotca discusses the legal implications for <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> amid recent privacy concerns https t co CSGAgUtbD3 We re in the dark on dietary supplements <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> epidemiologist <PERSON>JoAnn Manson</PERSON> is working to change that https t co afML0YNqEi Researchers trying to better understand and treat blood sugar disorders such as type 2 diabetes are studying cavefi https t co UaUq4vcuyb Visitors posing for photos with the <ORGANIZATION>John Harvard Statue</ORGANIZATION> may not know that the <ORGANIZATION>University</ORGANIZATION> s namesake and first major https t co 1XhoUiAFhO Q amp amp A with cyberlawclinic s vivekdotca about <ORGANIZATION>Facebook and Cambridge Analytica U S</ORGANIZATION> privacy protections and the re https t co yfKzMmzgNh RT <ORGANIZATION>GreenHarvard DYK Harvard</ORGANIZATION> has reduced water use by 24 since 2006 enough to fill harvardcrimson s <PERSON>Blodgett</PERSON> Pool 228 times WorldWa Maker is a generic term that would encompass both the ceramicist and the person soldering together a circuit We w https t co sM7nPQ4X3B RT BKCHarvard READING cyberlawclinic s vivekdotca talks with the <ORGANIZATION>Harvard Gazette</ORGANIZATION> about <ORGANIZATION>Facebook U S</ORGANIZATION> privacy protections amp amp regulat Fifty years after the release of the Kerner Report on race <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> Professor <PERSON>Orlando Patterson</PERSON> discusses the report https t co 3dxJTLFdq8 <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> epidemiologist <PERSON>JoAnn Manson</PERSON> is working on measuring the effectiveness of dietary supplements https t co <ORGANIZATION>njLkM7CdXt RT HVClub Austin Lee 16</ORGANIZATION> wanted to surround himself at <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> with people that he could grow from learn from and appreciate He found You should wait until the deal is done before saying thanks according to a new HarvardHBS working paper https t co TddBc1Ow98 RT HarvardChanSPH Experts say access to treatment for opioid addiction is dangerously inadequate https t co F1EirfkZoQ via <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> htt Parkland students visited <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> and discussed their dedication to reducing gun deaths and their plans to keep pus https t co Mx35JZ7Raf RT hseas Collaboration between NovartisScience wyssinstitute and hseas could lead to new biomaterial based cancer vaccine technology RT hseas Engineering Ph D candidate IntifadaBatata searches for rhyme and reason in poetry and science https t co GEZDXRBBpe WorldP RT HarvardIOP Did you miss ParklandForum last night Take a look at our TwitterMoments of how yesterday s event looked in the news and It s best to wait until negotiations are finished before saying thanks according to a new HarvardHBS working paper https t co vVaDZ1Lldv The Dickinson Room in <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> s HoughtonLib displays <PERSON>Emily Dickinson</PERSON> s writing table and chair portraits a porti https t co MYy6hUVKzl <PERSON>Linda McVeigh Mathews</PERSON> 67 was the first woman managing editor of The Crimson WomensHistoryMonth https t co 9l1EhOWz7Q Listen to <PERSON>Robert Frost</PERSON> read at <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> from his poem Stopping by Woods on a Snowy Evening https t co ljHq7VdBRi <ORGANIZATION>WorldPoetryDay RT</ORGANIZATION> niemanfdn 2018 Nieman Fellow Tahtone is working on a set of guidelines for fair and accurate coverage of Native Americans and their a At <ORGANIZATION>Harvard Parkland</ORGANIZATION> students shared how they have tried to transform the pain and tragedy they experienced in the https t co heuvLr4jxW Nanofiber dressings use proteins naturally occurring in plants and animals to promote healing and regrow tissue https t co 4fD4nTR4dy The inauguration for <ORGANIZATION>Lawrence S Bacow Harvard</ORGANIZATION> s 29th president will take place on Friday October 5 https t co joSu2sxFLH RT Kennedy_School What can we learn about social movements and organizing from the student activists from Parkland Watch live starting s Wound dressings created by researchers at hseas and wyssinstitute use proteins that naturally occur in plants and https t co jFxyJtwrm2 On this day in 1852 Uncle <PERSON>Tom</PERSON> s <LOCATION>Cabin</LOCATION> was published This poster is part of the collection of the Beecher Stowe https t co 3qEAexhWcy Experiences in <LOCATION>Russia Montana</LOCATION> and at <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> converge in freshman <PERSON>Dasha Bough</PERSON> s sand art creations https t co 7HqVie8QQE Parkland students Ryan_Deitsch MattxRed Emma4Change davidhogg111 cameron_kasky al3xw1nd amp amp JaclynCorin m https t co kWN4I7F5ec In order to combat the opioidepidemic there is an urgent need to extend treatment access https t co O2bwvalUXp RT JFKJrForum LIVE AT 6PM NeverAgain How Parkland Students are Changing the Conversation on Guns w Ryan_Deitsch MattxRed Emma4Cha RT harvardmed Macrophages play a critical role in our immune defense but they may also contribute to a type of thus far untreatable hear RT phs4girls <ORGANIZATION>Harvard President Drew Faust</ORGANIZATION> visits <ORGANIZATION>Philadelphia High School for Girls</ORGANIZATION> to stress the importance of higher education and the <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> research shows that the building blocks of life on <LOCATION>Earth</LOCATION> could have emerged from small amounts of cyanide a https t co tybEKSv8vV Lecturer at Kennedy_School discusses why the NeverAgain protest is doing well out of the gate and what it may nee https t co h9CmPEu7B3 RT HarvardAlumni Your ideas matter President <PERSON>Drew Faust</PERSON> told students in <LOCATION>Philadelphia</LOCATION> Your work is important and you have something In July 1976 the Schlesinger Library began a project of recording the autobiographical memoirs of a group of black https t co OF7vReE4gj RT HarvardChanSPH These new findings may significantly improve targeted drug delivery https t co lPD8weuDpF New wound dressings created by hseas and wyssinstitute dramatically accelerate healing and improve tissue regener https t co LbAsFC3G9i RT harvardmed Our research may help open up a new field that we might call microbial endocrinology https t co OVSPyVDZ8q <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> researchers showed that a mixture of cyanide and copper when irradiated with UV light could have produced https t co Mn73FlCIGs On March 20 HarvardIOP hosts NEVERAGAIN How Parkland Students are Changing the Conversation on Guns event wit https t co FynAGeKZ1V <LOCATION>Rhode Island</LOCATION> Governor <PERSON>Gina M Raimondo</PERSON> 93 will serve as chief marshal at <ORGANIZATION>Harvard s Commencement Exercises</ORGANIZATION> on May 2 https t co uBqxUTJozh <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> President elect <PERSON>Lawrence Bacow</PERSON> will lead the search for the next dean of the <ORGANIZATION>Faculty of Arts and Sciences</ORGANIZATION> https t co XUgR6CSdI3 <PERSON>Michael Smith Edgerley</PERSON> Family Dean of <ORGANIZATION>Harvard s Faculty of Arts and Sciences</ORGANIZATION> has announced he will step down to r https t co pxPmL5Djef RT HarvardAlumni 17 cities 7 countries 4 continents And most important of all thousands of our dear alumni and friends What a ride The inauguration events for <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> s 29th president <PERSON>Lawrence S Bacow</PERSON> will take place on Friday October 5 https t co 7aD9x46lNJ Playing in the sand takes on new meaning in freshman <PERSON>Dasha Bough</PERSON> s beautiful art https t co 7HqVie8QQE https t co 1h9SakLK4w A before school exercise program started by a group of moms is an effective path to helping kids lose weight accor https t co 5S1Da9bH8D On this day in 1932 novelist poet and critic <PERSON>John Updike</PERSON> was born <ORGANIZATION>Updike Harvard</ORGANIZATION> class of 1954 is pictured https t co g7lZkJ1nsm RT HarvardMHockey Thank you <PERSON>Ryan</PERSON> for three incredible years at <ORGANIZATION>Harvard Below</ORGANIZATION> are thoughts from DonatoRyan on his decision GoCrimson The wyssinstitute is developing a new type of coating for catalytic converters that is inspired by butterfly wings https t co Ke41BQylPS In 2016 the U S spent nearly twice as much on health care as other high income countries yet had poorer populati https t co 80OSVE7d7i On this day in 1932 American author and <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> graduate <PERSON>John Updike</PERSON> was born Manuscripts books photographs co https t co 7jPqQa7FRx A surgical adhesive developed by researchers at wyssinstitute can adhere to surfaces inside the body including th https t co w61jVVfoii These students are learning how hands on experience with art creates a new appreciation of the finished product https t co ZHdtOnwh4T RT HarvardWBB Welcome to the club UMBCAthletics SixteenOverOne https t co <ORGANIZATION>ayqlOvko9h Mary Lasker Radcliffe College</ORGANIZATION> Class of 1922 was an American health activist who worked to raise funds for medical https t co d2S9qfr2OX Board game aficionados We dug through HoughtonLib s archives to find the oldest games in their collections some https t co lofwE3ZnjI How might new U S sanctions impact <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> BelferCenter s <PERSON>Simon Saradzhyan</PERSON> discusses https t co 9Wq1kBPOk7 RT <ORGANIZATION>HarvardArchives Harvard</ORGANIZATION> faculty report on 3 18 1776 that we have this day the joyful news that the King s Troops have totally evacua A new grant from the <ORGANIZATION>Chan Zuckerberg Initiative</ORGANIZATION> will launch Reach Every Reader a literacy program that combines th https t co Xwq1wRrWd7 Having kids exercise an hour each day before school has been shown to lower BMI and encourage academic engagement https t co EGTNXNir6L <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> s <PERSON>CassSunstein</PERSON> has been named winner of the Holberg Prize one of the largest international awards given t https t co oV6hakOMl7 RT harvardmed Congratulations to all the medical students who matched today MatchDay2018 https t co 2dNs2YnekC RT harvardmed Happy Match Day Today fourth year medical students at HMS learned where they will spend their residencies MatchDay2018 ht For patients with certain conditions such as a hole in the heart the device might one day provide a lasting repair https t co E4ZPDPocUd <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> s longstanding commitment to shaping the future by driving the expansion of knowledge and the work of disc https t co 99vmXuVUFK What has science shown us about the importance of getting adequate sleep A researcher explains https t co IZDo7dV2SU WorldSleepDay A grant from the Chan Zuckerberg Initiative will launch Reach Every Reader a literacy program that targets early l https t co mGJCTWCZxU <PERSON>Simon Saradzhyan</PERSON> of BelferCenter discusses the impact that new U S sanctions may have on <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> https t co 9Wq1kBPOk7 The game collection at HoughtonLib dates back to the 17th century https t co Hfx0p4ZBRr https t co R7RQ8OsurP Researcher saradzhyan discusses the impact that new U S sanctions may have on <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> and what Americans misunder https t co isxNy9Wphh Inspired by a butterfly s wing researchers at the wyssinstitute are developing a new type of coating for catalyti https t co StkXWYdTfT RT harvardmed Researchers have discovered viral insulin like hormones raising the question of what their role might be in diabetes and o U S District Judge <PERSON>Deborah A Batts</PERSON> the nation s first openly gay African American federal judge is a graduate o https t co 5XRfzgi2pV Researchers hope the algorithm may one day allow for development of a system for real time earthquake detection https t co 0Jd2bv6DSx <LOCATION>Rhode Island</LOCATION> Governor <PERSON>Gina M Raimondo</PERSON> 93 will serve as class marshal at <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> s 367th Commencement on May 24 https t co bx2FmIYrHV RT HarvardLocal From vacation week activities to exhibition openings February was full of exciting events amp amp activities Learn about some The President s Administrative Innovation Fund works to enhance innovation and collaboration at <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> https t co bDzvbr5Oea RT hseas This device could provide lasting repair for organ defects without the risks common to more invasive types of surgery https t A recent experimental study finds that the mere scent of a romantic partner can lower stress levels even when that https t co 44mOwVmUlh The Climate Change Deep Dive presented a multi faceted look at the causes consequences and potential solutions fo https t co jzGO94Dxkv RT RadInstitute A forgotten 1932 opera by <PERSON>Shirley Graham Du Bois</PERSON> is unearthed at our SchlesingerLibrary and starts to make its way back Check out HoughtonLib s game collection which dates back to the 17th century https t co Hfx0p4ZBRr https t co d3Ss0JKByo RT HarvardHealth Targeting inflammation A novel anti inflammatory drug may discourage repeat heart attacks https t co z7k5kR546z Har In this class students create works of art in order to better understand the finished product https t co D9nbVCgzzp RT HarvardArchives His dauntless mind has journeyed from the beginning of time to the edges of space and back again illuminating the my RT BloombergDotOrg Our <ORGANIZATION>Bloomberg Harvard City Leadership Initiative</ORGANIZATION> convenes local leaders to discuss how to tackle pressing leadership a Congrats to Harvard_Law s CassSunstein winner of this year s <PERSON>Holberg</PERSON> Prize https t co NA1FK29WQu Despite its successful debut in 1932 the opera <PERSON>Tom Tom</PERSON> by composer <PERSON>Shirley Graham</PERSON> was never performed again https t co rfGwzGfB3s A <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> study found that physicians salaries and hospital services are in part what s behind the higher costs of https t co oOxlXzvNit Happy PiDay to all the math enthusiasts https t co vEMiXeqBtV Game night anyone HoughtonLib shows us beautiful board games dating back to the 17th century https t co 9cB9AE32WU In My Dinner with <PERSON>Stephen Hawking</PERSON> a science writer recalls the stories Hawking told a group of about 70 professo https t co OiffJWZrZP To find somewhere like the <LOCATION>Earth</LOCATION> we have to boldly go to the stars <PERSON>Stephen Hawking</PERSON> said at a 2016 lecture at Ha https t co fHXf3gGw5O We remember the remarkable life and legacy of renowned theoretical physicist <PERSON>Stephen Hawking</PERSON> seen here receiving a https t co 0uzVF7NEfC Researchers at <ORGANIZATION>WyssInstitute</ORGANIZATION> have developed a surgical adhesive that can adhere to surfaces inside the body inclu https t co hWlevksRgr A new <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> study reveals the key drivers behind high U S health care costs https t co BIz0z303yI <ORGANIZATION>Harvard President Drew Faust</ORGANIZATION> joined students at <ORGANIZATION>Philadelphia High School for Girls</ORGANIZATION> last week https t co hvBrePnsHZ The enduring charm of board games can be explored in a historical collection stored in a closet at HoughtonLib https t co j40ztzUICF Gay <PERSON>Seidman</PERSON> 78 was the first woman president in The <ORGANIZATION>Crimson</ORGANIZATION> s 104 year history WomensHistoryMonth https t co p6uNakYik4 RT harvardmed World renowned cellist and new HMS artist in residence YoYo_Ma will spend time with first year medical students this sprin <ORGANIZATION>University</ORGANIZATION> wide fun run on Friday March 23 This free untimed 5K will do three loops around historic <ORGANIZATION>Harvard Yard</ORGANIZATION> https t co YHdJLAxndg Snow day cheskyboy on Instagram https t co yLAdT0ka7v On this day in 1639 in recognition of <PERSON>John Harvard</PERSON> s bequest of his library 400 books and half his estate the r https t co xM8z9jLpd3 In 1932 this opera was a hit Why has no one seen it since https t co rfGwzGfB3s <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> grad student <PERSON>Simon Lock</PERSON> is the lead author of a study that theorizes that the moon emerged from a massive https t co 0Rdb2d1zj5 Researchers have identified a genetic switch that could improve memory in aging and reduce the symptoms of PTSD https t co KuuGKEiGY1 RT HarvardGSAS <PERSON>Corina Tarnita</PERSON> PhD 09 on how she found her passion at <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> and brought her interdisciplinary skills with her to Pr Due to blizzard conditions expected tomorrow <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> offices will be closed on Tuesday March 13 https t co Rj23oY5Qvi A new app lets you explore archaeological finds from <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> s earliest days https t co wdxYJwbNbc In his latest book E O <PERSON>Wilson</PERSON> urges the evolution and exploration of the symmetry between the natural sciences an https t co xf2ZSxoI9Z At a <LOCATION>JFK Jr Forum</LOCATION> talk at HarvardIOP <PERSON>Atul Gawande</PERSON> discussed the state of public health and the effectiveness of https t co Eb5wUAxDuM RT HarvardChanSPH In our latest podcast Why <LOCATION>India</LOCATION> s health system is not prepared for the growing threat posted by noncommunicable disea RT HarvardDivinity Satigata means progressing into mindfulness It also is a music group formed at HDS that blends <ORGANIZATION>Buddhist</ORGANIZATION> chanting m Study break Happy NationalNappingDay https t co WF1G12OGrf President <PERSON>Drew Faust</PERSON> joined students at <ORGANIZATION>Philadelphia High School for Girls</ORGANIZATION> phlschools last week to discuss the i https t co HH498QsdCg RT HarvardDivinity As if we couldn t be more proud of <ORGANIZATION>Navy SEAL</ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION>MTS</ORGANIZATION> candidate <PERSON>Dan Cnossen</PERSON> This weekend <PERSON>Dan</PERSON> won a gold medal in biath The Antiquities Act gives presidents power to protect federal land from development by creating national monuments https t co BMtvoZ5sau RT harvardmed Study reveals a surprising new role for the nervous system in deadly lung infections https t co kabLVeN0uS A surgical adhesive developed by researchers at the wyssinstitute adheres to surfaces inside the body including t https t co hEedNUsdcc The health effects of not getting enough sleep https t co JzJHWSdDLU Former U S Secretary of State <PERSON>HillaryClinton</PERSON> will receive the prestigious Radcliffe Medal on May 25 during Harvar https t co mKFYxIQkqA The current guidelines for breastcancer screening are based on data from primarily white populations which may le https t co H4ahfO3tXm American jazz legend <PERSON>Ella Fitzgerald</PERSON> received an honorary degree from <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> in 1990 WomensHistoryMonth https t co rALfY2Nvwl RT HarvardTrack_XC A new <ORGANIZATION>NCAA</ORGANIZATION> indoor record A national title in the 200m for <PERSON>Gabby Thomas</PERSON> 22 38 WOW GoCrimson NCAATF https t co RT HarvardChanSPH Want to eat in a way that s more environmentally friendly Here s how you can get started NationalNutritionMonth http A sleep researcher offers suggestions on the best way to bounce back from losing an hour when we spring ahead https t co msbCm33GiT On July 1 <PERSON>Emma Dench</PERSON> will take on the <ORGANIZATION>Graduate School of Arts and Sciences</ORGANIZATION> deanship full time https t co 4odENxMt92 President <PERSON>Faust</PERSON> is among the leaders of some of the nation s top colleges and universities who asked <ORGANIZATION>Congress</ORGANIZATION> to re https t co DVAuBt6XOw <PERSON>Hillary Clinton</PERSON> will receive the Radcliffe Medal which honors individuals whose lives and work have had a transfor https t co EATxiXRelw Many people will lose an hour of sleep as we spring ahead this weekend harvardmed s <PERSON>Jeanne Duffy</PERSON> discusses the https t co 2svDgEAUvN Read more about <PERSON>Cnossen</PERSON> s incredible journey in this 2016 profile https t co 5d3eFbbfyv https t co 3qkys68P3L Congratulations to former <ORGANIZATION>Navy SEAL</ORGANIZATION> and Kennedy_School alumnus <PERSON>Dan Cnossen</PERSON> on winning Paralympics Gold https t co nw70pMFNEV RT applytoharvard Special shoutout to Harvard2021 who found out today what House they ll call home for the next three years <ORGANIZATION>Braeden sha RT HarvardMBB Cambridge Philadelphia GoCrimson</ORGANIZATION> IvyMadness https t co <ORGANIZATION>SzIFlIawvC RT Kennedy_School Swanee Hunt</ORGANIZATION> says more women are taking political office to wage peace https t co WRIQAL4ZdZ A 30 million grant from the <ORGANIZATION>Chan Zuckerberg Initiative</ORGANIZATION> will launch Reach Every Reader a program that targets earl https t co d3s8QJouh7 E O <PERSON>Wilson</PERSON> talks about his latest book The Origins of Creativity https t co 8NtP4O7Ew2 FridayReads <PERSON>Mina Bissell</PERSON> graduate of <ORGANIZATION>Radcliffe College</ORGANIZATION> and HarvardMed has been recognized for her lifetime contributions to https t co bKh4xZTuLY <PERSON>Simone Passarelli</PERSON> PhD 20 is working to help reduce undernutrition in Ethiopian farming families https t co awfLWaEFP8 RT PHLschools What 3 words best describe <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> student <ORGANIZATION>Truth Talent Opportunity Dr Faust Harvard</ORGANIZATION> President Dr <PERSON>Faust</PERSON> t How can you bounce back from losing an hour of sleep when we spring ahead this weekend https t co b3Nm2p8zoi Researchers at wyssinstitute have developed a surgical adhesive that can adhere to wet and dynamic surfaces inside https t co 0bJqh9qe9V It s Housing Day with snowballs https t co uuc3LNhHvM https t co XMiQmw9NTR In his new book Vanishing Bone <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> surgeon <PERSON>William Harris</PERSON> describes the setbacks on the path to a breakthro https t co Rg2PaOAE0j Join the <ORGANIZATION>Harvard community for a University</ORGANIZATION> wide fun run on Friday March 23 https t co 08ncMU93vU We always joke about what makes <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> special but this is a good example of it You come here to get your MD de https t co rtKLwZG1sg A new analysis from a team of <ORGANIZATION>MGH</ORGANIZATION> investigators shows race bias in breast cancer screening https t co UASeKpOVId RT hseas Black women in STEM panel hosted by hseas NSBE sought to encourage and inspire students to pursue science careers https <PERSON>Drew Faust</PERSON> acclaimed historian of the Civil War and the first woman to lead <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> has advanced the <ORGANIZATION>University</ORGANIZATION> s https t co 1uUXjqdrBY Researchers at the wyssinstitute have developed a surgical adhesive that can adhere to wet and dynamic surfaces in https t co laGmJhgrb9 Snowy start to the day today https t co Lnr0V3NJvZ History and classics professor <PERSON>Emma Dench</PERSON> named dean of HarvardGSAS https t co j3pRZ9Y24N RT HarvardLocal Mentoring has been hands down my favorite extracurricular at <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> and has helped me think about learning and teachin RT harvardmed Four women surgeons share their stories of strength and resilience InternationalWomensDay https t co SHLTUWBmQg The letter signed by President <PERSON>Drew Faust</PERSON> called the tax unprecedented and damaging to charitable resources and https t co AOYCBLCVZk RT Kennedy_School Our alumna <PERSON>Reshma Saujani</PERSON> MPP 1999 founded Girls Who Code a nonprofit that has already helped teach 40 000 girls compu It s HousingDay2018 when freshmen are sorted into the 12 <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> Houses They got the news from upperclassmen sto https t co 1gsxSxY3Fz RT HarvardChanSPH For me the satisfaction is that things are better now and I had some part in it <ORGANIZATION>Alice Hamilton Harvard</ORGANIZATION> s first f During her 2013 visit to Harvard <PERSON>Malala Yousafzai</PERSON> said We are going to be the future Let us make today s dreams https t co YaGTSS1lr6 RT GreenHarvard Meet 5 <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> undergraduate women tackling climatechange across disciplines InternationalWomensDay https t co Nm6e Current guidelines can delay breast cancer diagnosis in nonwhite women https t co 8uKi6XJmto Many of their findings led to important discoveries about the universe and their work helped clear obstacles for w https t co H63ksSjXPd Using complicated calculations the women classified the stars determined their brightness and even discovered ne https t co EO8gOxvd68 On InternationalWomensDay read about the women computers who worked at the <ORGANIZATION>Harvard College Observatory</ORGANIZATION> from the https t co Oc9adAbfEi Reach Every Reader funded by a grant from the <ORGANIZATION>Chan Zuckerberg Initiative</ORGANIZATION> will help children thrive and succeed as https t co aatgY7sUgc Former U S Secretary of State <PERSON>HillaryClinton</PERSON> will receive the prestigious Radcliffe Medal on May 25 during Harvar https t co qGD5g59n70 RT HarvardBiz <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> s President on Leading During a Time of Change https t co GOO6R0M1Q6 The DACA Seminar a series of daylong events on campus explored questions about the termination of <ORGANIZATION>DACA</ORGANIZATION> and TPS d https t co 0kc03Y3W1U <ORGANIZATION>Swanee Hunt of Kennedy_School</ORGANIZATION> discussed lessons learned from the aftermath of the Rwandan genocide https t co uqN7CraMR0 RT hgse Thanks for joining MCCHarvardEd s Caring Schools CommonGood campaign launch And thank you to the 130 early leader schools for A 30 million grant from the <ORGANIZATION>Chan Zuckerberg Initiative</ORGANIZATION> will launch Reach Every Reader a literacy program that com https t co tzlJQegykS On this day in 1958 the groundbreaking for <ORGANIZATION>Quincy House</ORGANIZATION> took place Check out these photos from <ORGANIZATION>Harvard University</ORGANIZATION> https t co zmAiozjOqy This weekend s change to daylight saving time means an extra hour of light in the evening But adjusting to the los https t co KgYSa935V8 RT harvardmed <PERSON>Mary Ellen Avery</PERSON> s career in neonatology was filled with firsts including becoming the first to recognize the cause of res RT <ORGANIZATION>GreenHarvard Two Harvard</ORGANIZATION> green building projects achieve difficult certification the first and second in <LOCATION>Massachusetts</LOCATION> https t co <PERSON>Simone Passarelli</PERSON> PhD 20 is exploring how new breeds of chickens can reduce undernutrition and change the dynami https t co zcLN1le9OH <PERSON>Jonathan Guyer</PERSON> RI 18 is writing a book about the new wave of comic art that has swept the <LOCATION>Middle East</LOCATION> and North https t co Z3qcYLjORo We re generally not sleeping enough and most of the surveys show that about half of adults are not getting the re https t co 9DoYnwRtCc In his latest book E O <PERSON>Wilson</PERSON> urges the evolution and exploration of the symmetry between the natural sciences an https t co vsAgeE4rMt RT HarvardLibrary The harvardtheatre has digitized many of <ORGANIZATION>Virginia Woolf</ORGANIZATION> s personal photo albums which are viewable online https t A panel at <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> says a successful campaign banning landmines could provide a blueprint against nuclear arms https t co LFhv62vg3G RT harvardmed Targeting the nervous system could lead to nonantibiotic therapies for bacterial pneumonia https t co kabLVeN0uS During February school vacation students visited <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> to experience a day in the life of a college student https t co rLBFJ3yPPb How might the <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> administration s proposed changes to SNAP affect the country s largest nutritional safety net https t co DYrRaU1nd7 Formerly incarcerated students and activists come together at <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> to discuss the <ORGANIZATION>University</ORGANIZATION> s long relationship https t co gd1XFYhjAu <PERSON>Barbara Jordan</PERSON> lawyer educator politician leader of the <ORGANIZATION>Civil Rights Movement</ORGANIZATION> and the first Southern African A https t co JTcG4yUbTI RT ShorensteinCtr Join us today for the <ORGANIZATION>GoldsmithAwards Panel</ORGANIZATION> at 3 30pm Investigative Reporting Making an Impact on <ORGANIZATION>Policy amp amp Governa Harvard Foundation</ORGANIZATION> named Grammy Award winning recording artist songwriter and visual artist <PERSON>Solange Knowles</PERSON> as ar https t co yVvFRYwFmn RT wyssinstitute A new study published by a team at the <ORGANIZATION>Wyss Institute</ORGANIZATION> hseas and DanaFarber describes a cancer vaccine approach that u Our technology has the potential to change the way people interact with their electronic devices and with each oth https t co EzKlV9AWgT RT GreenHarvard Read the latest student essays from Humans Nature and the Environment a first year expository writing course which ex <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> grad student <ORGANIZATION>Simon Lock</ORGANIZATION> is the lead author of a study that theorizes that the moon emerged from a massive https t co 3aR0TCwkG8 This soft robot created by a team of researchers at hseas was inspired by snakes https t co 8dTd0Jgdbc Research from hseas and wyssinstitute could help eradicate tumors and prevent them from recurring https t co 1yATPUmN1q RT HarvardChanSPH In 1936 <PERSON>Ann Hoague Stewart</PERSON> became the first woman to receive a degree from the <ORGANIZATION>Harvard Chan School</ORGANIZATION> https t co <ORGANIZATION>DwjB1L RT Harvard</ORGANIZATION> A new <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> discussion series highlights the future of DACA and immigration policy and reform while working to understand At our recent Cultural Rhythms Festival solangeknowles was honored as <ORGANIZATION>Harvard Foundation</ORGANIZATION> s artist of the year Co https t co 4HliSXSQnI RT harvardmed Dr <PERSON>Elizabeth Hay</PERSON> chair of the <ORGANIZATION>Dept of Anatomy</ORGANIZATION> later the HarvardCellBio and the first woman to be made a full professo As <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> s coasts change as sea levels rise how can landscape design and knowledge of native plants help https t co MWbzLsyYmQ Signed petitions from October 1767 calling for Colonial Americans to boycott British goods were discovered in https t co uSXsGwFNfH <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> is hosting a conference on prison education which will bring together formerly incarcerated students and a https t co b8E5lTTIKI Congrats on your Oscars predictions <PERSON>Ben</PERSON> https t co 5Av8BOYxQc A new study may change the way you think about the moon https t co S9N56qjirW I see change in the young people of our country Panelists discussed hate in <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> at a recent HarvardIOP forum https t co 9k5K22YQOa RT harvardmed World renowned cellist and <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> alum <PERSON>Yo Yo Ma</PERSON> will visit HMS as an artist in residence https t co UHtFTXMhDZ I think we are not going to see a race that involves numbers we are going to see a race that involves quality and https t co LE26QcL5gk <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> researchers findings put the mountain laurel in rare company as one of the fastest moving plants on the gl https t co qqKKB15mcC Students <PERSON>Claire Abraham</PERSON> and <PERSON>Kemen</PERSON> discuss the less traditional homeschooling classrooms that brought them to <PERSON>Harv</PERSON> https t co AATDF990bf RT HarvardMBB IVY CHAMPS Final score <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> 93 <ORGANIZATION>Columbia</ORGANIZATION> 74 GoCrimson RoadtoIvyMadness https t co xbOMNfrl56 RT HarvardChanSPH A new discovery about asthma has opened a fresh potential pathway for treatment https t co Jx1WXGrmoO With U S and <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> modernizing their arsenals tensions are rising says Kennedy_School adjunct lecturer <PERSON>David</PERSON> E https t co cFD0kRjPbq <ORGANIZATION>Harvard College s Office for Equity Diversity and Inclusion</ORGANIZATION> has a new home in Grays Hall https t co xBS3ylMeU3 A new study theorizes that the moon emerged from a massive doughnut shaped cloud of vaporized rock called a synest https t co lqTaZepDSY The collection at <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> s HoughtonLib includes an early edition of the The Star Spangled Banner likely printe https t co cpIikYaMyF On this day in 1887 <PERSON>Anne Sullivan</PERSON> began teaching six year old <PERSON>Helen Keller Helen Keller</PERSON> went on to graduate from R https t co PKPeIgEZWc Ahead of the Academy Awards we asked nymag s <PERSON>David Edelstein</PERSON> 81 about his favorite films of the past year https t co qeuXd6uKrD For more than 50 years <PERSON>John Lewis</PERSON> has dedicated himself to the ideals of equality and decency standing up for wh https t co G6lfJwF3lt Imag