<ner>Women in the Humanities is expanding a research programme within the UniofOxford Explore The Suffrage Wall crea https t co inCQrFR2Lp RT HeatherKazara <PERSON>David Attenborough</PERSON> is holding the egg that I collected in his BBCTwo show <PERSON>Attenborough</PERSON> s Wonder of Eggs D That s my w RT tylerpager Savings groups are a particularly efficient and effective solution for poor communities that can t access traditional finan RT TheBHF Thanks to <ORGANIZATION>BHF</ORGANIZATION> funding scientists UniofOxford are set to test a new way of treating people with aortic valve stenosis https RT oxengsci Prof <PERSON>Tim Denison</PERSON> who will take up the post of Professor of Neurotechnology UniofOxford this summer has been named one of RT ShawTrust Hi UniofOxford We are running a competition in May aimed at disabled 13 24 year olds with an interest in IT Attendees are We have been informed by ucu that notice of industrial action at <LOCATION>Oxford</LOCATION> from April 16 is withdrawn We will act sw https t co KnUdkVaA1Y <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> s cool modernism O <PERSON>Keeffe</PERSON> to Hopper Exhibition now on at <ORGANIZATION>AshmoleanMuseum</ORGANIZATION> https t co kyy0Zt8ThT https t co cTyD99utPQ RT OxfordSparks EVENT Marie Curious Girls Exploring Science 29 Apr 2018 9 00am to 5 30pm Venue <PERSON>Denys Wilkinson</PERSON> Building Departmen RT oxfoundry At the <LOCATION>Oxford Foundry</LOCATION> we want to help our students shift their fear of failure to a fear of not trying Have you got any RT SkollCentre Research panel insight There are lots of structural barriers to systems change go into the system and build trust and a Pirates and poets suffragettes and explorers celebrate the achievements of women who dared to do the unexpected https t co HIfic0bWew RT risj_oxford The <ORGANIZATION>Power of Platforms</ORGANIZATION> key points from the inaugural lecture by rasmus_kleis Professor of <ORGANIZATION>Political Communication Unio RT</ORGANIZATION> PhilBoyleFCO Great to see tech and expertise helping in the fight against plague in <LOCATION>Madagascar</LOCATION> Thanks nanopore amp amp UniofOxford Female body shape gene may increase risk of type 2 diabetes Scientists have identified a gene linked to the creat https t co zic1LOFhl1 <ORGANIZATION>Oxford</ORGANIZATION> spinout Brainomix secures 7m investment to tackle strokes with AI The company was spun out from https t co wsvfO6I7rV Ancient bones suggest first humans travelled further than we think Scientists have discovered an ancient bone in S https t co 6b0Pj5NI1f <ORGANIZATION>Oxford</ORGANIZATION> student am_downes recently had two years worth of notes stolen in <LOCATION>Durham</LOCATION> please keep an eye out if you https t co xKmoBjLF6S RT sethmnookin New mobile phone app warns users when mosquitoes are nearby next step is to see if it can ID malaria carrying species Ma sethmnookin You can read more about our mosquito related research in our <LOCATION>Oxford</LOCATION> and the Mosquito series on <PERSON>Mediu</PERSON> https t co rYQj6KdwQL Oldest DNA from <LOCATION>Africa</LOCATION> offers clues to ancient cultures The discovery of DNA the oldest ever obtained from ancie https t co xEnZzmRq1p RT oxfoundry Overcome your fear of failure at the Foundry Join us on April 11 for the Fail Faire at the SkollWF for tales of epic entr RT OxMusicFaculty Conference and public performances 9 11April TORCHOxford OxHumanities UniofOxford OxfordLieder oxfordtimes https RT LEGOfoundation Happy to be joined by easypeasyapp at LEGOIdea2018 EP is a parenting app encouraging play amp amp interaction at home thro RT WorldLitNetwork kate_houlden speaking on <PERSON>Anna Kavan</PERSON> Queer Modernism and World Literature QueerModernism 2 30pm this Thursday 12th Are you a decider or a ditherer How long should we spend collecting relevant information to inform our choice https t co eWBvg38NV4 RT OxfordMedSci Staff amp amp students invited to share their views on sport <ORGANIZATION>UniofOxford Two</ORGANIZATION> surveys 1 for staff amp amp 1 for students are now RT spacegovuk We re inviting academic teams to provide full details of their proposals for experiments to fly on the Space_Station https RT SkollCentre Tune in next week as we cover the SkollWF through the medium of blogs 14 <ORGANIZATION>UniofOxford</ORGANIZATION> students will be covering a variet RT OxZooDept Congratulations to our HoD Ben_Sheldon_EGI recently awarded the prestigious <PERSON>Edward O Wilson</PERSON> Naturalist Award by <ORGANIZATION>ASNAmNat RT</ORGANIZATION> OxfordGradStudy We re delighted to announce the Grand Prize winners of this year s Graduate Photography Competition Congratulations t RT NIHRCRN_tvsm Healthy Join our study into limiting the impact of steroids If you are a healthy man aged between 18 60 and interested Journey into <ORGANIZATION>Tolkien</ORGANIZATION> s worlds in this once in a generation exhibition Maker of <LOCATION>Middle Earth</LOCATION> from June to October https t co NXxUyq4DJk Should we be for or against British citizens having to be able to speak English What makes a British artist sing i https t co PjB81LYy1q This Sir <ORGANIZATION>William Dunn School of Pathology</ORGANIZATION> annual lecture is held in honour of <PERSON>Norman Heatley</PERSON> who was a member of t https t co fdYbiAbBrB Bringing together talks workshops hands on activities and walking tours the OxMathsFest is an extravaganza of https t co 3PzVdi9VTd One of the most involving aspects of an academic career in Religious Studies is how it can bring you into contact https t co SsUTA8MOO7 Deep sea wildlife more vulnerable to extinction than first thought We have only known since the existence of unusu https t co Mq7cVhn60j RT BlavatnikSchool Sir <PERSON>Leonard Blavatnik</PERSON> is not a <ORGANIZATION>Trump</ORGANIZATION> donor nor is <ORGANIZATION>Oxford</ORGANIZATION> for sale Our dean <PERSON>NgaireWoods</PERSON> responds to article in the European undergraduate recruitment tour Meet us at one of our undergraduate admissions information sessions across https t co trkocs2jre If you go down to the woods today you re in for an interactive experience At WythamWoods1 visitors are encouragin https t co 8GrjvxCWiK After a Narrow Escape From Death School Beckons Grad student tylerpager writes for nytimes on his journey throu https t co NT18kj5ia0 Alchemy flushing toilets and blood letting The secrets of medieval <LOCATION>Oxford</LOCATION> revealed <PERSON>Davidmkeys</PERSON> writes for https t co lB9eBg8MZB RT oxfordrobots Not your usual Friday at the office https t co kTpkUHXPNP RT tylerpager Where doctors are few and far between treatable health problems often go ignored In my latest nytopinion piece from my t Deeds not Words blackwellbooks and WiH_Oxford are proud to present <PERSON>Helen Pankhurst</PERSON> at the bookshop as part of https t co DP9kom5kL3 RT oxqueerstudies We re delighted to have been shortlisted for the Vice Chancellor s Diversity Award for Teaching and <ORGANIZATION>Learning RT</ORGANIZATION> WildCRU_Ox 2018 <LOCATION>Cincinnati</LOCATION> Zoo Wildlife Conservation Award winner Dr <PERSON>Amy Dickman</PERSON> will be speaking on the 25th April at the Barrows C RT MedEngOxon Today UnivOxford begins hosting ConfMKempe three days of papers amp amp plenaries sharing the latest research on <PERSON>Margery Kempe</PERSON> RT PembrokeOxford Have you heard of SolidariTee This student led nationwide campaign aims to aid those suffering in the refugee crisis The Women in the Humanities research project create Suffrage Wall Women from around the <LOCATION>UK</LOCATION> who represent a variety https t co 0xzI9XoJRW Firefighting AI powered propaganda Dr vidunarayanan a researcher at the oiioxford discusses her work understa https t co 928BoYw8Yu RT Queenschoir A little snippet from our rehearsal this afternoon in <LOCATION>Stanford Memorial Church</LOCATION> for our concert tonight We are singing in _criminologist suttontrust No problem <PERSON>Alex Your</PERSON> online privacy depends as much on your friends data habits as your own AndrewTStephen L Or al Professor of https t co ol20p1DDYQ What happens if your heart stops It can be started again but does this mean your heart is truly fixed https t co ByJfDFjx0e RT OxfordGradStudy Grad student Cl udia <LOCATION>Coleoni</LOCATION> has had an eventful year since <ORGANIZATION>Oxford</ORGANIZATION> said Yes From the feeling of being in a <ORGANIZATION>Harry Po RT</ORGANIZATION> laurencejohn97 Queenschoir have arrived safely in <LOCATION>California</LOCATION> and are already busy rehearsing the joint items for our concert with St _criminologist suttontrust Hi <PERSON>Alex</PERSON> To the right of the piece there is a link to the full <ORGANIZATION>Stop Start</ORGANIZATION> report on the suttontrust site Exposure to household air pollution from using wood or coal for cooking and heating is associated with higher risk https t co LpUgSiuhC5 RT OxZooDept Yesterday we launched a new the_zooniverse project calling for volunteers to refine the mosquito detecting HumBug app L Early years provision a postcode lottery according to new report Government records of SureStart children s ce https t co cXndzKKcm5 RT ButtleUK As many as 1 000 life saving Sure Start centres for young children and families have closed across <LOCATION>UK</LOCATION> since 2009 twice as RT royalsociety What are the potential socio economic impacts of machinelearning over the next decade <PERSON>Peter Donnelly</PERSON> Professor of Stat RT BodleianHCL Mind Boggling Medical History A weird and wonderful game developed by <ORGANIZATION>Oxford</ORGANIZATION> s <PERSON>SalsyFrampton</PERSON> and colleagues funded by t What does it mean to study the Qur an historically In the first podcast of a four part series we consider how hist https t co Ji7a7GF5Me RT BruceReindeer Delighted overwhelmed and astonished to be shortlisted in two categories for the new Vice Chancellors Diversity award RT UNAUK We have only one planet <LOCATION>Earth</LOCATION> to call home Our challenge is to create and improve continually the conditions for every human be RT cindygallop Proud that my alma mater SomervilleOx uniofoxford is named after <PERSON>Mary Somerville</PERSON> who tutored <PERSON>Ada Lovelace</PERSON> the woman who Should all <LOCATION>UK</LOCATION> citizens speak English In a guest post for ArtsBlog <PERSON>Katrin Kohl</PERSON> Professor of German Literature an https t co gbrkzfKdXS Is smoking transmitted from one generation to another Dr <PERSON>Alexi Gugushvili DSPI_Oxford</PERSON> explains the background t https t co PPsXjweFgy RT WythamWoods1 If you missed seeing <PERSON>Attenborough</PERSON> at <LOCATION>Wytham Woods</LOCATION> on <ORGANIZATION>EasterWeekend</ORGANIZATION> you can catch up now on <ORGANIZATION>BBC</ORGANIZATION> iPlayer https t co Rq RT morethanadodo Actually no fluffy Easter chicks but prehistoric sea reptiles in our Jurassic Packs family event tomorrow Borrow one o Fortunes and Misfortunes of the Student Journalist by <PERSON>Jorge Lopez Llorente</PERSON> undergraduate at MansfieldOxford https t co UNy3WY5YrW RT BlavatnikAwards Blavatnik2018 PS amp amp E Inaugural Laureate Prof <PERSON>Henry Snaith Snatihgroup UniofOxford OxfordPhysics</PERSON> interviewed by Rach Audiences liked <PERSON>Debussy</PERSON> s music Critics were less enthusiastic It seemed so non traditional that they found it d https t co fuFWmyiQ7Z Economists are unfairly maligned but they are often pretty prejudiced themselves eortizospina researcher at https t co vjjRvz7FsL RT RDMOxford Congratulations to <PERSON>DrAJLewandowski</PERSON> who has been awarded a Fellowship from TheBHF to study how being born preterm impacts t The VarsityMatch and <ORGANIZATION>RFU</ORGANIZATION> have agreed a new 4 year deal for the historic rugby fixtures between <ORGANIZATION>UniofOxford</ORGANIZATION> and https t co p34ptyd9Qo Are you a decider or a ditherer How long should we spend collecting relevant information to inform our choice https t co 0OxkC7O4nM RT tylerpager Armed checkpoints broken bridges and roadside businesses My reflections from a 15 hour road trip with <PERSON>NickKristof</PERSON> in th <ORGANIZATION>Oxford</ORGANIZATION> spinout Brainomix secures 7m investment to tackle strokes with AI The company was spun out from https t co 3aWmFa6y6D RT AshmoleanMuseum Today is WorldPartyDay Here are some 17th century folk having a party in the woods The Country Dance etching and d RT SkollCentre We are pleased to announce that now ALL UniofOxford students and alumnae from full time programmes are eligible to apply You ve got to have technique composition is like aircraft design johnmrutter in dialogue with bobchilcott for https t co 7ySFFkx5P4 RT oxfordalumni Dr <PERSON>Neel Burton</PERSON> psychologist and philosopher UniofOxford discusses what it means to be lazy and whether it is a negativ RT missvarz I m SOO grateful Last night I was on <ORGANIZATION>Al Jazeera</ORGANIZATION> news aljazeeraenglish interviewed by the wonderful BarbaraGSerra discus RT britac_news British Academy Postdoctoral Fellow Dr <PERSON>Felix Pretis</PERSON> and his colleagues at <ORGANIZATION>UniofOxford</ORGANIZATION> have today published their paper il <ORGANIZATION>RT EPSRC International</ORGANIZATION> team involving ucl UniofOxford EdinburghUni imperialcollege and Cambridge_Uni tracks drug resistant gene f RT BlavatnikAwards The difference between an atom and a human is the same as between a human and the stars Watch Blavatnik2018 UK <ORGANIZATION>Ina Global Carnivore Conservation</ORGANIZATION> the WildCRU_Ox board game Can you save endangered carnivores across the world F https t co wxjafvskC6 Last year 3 2 million people visited the <ORGANIZATION>University</ORGANIZATION> s six cultural attractions the AshmoleanMuseum bodleianlibs https t co 24ku46vd7S Maker of <LOCATION>Middle Earth Journey</LOCATION> into <ORGANIZATION>Tolkien</ORGANIZATION> s worlds in this once in a generation exhibition From June to October https t co puUGQUUvvm I ve learned over months of interviewing a wide range of people historians politicians campaigners students https t co x7afciEDeR Why are protected areas important for elephants stress levels https t co cXYwYjWhVc https t co VlNHzgO67o So you think you re a chocolate expert Where does chocolate come from What s the difference between milk white https t co HbFuqcrGBc Happy Easter If you ve had too much chocolate this morning why not take a break and feast your eyes on the https t co MpHuVnfh5a Michelangelo Book your free ticket now From 6 March for four weeks only explore a remarkable group of drawings by https t co VSCVsQRL0p We offer apprenticeships in arts humanities medical amp amp plant sciences HR IT social amp amp digital media amp amp more https t co hQLQoOGloE How does electricity flow through small objects OxfordSparks goes to <ORGANIZATION>Oxford</ORGANIZATION> s Materials Department to find out https t co 3wAB1KIOkL We are scientists writers musicians engineers We are people To celebrate the 2018 Transgender Policy launc https t co 923ULr4AcF Global Carnivore Conservation the WildCRU_Ox board game Can you save endangered carnivores across the world F https t co zNw9jd8mhT Did you watch the <ORGANIZATION>OxfordSparks Facebook Live</ORGANIZATION> conducting an experiment on the MRI scanner to see how the brain iden https t co VnN040z5WQ USS pension dispute latest union members to be consulted on current proposal https t co MTrKQrckV9 Oldest DNA from <LOCATION>Africa</LOCATION> offers clues to ancient cultures The discovery of DNA the oldest ever obtained from ancie https t co Jy2f3rpzWe Did you know that for a long time there was no special GoodFriday observance <PERSON>Kirsty McHugh</PERSON> looks into defining https t co u4I2JYUxP6 RT arusbridger So proud of missvarz undergraduate at lmhoxford who was a Foundation Year pioneer and who responds so gracefully to som RT itvnews <ORGANIZATION>Oxford University</ORGANIZATION> student missvarz received racist abuse after urging youngsters from ethnic minority backgrounds to apply fo RT letsoxplore Challenge your students with <PERSON>Oxplore</PERSON> s BIG questions We draw on the latest research at <ORGANIZATION>Oxford University</ORGANIZATION> and totally free Start your Easter weekend with AshmoleanMuseum After Hours explore the museum after normal closing time Take in https t co 8ehijUiuY6 Making an Impact Dr <PERSON>Matt Perkins</PERSON> head of OxUInnovation explains how <ORGANIZATION>Oxford</ORGANIZATION> s culture of entrepreneurship has b https t co DtdYzb62te As part of the <ORGANIZATION>BBC</ORGANIZATION> s Civilisations Festival the AshmoleanMuseum will be hosting a variety of events to share ide https t co WMPBpmhRCY Today is MaundyThursday but what does maundy mean and where does Thursday come from https t co aIyuCt0OEU https t co Cntq41Ku7P RT missvarz Discussing racism in universities and the dangers of online abuse on ITV Thank you so much alstewitn for a wonderful interv Staffie76 alstewitn We are RT alstewitn missvarz So nice to meet you amp amp thanks for an important helpful interview I wish you well UniofOxford lmhoxford arusb In part three of our WomeninAI series Professor <PERSON>Marta Kwiatkowska</PERSON> a computer scientist at CompSciOxford discus https t co PcjAkEwpys RT oxengsci It may be a grey day but a colourful flag is flying on the top of the oxengsci Thom Building in anticipation of <ORGANIZATION>Internationa RT</ORGANIZATION> BBCBreakfast Thousands of teenagers are needed to trial Meningitis B vaccines You might want to SHARE this with any teens you kn RT prm_laurita You might think you know the Pitt Rivers but did you know about all this happening Pitt_Rivers https t co 5uI RT RareBooksOfBod Many happy returns to <PERSON>Hannah Glasse</PERSON> the original celebrity chef The art of cookery made plain and easy was publishe RT StAnnesOutreach Applications now open for our one night Residential Study Visits in Geography Music and English Modern Languages Ope RT DraysonHealth Great discussion by Professor <PERSON>David Clifton</PERSON> at yesterday s AIOxford expo talking about AI based healthcare systems and Meningitis B vaccine trial for teenagers launched <ORGANIZATION>NHS</ORGANIZATION> invites teenagers to take part in a study to see whether giv https t co KBv7LuyGoU RT PembrokeOxford Life s too short to let the fear of failure stop you from doing things and the more you do the more confident you ge RT OxfordGradStudy THANK YOU to our fabulously talented grad community on your Photo Competition entries so spectacular we couldn t hel RT OxMML_Schools The 3rd episode of the OxfordModLangs virtual book club for 6th formers is here and this time it s ITALIAN mfltwitter GirlsinTech RosariaTaddeo oxfordethicslab Yesterday we hosted a Facebook Live of an AI Expo discussion featuring https t co 6WZqDFY8i9 RT GirlsinTech Dr <PERSON>RosariaTaddeo</PERSON> is the Deputy Director of the oxfordethicslab at the <ORGANIZATION>UniofOxford Internet Institute</ORGANIZATION> at the <ORGANIZATION>GITCataly RT</ORGANIZATION> britac_news We re delighted to welcome the largest ever cohort of British Academy Postdoctoral Fellows an unprecedented two thirds of RT oxforduni_repo ORA has a new interface New functionality updated statistics and metrics and it looks a lot prettier Check out ARIEL mission to better understand exoplanet evolution gets green light UniofOxford are to play a key role in ARI https t co QyYBpwo0tv RT SkollCentre Are you a UniofOxford student or alumn with a social venture in need of seed funding Check out the our <ORGANIZATION>Skoll Venture Awa RT</ORGANIZATION> StephBrittain 1st April deadline to apply for the <ORGANIZATION>Interdisciplinary Conservation Network</ORGANIZATION> workshop this July Collaborate with amp amp lea RT NIHRCRN_tvsm Dr <PERSON>Matthew Snape</PERSON> was on BBCBreakfast this morning talking about a study that is vaccinating teenagers against meningitis Rage For and <ORGANIZATION>Against the Machine Paula Boddington</ORGANIZATION> discusses the infant field of ethics for ArtificialIntelligence https t co y4qjX8RkVs Changes in the structure and function of the hearts of people born prematurely may make them less able to cope with https t co vNc2qFKmo1 RT And_Cipriani ADHD tends to be a polarising topic with opinion quickly cited as fact This is particularly true in education very RT jasonnurse Meanwhile at AIOxford MaRy_N0 is presenting some of our research in CompSciOxford on using machine learning to detect o RT oxfordrobots ORI successful poster applicants Follow us on Instagram oxfordrobots and watch our story to see <PERSON>ORI</PERSON> in full swing at A RT morethanadodo The white blobs in this meteorite are calcium aluminium rich inclusions and are 4 568 billion years old This makes them A new clinical research and response network for epidemic infections has been launched in sub <LOCATION>Saharan Africa</LOCATION> with t https t co <ORGANIZATION>CLoBSmsNFN RT KelloggOx Oxford</ORGANIZATION> has always been my dream though it is a dream that comes with a significant financial component <ORGANIZATION>Dessa Meehan M RT</ORGANIZATION> PrincipalStAns We know getting to UniofOxford Open Days from the <LOCATION>North East</LOCATION> is expensive amp amp many parents aren t in a position to bring RT brawnm The Suffrage Wall was created to mark the centenary of women s suffrage in 2018 Top female leaders from around the <LOCATION>UK</LOCATION> were inv Michelangelo Book your free ticket now Until 2 April explore a remarkable group of drawings by <PERSON>Michelangelo</PERSON> which https t co hHQLeOlm2o Ever seen a Q amp amp A session from a driverlesscar Now s your chance Head to the OxfordSparks Facebook page at 11 30a https t co FAx4bkJwCj RT KebleOutreach Years 5 amp amp 6 pupils enjoying lunch in Hall amp amp all about study skills KebleCollege UniofOxford for the <ORGANIZATION>BrilliantClub Sch RT</ORGANIZATION> KelloggOx Congratulations to our student <PERSON>Chris Byrne</PERSON> for scoring the winning goal for UniofOxford at the <ORGANIZATION>100th Ice Hockey Varsity Mat Oxford</ORGANIZATION> to play key role in <LOCATION>UK</LOCATION> energy demand research centre <ORGANIZATION>UniofOxford</ORGANIZATION> is to take a lead role in a new research https t co qOlSBXDLIW WomeninAI SandraWachter5 lawyer amp amp Research Fellow in DataEthics AI robotics amp amp Internet Regulation cyber se https t co 1TWn3DEWQV <LOCATION>Britain</LOCATION> s role in the <LOCATION>Balkans</LOCATION> why <PERSON>Boris Johnson</PERSON> is about to turn pro <ORGANIZATION>EU</ORGANIZATION> <PERSON>Othon Anastasakis StAntsCollege</PERSON> and A https t co UblSNKw7nq RT SkillsOxSocSci Are you SocialSciences Dphil UniofOxford planning on conducting fieldwork in a high risk setting Watch methods and What does AI mean to the experts speaking at the uniofoxford AI Expo on March 27 What do you want to know about https t co 6RaBmDSyOo RT BSI_UK How are robotics and autonomous systems transforming manufacturing Join our panel discussion at 10 April in <LOCATION>Birmingham</LOCATION> and gai RT oxfordalumni A new drug has been developed to treat MS a condition that currently has no treatment Dr <PERSON>Matt Craner</PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION>UniofOxford</ORGANIZATION> i Congratulations to OUIHCMensBlues for winning the 100th Varsity Match in <LOCATION>Switzerland</LOCATION> https t co UHNR3Kzhwj https t co cm3r3RUu5E RT thisismani_ Check out my <ORGANIZATION>OXFORD</ORGANIZATION> UNIVERSITY ROOM TOUR video Accommodation at <ORGANIZATION>UniofOxford</ORGANIZATION> can vary across colleges so here s my video Read more about our honorary degree recipients for 2018 degrees will be awarded to wmarybeard SirMattBourne Lo https t co SP4262v436 RT BrightonDubai Syrian refugee <PERSON>Sulaiman</PERSON> who was offered a 110 scholarship to BrightonCollege after <PERSON>Richard Cairns</PERSON> heard about his sel RT RobertDPutnam I am deeply honored by <ORGANIZATION>Oxford</ORGANIZATION> a most distinguished institution with which I had had close times for more than a century <ORGANIZATION>RT OUIHCMensBlues Oxford</ORGANIZATION> win the <ORGANIZATION>100th Varsity Match</ORGANIZATION> in OT 4 3 A huge thank you to all players alumni fans families amp amp friends for u RT TheArtNewspaper <PERSON>J R R Tolkien</PERSON> show reveals Middle earth mastermind s unseen art https t co hmpuLBiJaR bodleianlibs UniofOxford ht RT BlavatnikAwards Blavatnik2018 <LOCATION>UK</LOCATION> finalist in chemistry Prof <PERSON>Philipp Kukura UniofOxford</PERSON> featured in ExeterCollegeOx News https Eggscited about Easter Join the Eggstraordinary Easter Eggventure with an egg hunters trail at morethanadodo https t co 7BWzbeGOlZ Last year 3 2 million people visited the <ORGANIZATION>University</ORGANIZATION> s six cultural attractions the AshmoleanMuseum bodleianlibs https t co oT7AXtFuyD What does AI mean to the experts speaking at the uniofoxford AI Expo on March 27 What do you want to know Comme https t co Mk96z5V0Qm Find out how to help ellieexpedition amp amp their elephant conservation citizen science project here https t co 3muSGoGlcK ARIEL mission to better understand exoplanet evolution gets green light UniofOxford are to play a key role in ARI https t co wrsrTJI9zn Well done to our DarkBlues rowing in the OUBCsquad and OUWBCsquad on their efforts today at the 164th BoatRace https t co 6SmKncrTfp What does AI mean to the experts speaking at the uniofoxford AI Expo on March 27 What do you want to know Comme https t co NlzsK8yEij RT 4Ted_ Big shout out to all of the RNLI lifeboat crews and lifeguards heading to <LOCATION>London</LOCATION> this weekend to keep everyone safe during the RT theboatraces The wait is finally over It s Race Day TheBoatRace2018 TheBoatRace BBCBoatRace https t co 9CWWa3VPCS RT SirMattBourne As if this were not honour enough I get to receive it alongside one of my movie idols the great MartinScorsese Unio Reinventing the role of student media by <PERSON>Theo Davies Lewis</PERSON> an undergraduate studying Archaeology and Anthropology https t co 3h1yC6intu Good luck to our DarkBlue squads competing in today s CR_UK BoatRace OUWBCsquad OUBCsquad <ORGANIZATION>Oxford</ORGANIZATION> https t co Bo358fPYNw Breaking news New offer in USS pensions dispute https t co hVY7WLO0dd Michelangelo Book your free ticket now From 6 March for four weeks only explore a remarkable group of drawings by https t co mqA25zpDr7 RT OxfordSparks Did you miss our new animation asking how How does electricity flow through small objects Watch here to find out htt What does AI mean to the experts speaking at the uniofoxford AI Expo on March 27 What do you want to know Comme https t co KHT6IjJIES RT Elpipster Yeti crabs we ve only known about them for 13 years How resilient have they been to environmental changes in the past an Treating depression in cancer increases quality of life but not length of life Researchers have found that trea https t co EV3CqT7TQj In my experience women are keen to see the outcome of an application and understand what their work and contributi https t co amviMQLJPd Things we learned this week Catch up with this week s <ORGANIZATION>UniofOxford</ORGANIZATION> research in 30 seconds https t co BTQDpqciNH Honorary degree recipients for 2018 announced read more about this year s seven recipients of honorary degrees fro https t co <ORGANIZATION>KgW66K5VQA RT</ORGANIZATION> GlobeMed <PERSON>Cameron Clarke</PERSON> a GlobeMedHU alumnus currently enrolled at <ORGANIZATION>UniofOxford</ORGANIZATION> as a <ORGANIZATION>Rhodes Scholar</ORGANIZATION> shares about how he discovered neiljeffares UKSupremeCourt Hello neiljeffares Our nomination and deliberation process is thorough and protract https t co Dp7zgGW2IZ What does AI mean to the experts at the uniofoxford AI Expo on March 27 Do you have a question about AI amp amp Ethics https t co 04ADi6Dfs4 RT timeshighered Interview with UniofOxford s <PERSON>Henry Snaith</PERSON> of SnaithGroup BlavatnikAwards winner and perovskite solar cells pionee <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> comes to the AshmoleanMuseum A ravishing new exhibition of eighty American modernist works of art opens t https t co w8LxWUTb6N RT theboatraces 3 days to go to The CR_UK Boat Race Who will be supporting the <ORGANIZATION>Dark Blue of Oxford</ORGANIZATION> OUWBCsquad OUBCsquad <ORGANIZATION>UniofOxf RT CompSciOxford Artificial Intelligence</ORGANIZATION> is the latest subject to be added to the iconic ladybirdbooks series The book written by wool RT oxfordenvsust WorldWaterDay Our students from <ORGANIZATION>UniofOxford</ORGANIZATION> have been sharing photo s of how they save water as part of the EcoPowe Oldest DNA from <LOCATION>Africa</LOCATION> offers clues to ancient cultures The discovery of DNA the oldest ever obtained from ancie https t co 1efRkqOfxy The <ORGANIZATION>UniofOxford</ORGANIZATION> will showcase its artificial intelligence AI research with a one day expo on 27 March 2018 https t co j10391akTD RT OxAthenaSWAN Register now for the next in the series of fantastic Women of Achievement Lectures UniofOxford with MorrisseyHelena o What does AI mean to the experts speaking at the uniofoxford AI Expo on March 27 What do you want to know Comme https t co Y2kV6x00VI RT stdavidscoll So excited to hear that our very own <PERSON>Amy Tilley Morgan McCarthy Natalia Tonner Annabel Foster</PERSON> amp amp <PERSON>Christopher Lee</PERSON> have b RT OxMathsFest Introducing Platonic solid number 1 a tetrahedron A tetrahedron is made up of 4 equilateral triangles can you make your RT OxUniEarthSci Did you know Maths A Level is essential for studying Earth Sciences UniofOxford To encourage those young mathematical RT creativelangs On WorldPoetryDay learn more about the wonderful multilingual poetry workshops being run OxfordSpiresAc with the ins Love and Math A public lecture given by <PERSON>Edward Frenkel</PERSON> a professor at the UCBerkeley talking around his best se https t co 4qCUQNghT2 RT EPSRC An international team of scientists including <ORGANIZATION>EPSRC</ORGANIZATION> supported researchers from <ORGANIZATION>UniofOxford</ORGANIZATION> solve mystery of why comets emit X Poetry with SimonArmitage celebrate WorldPoetryDay with our podcast series featuring <PERSON>Simon Armitage</PERSON> s public t https t co mMGinKXrBI RT oxfordalumni Today is WorldPoetryDay and we re celebrating by looking at <ORGANIZATION>Oxford Alumni</ORGANIZATION> who became brilliant poets Look out for posts RT OxMML_Schools On the OxfordModLangs schools blog this week Dr <PERSON>Kemp</PERSON> of SomervilleOx introduces us to <ORGANIZATION>Time amp amp Tense</ORGANIZATION> in French <ORGANIZATION>Literatu RT</ORGANIZATION> OxfordDiplomat If I am going to have a home away from home I am fortunate to call this mine UniofOxford https t co <ORGANIZATION>FuIIjAjNwp RT KevinBaughan Telegraph</ORGANIZATION> on the valley of death Pleased that innovateuk has funded great oxford spin outs such as oxbotica and a q RT UniofOxfordSI Happy WorldPoetryDay If you have a haiku limerick epigram or epitaph to share we d love to read it Tweet us your p 13 rise in visitors to UniofOxford gardens libraries amp amp museums More than 3 2 million people visited the Univers https t co EHkijhYf7d RT ExeterCollege Great to hear about one of our lecturers nominated for a teaching award by a former student now at <ORGANIZATION>UniofOxford ExeColl From</ORGANIZATION> one of the first Mr Men and one of the seven dwarves to happy hour happy is a word that crops up from child https t co cfqXcGVgKU RT PrincipalStAns I think that s 5 sessions in one day hundreds of pupils in <LOCATION>North East England</LOCATION> now know more about why UniofOxford ma RT oxfordclassics Come and check out letsoxplore <ORGANIZATION>Oxford</ORGANIZATION> and Cambridge Student Conferences OxOutreach CamOutreach UniofOxford OxCambS Scientists solve mystery of why comets emit X rays The mystery of how comets are able to emit X rays has been solv https t co 0eg1jYQ9td Premature hearts less able to cope with exercise Changes in structure and heart function of those born prematurely https t co iwSCLdIp49 The other side of the Big Bang The Big Bang has long been taken to be our universe s beginning However recent https t co gSkrg99K3z Can we bring laughter to a bad situation Researchers from <ORGANIZATION>UniofOxford</ORGANIZATION> teamed up with ClownsWithoutBorders and t https t co ygcF55YROX A new frontier Oil palm in the Peruvian Amazon Understanding the effects of <LOCATION>Peru</LOCATION> s new boom crop on the country s https t co Dpyan2ZQu5 OxVlog has returned The project is back with new Oxvloggers sharing new content Join <PERSON>Gayatri Tucker Jessica</PERSON> Na https t co 7a6GWWujpB RT BalliolOxford We are delighted to have awarded the Balliol Students Scholarship to a Syrian refugee who will be coming to <ORGANIZATION>Balliol</ORGANIZATION> in RT tylerpager Just returned from reporting with NickKristof in the <LOCATION>Central African Republic Here</LOCATION> s a few photos from our trip with stor RT rhodes_trust NBCNews caught up with <PERSON>JoryFleming Rhodesscholar</PERSON> in a charming interview about his Rhodesscholarexperience at <ORGANIZATION>Uniof RT</ORGANIZATION> en_route_paleo Even though they ve become part of everyday life I keep re discovering the beauty of the historical buildings of Unio morris86 Hi morris86 These online programmes are offered by OxfordSBS and presented in collaboration with https t co amgnZFrEya Completely committed to providing opportunities to local young people through our apprenticeships Our Apprentic https t co hIynUsAIjP RT StAnnesOutreach Excited to be back in the <LOCATION>North East Looking</LOCATION> forward to another week of school visits and outreach events oxoutreac RT OxExpPsy We wanted something that had a really strong research base <PERSON>Janet Cooper Stoke</PERSON> Speaks Out Find out how researchers OxEx Planet Dinosaur Join author <PERSON>Elaine Wickson</PERSON> for a talk packed with infographics dinosaurs and space inspired by h https t co AbsooABszW As part of the <ORGANIZATION>BBC</ORGANIZATION> s Civilisations Festival the AshmoleanMuseum will be hosting a variety of events to share ide https t co qeHLyuSDOW Do we see colour the same Surely if something is blue then we all see that it s blue fact But what if it s not https t co lo2nq6cZZX Since its inception tech transfer or university innovation has been a field dominated by the STEM sciences Un https t co AAUkC9F0mp Ever wondered how far UniofOxford research stretches The <ORGANIZATION>Global Challenges Research Fund</ORGANIZATION> supports interdisciplina https t co 0NURYg7Dgf At WythamWoods1 visitors are encouraging to use iRecord an app that allows all of <PERSON>Wytham</PERSON> s visitors to record an https t co 4fM1tTeAUz Explore an Oxford Civil War painting and help create a tactile version with the <ORGANIZATION>Oxfordshire Association</ORGANIZATION> for the Bli https t co GdlQwdvQS2 Museum of Natural History found squawking not tweeting at morethanadodo is one of the landmarks of <ORGANIZATION>Oxford Thi</ORGANIZATION> https t co c12MWGaAaP The term hippie trail began to circulate in the late 1960s it referred principally to the long route from <LOCATION>London</LOCATION> https t co KhnXPmK3Ds RT SteliosKiosses Today I m in awe of the sun and the light it shines on the beautiful ancient buildings of <ORGANIZATION>Oxford Oxford UniofOxfor RT</ORGANIZATION> a_n_s This is so awesome oxfordsparks Live broadcast of an fMRI experiment first ever from UniofOxford OxPER the winner must h RT letsoxplore Should you believe the history books Tweet us your questions and be sure to tune in to our <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> live stream with lea RT AshmoleanMuseum There were more than 3 2 million visits to UniofOxford museums libraries amp amp gardens in 2017 and 3 of us are now in t In stopping disease early diagnosis is key but hampered by expensive and time consuming blood tests But what if https t co 6DQL1DmMAS What have we learned this week from <ORGANIZATION>UniofOxford</ORGANIZATION> research Catch up with a week s worth of news in 40 seconds https t co Jmc4WdjB9h Health chiefs are failing to investigate a clear pattern of rising death rates amp amp worsening health outcomes in <LOCATION>Engla</LOCATION> https t co z5K7i53nLd RT BHFCymru Scientists UniofOxford are set to study how a stress chemical can worsen the development of cardiovascular disease Find out RT FerreroUK Today our Kinder team have some exciting news We are pleased to announce that <PERSON>Kinder</PERSON> has partnered with uniofoxford to su RT LVShaw 2017 figures from alva_uk today show UniofOxford s gardens libraries amp amp museums saw 13 rise in visitors https t co 5euAlG RT BentFlyvbjerg Recommendation of the Oxford MMPM from an alumnus and leading light in the industry Thank you Peter OxfordSBS oxso Friday 23 March marks <PERSON>William Smith</PERSON> s 249th birthday To celebrate head to morethanadodo to see the map that cha https t co ofWU82uGnP Maker of <LOCATION>Middle Earth Journey</LOCATION> into <ORGANIZATION>Tolkien</ORGANIZATION> s worlds in this once in a generation exhibition From June to October https t co tAIr9JSyVU Women in Medical Science Listen to successful female scientists share their stories and speak candidly about their https t co 6a8gvIENQI YeovilCollege Congratulations Luke Number of known stroke risk genes tripled An international team of researchers part funded by the TheBHF has ide https t co tLvkXnVYWR When it comes to science diversity is vital If we want the best scientists then we need to accept everyone regar https t co CHkxPdsRHA RT TheBHF Read about the exciting research Dr <PERSON>Nicola Smart</PERSON> is undertaking UniofOxford to develop treatments that could give damaged hear RT brawnm OctaviaGoredema MBE TwentyTenTalent and MBDiversityLead at <ORGANIZATION>UniofOxford</ORGANIZATION> for IWD2018 Check my Instagram link for details ab The <ORGANIZATION>UniofOxford</ORGANIZATION> will showcase its artificial intelligence AI research with a one day expo on 27 March 2018 https t co Tvs1e3jcXT So if you feel like you re in a black hole don t give up There s a way out Remembering <PERSON>Stephen Hawking Oxfor</PERSON> https t co Jvrx5mc9n4 RT AshmoleanMuseum We re also very excited that the <ORGANIZATION>UniofOxford s Libraries Museums amp amp Gardens</ORGANIZATION> have been shortlisted by <PERSON>MandHShow</PERSON> for b Who do you think you really are A genetic map of the British <LOCATION>Isles</LOCATION> By constructing the first fine scale map of th https t co 9Hh71lOHTN YeovilCollege Well done <ORGANIZATION>Jordan RT</ORGANIZATION> BrookesStaff Making a Difference Social Sciences amp amp Impact Conference 19 April St Anne s College We re joint hosting with <ORGANIZATION>UniofOxfor RT</ORGANIZATION> BlavatnikAwards Congratulations to Prof <PERSON>Timothy Behrens</PERSON> behrenstimb Blavatnik2018 Inaugural <LOCATION>UK</LOCATION> Finalist in Life Sciences OxNeuro N stackx__ Hello Yes of course please see the international students page for further information https t co HgNaHxWk0f RT <ORGANIZATION>NASA</ORGANIZATION> Remembering <PERSON>Stephen</PERSON> Hawking a renowned physicist and ambassador of science His theories unlocked a universe of possibilities th RT letsoxplore Here it is our Big Question for Friday s live stream Tweet us your thoughts amp amp questions and be sure to tune in on Fac Social media and internet not cause of political polarisation <ORGANIZATION>New UniofOxford</ORGANIZATION> research suggests that social medi https t co c4yoV3DlGG RT UnivOxford It is with great sadness that College notes the passing of Professor <PERSON>Stephen</PERSON> Hawking Univ OM 1959 Physics and Honorary We re very proud to call <PERSON>Stephen Hawking</PERSON> an alumnus of <LOCATION>Oxford</LOCATION> and enormously saddened by his passing Our thoughts https t co PVMDAjbsZa ALERRT epidemic research network launched in sub <LOCATION>Saharan Africa</LOCATION> A new clinical research and response network for e https t co ABdesr9Uyf RT anandMenon1 Universities need to think about what and who they are for AlanJWager and I on chhcalling and DavidLammy https Global Carnivore Conservation the WildCRU_Ox board game Can you save endangered carnivores across the world Fi https t co AR68okiR7q Computer simulations move step closer to reducing animal use in drug testing The march towards replacing animals i https t co 5wvPiWldLM RT ERC_Research How to provide legal protection to refugees arriving in <LOCATION>Europe</LOCATION> ERC grantee ProfCCostello UniofOxford re examines refu RT JennerInstitute We have people with many talents here at the JennerInstitute NDMOxford UniofOxford Congratulations Dr <ORGANIZATION>Nawamin Pinp RT</ORGANIZATION> nvidia Researchers UniofOxford are using mobile phones and <ORGANIZATION>GPU</ORGANIZATION> accelerated deeplearning to detect mosquitoes and battle the deadly d <ORGANIZATION>Oxford</ORGANIZATION> 3D bioprinting company <ORGANIZATION>OxSyBio</ORGANIZATION> secures 10m in funding https t co 4N45U3K0fP https t co ZAFzgTTM1U Does eating too many bananas makes you grow more body hair by increasing levels of potassium Are maggots are used https t co VRv0obvSpZ Find out how to help ellieexpedition amp amp their elephant conservation citizen science project here https t co mlyyH0Wya8 RT DFID_Research For ScienceWeekUK we re celebrating scientific leadership from Reach_water amp amp uniofOxford on their research to improv What are the chances that negotiations with the Democratic People s <LOCATION>Republic of Korea</LOCATION> to make the world a safer pl https t co psr9EDPU0y RT OxfordSparks FACEBOOK LIVE TODAY AT 3 30pm with Dr <PERSON>Michael Browning</PERSON> who we will be asking about brain based treatments for depressio RT morethanadodo Can you save the world s carnivores Gather your tools answer research questions and find African lions Malaysian Clo RT BHFpolicy Thanks to <ORGANIZATION>BHF</ORGANIZATION> funding scientists <ORGANIZATION>UniofOxford</ORGANIZATION> will try to identify new reasons why children are born with heart defects ht RT enterprisingox Meet this week s Oxford Entrepreneur Uncovered Dr <PERSON>Andy Woods</PERSON> FlyingFishR AndyTWoods https t co nDUGCbb95u start It s BrainAwarenessWeek Throughout the week OxfordSparks will be bringing you Twitter takeovers a different Fac https t co eqIbChHIbc RT EqualityinHE Highlighting womeninHE ClaraMBarker In addition to managing the Centre for Applied Superconductivity UniofOxford Cl RT TDaviesLewis I was delighted to write for UniofOxford on my interviewing on my OxideRadioLive show Have a read here https t co j RT ChesneyCharlie If you re thinking about joining the BCM course at oxfordgeography take a listen to the latest BCM podcast where cat RT georgeinstitute Meet brendonneuen one of our PhD students working in chronic kidneydisease and recent recipient of a full UniofOxf Laura Varnam Lecturer in English Literature UniofOxford writes for ConversationUK <ORGANIZATION>Du Maurier</ORGANIZATION> s <PERSON>Rebecca</PERSON> at 80 https t co FVIpUCYidP A Question of Taste Extract your DNA to search for the gene that makes you a sprout hater or sprout lover and dis https t co j0wQy6RPwo You asked When will I know if I ve been awarded a scholarship Excellent question Here s a little bit more about https t co E6JIEspcDf Brexit and <LOCATION>Britain</LOCATION> s Universities by Professor <PERSON>Anand Menon Dr Alan Wager of KingsCollegeLon</PERSON> and the <LOCATION>UK</LOCATION> in a C https t co gRKkUhTUiN <ORGANIZATION>Oxford</ORGANIZATION> researchers chosen as New Generation Thinkers Two of <ORGANIZATION>Oxford</ORGANIZATION> s early career academics have been chosen among https t co 4TCFaAKP2x The AshmoleanMuseum celebrates education appeal success <LOCATION>Britain</LOCATION> s first public museum has succeeded in raising th https t co btTRe5lKnA Have you been inspired by your surroundings whilst studying at <ORGANIZATION>Oxford</ORGANIZATION> Are you a keen photographer Then enter the https t co chTb7DlM1J Tea time Learn about the art of tea in <LOCATION>Japan</LOCATION> enjoy a bowl of green tea and watch a demonstration in the https t co b7DrKDzBEr Congratulations to everyone going to OxfordUNIQ We also offer lots of opportunities to learn more about subject https t co LM5nUMRKiR For the first 15 years of her professional life <PERSON>CarlynSamuel</PERSON> had a successful PR career At 38 she made the dec https t co cKPWloEIgO RT CompSciOxford A 6 minute film about future virtual humans is now on YouTube It incorporates material from research by Prof <PERSON>Blanca Rod</PERSON> As part of the <ORGANIZATION>BBC</ORGANIZATION> s Civilisations Festival the AshmoleanMuseum will be hosting a variety of events to share idea https t co 5AyKyEAIFJ RT LutonSixthForm Bit of lunchtime reading for you if you haven t already seen it A LutonSixthForm autism support worker has been r <ORGANIZATION>Penguins</ORGANIZATION> aspirin tattoos and leopards all feature in things we ve learned from <ORGANIZATION>UniofOxford</ORGANIZATION> research this week https t co <ORGANIZATION>HSZDfcwVzq Sharp</ORGANIZATION> rise in heart disease patients with five or more other conditions The proportion of people experiencing hear https t co RgboPRgJOn Cultural barriers to tackling the superbug crisis Research led by <ORGANIZATION>UniofOxford</ORGANIZATION> has revealed how the complex cultur https t co lTtCIhcIC2 A project led by WildCRU s Dr <PERSON>Amy Dickman</PERSON> from the <ORGANIZATION>Department of Zoology</ORGANIZATION> worked with communities in <LOCATION>Tanzania</LOCATION> to tr https t co fc24aXlatN 100 years of suffrage how far have we come A discussion to celebrate InternationalWomensDay2018 Leading figure https t co fyDim07teA <PERSON>Don</PERSON> t wait to be asked don t count on others play the long game actively own your career amp amp develop a unique le https t co fBrGcmVN1D DrSophieSmith We are deeply sorry for this and for offence caused International Women s Day is hugely important t https t co QmvwGMbf3d WomenInScience Find out more about women scientists from the past from <PERSON>Caroline Herschel</PERSON> who discovered severa https t co sCDDJE0pDH RT RDMOxford Happy InternationalWomensDay ICYMI Find out more about what drives just some of our inspirational female scientists in th AlbertGiubilini Hi <PERSON>Alberto</PERSON> the interview is in association with oxfoundry an entrepreneurial hub from https t co fvM1f1RkyT RT OxfordFLJS For IWD2018 Prof Sir <PERSON>Adam Roberts</PERSON> pays tribute to UniofOxford alumnus <PERSON>Gertrude Bell</PERSON> intrepid explorer multi linguist w LIVE NOW Join victoriabeckham and <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> s nicolamen in conversation on IWD2018 as part of <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> s globa https t co FA4e2YeEYR RT lmhoxford LMH is proud to celebrate International Women s Day We were the first <ORGANIZATION>Oxford College</ORGANIZATION> to admit women This short film celebr InternationalWomensDay is a global commitment to honouring the cultural social economic political amp amp academic co https t co yIVdpQqgXW Join victoriabeckham and <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> s nicolamen in conversation on InternationalWomensDay as part of <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> s gl https t co EeFgLROXq0 ArtisticLicence A fresh ear for late Schumann https t co r48Xv6byhl https t co opETCqfp7U SaturDIY Family friendly activities inspired by the <ORGANIZATION>Sappho</ORGANIZATION> to Suffrage exhibition make your own campaign badges a https t co 2NhyZTVYKP How does your brain acquire its shape What happens during trauma Tune in to the <ORGANIZATION>UniofOxford Facebook</ORGANIZATION> page at 5p https t co tVxLyt6Fj1 Get that noggin in gear and hop aboard the brain train To highlight BrainAwarenessWeek the Brain Discovery Festiv https t co yJCnmGas88 RT bankratravel On this day 3 years ago our co founder shani_akilah received her MSc offer in African Studies at UniofOxford Today we Could aspirin be used to treat tuberculous meningitis Professor <PERSON>Guy Thwaites Director of TropMedOxford</PERSON> explains https t co Om9OrbccaN Have you signed up for OxfordSparks amp amp OxNeuro Brain Discovery Festival starting 12 March There will be daily <ORGANIZATION>Fac</ORGANIZATION> https t co jMOOj2Z0GZ RT OxUniMaths Judging by recent posts you might think we have the brain on the brain Well you re right This week <PERSON>Alain Goriely</PERSON> s OxUni Michelangelo Book your free ticket now From 6 March for four weeks only explore a remarkable group of drawings by https t co VEpgRKy3xO RT OxOutreach Our 2019 undergraduate prospectus is now available to download Visit https t co 5DV9laWuJa https t co YYofaOEU9t Cancer vaccine firm <ORGANIZATION>Oxford Vacmedix</ORGANIZATION> closes 12 5m Series A funding <ORGANIZATION>Oxford Vacmedix UK Limited OVM</ORGANIZATION> a <LOCATION>UK</LOCATION> based bi https t co 7zUhpzPmQp RT altoncollege <PERSON>Alumna Isabel Carter</PERSON> is leading a Geological Mapping expedition to <LOCATION>South Greenland</LOCATION> in the summer as part of her Earth Sci 100 years of suffrage how far have we come A discussion to celebrate InternationalWomensDay Leading figures fr https t co Myobx0PIyJ RT ChCh_Access Very much looking forward to speaking to pupils and parents from AshmoleAcademy today about applying to UniofOxford Ox Dying for the group what motivates the ultimate sacrifice Whether idolised as heroes or demonised and labelled te https t co HRiR6tW57M Have you signed up for OxfordSparks amp amp OxNeuro Brain Discovery Festival starting 12 March There will be daily <ORGANIZATION>Fac</ORGANIZATION> https t co KAgds1i7ZT From scoring goals to winning votes How three footballers strike out as politicians from OxPolBlog https t co 87jzSDaflB RT <ORGANIZATION>BBC</ORGANIZATION> Explore humanity s desire to create Civilisations Starts on 1st March at 9pm on BBCTwo Presented by simon_schama DavidOlu RT enterprisingox Student or recent graduate UniofOxford with your own business or startup <ORGANIZATION>Apply for Santander Universities Entrepr RT</ORGANIZATION> OldieMagazine <PERSON>Michael Woolridge</PERSON> the Head of Computer Science at the UniofOxford talks to annabel_sampson about his Ladybird Guide The OxUniApprentice schemes offer a fantastic opportunity for young people and current members of staff to earn wh https t co PS3UOn7BXw RT OxUniApprentice We are celebrating NAW2018 in the <ORGANIZATION>Oxford Mail</ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION>Oxford Times</ORGANIZATION> great quotes from our UniofOxford apprentices get RT PrincipalStAns Last Summer <PERSON>Bryan Stephenson</PERSON> was StAnnesCollege to receive an honorary doctorate from UniofOxford Last night he was RT BBCOxford Sir <PERSON>Roger Bannister</PERSON> epitomised what it means to be a living legend says UniofOxford Vice Chancellor <PERSON>Louise Richardson</PERSON> in Sir <PERSON>Roger Bannister</PERSON> the first person to run a mile in under four minutes died on March 3 2018 at the age of 88 H https t co Lx19pnfInh Interested in joining an apprenticeship scheme Take a look at the UniofOxford apprenticeship opportunities page https t co JjQEs8E13b Remembering Sir <PERSON>Roger Bannister</PERSON> Hear the athlete doctor and academic relive running the first sub four minute mil https t co VjHe3wvMUd Two sides of transparency how audits sometimes help sometimes harm women s political representation from the https t co R2nQfuIWU9 Remembering Sir <PERSON>Roger Bannister</PERSON> here is a video of him carrying the Olympic torch around our <LOCATION>Iffley Road</LOCATION> track in https t co 5NK7KLEwor Lord <PERSON>Patten</PERSON> of Barnes Chancellor He was not just one of the great athletes of the last century but a superb doct https t co TjH3D5hucI Prof <PERSON>Louise Richardson</PERSON> Vice Chancellor <PERSON>Roger Bannister</PERSON> epitomised what it means to be a living legend He was a https t co kfy3PiVfoI RT guardian_sport Sir <PERSON>Roger Bannister</PERSON> first athlete to run a mile in under four minutes dies aged 88 https t co UMaUDPyIHN By seanin Predicting <PERSON>Donald Trump</PERSON> s presidency via sheep entrails must rank among the most unusual exercises in academic outr https t co seFYo0fJ34 <ORGANIZATION>EDAW</ORGANIZATION> part 2 There are some problems an app can t solve But my research and personal experience suggests why https t co inC8HIL1E8 Why Oxford archaeologists dream of seeing the <ORGANIZATION>Palmyra Arch</ORGANIZATION> rebuilt by Syrians As Islamist militants are driven fin https t co JhQlJlXGX7 New speed record for trapped ion building blocks of quantum computers Researchers have set a new speed record f https t co QFA0UxqlNI Fort Finders Hillfort atlas wins industry recognition at international conference The unique resource provides f https t co VnRoBUFvrd <ORGANIZATION>EDAW</ORGANIZATION> part 1 We read words everyday Some of these words are helping people with eatingdisorders and others ar https t co Ylj3HcTy8o Did you know a trench dug around <LOCATION>Bartlemas Chapel</LOCATION> off the <LOCATION>Cowley Road</LOCATION> unearthed evidence of the earliest 12th cen https t co FUVNwHxsOa RT IndigArtStories Past IA amp amp S winner BillyRayB was recently featured in this great CBCEdmonton piece <PERSON>Billy</PERSON> was the 1st EVER First Natio RT HertfordCollege <LOCATION>Hertford</LOCATION> looks pretty as a picture in the snow from up here snow BeastFromTheEast https t co 0RmK9bLQQx RT britac_news From improving trust to modernising corporate law here are the FutureOfTheCorporation research projects addressing the k New study confirms <LOCATION>Cambodia</LOCATION> s last leopards on brink of extinction new study confirms world s last breeding popul https t co SSpBEuiZy7 RT school_of_arch <PERSON>Margaret</PERSON> is a DPhil grad student School_of_ arch amp amp she likes snow <PERSON>Margaret</PERSON> studies Stone Age glue that s tree sap to lsu oxzoodept <ORGANIZATION>NASA</ORGANIZATION> Northeastern stonybrooku WHOI penguin_watch Video penguin_watch UniofOxford and lsu <PERSON>Tom Hart Mike Polito Antarctic Penguin</PERSON> hotspot discovery fuels need for marine reserve Scientists have discovered a thriving colony of https t co xLIGTLwhug RT LVShaw We re really excited that 3 of UniofOxford s AshmoleanMuseum s incredible artefacts are included in Civilisations virtual RT AshmoleanMuseum <PERSON>Thomas Bodley</PERSON> founder of the BodleianLibs the main UniOfOxford research library was born onthisday in 1545 htt Copthall_School Have a great time <ORGANIZATION>Architha RT</ORGANIZATION> Joey7Barton A clip from ep 5 of my podcast The Edge with UniofOxford Dr <PERSON>Kevin Dutton</PERSON> My summary of the relevance of psychopat RT waverly_sm Surreal but gratifying to see myself in high resolution no less on the UniofOxford Medium page I ve always been fairly JeanBalchin CrAaronHawkins Well done Jean We hope you re looking forward to starting <ORGANIZATION>RT EPSRC Researchers UniofOxford</ORGANIZATION> set a new speed record for the logic gates that form the building blocks of quantum computing https <LOCATION>Amazon</LOCATION> rainforests that were once fire proof have become flammable To figure out just how bad the problem is https t co qjRgazbkUl We have lots of workshops to help you respond to the demands of life at university If you re experiencing low mood https t co 1JDilQrDFg RT OxfordGradStudy What a great opportunity to gaze lovingly at some of the most beautiful libraries UniofOxford on <ORGANIZATION>WorldBookDay</ORGANIZATION> http RT physorg_com New speed record for trapped ion building blocks of quantum computers UniofOxford nature https t co moLtpGocdY Have you signed up for OxfordSparks amp amp OxNeuro Brain Discovery Festival starting 12 March There will be daily <ORGANIZATION>Fac</ORGANIZATION> https t co 686uDOuw7w RT TORCHOxford Happy WorldBookDay Did you know <ORGANIZATION>UniofOxford</ORGANIZATION> has 12 million books in over 100 libraries https t co qPbtC9wrBU https ambersmith1801 OxfordUNIQ evebennettx Well done Amber The UniofOxford <LOCATION>Scotland</LOCATION> tour March 2018 Join us at one of our undergraduate admissions sessions https t co ER897kaV3Q RT UniofOxfordSI Today is <PERSON>UniMentalHealthDay</PERSON> and the theme this year is Community If you want to take part in wellbeing activities t Should home based blood pressure monitoring be commonplace in NHS GPs should encourage patients with hypertension https t co jv0MELRhYQ RT GeorgeInstUK TODAYshow in <LOCATION>US</LOCATION> covers findings of GeorgeInstUK research showing women with bigger waists relative to their hips face a RT CorpusOxfordDev Dydd G yl Dewi Hapus https t co Xuc4KxITHI This year s UniMentalHealthDay theme is community We speak to <PERSON>Gregg Margaret Dan</PERSON> amp amp <LOCATION>Waverly</LOCATION> about their https t co 3cedXargoz Unlocking the world s oldest mystery script The world s oldest undeciphered script may soon be cracked at <ORGANIZATION>Oxford</ORGANIZATION> w https t co JmmhaQUlqL RT ragehomaar Very glad to see that colleges at my alma mater UniofOxford are flying LGBT flag today https t co 9ELUnBB5Tm RT MRC_WIMM Today is <PERSON>RareDiseaseDay</PERSON> and this year s theme is research Throughout the day we will be sharing videos where our researc <ORGANIZATION>Apple</ORGANIZATION> shape more strongly linked to risk of heart attack in women New research has found women with bigger waist https t co CnMrdn8Bed RT OxZooDept OTD in 1915 Sir <PERSON>Peter Medawar</PERSON> was born A student magdalenoxford UniofOxford he graduated with a first class honours in z RT OxfordUNIQ Yr12 Fancy helping to unravel the story of our universe How about analysing Higgs Hunters data with OxfordPhysics at U If you were asked to name a weapon used in WWI you d probably think of gas attacks or artillery or tanks But a https t co wxUbVEZKyi This is tylerpager an MSc Comparative Social Policy student <PERSON>Tyler</PERSON> has won a journalism competition and will trav https t co NO7TupjDUg My rainbowfamily suddenly expanded in the best way possible <PERSON>HannahBoschen</PERSON> part of the <ORGANIZATION>LGBT Advisory Group</ORGANIZATION> https t co CprcrnFRkV RT HertfordCollege It s beginning to look a lot like Christmas again BeastFromTheEast snow SheldonianOxUni bodleianlibs UniofOxfo There are now fewer than 25 000 lions left in the wild But while there is general public appreciation of the conse https t co QEQZ148QuU When the ground shakes on <LOCATION>Earth</LOCATION> we call them earthquakes Earthquakes teach us a lot about the makeup of the planet https t co hwVbaBf9rF RT OxfordStudents Who deserves an award for being the best teacher at <ORGANIZATION>UniofOxford Now</ORGANIZATION> is your time to have your say https t co zLhHQ RT Kathryn_EB Love my new lanyard from <ORGANIZATION>UniofOxford</ORGANIZATION> proud ally <ORGANIZATION>LGBTHM</ORGANIZATION> https t co 0wKt2lnDSG There are few places as rich in visible heritage as Oxford Now museums galleries and historic country houses are https t co xPzZQb9WRm RT magdalenoxford I spoke too soon https t co WqXc2AegvK RT OxfordGradStudy Started but not finished applying for 2018 19 entry Planning to submit Most courses close on 9 March so we strong In 2017 The Oardinary Boys rowed across the <LOCATION>Atlantic Ocean</LOCATION> in aid of ARUKnews and AgainstMalaria Read more abo https t co GbpkV3gxJR Oxford Sustainable Fuels to tackle plastic crisis by recycling waste into fuels https t co vAwBzAOCSH https t co 7t03tW8qNw RT OxfordSparks Volcanoes Listen to this episode of themonkeycage all about volcanoes feat ultraplinian amp amp tamsinmather OxUniEarthS RT oxfordenvsust FairtradeFortnight has started From 26 February to 11 March a range of events amp amp talks will be taking place around Un Proteins assemble Study sheds new light on our biochemical workhorses https t co qouyGB4KTh ScienceBlog https t co Yr9HIuhiUh RT oxford_thinking I don t know where I would be now had it not been for the scholarship The impact has been immeasurable DPhil stu RT Jamie_Green94 I m in this video talking about my experiences as a disabled student <PERSON>UniofOxford</PERSON> managed to get a football referenc RT MissBarkerEng Been geeking out and would recommend this podcast going to use some of the material to help me stretch amp amp challenge my Predicting <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> through sheep entrails Revolutionising museum visits for the blind Unlocking the world s oldest https t co 12c5ciKvxf Interested in joining an apprenticeship scheme Take a look at the UniofOxford apprenticeship opportunities page https t co I783rYDYPE Are you looking for specific places in <LOCATION>UniofOxford</LOCATION> where you can find startup and entrepreneurship support and r https t co nFNEOtosCJ Is <LOCATION>Turkey</LOCATION> really facing an exodus It s not that simple <PERSON>Emre Eren Korkmaz</PERSON> post doctoral researcher in Migration https t co 3Yb0Ypzt8n New research has shown that elephants like many other mammals move on average distances two to three times shorte https t co rNJQdko5UK Oxford compsciox researchers work with <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> to improve secure group messaging A team from the department led https t co XYYCgKyyqO Storing human organs at room temperature organ_ox develops organ preservation technologies invented by Professor https t co jmu1NA6yar An image of a single positively charged strontium atom held near motionless by electric fields has won the prize https t co outFSHu478 Intensive home based and effective treatment of postnatal depression has been shown to be associated with positive https t co CugsSNWCx4 I go out of my way to let people know that being female being transgender being of any minority is not a barri https t co anEkveZoQw Meet the faculty and find out about oiioxford courses with their virtual OxOpenDay https t co jsiUfGCvTK https t co FIVJqTjhhH What did we learn about AI antidepressants echo chambers and the <LOCATION>Paris</LOCATION> climate agreement from <ORGANIZATION>UniofOxford</ORGANIZATION> https t co 7qqQxd5BrD The <ORGANIZATION>UniofOxford</ORGANIZATION> will showcase its artificial intelligence AI research with a one day expo on 27 March 2018 https t co <ORGANIZATION>AssNZrY1ke RT OxfordSparks Facebook LIVE Twitter Takeovers</ORGANIZATION> interactive games amp amp more All part of our Brain Discovery Festival 12 16 March Sign u Why does it take so long to see a GP Dr <PERSON>Kamal R Mahtani</PERSON> an <LOCATION>Oxfordshire</LOCATION> based GP and deputy director of https t co Lel4vKCqBH Companies advertise that they can find you love through the power of scent but are pheromones a chemical way to fi https t co XBTHEofj1I RT ChCh_Oxford We re excited to launch our new Horizons academic enrichment programme today in Barnet Run by ChCh_Access it ll support <ORGANIZATION>Health Data Research UK</ORGANIZATION> is awarding 30 million funding to six sites across the <LOCATION>UK</LOCATION> including the <ORGANIZATION>University of Oxf</ORGANIZATION> https t co vbFkPeI5iZ Groundbreaking study comparing 21 commonly used antidepressants concludes that all are more effective than placebo https t co uqQJeyv3XW RT oxfordalumni There will be events happening around <LOCATION>Oxford</LOCATION> on 1 March in support of <ORGANIZATION>University Mental Health Day</ORGANIZATION> You can find out more RT edengirlsWF The <ORGANIZATION>Brilliant Club</ORGANIZATION> has arrived at <ORGANIZATION>St John s College Oxford University UniofOxford BrilliantClub</ORGANIZATION> https t co Rdf2cLh6ms A new exhibition about the history of settlers in <LOCATION>Britain</LOCATION> has opened at the <ORGANIZATION>Oxford University Museum of Natural</ORGANIZATION> His https t co Fbq9oo1ypb RT HannahBoschen Thank you asadd for an excellent talk for LGBTHM18 last night UniofOxford presence protest progress I still remem RT HannahBoschen The fabulous Kevin_Coutinho from the utterly brilliant <ORGANIZATION>Equality amp amp Diversity Unit UniofOxford</ORGANIZATION> at last nights LGBTHM RT KelloggOx For InternationalWomensDay join us for a panel discussion about women in the workplace free to all Thursday 8th March 17 Social media and internet not cause of political polarisation <ORGANIZATION>New UniofOxford</ORGANIZATION> research suggests that social medi https t co JNEihiytED The UniofOxford <LOCATION>Scotland</LOCATION> tour March 2018 Join us at one of our undergraduate admissions sessions https t co 1q59pjaraY Primary school intervention developed by <ORGANIZATION>Oxford</ORGANIZATION> researchers to be delivered by <ORGANIZATION>NuffieldFound</ORGANIZATION> and OxUniPress https t co IhhZS1qQe2 We have over 10 000 graduate students from 150 different countries making up almost half of the UniofOxford s stu https t co PHJsfwjHq1 RT Rare_London A change is going to come TargetOxbridge to support 160 talented black candidates in 2018 up from 45 in 2017 supported RT lmhoxford For InternationalWomensDay conference at LMH free to all UniofOxford Sat 3rd March 3 6pm SPEAKERS <PERSON>Brenda Kelly</PERSON> Sne Have you been inspired by your surroundings whilst studying at <ORGANIZATION>Oxford</ORGANIZATION> Are you a keen photographer Then enter the https t co Sl9PZZdFuP RT psychmag Securing survival in populist times <PERSON>John Richer UniofOxford</PERSON> builds on the ideas of JonHaidt to consider the impact of ins The <LOCATION>UniofOxford Northern Ireland</LOCATION> outreach tour programme of outreach activities for Northern Irish students and https t co 1jJ0CDmsuU UniofOxfordSI You can also stay updated by checking the UniofOxfordSI feed CuriousCabbage CuriousCabbage OxfordUCU Hi Harry Please contact academicadmin comms admin ox ac uk for more information ArtisticLicence The new campaign for working class students in <LOCATION>Oxford</LOCATION> https t co MPz4pcsIPw https t co 5cDQOw4gnx CuriousCabbage OxfordUCU Hi Harry Please see the latest UCU industrial action update here https t co R5vVXwr5Gz Holding back the rising tide <PERSON>Luke Jackson</PERSON> from INETOxford speaks to ScienceBlog on how achieving the <LOCATION>Paris</LOCATION> Agre https t co yG7e2HR1Je RT bodleianlibs Free tickets for our upcoming once in a lifetime exhibition <ORGANIZATION>Tolkien Maker of Middle</ORGANIZATION> earth are now available for booki RT UniofOxfordSI Nominations for the Vice Chancellor s Diversity Awards close soon If you know someone who has been involved in an initi RT OasisSilvertown We loved our visit to <PERSON>KebleOutreach UniofOxford</PERSON> with <PERSON>BrilliantClub</PERSON> yesterday A real taste of university life http RT BethLAsbury Celebrating LGBTHM18 AshmoleanMuseum UniofOxford with this 13th century figure of the bodhisattva <PERSON>Guanyin</PERSON> written about <PERSON>Jim Naismith</PERSON> Professor at <ORGANIZATION>Jesus College</ORGANIZATION> will be discussing the life and work of <PERSON>Rosalind Franklin</PERSON> this Thursday a https t co eD0dTBMsnl RT OxfordTemps Feeling the love at <ORGANIZATION>TSS</ORGANIZATION> FlyingTheFlag LGBTHistoryMonth https t co qGlQXTK7Th The <ORGANIZATION>UniofOxford</ORGANIZATION> will showcase its artificial intelligence AI research with a one day expo on 27 March 2018 https t co 7m1iDADSCU RT Addeys300 Our very own Miss <PERSON>Williams</PERSON> explaining the UniofOxford application process at our oxfordblackalum event yesterday inspired Scientists shed light on <LOCATION>Burgess Shale</LOCATION> preservation for first time https t co <ORGANIZATION>Wg4udXeDiF Image Yale</ORGANIZATION> https t co RwPBhXXSZm RT magdalenoxford Not long to wait Spring is almost here springflowers https t co X6BwafWxTW Are you an early stage startup The oxfoundry has a new accelerator LEV8 Officially OPEN for applications until https t co BM96M6CWsx RT AshmoleanMuseum Here is another print from our <LOCATION>Oxford</LOCATION> series this week Do you recognise the location depicted here by <ORGANIZATION>Thomas Rowland RT</ORGANIZATION> Rare_London BIG NEWS TargetOxbridge has more than trebled the no of black students we can support thanks to increase in Uniof Success and expansion for <ORGANIZATION>TargetOxbridge Programme</ORGANIZATION> to support talented black applicants expands with support from https t co 58cDeoRRFs RT oxford_thinking Say hello to <PERSON>Claire</PERSON> Thanks to support from the <ORGANIZATION>Swarovski Foundation</ORGANIZATION> she will soon join OxfordGeography s growing i RT NIHRCRN_tvsm People in <LOCATION>Buckinghamshire</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Oxfordshire</LOCATION> over 50 invited by <ORGANIZATION>NHS</ORGANIZATION> to join a pioneering UniofOxford study OxfordHealthNHS RT pewtrusts The world s aging populations Burden or boon UniofOxford s profsarahharper breaks down the facts in PewTrend https t RT ftlive FT chief economics commentator <PERSON>Martin Wolf</PERSON> chats to Sir <PERSON>John Vickers</PERSON> of UniofOxford at the FTGlobalBanking Conference discus Whether it s the way we speak or the sports team we support the little differences between us can carry clues to https t co eQQmSNr7jP <LOCATION>Kakau</LOCATION> and Batok Talk Tattoos from <LOCATION>Hawaii</LOCATION> and the <LOCATION>Philippines</LOCATION> Discover more with anthropologist <PERSON>Analyn Salvador</PERSON> Am https t co pKLt5RBIEP Don t forget that it is OxOpenDay every day with oiioxford s virtual open days https t co LzacIp4lsx https t co CFPAtrufQd Could Counterfactuals Explain Algorithmic Decisions Without Opening the Black Box Head over to the oiioxford site https t co 8W8egq3NHg <ORGANIZATION>Oxford University s OxfordPlants</ORGANIZATION> has announced a partnership with the powcharities that will support the work of https t co w0otMMg21v Should Politics be taught within secondary school <PERSON>Elena Jones</PERSON> discusses on the OUPAcademic blog https t co hkGJ2MtWT4 Reflected and refracted light creates the many bright and shining colours found in some insects Read more on the https t co FSJIDRA1G6 Neuroscientists put the dubious theory of phrenology through rigorous testing for the first time <PERSON>Harriet Dempsey</PERSON> https t co icqyfxD4Wq BrazilWeek2018 <ORGANIZATION>UniofOxford s Brazil Week</ORGANIZATION> aims to raise awareness about the richness and diversity of Brazilian https t co pUra4i2d02 Studying the formation and evolution of galaxies is one of the largest research areas in <LOCATION>Oxford</LOCATION> and The Global Je https t co qyW5dyOiKU <ORGANIZATION>St Hilda</ORGANIZATION> of Whitby A Cantata Celebrating the 125th Anniversary of <ORGANIZATION>St Hilda</ORGANIZATION> s College Sunday 18 February https t co hrnKiBGiIH Following the recent lion poisoning in <LOCATION>Ruaha Tanzania</LOCATION> WildCRU_Ox ruahacarnivores discuss working with communiti https t co qTLTt2QGQy RT OxfordMedSci Have you put in your application for The oxfoundry accelerator LEV8 Available for an early stage venture or start up w Fossil image <LOCATION>Waptia</LOCATION> fossil <ORGANIZATION>Yale RT</ORGANIZATION> AshmoleanMuseum Happy ChineseNewYear Chinese New Year also known as the Spring Festival is a celebration that takes place at the t What have we learned from <ORGANIZATION>UniofOxford</ORGANIZATION> research about rabbits dementia risk ancient life on earth and income re https t co SeuXs6CbCN RT TargetOxbridge It s great to be working even more closely with UniofOxford and Cambridge_Uni and we can t wait to meet our new coho <PERSON>Don</PERSON> t miss Imagining the Divine Arts and the Rise of World Religions closing February 18 AshmoleanMuseum https t co Y4WBtdIaN0 Do you see a tiny dot The dot is a single strontium atom held near motionless by electric fields <PERSON>David Nadlinger</PERSON> https t co 8J8OdaAlPm The history of domestication a rabbit s tale Wild rabbits are thought to have been first tamed in 600 A D by Fre https t co vtwq9rPXkF RT greentempleton <ORGANIZATION>Green Templeton College</ORGANIZATION> is proud to support the LGBT community LGBTHistoryMonth GreenTempleton https t co bzWQnC RT PembrokeOxford There is some science behind that gut feeling Amazing stuff from <LOCATION>Pembroke</LOCATION> DPhil student <PERSON>Katerina</PERSON> on OxfordSpark Kelp our corals Many people know about the importance of conserving coral reefs to protect marine biodiversity bu https t co xEzF718omv RT OrstedUK We ve signed 5 year partnership with UniofOxford to optimise wind turbine foundations part of our commitment to reduce cos Have fun with the family this half term and get mindgrowing There s lots to do and see for free in Oxford Univers https t co YnICuWae7L RT CommanderMLA A different pale blue dot UniofOxford PhD candidate <PERSON>David Nadlinger</PERSON> took this pic of a SINGLE ATOM whaaat https RT ndorms Congratulations to UniofOxford ndorms professors that have been shortlisted by CR_UK for a 20M CRUKGrandChallenge award h RT TheBHF Thanks to <ORGANIZATION>BHF</ORGANIZATION> funding scientists UniofOxford are aiming to determine the long term effects of diet and exercise programmes on ArtisticLicence The new campaign for working class students in <LOCATION>Oxford</LOCATION> https t co F09BQrII9F bethanyawhite https t co 4iYJvkb2t6 The history of domestication a rabbit s tale https t co SJWNN2juWs https t co VkdNyt7Axc What does it mean to be LGBT today <PERSON>Don</PERSON> t miss the this year s annual lecture organised by the LGBT Staff Netwo https t co AUMIaqs4gd <PERSON>Don</PERSON> t wait to be asked don t count on others play the long game actively own your career and develop a unique https t co o4hL8ndNqR Did you know that Common Puffins go by the scientific name Fratercula arctica meaning the little friar of the nor https t co bmq7x95ovA The revolution in dating is not dating apps but our hugely extended lifespan and the possibility of a post menopa https t co 2C2pNnRhQM Have fun with the family this half term and get mindgrowing There s lots to do and see for free in Oxford Univers https t co 4LYo8uplYA The topsy turvy world of air quality Amid a furious debate about air quality <PERSON>Nick Molden</PERSON> has buckled up his belt https t co fkdriUBQOy RT AshmoleanMuseum Looking for family friendly activities this half term break Join us for a ChineseNewYear party this Wed or Thu from The latest update of the Global Multidimensional Poverty Index has revealed new insights into poverty worldwide https t co Dso3Xg3xo6 Find out how to help ellieexpedition amp amp their elephant conservation citizen science project here https t co JHjHcQVJcP The oxfoundry has a new accelerator LEV8 Officially OPEN for applications from early stage startups with a https t co 4BVTrMYHGU What in the Word The mawkish misnomer of maudlin https t co UD8mh3NjfH OxfordWords https t co N6S0upCz1i RT AshmoleanMuseum We ll be tracing <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> from the Roaring Twenties through to the end of the Great Depression at our next late night The Philippines War on Drugs https t co VJzgSsm0RW OxHRH https t co 38r6gRqlYd What if the whole world used the same writing system Should we all write in Chinese Join UniofOxford academics B https t co qJPCCRWzqu Yaas and Drag improv and play <PERSON>Edward Scrivens</PERSON> DPhil student in Egyptology examines how his own experiences https t co x3BM3ry4g3 Analysing the ways in which our urban environment affect our wellbeing Dr <PERSON>Andreza Aruska de Souza Santos</PERSON> reflects https t co 4WH4MVLMY9 <ORGANIZATION>MRC</ORGANIZATION> podcast Professor of Child and Adolescent Psychiatry <PERSON>Alan Stein</PERSON> talks about how his research is helping HIV po https t co 5xEvZ48GE6 Study of <LOCATION>Trinidad</LOCATION> s <LOCATION>Pitch Lake</LOCATION> artefacts identifies earliest wood carvings from the <LOCATION>Caribbean</LOCATION> https t co Ql3AKOj1RZ My message to young girls is that science is for everyone including you Why do we need WomenAndGirlsInScience https t co Ev9IluyYh4 We hear a lot about the migrant amp amp refugee crisis The topic has become a source of polarising views fear amp amp tensi https t co rwbbUwHE6G Blockchains for Governmental Services Design Principles Applications and Case Studies Read more on the https t co zHNIe4olie I didn t know that I was an entrepreneur Heck I couldn t even spell the word entrepreneur consistently until abo https t co ppbkF0Yujr NaturalMotion is the most successful company ever to emerge from the OxZooDept and a prime example of how pure https t co SDKwGu0Prm This term first generation students at the UniofOxford have been taking photos to raise awareness of https t co QrEi7EAR9b Gauge theory where particle physics and mathematics meet UniofOxford Mathematician Dr <PERSON>Yuuji Tanaka</PERSON> describes hi https t co xDebkb5fsX What do plastic fakenews optimism and crash diets all have in common They are components of things we learned https t co gcBkYzObMT Modern meets medieval Intriguing entries to medieval book design competition go on display at bodleianlibs <LOCATION>Weston</LOCATION> https t co MtKA1FykwY The <ORGANIZATION>UniofOxford</ORGANIZATION> will showcase its artificial intelligence AI research with a one day expo on 27 March 2018 https t co Fr4bpOKjE4 RT BrasenoseNews Thanks for coming today Rokeby_School we enjoyed your enthusiasm and excellent questions Thanks too for the moderate Acid drainage the global environmental crisis you ve never heard of <PERSON>Stephen Tuffnell</PERSON> Associate Professor of Mode https t co ZjU21TXw4L RT ClaraMBarker Wow a shout out from the royalsociety Thank you The amazing support of OxfordMaterials mplsoxford amp amp UniofOxford all On the day of Vote100 <ORGANIZATION>PrincipalStAns Helen King</ORGANIZATION> unveiled a plaque in <LOCATION>Cirencester</LOCATION> which remembers Grace Hadow https t co RlLqvfmhBk RT OxfordSparks NEW ANIMATION Did you know the DNA of any two people on the planet is around 99 9 per cent identical A recent study b <ORGANIZATION>Health Data Research UK</ORGANIZATION> is awarding 30 million funding to six sites across the <LOCATION>UK</LOCATION> including the <ORGANIZATION>University of Oxf</ORGANIZATION> https t co q74qyUjINz ArtisticLicence I was here in Ancient <LOCATION>Egypt</LOCATION> Names dates bad jokes life advice this is graffiti but not as https t co fXkMiZhUCq LIVE <PERSON>Michael Bonsall</PERSON> now speaking on Scaling the Maths of Life <PERSON>Michael</PERSON> is discussing how we can use maths to li https t co mJfRgNVvM4 RT AbiSKINS I ve started a new study at OxPrimaryCare UniofOxford interviewing research nurses research midwives amp amp research allied hea RT oxfordenvsust The <ORGANIZATION>University of Oxford</ORGANIZATION> is CIBSE s 2018 Building Performance Champion Thank you to everyone involved in the 200 proj The oxfoundry has a new accelerator LEV8 Officially OPEN for applications from early stage startups with a https t co pLeddOExIj RT BentFlyvbjerg Only 3 days until the Winter Olympics in <LOCATION>Korea</LOCATION> For a study of cost and cost overrun of the big party see the Oxford Tonight Join us on the <ORGANIZATION>UniofOxford Facebook</ORGANIZATION> page to see <PERSON>Michael Bonsall</PERSON> speaking LIVE from the <ORGANIZATION>Maths Institute</ORGANIZATION> at https t co xHGCeXlvmT If world health chiefs don t listen we ll see a new pandemic warns top UniofOxford malaria expert Read more abo https t co qmEKw3PiIZ RT b_anandana Great opportunity for early stage start ups oxfoundry is open to UniofOxford students and alumni within 10 years of grad A network of <PERSON>Donald Trump</PERSON> supporters shares the widest range of junk news on Twitter and a network of extreme fa https t co UPHDei3KHR The turinginst and UniofOxford are launching a new collaboration bringing together the fields of psychiatry and https t co 0vm3bICcXq RT davidmpyle Set your radios and phones Next week tamsinmather and ultraplinian are talking to iamjobrand profbriancox and robini Live Are you sharing too much on social media Head to our Facebook page now to see jasonnurse talking to https t co hzS2MN7OVG RT ChCh_Oxford We ve raised the Votes for Women flag in <LOCATION>Peckwater Quad</LOCATION> to mark 100 years since the Representation of the People Act when Oxford Sustainable Fuels to tackle plastic crisis by recycling waste into fuels OxUInnovation is launching new https t co ID1k1BG113 RT OxMusicFaculty Today our votesforwomen flag is flying over the Faculty Suffrage100 Suffragette100 TORCHOxford UniofOxford https RT OxZooDept Congratulations to macdonalddw of WildCRU_Ox UniofOxford named as a finalist for lifetime achievement Award for <ORGANIZATION>Conservat RT</ORGANIZATION> SPC_Alumni Celebrating 100years of Suffrage St Peter s is flying the flag as we remember those who fought to give women the right to How can you stay safe online What shouldn t you share on social media Head to our Facebook page today at 3 30pm t https t co g53SdE6mI2 RT ndorms Its LGBTHistoryMonth and ndorms is excited to be involved in this celebration of LGBT communities proud achievements amp amp cultur RT pnhoward gorgeous dataviz from <ORGANIZATION>FinancialTimes</ORGANIZATION> about our latest research Far right and <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> supporters the biggest and most isol The <ORGANIZATION>EU Ethics Advisory Board</ORGANIZATION> has just released a new report on digital ethics co authored by oiioxford s Prof <PERSON>Luc</PERSON> https t co FwoVa3QgVp RT wadhamoxford Marking 100 years since some women were granted the right to vote we re proudly flying the suffrage colours https RT wadhamoxford Preparing to raise the Votes for Women flag over <ORGANIZATION>Wadham College Oxford</ORGANIZATION> this morning Suffrage100 UniofOxford TORCHOxfor Celebrating 100 years of Suffrage Today flags are flying all over <ORGANIZATION>Oxford</ORGANIZATION> as we celebrate 100 years since some wom https t co Q3eMsmPo8g Viewing ourselves and others through rose tinted glasses Humans can be vicariously optimistic for those we car https t co g7QpYP9vby What is musclememory Does it involve changes in to brain structure What is happening in the brain when we learn https t co vLItF6eXTl RT keitoxford Waste plastic could be turned into fuel by <ORGANIZATION>UniofOxford</ORGANIZATION> spinout thetimes https t co Ocxc0QcFWQ <ORGANIZATION>StartedinOxford RT</ORGANIZATION> GivernyMcAndry Very excited to be taking the first steps to bring the work of singinginside from our homes in <LOCATION>London</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Cambridge</LOCATION> to My journey leading up to OxfordSBS has always been guided by one principle to put the impact of the work I m doi https t co YAmSdVH74H RT AtmosScience Important steps have been made to improve weather forecasts since winds high up in the atmosphere can now be predicted How can you stay safe online What shouldn t you share on social media Head to our Facebook page tomorrow at 3 30p https t co JIRPES2gMn RT Guinnessisgd4u With the help of a lot of blu tac <ORGANIZATION>Radcliffe Humanities</ORGANIZATION> has its LGBT flags up for LGBTHistoryMonth in our front windo The UniofOxford will showcase its artificial intelligence AI research with a one day expo on 27 March 2018 https t co Iad7n5bEqu How is your lifestyle affecting your brain <ORGANIZATION>Oxford</ORGANIZATION> s neuroscientists answer some questions from The Big Brain Compe https t co UGupdRkFj6 My interest in stories poetry drama and art helps me to think about problems in new ways I always wanted to do https t co PiqkfHc07E Don t miss Imagining the Divine Arts and the Rise of World Religions open until February 18 AshmoleanMuseum https t co 8O5OpUoeeH Did you know more than 200 people are recruited into cancer studies every day Beating cancer is all about https t co oyLSCPuiuh Scaling the Maths of Life watch <PERSON>Michael Bonsall</PERSON> discussing how we can use maths to link between scales of organisa https t co MsLX3xoY0a You can join the <ORGANIZATION>Oxford BioBank</ORGANIZATION> and support research into conditions such as diabetes heart disease and obesity V https t co TVPXj0ORRN Bookings are now open for the 2018 <ORGANIZATION>UniofOxford</ORGANIZATION> amp amp Cambridge_Uni Student Conferences Read more about the eight fre https t co t7HBRkTrhX Don t miss TheIrisProject Festival of Imagined Worlds 9 February 2018 at Cheney_School The event will celebrat https t co QrLG3xH16T PostnatalDepression which is persistent whether moderate or severe increases mothers risk of continuing to expe https t co Wa7104ktRY VR use in psychological therapies the effects of having a mother in prison benefits of emerging tech and links https t co NsK1jxAt6o What do we know about the effects of mindfulness meditation and yoga on the brain Neuroscientists at https t co UbPDQH2lLV RT jasonnurse Use wearables smart watches fitness trackers etc Be mindful of the security amp amp privacy risks accompanying them and Reburying <LOCATION>Britain</LOCATION> s most notorious king music liturgy and practicalities Dr <PERSON>BuckleAlexandra</PERSON> and Professor <PERSON>Mar</PERSON> https t co Oz1hO8z0Ew Parenting programme brings joy to <LOCATION>Africa</LOCATION> s poorest communities New research has revealed that a widely used ado https t co U2itRcggoU RT OfficialNIHR Congratulations to <PERSON>ProfDFreeman</PERSON> and his team 2017 <ORGANIZATION>NIHR</ORGANIZATION> i4i Challenge Award winners We re delighted to support such a Do you speak Latin You probably do If you ve ever used a memo or got a train via <LOCATION>London</LOCATION> or watched <ORGANIZATION>Arsenal</ORGANIZATION> vers https t co 5bFi7Gwshn RT idalinabaptista KelloggOx joins UniofOxford celebration of LGBTHistoryMonth LGBTQ by flying flag w awesome cake by Chef <PERSON>John RT</PERSON> suttontrust Applications for our teacher summer schools at <ORGANIZATION>Oxford University</ORGANIZATION> are now open If you are a humanities or STEM teacher at <ORGANIZATION>RT CorpusOxfordDev Corpus OrielOxford</ORGANIZATION> and BNC_Members amongst the UniofOxford colleges celebrating LGBT History Month this morning h RT OxfordLawFac Proving academic research can impact court decisions Prof <PERSON>Dapo Akande</PERSON> and Judge <PERSON>Malcolm Wallis</PERSON> discuss the importance o DPhil student <PERSON>Paola Castaneda</PERSON> TSUOxford talks about her research exploring bicycle activism or biketivism https t co Z49HwpR9Gq <ORGANIZATION>NHS</ORGANIZATION> mental health services to offer virtual reality treatment OfficialNIHR awarded 4 million to enable state of https t co BZS6JLcE20 RT UniofOxfordSI TimeToTalk day is about reminding people that there is nothing wrong with talking about mental health If you ever need What does it mean to be LGBTQ today The 20 February LGBTHM Annual Lecture with asadd <PERSON>Asad Dhunna</PERSON> has written https t co 6b14PgemFP Professor <PERSON>Marina Jirotka CompSciOxford</PERSON> was one of the contributors to a major report by academics that is callin https t co i6SMgqELLu RT HertfordCollege The <LOCATION>Clarendon Building</LOCATION> is looking a little moody from the <ORGANIZATION>Development Office</ORGANIZATION> https t co rQRMkdq4Z9 RT GeorgeInstUK Could you be a SoapboxScience speaker inspiring more WomenInSTEM For the 3rd year running this Oxford event will giv RT SPC_Alumni Our LGTBTQ Welfare Officer <PERSON>Hamish</PERSON> is super excited about the glorious bunting SPC are displaying for the whole of <ORGANIZATION>Februar RT</ORGANIZATION> THEUniAdvice Best universities for medicine 2018 https t co 9LWYEKIB9t UniofOxford Cambridge_Uni <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> imperialcollege <ORGANIZATION>Stanfo Global</ORGANIZATION> information analytics business ElsevierConnect is donating 1 million to oxunimaths in support of fellows https t co TXugHzzFjb Fens aren t just muddy mosquito ridden wetlands they are miraculous historical archives going back tens of thousa https t co 1DerwOIKmI RT yloxford Learning for our Millennium Read our guest blog for OurWorldInData exploring changing face of education access quality amp amp Ringing in the changes by pulling out all the stops to turn over a new leaf Or passing the buck leaving someone in https t co puOi6ZyEQw The sudden death of over 200 000 saiga antelopes in <LOCATION>Kazakhstan</LOCATION> affecting more than 80 of the local population and https t co VFnGsSMYeJ Safeguarding children when sentencing mothers <ORGANIZATION>UniofOxford</ORGANIZATION> has collaborated with the PRTuk to create new resource https t co i3nk68Jg3o We offer apprenticeships in arts humanities medical amp amp plant sciences HR IT social amp amp digital media amp amp more https t co mXFkEXXwwK RT letsoxplore We ll be live this time next week from UniofOxford to classrooms right across the country <ORGANIZATION>Oxford</ORGANIZATION> specialists will be c RT jesus_access Check out this amazing and free event coming up at <ORGANIZATION>UniofOxford s Jesus College</ORGANIZATION> organised by spectrawomen to empower yo RT Saddy_94 Last day to apply Honestly I cannot stress enough apply for UNIQ It allows you to experience <ORGANIZATION>Oxford</ORGANIZATION> for a week to see if Should flu be treated with antiviral drugs in primary care Prof Butler OxPrimaryCare amp amp CwmTaf is lead investig https t co Ltls1zRQ9v RT oxsocsci Tune in at 10am on BBCWomansHour this morning to hear ShonaMinson OxfordLawFac talk about her ESRC <ORGANIZATION>IAA</ORGANIZATION> funded work <ORGANIZATION>Shon RT</ORGANIZATION> OxfordSparks New research UniofOxford reveals how disordered materials substances with amorphous or glassy structures as opposed The application deadline for OxfordUNIQ is tomorrow There are 875 places available for one week in July or August https t co tVeOyURyUV The Facts Facing the <LOCATION>UK</LOCATION> s Future A Colloquium at QueensCollegeOx https t co UjhBNCQ2Km https t co jejBg1X1Ld RT MBDiversityLead Our Founder amp amp CEO spoke at UniofOxford StJohnsOx OxfordACS Women s Careers Networking Dinner on Friday sharing less RT OxfordSBS Distinguished Speaker Seminar <PERSON>Mark Wilson</PERSON> Group CEO of avivaplc will reflect on what he calls being a good ancestor and Ethics in ehealth let s talk about equity UniofOxford MSc Graduate vasilis_nittas writes for HIMSSInsights th https t co 8LdmEkhkN7 RT NIHRCRN_tvsm Researchers at OUHospitals have recruited the world s first patient for a gene therapy trial for Haemophilia B Read mo RT enterprisingox Meet this week s Oxford Entrepreneur Uncovered <PERSON>Liz Eden</PERSON> from openbenches https t co 9i40749dyJ summerbeth https RT tamsinmather My thoughts about Living with Volcanic gases amp amp UNRESPproject on the UniofOxford Science blog https t co 1A8yS1rqWe O FakeNews was the <PERSON>Collins</PERSON> dictionary phrase of the year in 2017 but as rasmus_kleis Director of Research for https t co UzdfnvjAl3 RT BBCPhilharmonic Pianist <PERSON>Zoe</PERSON> who has been blind since birth has been offered a place to study music at UniofOxford https t co <ORGANIZATION>Nibv RT GPGautamPatel Great</ORGANIZATION> work suttontrust twenty years ago I participated in one of the first <ORGANIZATION>Sutton Trust Summer Schools</ORGANIZATION> and for the f I have a job that pays well and I m happy in it It s just proof of the longevity of apprenticeships Miranda Re https t co nwYdhmLBcr How the Victorians help explain our obsession with the microbiome DrETaylorBrown Postdoctoral Research Fellow https t co FKlTnf2b7G Redefining how we classify disease The <ORGANIZATION>Kennedy Institute of Rheumatology</ORGANIZATION> is a world leading medical research cent https t co D76HeTa1sO Dr <PERSON>Andrew Gosler</PERSON> oxford_anthro discusses the inspiration he receives from working so closely with nature in thi https t co 6L4odRtl0G OxVlog has returned The project is back with new Oxvloggers sharing new content Join <PERSON>Gayatri Tucker Jessica</PERSON> Na https t co CkBa0ot0Pi Thermo fluids Researcher drpriaero and <PERSON>Gladys Ngetich</PERSON> oxengsci feature in BBCNews piece Why are there so few https t co LpwAJHQDR5 Ever wondered what vegetable consumption per capita looks like Or seen how cereal preferences vary across the worl https t co qbeggDlZzO Many languages spoken globally can trace their history back to just a few sources Now <ORGANIZATION>Oxford</ORGANIZATION> researchers have recr https t co VSvAJeSwXI Daredevils regularly bail out at high altitude to skydive through Earth s atmosphere but what would it be like to s https t co imUwCY9vij Suffragetto The only surviving copy of an Edwardian era board game pitching suffragettes against policemen is to g https t co YqcBN7cBPT Bodies lounging on lush grass or jumping into chilly spring fed ponds soft boiled eggs and ripe fruits bursting w https t co lUR1CAU0Sq RT OxUniEarthSci Brief but brilliant tour for Y10s from Tretherras visiting <ORGANIZATION>UniofOxford</ORGANIZATION> with ExeterCollegeOx ExColOutreach today Com The bus doesn t always arrive on time and your favourite dish is not always on the menu at the local restaurant wh https t co WsRETsoSyy What do Asian elephants battery research Game of Thrones and mobile phones have in common Find out in things we https t co LCdKn7Y2vb RT AshmoleanPress Thanks to dazed for picking AmericasCoolModernism AshmoleanMuseum as an Art exhibition to leave the house for in 201 RT ymalhi A fun visual summary of ERC_Research supported talk on tropical forest tipping points at the IdeasLab at WEF18 https t co j The sudden death of over 200 000 saiga antelopes in <LOCATION>Kazakhstan</LOCATION> which affected more than 80 of the local populatio https t co OaZXCO3Lpn Meet the lmhoxford Foundation Year students The Foundation Year is a one year fully funded course that takes st https t co XuNcZlcGaI Much like animals and to a degree humans bacteria enjoy a good fight They stab shove and poison each other in pu https t co TDfQZwX5w5 Wild Sri Lankan elephants retreat from sound of Asian honey bees For the first time researchers have shown that A https t co j2CsHWmNEz RT oxmartinschool On Tues 30th January Dr <PERSON>Samuel Wasser</PERSON> will describe his use of genetic tools to identify the source of <LOCATION>Africa</LOCATION> s major <LOCATION>Oxford</LOCATION> to have key role in multi million pound energy storage research <ORGANIZATION>Oxford University</ORGANIZATION> is to be a key player in https t co 7Nyd0ElYCJ RT OxfordSBS Learn about the incredible work of Mirakle Couriers the delivery company founded by MBA alumnus <PERSON>Dhruv Lakra</PERSON> that is changin RT morethanadodo Seth 6 is over the moon that the fossil he found in the school playground is part of a 300 million year old brachiopo 6edYFro Cambridge_Uni YGBroMorgannwg <ORGANIZATION>Llongyfarchiadau Global</ORGANIZATION> commission to examine how new tech can benefit poorest BlavatnikSchool and the gatesfoundation have laun https t co onxK9Mcqp8 RT OxfordUNIQ Studying Further Maths A level but not sure what you want to do at <ORGANIZATION>University UniofOxford</ORGANIZATION> is delighted to welcome A leve IzzyCoppx CefnHengoed Let us know if you have any questions about applying or life at the University We ll be very happy to help RT UKSINet Seeing doesn t always need eyes Check out this cool research from <ORGANIZATION>UniofOxford</ORGANIZATION> https t co aF6yAjQa10 His knife see rustic Labour dicht An cut you up wi ready slicht Trenching your gushing entrails bricht Like on https t co O3bkqAV1FD One week left to apply for OxfordUNIQ There are 875 places available for one week in July or August and 100 plac https t co n3v5AunVi2 Got gout Grab an owl This week in ArtisticLicence bethanyawhite speaks to DanielWakelin1 about Revolting Rem https t co WV9hil4kgm <PERSON>Vyacheslav Polonski</PERSON> cofounder of AvantAnalytics who recently completed a DPhil at the oiioxford has featured in https t co pDuunwFLAE RT Saddy_94 If you re on the fence I cannot recommend UNIQ enough It s a fantastic opportunity and a great insight into UniofOxford fo The fast spread of mobile phones across low income countries like <LOCATION>India</LOCATION> can make it harder for poorer people withou https t co w8a8lsCxXJ The latest update of the Global Multidimensional Poverty Index has revealed new insights into poverty worldwide https t co zRvdQHholK ashtonsixthform DCC_News <ORGANIZATION>Congratulations Elleanor RT</ORGANIZATION> _RKapuku Of course if you ve been following me for a while OxfordACS has always been way ahead of the game Black and in year 12 Sh GowerCollegeSwa Cambridge_Uni Well done everyone <ORGANIZATION>RT BBC</ORGANIZATION> The year 2045 could be the year in which machines will be able to do everything that humans can according to a UniofOxford profe RT oxqueerstudies Two fab LGBTQ history month events happening UniofOxford on 2nd of Feb <ORGANIZATION>LGBTQ National Trust Workshop</ORGANIZATION> AND history wo IzzyCoppx CefnHengoed We are so glad you had a good time Izzy Spinout company AnimalDynamic is applying insights to create systems capable of performance beyond anything curren https t co elrzrmWPYh Suffragetto The only surviving copy of an Edwardian era board game pitching suffragettes against policemen is to g https t co VD5PK0FpS6 Environmentally Displaced People Emeritus Professor <PERSON>Roger Zetter</PERSON> former Director of the refugeestudies Centre o https t co nxYeTbL1nB RT physicsonpointe Thrilled to be on Forbes artandculture 30 under 30 list Thank you Forbesunder30 https t co PQL4da3FET forb The <ORGANIZATION>WHO</ORGANIZATION> estimates that 1 6 million people in the developing world die each year from smoke inhalation due to cooki https t co XPQFNsfBII European Cities Could Avoid up to 10 000 Premature Deaths by Expanding Cycling Networks Read more about the new https t co ufOI8GgDkS Sa d <ORGANIZATION>Business School</ORGANIZATION> alumni <PERSON>Scott Gorman</PERSON> and <PERSON>Christopher Larson</PERSON> are crowdfunding for a new documentary titled <ORGANIZATION>Mobil</ORGANIZATION> https t co EL982okSCV Smart sensor could revolutionise crime and terrorism prevention UniofOxford engineers have used material compound https t co wLM8eg8b5D RT OxReach Great to see WW1Centenary s DigitisationDays being shared by Daily_Express https t co Hef0Xfu9oB Will you help organise a At least 6 billion broiler chickens are produced in <LOCATION>Europe</LOCATION> every year including over 800 million in the <LOCATION>UK</LOCATION> and th https t co r2SfPVAhjA VoxPop new Classics podcast series bridging the gap between Classics and daily life What does the myth of <PERSON>Narcis</PERSON> https t co zUnvJnAVon Decisions require a good forecast and AI agents are almost always better at forecasting than their human counter https t co mZZqeRG6Rw OxVlog has returned The project is back with new Oxvloggers sharing new content Join <PERSON>Gayatri Tucker Jessica</PERSON> Na https t co l2HrKuaaqe Outreach activities in <LOCATION>Scotland</LOCATION> we conduct a programme of outreach activities for Scottish students and teachers https t co yStVDzzc2h Why do we think of <PERSON>Jesus</PERSON> with a beard Or <PERSON>Buddha</PERSON> as cross legged Read more about reflections on Imagining the Div https t co njJeFiRwvo The tall and the short of it 