<ner>image Page Header Open Journal Systems Journal Help User Username Password Remember me Journal Content Search Search Scope All Authors Title Abstract Index terms Full Text Browse By Issue By Author By Title Other Journals Font Size Current Issue image Atom logo image RSS2 logo image RSS1 logo Article Tools image Abstract image Print this article image Indexing metadata image How to cite item image Email this article Login required image Email the author Login required About The Authors Nic DePaula Ph D candidate in the <ORGANIZATION>Department of Information Science</ORGANIZATION> and lecturer in the <ORGANIZATION>Departments of Information Technology Management and Information Science</ORGANIZATION> at the <ORGANIZATION>University at Albany State University of New York Ersin Dincelli Ph D</ORGANIZATION> candidate in the <ORGANIZATION>Department of Information Science</ORGANIZATION> and an adjunct professor in the <ORGANIZATION>Departments of Information Technology Management and Information Science</ORGANIZATION> at the <ORGANIZATION>University at Albany the State University of New York Home About Login</ORGANIZATION> Register Search Current Archives Announcements SUBMISSIONS Home gt Volume 23 Number 4 2 April 2018 gt DePaula image First Monday image Information strategies and affective reactions How citizens interact with government social media content by <PERSON>Nic DePaula</PERSON> and <PERSON>Ersin Dincelli</PERSON> image Abstract As social media use grows among the general population becoming a major source of information government organizations around the world have widely adopted these platforms While researchers on government social media have acknowledged the potential functions of these technologies for participatory democracy transparency and collaboration we have come to learn that prominent social media sites are also sites for marketing and favorable presentations Given the diversity of content that may flow through a government social media channel what kind of content is actually adopted Moreover how do users react to these diverse content types In this empirical study we collected <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> posts of local government departments across the <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> and categorized each post content using a framework of government social media communication strategies We then analysed differences in users reactions in the form of likes comments and shares to distinct types of content We found a number of statistically significant results providing some evidence for the effects of communication strategy or content type on measures of user interaction Our results highlight the affective and symbolic nature of social media but also point to higher levels of interaction to instances where governments themselves engage in dialogue with citizens We believe these results are important for scholars and proponents of government communication as they complicate the notion that social network sites can be a generative source of rational critical thought and deliberative conversations Contents Introduction Government communication and information strategies User interaction with social media content Methodology Empirical results Discussion The affective bias Conclusions and future work bookmark p1 Introduction As social media use grows among the general population becoming major sources of information for youth and adult alike <PERSON>Greenwood</PERSON> et al 2016 government organizations around the world are widely adopting the platforms from local government departments in <LOCATION>Albuquerque New Mexico</LOCATION> to the bureaucratic departments of the <ORGANIZATION>European Union Commission Unlike</ORGANIZATION> individual agents that adopt the platforms to browse content and interact with posts as they see fit however governments serve more as information disseminators and of course are highly regulated bodies with their approach to the media quickly becoming delineated via policy guidelines and strategies <PERSON>Klang</PERSON> and Nolin 2011 <PERSON>Meijer</PERSON> and Thaens 2013 <PERSON>Mergel</PERSON> 2016 Earlier work on government adoption of social media conceived of these tools as transparency and anti corruption tools Bertot et al 2010 that could be used for participatory citizen coproduction and mass collaboration Linders 2012 Mossberger et al 2013 U S president <PERSON>Barack Obama</PERSON> in his first days in office developed an open government memorandum which instructed all federal agencies to become more transparent participatory and collaborative with citizens <PERSON>Obama</PERSON> 2009 Given the emergent popularity of social media then they naturally became tools through which transparency participation and collaboration goals could be accomplished Nevertheless the most common reason cited for actually adopting the tools at least in one study of the U S federal government was simply fulfilling the top down mandate rather than any particular organizational need or citizen demand <PERSON>Mergel</PERSON> 2013b Moreover as problems with social media now abound e g misinformation echo chambers algorithmic control their potential for collaborative partnerships need to be understood within the logic or tendencies that characterize their actual adoption e g Dijck 2013 Fuchs 2017 Although many a platform may be called social media and our theorization is geared toward understanding social network sites and digital Internet technologies more generally in this paper our original empirical analysis is based on <ORGANIZATION>Facebook Facebook</ORGANIZATION> is the largest social network site in the world and it is where most government agencies and departments locate their particular pages or channels Other channels such as <ORGANIZATION>Instagram</ORGANIZATION> and Snapchat are becoming more popular and prominent in government in the <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> Stone 2015 Nevertheless the literature has not given much attention to the multifaceted nature of government communication in any of these platforms or questioned the paradoxes of their uses Although previous research has found that <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> users are more interested in fun and private issues rather than serious government information bookmark 1a 1 this has not been noted as a problem for e government theory There are benefits to technology innovation that are generally supported in the literature <PERSON>Sandoval Almazan</PERSON> et al 2018 and many purposes can be overwhelmingly considered productive such as in emergency and crisis management situations <PERSON>Kavanaugh</PERSON> et al 2012 <PERSON>Hagen</PERSON> et al 2017 However the problem is not that e government promises of an increase in interaction participation and collaboration are more rhetorical than reality <PERSON>Sandoval Almazan</PERSON> and <PERSON>Gil Garcia</PERSON> 2012 but that popular social media technologies are systematically driven for emotional responses not for deliberated or rationalized discussions and interactions Our research questions are thus the following What types of content do governments post on social media Moreover how do users react to different types of content For the empirical component of this study we first used a typology of government social media communication to categorize the distinct types of content that governments may adopt on <ORGANIZATION>Facebook We</ORGANIZATION> retrieved 1 421 posts from various local governmental <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> pages across the U S and coded the distribution of content across selected government department pages We also developed a set of conservative hypotheses of how users are likely to interact with distinct types of content and carried out statistical tests to help us answer whether or not particular types of content had significant effects on how much users like share or comment on a respective piece of information We conclude the paper with a discussion on the nature of social media interaction in a governmental context In light of contemporary literature on the affective nature of social media and the affective nature of politics more broadly as well as the empirical results of our analysis we find that counts of <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> reactions are biased toward affective and symbolic content thus potentially not suitable for measuring open government and democratic values such as transparency deliberation and rational engagement However users do respond positively to instances where governments use the platform for online dialogue which seems positive for proponents of citizen government engagement However in this research we did not examine content of government citizen dialogue simply the instances where some exchange existed To understand the extent to which social media can be successful for the political process including government bureaucratic activity and the quality of citizen participation requires a deeper investigation into communicated content and meaning of sharing and liking behavior While we do not address all of the intricacies of this phenomena this research develops empirical and theoretical understanding of the tendencies that drive social media behavior inside and outside a governmental context image bookmark p2 Government communication and information strategies Research on government use of social media has in the past focused on the use of social media for democratic goals of transparency participation and collaboration Bertot et al 2010 <PERSON>Harrison</PERSON> et al 2012 <PERSON>Mergel</PERSON> 2013a However SNS and social media are inherently tools for identity construction <PERSON>Nadkarni</PERSON> and <PERSON>Hofmann</PERSON> 2012 the exchange of values based symbolic content <PERSON>Penney</PERSON> 2015 acts of social grooming Tufekci 2008 and marketing <PERSON>Bellstr</PERSON> m et al 2016 Although certain activities such as collaboration or different types of crowdsourcing functionality are not generally carried out on social networking sites such as <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> and Twitter the communicated content openly posted and shared on these platforms may be coded based on a set of communication or information strategies which we assume to be reflected by the type of content government agencies are posting and sharing Government social media activity is a relatively regulated activity <PERSON>Klang</PERSON> and Nolin 2011 <PERSON>Mergel</PERSON> 2016 Moreover individuals working as governmental communicators have specific intentions in the creation of public <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> posts and other similar acts Searle 1969 In this study we therefore analyze and code the content or meaning of the post via a framework of types of communication or communication strategies that reflect the context of the communication i e social media and the intentions that government agencies demonstrate in these contexts The framework is divided into more specific and more general categories namely information provision input seeking online dialogue off line interaction and symbolic presentation as summarized in <PERSON>DePaula</PERSON> et al 2018 and Table 1 Information provision is understood as the publication of government information and content that fulfils the transparency mandate of government <PERSON>Bertot</PERSON> et al 2010 a defining characteristic of political democracies <PERSON>Harrison</PERSON> et al 2012 In the framework adopted here we distinguish between 1 descriptive information about governmental programs events and policy as operations and events information and 2 instructions to keep safety and welfare as public service announcements Operations and events information is information about the government that could be useful or important for citizens to know fulfilling at least a minimum level of transparency Public service announcements however are instructions or messages that governments give in order to produce broad responses in society in regards to their safety or awareness about social issues Shoemaker 1989 These public directives are related to crisis communication where individuals must be quickly instructed on how to respond to dangerous and difficult situations one reason for which social media has been adopted <PERSON>Graham</PERSON> et al 2015 <PERSON>Hagen</PERSON> et al 2017 One of the main reasons social media have been categorized as beneficial for governments is that they provide convenient platforms from which agencies and departments can seek citizen information or input <PERSON>Mergel</PERSON> 2013b Input may be obtained by organizations via internal observation of user behavior on a given platform which cannot be captured from research analysis of public posts published by the departments themselves However governments have been observed to post requests for feedback from citizens in the form of surveys or polls Waters and <PERSON>Williams</PERSON> 2011 We refer to this type of communication as citizen information since the input sought is in reference to how citizens think or behave Moreover the literature has noted that government communication also involves more tangible types of input seeking in the form of fundraising and donations Golbeck et al 2010 <PERSON>Hofmann</PERSON> et al 2013 which we refer to as simply fundraising Input seeking efforts may be characterized as two way asymmetric <PERSON>DePaula</PERSON> and Dincelli 2016 since there are instances where it is not clear how the organization itself will respond to the input sought and obtained bookmark tab1 Table 1 General and specific categories of government social media content Information provision Operations amp events Content on agency policy operations and events Public service announcements Regarding safety health and well being Input seeking Citizen information Requesting feedback opinion use of survey or poll Fundraising Asking for donations and contributions to a cause Online dialogue off line interaction Online dialogue Response by agency to user comment on agency post Off line discussion Off line event to discuss particular policy issue Off line collaboration Asking citizens to become active and volunteer Symbolic presentation Favorable presentation Positive imagery self referential language of gratitude and praises of itself Political positioning Taking or expressing a position on a political issue Symbolic act Expressing congratulations condolences to others References to holiday cultural and historical symbols Marketing Presentation of features with intention to attract individuals to acquire or consume Social media facilitate interaction via comments by allowing users to add comments to posts and reply to those comments therefore producing some level of dialogue or conversation It has been argued that these interactions may improve relationships that governments have with their communities Bovaird 2007 However in practice the interaction over social media platforms may be limited to simple questions and answers and real time announcements Nevertheless governmental departments at least to a large extent allow users to comment on content that governmental organizations post When governmental organizations themselves reply to these comments we refer to it as online dialogue Although the extent of dialogue is relative for this study we simply measure this variable as binary Given the liberal democratic nature of governments discussed in this paper we also sought to capture instances where governments made references to off line interaction both in the form of off line discussions where citizens met with officials and discussed policy issues or off line collaborations where opportunities were publicized for people to volunteer for a project or assist in some community based activity What we broadly term symbolic presentation are a set of information strategies that reflect both socially symbolic content and self presentational strategies The literature on government use of social media has not integrated or discussed at length the nature of symbolic and presentational exchanges on social media However outside of government social media are tools that enable performance via self presentation boyd and <PERSON>Ellison</PERSON> 2007 <PERSON>Nadkarni</PERSON> and <PERSON>Hofmann</PERSON> 2012 and become spaces of social grooming where content exchange and the use of language are used to signal social status or develop information fashions <PERSON>Donath</PERSON> 2007 Tufekci 2008 Similarly in this realm social media are used for the adoption and distribution of visual symbols in order to communicate particular social values such as was the case with the equal sign and marriage equality campaign on <ORGANIZATION>Facebook Penney</ORGANIZATION> 2015 which we infer reflects the strong visual and image based characteristic of social media <PERSON>Treem</PERSON> and <PERSON>Leonardi</PERSON> 2012 More specifically what we refer to as favorable presentation are the strategic attempts to create a portrayal of an individual or organization in order to induce attributions of likability and in general create a positive image of the individuals or organizations involved This type of communication has also been conceived as a type of impression management <PERSON>DePaula</PERSON> and Dincelli 2016 and is similar to marketing which works with an affective dimension in order to present a product and attract people to consume it Bruner 1990 What we refer to as political positioning are instances where a political opinion is expressed which we assume to signal political values and are often associated with a political person Symbolic acts are communication with reference to other types of social values such as social status social affiliations and fashions as well as social grooming aids which tell others you are thinking about them <PERSON>Donath</PERSON> 2007 This symbolic content may refer to more universal values or emotions e g feeling good from the good nature of people or are more ideologically based e g references to one s own cultural characteristic or history Dijck 2013 Although the exchange of this symbolic content may serve as signals of sociality and politeness it is unclear whether or not such exchanges strengthen government citizen partnerships and efforts to collaborate or reflect actual improvements in the government s relationship with their constituency Although some characterize these symbolic acts as important part of human evolution Dunbar 1996 others characterize these exchanges as meaningless social chatter to stimulate peace and contentment bookmark 2a 2 image bookmark p3 User interaction with social media content The basic ways that users can react or interact with social media content are by liking sharing and or commenting Studies in e government and government information management have explored how users respond to content in the form of likes shares and comments <PERSON>Hofmann</PERSON> et al 2013 Bons n et al 2015 Lappas et al 2017 These forms of social media reactions are often understood as measures of success <PERSON>Mergel</PERSON> 2013a or effectiveness <PERSON>Lappas</PERSON> et al 2017 in a governmental context However researchers on social media more broadly have noted that social media reactions and interactions in general are about the affective or emotional response that content brings <PERSON>Grusin</PERSON> 2010 Papacharissi and de <PERSON>Fatima Oliveira</PERSON> 2012 Paasonen 2016 Tettegah 2016 As a case in point in January 2016 <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> made available as part of its platform new possible reactions to posts all of which were emotionally focused sad angry wow and happy Given that part of the data for this study did not include all of these new reactions we limit this study to the traditional three reactions Studies on government social media often distinguish between these three functions Likes have been conceived as a type of attitude expression <PERSON>Lappas</PERSON> et al 2017 and a measure of popularity Bons n et al 2015 shares have been conceived as advocacy <PERSON>Lappas</PERSON> et al 2017 and participation <PERSON>Zavattaro</PERSON> et al 2015 and comments have been conceived as commitment <PERSON>Bons</PERSON> n et al 2015 engagement and networking <PERSON>Mergel</PERSON> 2013b Whereas liking and sharing a post only require individuals to click a button as a type of push button response commenting may be considered a more involved type of interaction Additionally although both liking and sharing content may make content become viral i e quickly and highly distributed across a network people may like a post because it brings pleasure to them <PERSON>Lee</PERSON> et al 2013 whereas they may share a post because they think the content is useful or interesting to others <PERSON>Berger</PERSON> and Milkman 2012 To better understand the tendencies and logic of social media communication and interactions we here review the literature on how type of content affects social media reactions We develop hypotheses to test the effects of content or information the communication strategies on likes shares and comments separately as the distribution seems to be heterogeneous across types of responses <PERSON>Bons</PERSON> n et al 2015 Although we recognize that liking is an affective reaction itself sharing and commenting may be considered to serve non emotional purposes e g to increase knowledge discussion provide different perspective Moreover observing if liking behavior is indeed correlated with other emotional content e g symbolic acts marketing provides valuable empirical evidence However given the limited nature of this paper and existing theory on the subject we only develop hypotheses for some of the more prominent types of relationships expected These hypotheses are relatively conservative and derived from previous related work Interaction with marketing and favorable presentation Empirical research examining how individuals react or respond to features of marketing and favorable content on social media is limited findings thus far suggest that the relationship is negative <PERSON>Berger</PERSON> and Milkman 2012 <PERSON>Bons</PERSON> n et al 2015 This should not be surprising as individuals may easily discern the nature of an advertisements or publicity campaigns as propaganda In a study of government content on <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> citizens did not engage through likes shares and comments with marketing content as much as other types of content e g public transportation and environment <PERSON>Bons</PERSON> n et al 2015 In a study of German municipalities advertisements received less comments than other types of content on Facebook In the for profit marketing context the brand name included on posts had a significant and negative effect on the number of likes the post received <PERSON>Swani</PERSON> et al 2013 Direct calls to purchase also had a negative effect on number of likes however this relationship was not significant <PERSON>Swani</PERSON> et al 2013 In another for profit context <PERSON>Lee</PERSON> et al 2013 found that informative content e g price product availability product mention had a significant and negative impact on engagement measured by likes and comments The informative value therefore may have been interpreted by users as mere characteristics of a clear advertisement We thus make the following hypotheses H1 Content coded as favorable presentation are less likely to receive likes h1a comments h1b or shares h1c than content not categorized as such H2 Content coded as marketing are less likely to receive likes h2a comments h2b or shares h2c than content not categorized as such Interaction with symbolic acts Symbolic acts are pieces of information that reflect a social custom politeness or friendly formality These are messages that refer to phatic expressions or grooming talk and that may express perhaps implicitly political and social values We assume this type of content to be more strongly related to emotional expressions Massumi 2015 Although such a categorical variable has not been studied in the government information context in related research posts that were characterized with emotions humor and philanthropic language had a significant and positive effect on interactions measured by number of likes and comments received <PERSON>Lee</PERSON> et al 2013 Other studies also found that the presence of emotions made content particularly viral <PERSON>Stieglitz</PERSON> and <PERSON>Dang Xuan</PERSON> 2013 Content that induces high arousal emotions i e awe anxiety and anger were found to be particularly effective in making content more engaging and shared in the context of distributing news articles via e mail <PERSON>Berger</PERSON> and Milkman 2012 Emotional or affective content is not generally acknowledged in studies of government information and communication However in the study of <PERSON>Hofmann</PERSON> et al 2013 for example non government related information seemed to be the type of content that received the most likes leading to the suggestion that <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> users are more interested in fun and private issues than in more serious reports on government activities bookmark 3a 3 This type of content however was not theorized and it was labeled as other <PERSON>Hofmann</PERSON> et al 2013 Here we find it appropriate to make the following hypothesis H3 Content coded as symbolic acts are more likely to receive likes h3a comments h3b or shares h3c than content not categorized as such Interaction with government information In economics it is understood that despite occasions in which selfish gain takes priority humans often interact with others via gift exchanges and by generating reciprocity <PERSON>Fehr</PERSON> et al 1998 Therefore online individuals may share content when there is no clear and direct gain from it but when they believe others find it useful or interesting <PERSON>Berger</PERSON> and Milkman 2012 However there is little research examining how users respond to government information on social media In a meta analysis perceived usefulness was found as one of the best predictors of intention to use e government services <PERSON>Rana</PERSON> et al 2015 Of course in a study of perceived usefulness different individuals may find different characteristics of the e government service useful Nevertheless informative components such as the presence of a URL for more details has been found to be significant in predicting sharing of information <PERSON>Stieglitz</PERSON> and Dang Xuan 2013 In the government context citizens have reported expectations that government agencies share information online about its services operations and events <PERSON>Johannessen</PERSON> et al 2012 <PERSON>Hofmann</PERSON> et al 2013 found that some of the most discussed comments topics included content about administrative news of the government units Given this theorization in the literature we thus make the following hypothesis in relation to how users respond to government information H4 Content coded as information provision are more likely to receive likes h4a comments h4b or shares h4c than content not categorized as such Interaction with input seeking and government dialogue It is not entirely clear from existing literature how users react and interact to instances where governments are seeking input from users or when they initiate dialogue with users via a social media platform Based on intuitive assumptions we expect that users react positively i e like share or further comment to government efforts to obtain citizen feedback and provide opportunities for a citizen voice to be heard Moreover certain input seeking efforts could greatly benefit from the distributive power of social networking sites If users recognize the need for content to be shared to be effective they may elect to share content In the study of <PERSON>Johannessen</PERSON> et al 2012 citizens reported expectations that governments not only provide useful information but also that governments engage in dialogues with the community at large and with businesses in particular Moreover citizens expected that governments create a forum for debates where communicative interaction may take place <PERSON>Johannessen</PERSON> et al 2012 We therefore anticipate that content that refers to input seeking efforts references to off line interaction between governments and citizens and instances where governments respond to comments from citizens are likely to receive more virtual interaction via likes shares or comments We thus hypothesize H5 Content coded as input seeking are more likely to receive likes h6a comments h6b or shares h7c than content not categorized as such H6 Content coded as dialogue and interaction are more likely to receive likes h7a comments h7b or shares h7c than content not categorized as such image bookmark p4 Methodology Selection of posts and coding To select a representative sample of local government <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> posts to analyze we used a stratified sampling methodology We randomly selected four states of each major U S census region and then selected their largest city by population For each of the 16 cities selected we used the <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> built in search function to identify all governmental departments with a Facebook page for that city From this set of 121 agencies we randomly selected 55 department pages approximately 50 percent For each page we retrieved all posts from 1 August 2015 to 1 August 2016 14 482 and then randomly selected 10 percent of those posts ultimately for a sample of 1 421 unique posts to manually code The multiple steps of sampling in the stratification process were carried out in order to obtain a manageable amount of posts to manually code Although we would have liked to carried out automated analyses of larger sample sizes we believe that we obtained a relatively representative sample of government department <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> posts for the period at question We further justified this sampling strategy in <PERSON>DePaula</PERSON> et al 2018 The posts were coded as reflecting one or more of the different types of communicated content as outlined in Table 1 Given the complexity of the content categories and multiple messages that could be inferred from a single post our coding rules by design attempted to avoid double coding However given the nature of the message of each post it was virtually impossible to not consider double coding without disregarding important content from the post Not counting instances of online dialogue which were responses that the department gave to a user comments eight percent of the posts were double coded Approximately 43 percent of the double coded posts were between symbolic acts and favorable presentation and 52 percent of the double coded posts were between operation events with another category Two of the authors carried out the development of coding rules during a pilot and confirmatory study After establishing the rules we recruited a third coder to test our categories and coding instructions Details of the coding may be found in <PERSON>DePaula</PERSON> et al 2018 Ultimately inter coder reliability yielded almost perfect agreement k gt 0 81 for the four broader categories and almost perfect or substantial agreement k gt 0 61 for the more specific categories All tests were significant p lt 0 001 Analysis The unit of analysis in this study is the <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> post of a local government agency The category of content is considered the independent variable and the number of likes comments and shares dependent variables the values are normalized for the number of page likes of each page which we assume is a rough estimate of the users who have had access to the content Normality of the data for all categories of content was tested using the <PERSON>Shapiro Wilk</PERSON> test of normality Homogeneity of variances was tested using <PERSON>Levene</PERSON> s test of homogeneity We used independent samples t test to analyze the effect of each type of content on user response for those categories that did not violate assumptions of normality and homogeneity of variances We followed <PERSON>Welch</PERSON> s t test procedure a non parametric alternative of t test in cases where the data was non normally distributed distributions in each group did not have the same shape or the assumption of homogeneity of variance was violated <PERSON>Siegel</PERSON> and <PERSON>Castellan</PERSON> 1988 image bookmark p5 Empirical results In this section we provide some descriptive statistics of our sample In Table 2 we present some statistics regarding the five most popular pages based on percentage of city population that liked the page All measures are for the period from August 2015 to August 2016 The table shows that a variety of government department types that are popular on <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> including fire police arts and city departments However it should be noted some of the other more popular pages are also for fire and police departments Local government fire departments as well as police departments seem to be more often present or popular on <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> compared to all other department types The oldest agency on <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> from our sample was <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> s <ORGANIZATION>Parks and Recreation Department</ORGANIZATION> with the earliest post identified as from June 2008 As Figure 1 shows the popularity of local government department pages seemed to follow a power law distribution a few pages have a relatively high percentage of the city population connected on <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> but most government pages i e 65 percent of them have less than one percent of their respective city population liking them on Facebook Details of the long tail may be observed on the inset graph of Figure 1 We refrained from providing aggregate measures such as average page likes for all pages given the large differences of activity across all individual <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> pages bookmark tab2 Table 2 Five most popular pages based on percentage of city population that liked the page 2015 2016 City Department Average page likes one year period Percentage increase in likes one year period Percentage of city population who liked the page Earliest post found <ORGANIZATION>Boston Mass Police</ORGANIZATION> 168 957 18 8 26 2 1 February 2010 <ORGANIZATION>Jonesboro Ark Animal</ORGANIZATION> 10 805 17 9 15 1 20 July 2010 <ORGANIZATION>Bridgeport Conn Fire</ORGANIZATION> 8 943 4 3 6 1 10 December 2009 <LOCATION>Washington</LOCATION> D C Arts 31 079 24 9 4 7 11 February 2009 New York N Y City 378 158 14 8 4 4 14 April 2011 bookmark fig1 image Percentage of city population that likes the department page on <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> for all 55 agencies in the sample in descending order Figure 1 Percentage of city population that likes the department page on <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> for all 55 agencies in the sample in descending order inset graph focus on lt five percent General categories of content In the whole sample analyzed approximately 62 percent of posts were coded as information provision 2 5 percent as input seeking 8 3 percent as online dialogue off line interaction and 40 percent as symbolic and presentational exchanges as summarized in Table 3 Notice that double coding was permissible in certain instances A series of t tests were carried out separately for likes comments and shares to compare if the use of any of the communication strategies significantly affected the quantity of user response measures i e likes comments and shares Independent samples t test was run for all general categories given the results of normality test for these variables bookmark tab3 Table 3 General categories of content and relationship with user response measures Note p lt 05 n Likes Shares Comments Information provision 885 Less Less Less Input seeking 35 Less More Less Dialogue Interaction 114 More More More Symbolic presentation 581 More More More As summarized in Table 3 among the general categories posts coded as symbolic presentation M 129 98 SD 481 08 received significantly more likes than the posts that were not coded in this category M 24 16 SD 80 04 Posts that reflected symbolic presentation and dialogue interaction as general categories received significantly more comments than posts not coded as such Information provision posts had significantly less likes M 34 33 SD 112 10 and significantly less comments M 3 21 SD 14 41 than posts that were not coded as information provision M 68 72 SD 321 68 M 7 90 SD 23 39 The direction of relationship may be observed for other categories in Table 3 however the differences were not significant p lt 05 Specific categories of content The distribution of specific categories of content and the relationship with user response is presented in Table 4 A <PERSON>Welch</PERSON> s t test was run for the analyses of symbolic acts and operations events given results from the normality tests for these variables We used independent t test for the other variables As a summary of significant results posts coded as symbolic acts M 145 60 SD 338 91 and online dialogue M 165 40 SD 236 49 received significantly more likes than posts that were not categorized as such M 46 94 SD 308 99 and M 62 35 SD 320 75 respectively Moreover symbolic acts M 9 12 SD 22 90 favorable presentation M 7 64 SD 23 52 and online dialogue M 12 73 SD 16 38 received significantly more comments than posts that were not categorized in these categories M 3 90 SD 16 95 M 4 41 SD 17 14 and M 4 58 SD 18 47 respectively On the other hand posts that were coded as operations events information had significantly less likes M 37 14 SD 120 36 and significantly less comments M 3 56 SD 15 52 than the posts that were not coded in this specific category M 99 33 SD 436 30 and M 6 48 SD 21 02 Also posts that were coded as public service announcements had significantly less likes M 9 4 SD 20 35 and significantly less comments M 0 45 SD 1 63 than posts that were not coded in this category M 70 07 SD 324 74 for likes and M 5 19 SD 18 84 for comments bookmark tab4 Table 4 Specific categories of content and relationships with reaction measures Note p lt 05 n Likes Shares Comments Operations amp events 729 Less Less Less Public service announcement 62 Less Less Less Feedback 21 Less More Less Fundraising 14 Less Less Less Online dialogue 70 More More More Call for discussion 24 Less Less Less Call for collaboration 24 More More More Favorable presentation 249 More More More Political positioning 27 More More More Symbolic act 295 More Less More Marketing 67 More More More image bookmark p6 Discussion The affective bias This study analyzed the relationship between user response and the types of social media content created by local government departments in the U S for Facebook We first hypothesized that posts of information provision would be positively related with measures of likes shares and comments This was based on the notion that individuals may appreciate useful information about their local governments and would demonstrate this appreciation by engaging with content through liking sharing and or commenting Since the analysis assumes those who engage with posts already need to follow an organization this was not a particularly difficult test We found that content coded as policy operations and events received significantly less likes and comments than content coded in other categories The same was the case for posts coded as public service announcements Posts coded as favorable presentation which we hypothesized to affect the message negatively received significantly more comments that posts coded in other categories Although not statistically significant posts coded as favorable presentation and posts coded as marketing which we also assumed would affect user response negatively actually received more likes and more shares than posts not coded as such We hypothesized that posts coded as input seeking would receive more likes shares or comments However these differences were not significant and posts of this general category received on average less likes shares and comments than posts coded in other categories As predicted posts coded as symbolic acts received significantly more likes and comments than posts that did not receive this designation and posts coded as online dialogue also received significantly more likes and comments that posts not coded in this designation However it should be noted online dialogue refers to posts that had a government response to a user comment These posts are more likely to have more comments that other types of posts However this fact itself does not explain why posts that had government responses received significantly more likes than posts that did not receive this designation We interpret these results as a reflection of the affective and image based tendency of social media behavior and a lack of manifested interest for content that is simply of a factual nature or linguistically elaborate what we may term an affective bias At the turn of the new millennium researchers in neuropsychology e g <PERSON>Damasio</PERSON> 1994 humanities e g Sedgwick 2003 and politics e g Massumi 2015 began to develop a notion of affect in their interpretation of how human experiences are characterized in the twenty first century It is not through ideology but through affect that the public is mobilized to act bookmark 4a 4 politically Our experiences are mediatic and mediated e g through mobile computers Internet interfaces what <PERSON>Grusin</PERSON> refers to as mediality Although there are many interpretations of how affect and mediality work in the world today e g Leys 2011 these concepts seem to a lesser or greater extent necessary to understand patterns of behavior on social media sites As Grusin 2010 writes of social media interacting with such sites is made pleasurable or desirable in part because they work to produce and maintain positive affective relations with their users to set up affective feedback loops that make one want to proliferate one s media transactions Indeed something as seemingly innocuous as the fact that <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> offers its users the option to like or unlike an item but not to dislike it epitomizes its bias towards fostering positive individual and collective affect bookmark 5a 5 <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> still does not offer the option to dislike however it now includes more emotion buttons i e love haha wow sad angry to be used as recorded reactions to posts Although this shows that the bias of these systems is not only to foster positive affect e g you can now post an angry face the site continues to epitomize the affective intensity of these platforms Paasonen 2016 <PERSON>Grusin</PERSON> 2010 writes that affect is a type of emotional or subjective feeling prior to and independent of the cognitive impact or interpretation bookmark 6a 6 that an event produces As such affectivity is distinguished and contrasted with ideology which are rationalized and at least to some extent reasoned systems of belief Although ideology may still be in place its materialization is through affect and the affect itself becomes more important than the ideology Massumi 2015 In the political domain power itself no longer operates through normative ideas based on ideological explanations but through affect itself As <PERSON>Brian Massumi</PERSON> 2015 puts it in an interview The legitimisation of political power of state power no longer goes through the reason of state and the correct application of governmental judgment It goes through affective channels Affect is now much more important for understanding power even state power narrowly defined than concepts like ideology <PERSON>Grusin</PERSON> further suggests that there is a strong relation between how affect operates on the world today and how mediality is experienced in everyday life Mediality contrasts with a notion of representationality that is representational truth Epitomized by social network sites but affecting all mediated interaction mediality is more concerned with mobilizing people or populations bookmark 7a 7 than with any type of factual and correct reference to some external objective phenomenon in the world Given this understanding it becomes possible to explain the empirical results obtained in this study From Table 4 one should note that the first six categories of communication all referring to factual and operational information provision and efforts to obtain information and feedback from citizens correspond generally to less forms of social media interaction This is the case for 11 of the 12 categories under information provision and input seeking studied i e only efforts for citizen feedback were associated with more shares but not significantly In contrast 11 of the 12 categories under symbolic presentation were associated with more interaction in general i e only symbolic acts were associated with less shares but not significantly The consistency in the direction of user interaction with our broad categories e g less for information provision in general more for symbolic presentation in general gives some support that the categories form a distinct entity At the same time our results also suggest that there is homogeneity on how users react via likes shares and comments Studies on this type of comparison have not found consistent results e g Bons n et al 2015 <PERSON>Lee</PERSON> et al 2013 Nevertheless the consistency of direction in our results for the three types of responses are explained by the theory that the underlying mechanisms of generating interaction on social network sites is one of affective intensity Therefore responses of likes shares and comments are all going to be driven by sentimentality rather than the possibility for debate or policy discussion The presence of online dialogue by the government agency received significantly more likes and comments compared to all posts without dialogue Once governments engage citizens further engage and respond What needs to be further examined are the characteristics of this dialogue and their actual adoption as policy Research on government social media communication often assumes that if engagement is happening it is positive and commendable In this work we have observed that responses from the government agency were appreciated by the public i e via likes However we did not investigate the quality of conversation on the site Recent evidence from <LOCATION>China Medaglia</LOCATION> and <PERSON>Zhu</PERSON> 2017 suggests that social network sites in this case Weibo are not sites of deliberation as exemplified by the ideal public sphere of Habermas 1989 or any prerogative for informed and reasoned discussion Indeed we may explain the greater levels of user interaction to government comments precisely based on the emotional nature of social media responses Personalized attention may affect reaction behavior However we can also conceivably propose that reaction behavior is a sign of appreciation for the receipt of informative and therefore valuable content We leave these questions for further research image bookmark p7 Conclusions and future work Our empirical study found evidence that user interaction or reaction behavior on <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> pages of local governments in the U S are significantly more often associated with symbolic and image based content than content not characterized as such At the same time factual policy information and information about operations and events are associated with less likes shares and comments in general and statistically significantly for some categories This is explained by the affective nature of social media behavior which does not emphasize critical and reasoned dialogue but pre cognitive and emotional behavior Although studies on government social media have similar findings on how users respond to governmental content they have suggested governments should follow these tendencies and further deploy content that will attract likes shares and comments e g <PERSON>Mergel</PERSON> 2013a <PERSON>Zavattaro</PERSON> et al 2015 However we question whether these government information strategies would assist with a politically informed dialogue Should we characterize government publication of viral pictures and one sided self presentations as measures of transparency Nevertheless we found variations in how departments adopt distinct information strategies which needs to be more systematically analyzed Moreover there were positive measures of interaction in terms of government dialogue which may point to the value of government information to citizens via social media Ultimately compared to Web sites the platforms provide a more virtual interactive environment through which governments may communicate with citizens Also there may be a rationale for the principle of affective intensity as emotions of course are part of human interaction However we also expect governments are going to use platforms to create an unchallenged image of themselves and that the tendency of social media reactions are toward positive imagery and high arousal We thus suggest that the principles of open and democratic government including the goals of transparency and public deliberation will not be so easily realized on social media image End of article bookmark author About the authors <PERSON>Nic DePaula</PERSON> is a Ph D candidate in the <ORGANIZATION>Department of Information Science</ORGANIZATION> and lecturer in the <ORGANIZATION>Departments of Information Technology Management and Information Science</ORGANIZATION> at the <ORGANIZATION>University at Albany State University of New York</ORGANIZATION> He conducts research in the areas of information policy political communication and media studies E mail ndepaula at albany dot edu <PERSON>Ersin Dincelli</PERSON> is a Ph D candidate in the <ORGANIZATION>Department of Information Science</ORGANIZATION> and an adjunct professor in the <ORGANIZATION>Department of Information Technology Management and Information Science</ORGANIZATION> at the <ORGANIZATION>University at Albany the State University of New York</ORGANIZATION> His primary research interests include individual behavior in the context of information security and privacy cybersecurity education and cross cultural issues in information systems Notes bookmark 1 1 <PERSON>Hofmann</PERSON> et al 2013 p 391 bookmark 2 2 Smail 2008 p 176 bookmark 3 3 <PERSON>Hofmann</PERSON> et al 2013 p 391 bookmark 4 4 <PERSON>Grusin</PERSON> 2010 p 77 bookmark 5 5 Grusin 2010 p 3 bookmark 6 6 Grusin 2010 p 79 bookmark 7 7 Ibid References <PERSON>Peter Bellstr</PERSON> m <PERSON>Monika Magnusson John S ren Pettersson</PERSON> and <PERSON>Claes Thor</PERSON> n 2016 Facebook usage in a local government A content analysis of page owner posts and user posts Transforming Government People Process and Policy volume 10 number 4 pp 548 567 doi https doi org 10 1108 TG 12 2015 0061 accessed 17 March 2018 <PERSON>Jonah Berger</PERSON> and <PERSON>Katherine</PERSON> L Milkman 2012 What makes online content viral <ORGANIZATION>Journal of Marketing Research</ORGANIZATION> volume 49 number 2 pp 192 205 doi https doi org 10 1108 TG 12 2015 0061 accessed 17 March 2018 <PERSON>John C Bertot Paul T Jaeger</PERSON> and <PERSON>Justin M Grimes</PERSON> 2010 Using ICTs to create a culture of transparency E government and social media as openness and anti corruption tools for societies Government Information Quarterly volume 27 number 3 pp 264 271 doi https doi org 10 1108 TG 12 2015 0061 accessed 17 March 2018 <PERSON>Enrique Bons</PERSON> n <PERSON>Sonia Royo</PERSON> and <PERSON>Melinda Ratkai</PERSON> 2015 Citizens engagement on local governments <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> sites An empirical analysis The impact of different media and content types in <LOCATION>Western Europe</LOCATION> Government Information Quarterly volume 32 number 1 pp 52 62 doi https doi org 10 1016 j giq 2014 11 001 accessed 17 March 2018 Tony Bovaird 2007 Beyond engagement and participation User and community coproduction of public services <ORGANIZATION>Public Administration Review</ORGANIZATION> volume 67 number 5 pp 846 860 doi https doi org 10 1111 j 1540 6210 2007 00773 x accessed 17 March 2018 danah m boyd and <PERSON>Nicole B Ellison</PERSON> 2007 Social network sites Definition history and scholarship <ORGANIZATION>Journal of Computer Mediated Communication</ORGANIZATION> volume 13 number 1 pp 210 230 doi https doi org 10 1111 j 1083 6101 2007 00393 x accessed 17 March 2018 <PERSON>Gordon C Bruner</PERSON> 1990 Music mood and marketing <ORGANIZATION>Journal of Marketing</ORGANIZATION> volume 54 number 4 pp 94 104 doi http dx doi org 10 2307 1251762 accessed 17 March 2018 <PERSON>Antonio Damasio</PERSON> 1994 Descartes error Emotion reason and the human brain <ORGANIZATION>New York Putnam Nic DePaula</ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON>Ersin Dincelli</PERSON> 2016 An empirical analysis of local government social media communication Models of e government interactivity and public relations dg o 16 Proceedings of the 17th <ORGANIZATION>International Digital Government Research Conference on Digital Government Research</ORGANIZATION> pp 348 356 doi http dx doi org 10 1145 2912160 2912174 accessed 17 March 2018 <PERSON>Nic DePaula Ersin Dincelli</PERSON> and <PERSON>Teresa M Harrison</PERSON> 2018 Toward a typology of government social media communication Democratic goals symbolic acts and self presentation Government Information Quarterly volume 35 number 1 pp 98 108 doi https doi org 10 1016 j giq 2017 10 003 accessed 17 March 2018 <PERSON>Jos van Dijck</PERSON> 2013 The culture of connectivity A critical history of social media <ORGANIZATION>New York Oxford University Press</ORGANIZATION> <PERSON>Judith Donath</PERSON> 2007 Signals in social supernets <ORGANIZATION>Journal of Computer Mediated Communication</ORGANIZATION> volume 13 number 1 pp 231 251 doi https doi org 10 1111 j 1083 6101 2007 00394 x accessed 17 March 2018 <PERSON>Robin Dunbar</PERSON> 1996 Grooming gossip and the evolution of language <ORGANIZATION>Cambridge Mass Harvard University Press</ORGANIZATION> <PERSON>Ernst Fehr Georg Kirchsteiger</PERSON> and <PERSON>Arno Riedlc</PERSON> 1998 Gift exchange and reciprocity in competitive experimental markets <ORGANIZATION>European Economic Review</ORGANIZATION> volume 42 number 1 pp 1 34 doi https doi org 10 1016 S0014 2921 96 00051 7 accessed 17 March 2018 Christian Fuchs 2017 Social media A critical introduction Thousand Oaks Calif Sage <PERSON>Jennifer Golbeck Justin M Grimes</PERSON> and <PERSON>Anthony Rogers</PERSON> 2010 Twitter use by the <ORGANIZATION>U S Congress Journal of the American Society for Information Science and Technology</ORGANIZATION> volume 61 number 8 pp 1 612 1 621 doi https doi org 10 1002 asi 21344 accessed 17 March 2018 <PERSON>Melissa W Graham Elizabeth J Avery</PERSON> and Sejin Park 2015 The role of social media in local government crisis communications <ORGANIZATION>Public Relations Review</ORGANIZATION> volume 41 number 3 pp 386 394 doi https doi org 10 1016 j pubrev 2015 02 001 accessed 17 March 2018 <PERSON>Shannon Greenwood Andrew Perrin</PERSON> and <PERSON>Maeve Duggan</PERSON> 2016 Social media update 2016 <ORGANIZATION>Pew Research Center</ORGANIZATION> 11 November at http www pewinternet org 2016 11 11 social media update 2016 accessed 30 November 2016 <PERSON>Richard Grusin</PERSON> 2010 Premediation Affect and mediality after 9 11 <ORGANIZATION>New York Palgrave Macmillan</ORGANIZATION> J rgen Habermas 1989 The structural transformation of the public sphere An inquiry into a category of bourgeois society Translated by <PERSON>Thomas Burger</PERSON> with the assistance of <ORGANIZATION>Frederick Lawrence Cambridge Mass MIT</ORGANIZATION> Press <PERSON>Loni Hagen Thomas Keller Stephen Neely Nic DePaula</PERSON> and <PERSON>Claudia Robert Cooperman</PERSON> 2017 Crisis communications in the age of social media A network analysis of <PERSON>Zika</PERSON> related tweets <ORGANIZATION>Social Science Computer Review</ORGANIZATION> 21 August doi https doi org 10 1177 0894439317721985 accessed 17 March 2018 <PERSON>Teresa M Harrison Santiago Guerrero G Brian Burke Meghan Cook Anthony Cresswell Natalie Helbig Jana Hrdinova</PERSON> and <PERSON>Theresa Pardo</PERSON> 2012 Open government and e government Democratic challenges from a public value perspective Information Polity volume 17 number 2 pp 83 97 doi https doi org 10 3233 IP 2012 0269 accessed 17 March 2018 <PERSON>Sara Hofmann Daniel Beverungen Michael</PERSON> R ckers and J rg Becker 2013 What makes local governments online communications successful Insights from a multi method analysis of <ORGANIZATION>Facebook Government Information Quarterly</ORGANIZATION> volume 30 number 4 pp 387 396 doi https doi org 10 3233 IP 2012 0269 accessed 17 March 2018 <PERSON>Marius Rohde Johannessen Leif Skiftenes Flak</PERSON> and ystein Saeb 2012 Choosing the right medium for municipal eparticipation based on stakeholder expectations In <PERSON>Efthimios Tambouris Ann Macintosh</PERSON> and ystein Saeb editors Electronic participation Lecture Notes in Computer Science volume 7444 <LOCATION>Berlin Springer</LOCATION> pp 25 36 doi https doi org 10 1007 978 3 642 33250 0_3 accessed 17 March 2018 <PERSON>Andrea L Kavanaugh Edward A Fox Steven D Sheetz Seungwon Yang Lin Tzy Li Donald J Shoemaker Apostol Natsev</PERSON> and Lexing Xie 2012 Social media use by government From the routine to the critical Government Information Quarterly volume 29 number 4 pp 480 491 doi https doi org 10 1016 j giq 2012 06 002 accessed 17 March 2018 <PERSON>Mathias Klang</PERSON> and Jan Nolin 2011 Disciplining social media An analysis of social media policies in 26 Swedish municipalities First Monday volume 16 number 8 at http firstmonday org article view 3490 3027 accessed 18 October 2017 doi http dx doi org 10 5210 fm v16i8 3490 accessed 17 March 2018 G Lappas A Triantafillidou A Deligiaouri and A Kleftodimos 2017 Facebook communication strategies and their effectiveness A case study of Greek local municipal governments <ORGANIZATION>MISNC</ORGANIZATION> 17 Proceedings of the 4th Multidisciplinary International Social Networks Conference article number 22 doi http dx doi org 10 1145 3092090 3092114 accessed 17 March 2018 <PERSON>Dokyun Lee Kartik Hosanagar</PERSON> and <PERSON>Harikesh Nair</PERSON> 2013 Advertising content and consumer engagement on social media Evidence from <ORGANIZATION>Facebook Management Science</ORGANIZATION> at https ssrn com abstract 2290802 accessed 3 December 2016 <PERSON>Ruth Leys</PERSON> 2011 The turn to affect A critique Critical Inquiry volume 37 number 3 pp 434 472 doi http dx doi org 10 1086 659353 accessed 17 March 2018 <PERSON>Dennis Linders</PERSON> 2012 From e government to we government Defining a typology for citizen coproduction in the age of social media Government Information Quarterly volume 29 number 4 pp 446 454 doi https doi org 10 1016 j giq 2012 06 003 accessed 17 March 2018 <PERSON>Brian Massumi</PERSON> 2015 Politics of affect Cambridge Polity <PERSON>Albert Meijer</PERSON> and <PERSON>Marcel Thaens</PERSON> 2013 Social media strategies Understanding the differences between North American police departments Government Information Quarterly volume 30 number 4 pp 343 350 doi https doi org 10 1016 j giq 2013 05 023 accessed 17 March 2018 Ines Mergel 2016 Social media institutionalization in the U S federal government <ORGANIZATION>Government Information Quarterly</ORGANIZATION> volume 33 number 1 pp 142 148 doi https doi org 10 1016 j giq 2015 09 002 accessed 17 March 2018 <PERSON>Ines Mergel</PERSON> 2013a A framework for interpreting social media interactions in the public sector <ORGANIZATION>Government Information Quarterly</ORGANIZATION> volume 30 number 4 pp 327 334 doi https doi org 10 1016 j giq 2013 05 015 accessed 17 March 2018 <PERSON>Ines Mergel</PERSON> 2013b Social media adoption and resulting tactics in the U S federal government <ORGANIZATION>Government Information Quarterly</ORGANIZATION> volume 30 number 2 pp 123 130 doi https doi org 10 1016 j giq 2012 12 004 accessed 17 March 2018 <PERSON>Karen Mossberger Yonghong Wu</PERSON> and <PERSON>Jared Crawford</PERSON> 2013 Connecting citizens and local governments Social media and interactivity in major U S cities Government Information Quarterly volume 30 number 4 pp 351 358 doi https doi org 10 1016 j giq 2013 05 016 accessed 17 March 2018 <PERSON>Ashwini Nadkarni</PERSON> and <PERSON>Stefan G Hofmann</PERSON> 2012 Why do people use <ORGANIZATION>Facebook Personality and Individual Differences</ORGANIZATION> volume 52 number 3 pp 243 249 doi https doi org 10 1016 j paid 2011 11 007 accessed 17 March 2018 <PERSON>Barack Obama</PERSON> 2009 Transparency and open government Memorandum for the heads of executive departments and agencies <ORGANIZATION>White House</ORGANIZATION> 21 January at https obamawhitehouse archives gov the press office transparency and open government accessed 17 March 2018 <PERSON>Susanna Paasonen</PERSON> 2016 Fickle focus Distraction affect and the production of value in social media First Monday volume 21 number 10 at http firstmonday org article view 6949 5629 accessed 16 October 2017 doi http dx doi org 10 5210 fm v21i10 6949 accessed 17 March 2018 <PERSON>Zizi Papacharissi</PERSON> and <PERSON>Maria de Fatima Oliveira</PERSON> 2012 Affective news and networked publics The rhythms of news storytelling on <ORGANIZATION>Egypt Journal of Communication</ORGANIZATION> volume 62 number 2 pp 266 282 doi https doi org 10 1111 j 1460 2466 2012 01630 x accessed 17 March 2018 <PERSON>Joel Penney</PERSON> 2015 Social media and symbolic action Exploring participation in the <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> red equal sign profile picture campaign <ORGANIZATION>Journal of Computer Mediated Communication</ORGANIZATION> volume 20 number 1 pp 52 66 doi https doi org 10 1111 jcc4 12092 accessed 17 March 2018 Nripendra P <PERSON>Rana Yogesh K Dwivedi</PERSON> and <PERSON>Michael D Williams</PERSON> 2015 A meta analysis of existing research on citizen adoption of e government <ORGANIZATION>Information Systems Frontiers</ORGANIZATION> volume 17 number 3 pp 547 563 doi https doi org 10 1007 s10796 013 9431 z accessed 17 March 2018 <PERSON>Rodrigo Sandoval Almazan</PERSON> and <PERSON>J Ramon Gil Garcia</PERSON> 2012 Are government Internet portals evolving towards more interaction participation and collaboration Revisiting the rhetoric of e government among municipalities <ORGANIZATION>Government Information Quarterly</ORGANIZATION> volume 29 supplement 1 pp s72 s81 doi https doi org 10 1016 j giq 2011 09 004 accessed 17 March 2018 <PERSON>Rodrigo Sandoval Almazan David Valle Cruz</PERSON> and <PERSON>Andrea L Kavanaugh</PERSON> 2018 The diffusion of social media among state governments in <ORGANIZATION>Mexico International Journal of Public Administration</ORGANIZATION> in the Digital Age volume 5 number 1 pp 63 81 doi https doi org 10 4018 IJPADA 2018010104 accessed 17 March 2018 <PERSON>John R Searle</PERSON> 1969 Speech acts An essay in the philosophy of language <ORGANIZATION>London Cambridge University Press Eve Kosofsky Sedgwick</ORGANIZATION> 2003 Touching feeling Affect pedagogy performativity <ORGANIZATION>Durham N C Duke University Press</ORGANIZATION> <PERSON>Pamela J Shoemaker</PERSON> editor 1989 Communication campaigns about drugs Government media and the public <ORGANIZATION>Hillsdale N J L Erlbaum Associates</ORGANIZATION> <PERSON>Sidney Siegel</PERSON> and N <PERSON>John Castellan</PERSON> 1988 Nonparametric statistics for the behavioral sciences Second edition <ORGANIZATION>New York McGraw Hill Daniel</ORGANIZATION> Lord <PERSON>Smail</PERSON> 2008 On deep history and the brain <ORGANIZATION>Berkeley University of California Press</ORGANIZATION> <PERSON>Stefan Stieglitz</PERSON> and Linh Dang Xuan 2013 Emotions and information diffusion in social media Sentiment of microblogs and sharing behavior <ORGANIZATION>Journal of Management Information Systems</ORGANIZATION> volume 29 number 4 pp 217 248 doi https doi org 10 2753 MIS0742 1222290408 accessed 17 March 2018 Maddle Stone 2015 8 government Instagram accounts you should definitely follow <ORGANIZATION>Gizmodo</ORGANIZATION> 22 July at https gizmodo com 8 government instagram accounts you should definitely f 1719387212 accessed 12 January 2018 <PERSON>Kunal Swani George Milne</PERSON> and <PERSON>Brian P Brown</PERSON> 2013 Spreading the word through likes on Facebook Evaluating the message strategy effectiveness of Fortune 500 companies <ORGANIZATION>Journal of Research</ORGANIZATION> in Interactive Marketing volume 7 number 4 pp 269 294 doi https doi org 10 1108 JRIM 05 2013 0026 accessed 17 March 2018 <PERSON>Sharon Tettegah</PERSON> editor 2016 Emotions technology and social media <LOCATION>London</LOCATION> Academic Press <PERSON>Jeffrey W Treem</PERSON> and <PERSON>Paul M Leonardi</PERSON> 2012 Social media use in organizations Exploring the affordances of visibility editability persistence and association <ORGANIZATION>Annals of the International Communication Association</ORGANIZATION> volume 36 number 1 pp 143 189 doi https doi org 10 1080 23808985 2013 11679130 accessed 17 March 2018 Zeynep Tufekci 2008 Grooming gossip <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> and MySpace What can we learn about these sites from those who won t assimilate <ORGANIZATION>Information Communication amp Society</ORGANIZATION> volume 11 number 4 pp 544 564 doi https doi org 10 1080 13691180801999050 accessed 17 March 2018 <PERSON>Richard</PERSON> D Waters and <PERSON>Jensen</PERSON> M Williams 2011 Squawking tweeting cooing and hooting Analyzing the communication patterns of government agencies on <ORGANIZATION>Twitter Journal of Public Affairs</ORGANIZATION> volume 11 number 4 pp 353 363 doi https doi org 10 1002 pa 385 accessed 17 March 2018 Staci M Zavattaro P Edward French and Somya D Mohanty 2015 A sentiment analysis of U S local government tweets The connection between tone and citizen involvement Government Information Quarterly volume 32 number 3 pp 333 341 doi https doi org 10 1016 j giq 2015 03 003 accessed 17 March 2018 Editorial history Received 2 March 2018 accepted 14 March 2018 image Creative Commons License This paper is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution NonCommercial NoDerivatives 4 0 <ORGANIZATION>International License Information</ORGANIZATION> strategies and affective reactions How citizens interact with government social media content by <PERSON>Nic DePaula</PERSON> and <PERSON>Ersin Dincelli</PERSON> First Monday Volume 23 Number 4 2 April 2018 http firstmonday org ojs index php fm article view 8414 6695 doi http dx doi org 10 5210 fm v23i4 8414 image Bookmark and Share A Great Cities Initiative of the <ORGANIZATION>University of Illinois at Chicago University Library First</ORGANIZATION> Monday 1995 2018 ISSN 1396 0466</ner>
