<ner>image DHQ Logo image Digital Humanities Quarterly Logo homesubmissionsabout dhqdhq peoplecontact Current Issue 2017 11 3 Preview Issue 2017 11 4 Previous Issues 2017 11 2 2017 11 1 2016 10 4 2016 10 3 2016 10 2 2016 10 1 2015 9 4 2015 9 3 2015 9 2 2015 9 1 2014 8 4 2014 8 3 2014 8 2 2014 8 1 2013 7 3 2013 7 2 2013 7 1 2012 6 3 2012 6 2 2012 6 1 2011 5 3 2011 5 2 2011 5 1 2010 4 2 2010 4 1 2009 3 4 2009 3 3 2009 3 2 2009 3 1 2008 2 1 2007 1 2 2007 1 1 Indexes Title Author image sidenavbarimg ISSN 1938 4122 Announcements Call for Reviewers Call for Submissions image button1 addthis gif DHQ Digital Humanities Quarterly 2017 Volume 11 Number 3 2017 11 3 XML Discuss Comments A Pedagogy for Computer Assisted Literary Analysis Introducing GALGO Golden Age Literature Glossary Online Nuria Alonso Garc a lt nalonsog_at_providence_dot_edu gt <ORGANIZATION>Providence College</ORGANIZATION> <PERSON>Alison Caplan</PERSON> lt acaplan_at_providence_dot_edu gt <ORGANIZATION>Providence College Brad Mering</ORGANIZATION> lt brad_dot_mering_at_gmail_dot_com gt Mervideo Abstract This paper describes a digital teaching application that approaches the study of language and literary works from a social semiotic perspective and represents an innovative pedagogical model for world language and literature classes The Golden Age Literature Glossary Online known by the acronym <ORGANIZATION>GALGO</ORGANIZATION> consists of an online glossary of select keywords from canonical texts of Golden Age Spanish literature whose multiple connotations illuminate important linguistic and social concepts of the 16th and 17th centuries GALGO incorporates British cultural historian <PERSON>Raymond Williams</PERSON> methodology in his Keywords A Vocabulary of Culture and <ORGANIZATION>Society</ORGANIZATION> namely identifying problem laden words or keywords charting their distinct usages across texts and reflecting critically on clusters of associated words GALGO seeks to instantiate language as social semiotic by linking the semantic configurations of a literary work simultaneously to the cultural environment the linguistic system and the social system Applying the conceptual design of M A K <PERSON>Halliday</PERSON> s social semiotic model GALGO s interpretive apparatus provides the field of discourse or context of situation for the text in which a specific keyword appears The field of discourse presents clusters word groupings of semiotic affinity that describe the social action that is taking place in the text GALGO also performs an interpretation of the tenor of discourse highlighting sociological variables connected to class status gender role and racial category that refine a keyword s meaning from the perspective of interpersonal relationships Finally GALGO adds commentary on discursive structures such as patterns of grammar syntactic nuances and figurative language that surround the keyword in the text GALGO s strength resides in the synchronic connectivity that the system facilitates when identifying the constellation of meanings for any given keyword From a technical perspective the system has the ability to efficiently identify the absolute position of all uses of a keyword across multiple texts so that large texts can be managed and search times minimized for both users and system administrators GALGO is constructed in such a way that users can not only access existing analysis within the database but also can assume when instructed to do so the role of the system administrator and contribute their own annotations A team of faculty and student administrators are currently building the database with research previously collected in Spanish Golden Age literature seminars <ORGANIZATION>Providence College</ORGANIZATION> students have utilized the social semiotic methodology underlying GALGO for several years now with successful outcomes both in terms of their growth as language majors and critical thinkers If teaching is largely about faculty student interaction then we have to recognize that human interaction is changing <PERSON>Bowen</PERSON> 2012 49 New tools that foster new insights into work with the ever increasing amount of digital data available to us are not a luxury but a necessity who better to develop them than humanists who have both a knowledge of the content domain and of the content as data <PERSON>Schreibman</PERSON> and <PERSON>Hanlon</PERSON> 2010 41 1 The dialogue between the digital and the humanities has not been fluid and continues to raise skepticism among a majority of humanists in this third decade since the advent of the field of <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> DH A primary concern is the ready appropriation of empiricist rather than humanistic methods of inquiry in the creation of DH tools <PERSON>Johanna Drucker</PERSON> is among the most vocal in lamenting that computer generated humanities scholarship by in large seeks positivistic strictly quantitative mechanistic reductive and literal scientific ends and undermines the humanities constructivist approach to knowledge as knowing observer dependent emergent and process driven rather than entity defined Drucker 2012 DH scholars are creating with powerful platforms that support large corpus processing data mining and modeling ever more complex and innovative projects that nonetheless mute in <PERSON>Drucker</PERSON> s view the core critical principles and affective experiences that have traditionally lay at the heart of work in the humanities 2 The subject of this paper GALGO Golden Age Literature Glossary Online was developed with a humanistic method of inquiry in mind and may resolve the issues raised by <PERSON>Drucker</PERSON> and offer new pedagogical insights into computer assisted reading and analysis of texts The potential benefits of the introduction of instructional platforms such as GALGO within the larger field of <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> are multiple 1 a wide variety of small scale digital text analysis projects like those suggested on the MLA Commons site Literary Studies in the Digital Age can be developed for classroom use and then elaborated on if proven to be of value 2 students more adept at using digital technology will be able to contribute in significant ways to tool development <PERSON>Clement</PERSON> 2013 11 and to engage in professional scholarship mentored by faculty <PERSON>Inman Berens</PERSON> 2014 6 7 and 3 the role that the cultural canon performs within local and global societies can be more broadly and effectively explored enabling the humanities discipline to undergo a much needed change 3 In the domain of digital text analysis <PERSON>Franco Moretti</PERSON> s celebrated distant reading model seems to bear out the same epistemological divide discussed above Illuminating and potentially canon busting the manipulation of massive datasets suggests more innovative means by which to evaluate formal and generic literary conventions but involves a little pact with the devil we know how to read texts now let s learn how not to read them <PERSON>Moretti</PERSON> 2013 48 At the same time a hybrid approach that combines distant reading practices with close or traditional ones as we adopted in GALGO is spawning new non empirical interpretive paradigms in which machine computational methods and human qualitative analyses interact dynamically to explore new ways of reading or just as important new understandings of how we have always read Liu 2012 14 15 Web based text analysis and visualization tools are being reimagined as vehicles that allow scholars to perform a range of hermeneutical and creative functions from instantiating dominant literary critical theories <PERSON>Ramsey</PERSON> and Rockwell 2012 Clement 2013 <PERSON>Olsen</PERSON> 1993 1994 to playing with or altering a text s language and form Sinclair 2003 4 The impulse to bridge distant and close reading strategies emerges naturally in 21st century college and high school classrooms where educators must respond to the ubiquitous use of technology by students their shorter reading span Hayles 2010 and their need for distraction When genuinely affected by the material today s learners also exhibit a capacity for disciplined reading and study Young people in online forums are engaging in close reading activities directed toward popular music or cult television shows sometimes engaging in prolonged and impassioned debate about what such works mean and how they convey their meanings <PERSON>Jenkins</PERSON> and <PERSON>Kelley</PERSON> 2013 514 The goal in the college classroom should not be to allow for open ended digital play and exploration of the kind that professional humanities scholars are motivated to undertake because as one learner noted The amount of information can truly be overwhelming and a large part of the success of this exercise seems to lie in not only how to use the digital tools to the best advantage but in avoiding dead ends Fyfe 2011 87 The pedagogical objective then is to foster curated opportunities for students in the humanities to engage in theoretically informed learning that takes full advantage of new media methods <PERSON>Drucker</PERSON> 2012 Brier 2012 As instructors we can play an important role in ensuring that they get a critical vocabulary for thinking about the intersections between media language and culture <PERSON>Jenkins</PERSON> and <PERSON>Kelley</PERSON> 2013 639 and they interact with literary texts meaningfully 5 In this paper we first introduce readers to GALGO s social semiotic model for digital literary analysis then we describe in detail GALGO s technical apparatus and illustrate its functionality and lastly we discuss multimodal literacy and reflect on GALGO s potential to engage 21st century learners in classic literary analysis 1 A <ORGANIZATION>Social Semiotic Model for Digital Literary Analysis</ORGANIZATION> Accessing the Language of Golden Age Spanish Culture 6 With increasing frequency over the last decade students in our foreign language literature classes remark that they often find it difficult to relate to terms and themes in the canonical works that they are studying since they perceive them as obsolete and irrelevant Students want to read literature that reflects their concerns and that offers them ways to address those concerns from varied perspectives The main pedagogical challenge then lies in guiding students to see the interconnectedness between early modern and contemporary language usage at the semantic and syntactic levels 7 Our research has demonstrated that the keyword analysis developed by British cultural historian <PERSON>Raymond Williams</PERSON> provides a particularly amenable approach for engaging students in the study of foreign language and literature honing in as it does on charged social and political terms that span societies and time periods <PERSON>Alonso Garc</PERSON> a and <PERSON>Caplan</PERSON> 2014 <PERSON>Williams</PERSON> methodology namely identifying problem laden words or keywords interpreting their meanings in various contexts and reflecting critically on clusters of associated words serves to bring to the fore in any text an array of linguistic and historical questions to be researched and discussed The keyword sociolinguistic framework allows for an exploration of the vocabulary of a crucial area of social and cultural discussion which has been inherited within precise historical and social conditions and which has to be made at once conscious and critical subject to change as well as to continuity <PERSON>Williams</PERSON> 1983 24 Keywords are large words <PERSON>Hart</PERSON> et al 2005 5 that are polysemic used often and in at least two different situational contexts and patterned towards important social ends <PERSON>Halliday</PERSON> and Hasan 1989 vii For <PERSON>Williams</PERSON> in the mid 20th century they were culture society democracy class etc For students of Golden Age <LOCATION>Spain</LOCATION> they tend to be moral and social terms inflected by the period s dominant philosophical concerns for example fuerza 1 courage 2 brute strength 3 the force of truth and gentileza 1 cultivated manner and appearance 2 moral uprightness The polysemy of a word can be so extensive that it may include conflicting meanings as in voluntad 1 the rational will part of the human soul that seeks the moral good 2 free choice 3 uncontrolled sexual desire 8 Undergirding <PERSON>William</PERSON> s keyword study is a social semiotic theory of language which understands language as text delivered in a specific context of social interaction and constructed from linguistic codes derived from the culture <PERSON>Halliday</PERSON> and Hasan 1989 From this theoretical perspective the situational context determines the text and textual analysis should reflect a movement from the outside inwards We have taken as our starting point the observation that meanings are created by the social system and are exchanged by the members in the form of text Persistence and change in the social system are both reflected in text and brought about by means of text text as the semantic process of social dynamics Halliday 1978 141 9 <PERSON>Yuri Lotman</PERSON> in his groundbreaking work on a semiotic theory of culture finds the language of literary texts to be the best vehicle for identifying specific semiotic codes prevalent among different social groups in different historical periods In the literary text there is an optimal correlation whereby the conflicting structures are disposed not hierarchically but dialogically on the same level This is why a literary narrative is the most flexible and effective modeling mechanism for describing extremely complex structures and situations in their entirety <PERSON>Lotman</PERSON> 1990 163 Cultural semiotics justifies the study of the literary canon as a rich source of cultural memory a portrait of the peculiar idiosyncrasy of an era and an open examination of social and racial taboos In the case of Spanish culture reading <PERSON>Cervantes</PERSON> and his Golden Age contemporaries bears this out Los caracteres peculiares de nuestro idioma no han tenido manifestaci n literaria m s amplia varia y plena que en las obras cervantinas The works of <PERSON>Cervantes</PERSON> exhibit the most sweeping most varied and fullest representation of the unique attributes of our language Lapesa 1962 vii 10 <ORGANIZATION>GALGO</ORGANIZATION> an online glossary of select keywords from the Spanish Golden Age 1 seeks to instantiate language as social semiotic by linking the semantic configurations of a literary text simultaneously to the cultural environment the linguistic system and the social system Halliday 1978 142 The computer is an ideal semiotic machine <PERSON>Olsen</PERSON> 1993 1994 313 to expose these overlapping layers of meaning Applying the conceptual design of M A K <PERSON>Halliday</PERSON> s social semiotic model GALGO s interpretive apparatus provides the field of discourse or context of situation for the text in which a specific keyword appears The field of discourse presents clusters word groupings of semiotic affinity that describe the social action that is taking place in the text GALGO also performs an interpretation of the tenor of discourse highlighting sociological variables connected to class status gender role and racial category that refine a keyword s meaning from the perspective of interpersonal relationships Finally GALGO adds commentary on discursive structures such as patterns of grammar syntactic nuances and figurative language that surround the keyword in the text 11 This method encourages students to unravel the cultural genealogy of pivotal terms that resist easy signification and whose lexical value s often differ from today s All keyword definitions undergo a multilayered social semiotic analysis that can be compared and contrasted across texts You ve got to see the text as an actualized potential which means that you have got to study the potential We are interested in what a particular writer has written comparatively against the background of what he might have written against the background of other things he has written or that other people have written Halliday 1978 57 58 In this way GALGO guides learners to pursue the deep connections that exist between language literature and society 2 The <ORGANIZATION>Digital Tool Navigating GALGO</ORGANIZATION> 2 12 <ORGANIZATION>GALGO</ORGANIZATION> s strength resides in the synchronic connectivity that the system facilitates when identifying the constellation of meanings for any given keyword From a technical perspective the database development has been a complex process requiring multiple prototypes of the glossary and many iterations of interface applications The system must have the ability to identify the absolute position of all uses of a keyword across multiple texts and perform this task in an efficient way so that large texts can be managed and search times minimized for both users and system administrators GALGO is constructed in such a way that users can not only access existing analysis within the database but also can assume when instructed to do so the role of the system administrator and contribute their own annotations 13 When a user logs on to read a particular literary work the document is loaded first into a browser frame Once the work is loaded it opens the user side interface The user interface is straightforward so that one can quickly locate specific keywords in the work view definitions and visualize the web of semantic relationships that surround those keywords A persistent navigation system lists the keywords in the database to the far right of the literary work and gives the multiple definitions for each word There are hyperlinks to the 17th and 18th century Spanish dictionaries from which the definitions are taken and GALGO s English translations are derived 3 Figure 1 is a screenshot taken from GALGO that illustrates the multiple definitions for the keyword honra its conjugations under Variations in the <ORGANIZATION>La Celestina</ORGANIZATION> and links to all of the uses of honra One can at any time browse a work by keyword clicking on a specific instance through Uses in this Work and navigate to that textual location image Figure 1 14 Users can opt to read the entire work linearly viewing it as a single continuous page When they come to a highlighted keyword they click on that word to see the specific contextualized definition That specific definition is given along with links to other places where that definition appears both in the work being read as well as in other works in the database The purpose of the glossary is not simply to trace the usage of a particular word but rather to trace the usage of a particular definition of a particular word across many texts Figure 2 and Figure 3 show screenshots of the same definition for honra in two different works <LOCATION>La Celestina</LOCATION> and El Abencerraje Comparing these distinct analyses of the definition by exploring Other Places this Definition is Found serves to expand and clarify its meaning for the reader 15 image Figure 2 16 image Figure 3 17 GALGO s main feature is a powerful clustering analysis tool that allows users to see how a particular definition of a keyword is determined A list of grouped terms given in the field of discourse reveals the pertinent vocabulary to focus on in and around the keyword The analysis of the role relationships in a literary passage appears as the tenor of discourse identifying social discourse categories at play such as identity class ethnicity or gender Finally the commentary box links form with content deciphering the relevant rhetorical strategies Figure 4 Figure 5 and Figure 6 offer views across different works that detail the interwoven strands of meaning 18 image Figure 4 19 image Figure 5 20 image Figure 6 21 The process of data entry and keyword annotation has been successfully streamlined for system administrators in this current version of GALGO To create a new text all the administrator needs to do is fill out a simple web form providing a title specific metadata and uploading a TEI XML encoded text file Once uploaded the text document is read into a buffer The document is stored on the server in its unaltered state so it can be used later as an inviolable document of record The search index contains every keyword in the work and its absolute position in that work Each word also contains an absolute unique identifier allowing the system to quickly locate that word in every other work 22 Administrators enter a keyword manually and the application scans the document to find and highlight every instance of the keyword and prepares a list of those keywords in the database When administrators click on an undefined usage either in the document or in the word use list an editing interface opens In this interface a definition from a list of definitions already associated with the keyword can be selected or a new definition can be entered Upon submitting the definition is associated with both the keyword itself and with the particular usage selected The clustering tool allows administrators to annotate these definitions explaining why certain word clusters are key to understanding the text referencing both field and tenor of discourse A client side selection tool permits the administrators to determine the boundaries of the text by choosing neighboring terms to cluster with the keyword These words their position in the text and the keyword itself together make up the field of discourse 23 GALGO is comprised of a team of faculty and student administrators who are building the database with research previously collected in Spanish Golden Age literature seminars <ORGANIZATION>Providence College</ORGANIZATION> students have utilized the social semiotic methodology underlying GALGO for several years now with successful outcomes both in terms of their growth as language majors and critical thinkers <PERSON>Alonso Garc</PERSON> a and <PERSON>Caplan</PERSON> 2014 114 115 Currently the keyword analysis completed in these classes is being input and following that work the system will be expanded to include five additional literary works from the period and five new keywords The project has received public recognition from <ORGANIZATION>Providence College</ORGANIZATION> the digital humanities community and the local <LOCATION>Rhode Island</LOCATION> Spanish speaking media 4 24 Given that the sophisticated and powerful digital architecture behind GALGO can accommodate any set of works whether in another language or another discipline we are in the process of seeking feedback from a broader audience of colleagues and students Focus groups will be conducted to test the platform s capabilities and discuss its applicability beyond the field of Spanish literary studies The nature of <ORGANIZATION>GALGO</ORGANIZATION> s new analytical and visualization functions will be impacted by the results of the focus group sessions Future system development might include advanced language manipulation and search functions In particular it might include language specific stemming index algorithms that would make it possible to match natural language terms and clusters across multiple works There could also be a quantitative facet to the cluster analysis that would determine the keyword s distributional profile 5 DP with respect to underlying semantic relationships GALGO s interface could be enhanced to provide dynamic views that reveal the distribution and intricacy of clustered lexical webs across any corpus 3 Multimodal Literacy Blending Old Literature with New Media 25 Students in the 21st century are equipped with a set of literacy skills honed through their extensive interactions on social media that enables them to communicate instantly with combinations of words images and videos The intertextuality of messages and unlimited data stream as well as the participatory atmosphere of cyberspace have expanded the ways in which young people amass knowledge understand concepts and interact in the world In their high school and college classes the <ORGANIZATION>Google Generation</ORGANIZATION> inclined to interact with texts more freely is reluctant to interpret meaning solely in the context of a single mode and expects to generate its own questions with respect to the subject matter <PERSON>Calandra</PERSON> and <PERSON>Lee 2005 Giglio</PERSON> and Venecek 2009 Arguably faculty today have the responsibility to meet students on their turf and honor their existing interests and expertise <PERSON>Jenkins</PERSON> and <PERSON>Kelley</PERSON> 2013 to better support them in their long term intellectual pursuits <PERSON>Bowen</PERSON> and Witthaus 2013 26 An entirely new textual landscape has emerged as a result of on screen communication environments Carrington 2005 Just as occurred with the introduction of printing over five hundred years ago information technology is spawning new practices of creating reading and interpreting texts Digitized documents represent a vast expanse of varied data that can be instantaneously searched sorted and categorized The theory of multimodal literacy <PERSON>Kress</PERSON> and van <PERSON>Leeuwen</PERSON> 2001 <PERSON>Kress</PERSON> 2003 posits that assimilating the semiotic resources of written language audiovisual images and interactive elements on screen is a distinct but not incompatible exercise from that of print based reading and writing Textuality as such survives the technological revolution intact Electronic technology does not replace the text but actually extends and supplements certain features of textuality by increasing our power to switch between texts of various kinds <PERSON>Harpham</PERSON> 2005 24 The interactive modality offered by the electronic medium has led to a form of reading coined hyperreading computer assisted human reading that includes strategies such as skimming hyperlinking and scanning <PERSON>Hayles</PERSON> 2010 66 Our digital tool GALGO is founded on hyperreading It enables a reader quickly to construct landscapes of associated research fields and subfields it shows ranges of possibilities it identifies texts and passages most relevant to a given query and it easily juxtaposes many different texts and passages Hayles 2010 66 27 <PERSON>Nicholas Carr</PERSON> says this reliance on digital multimedia disembodied texts <PERSON>Nicholas</PERSON> and <PERSON>Clark</PERSON> 2012 97 is altering the depth not only of our thoughts but also of our emotions Certainly hyperreading has its fair share of detractors Hayles 2010 and <PERSON>Carr</PERSON> is the most cogent voice in arguing that it spawns shallow thinking Carr 2010 But in other significant ways textual fragmentation captures what the study of language has always entailed looking through language to the reality that it represents and looking at the language that represents it Kramsch 2002 By highlighting patterns parallelisms and intertextual juxtapositions hyperreading draws on visual techniques used in viewing a painting Kramsch 2002 and aligns well with the rich tradition of annotation found in cultural artifacts of earlier historical periods Before the mid 18th century many Western readers if they read at all sampled from a variety of texts for which a linear reading would not be advisable periodicals almanacs collections the Bible <PERSON>Jenkins</PERSON> and <PERSON>Kelley</PERSON> 2013 2018 28 Multimodal learners employ hyperreading to navigate the Web according to their own interests and intuitively perceive reading and writing as social cultural and creative processes rather than simply as motor skills or linguistic acts Gee 2010 O <PERSON>Halloran</PERSON> and <PERSON>Lim</PERSON> define the multimodal literate person as one who is sensitized to the meaning potential and choices afforded in the production of the text rendering an enhanced ability to make deliberate and effective choices in the construction and presentation of knowledge O <PERSON>Halloran</PERSON> and Lim 2011 4 Technology offers opportunities for discourse analysis that the fixity of one graphic representation the printed page <PERSON>Jewitt</PERSON> 2005 cannot and frees the reader to create multiple paths and relate with the text in a personally meaningful way 29 We believe then that textual analysis in the digital era has the potential to connect readers in more direct ways with primary sources from the distant past By ensuring that close reading interacts synergistically with the kind of Web and hyperreading in which our young people are increasingly immersed <PERSON>Hayles</PERSON> 2010 75 students of the humanities can surpass space and time boundaries and effectively activate the meaning generating mechanism <PERSON>Lotman</PERSON> 1990 of older canonical literature Text and readership seek mutual understanding They adapt to each other A text behaves like a partner in dialogue it re orders itself as far as its supply of structural indeterminacy allows in the image of the readership And the reader responds likewise using his or her informational flexibility for the restructuring which will draw him or her closer to the world of the text <PERSON>Lotman</PERSON> 1990 80 Conclusion 30 The vitality of literary classics depends on the ability and interest of each new generation of readers to participate actively in a process of continuous semantic ex change In alignment with this objective GALGO prioritizes two functions that other text analysis applications like Voyant Sinclair 2016 NVivo software and Paper Machines do not curation and contextual meaning <ORGANIZATION>GALGO</ORGANIZATION> allows a professor to create a curated exhibit in order to help students see the ebb and flow of particular words throughout a set of works Voyant for example is good at showing the usage cases of a particular word across a work but there is no way for a student encountering a complex work for the first time to make semantic connections without help Additionally with <ORGANIZATION>GALGO</ORGANIZATION> students can annotate a text themselves and a professor can review their work creating opportunities for guided self discovery and in depth conversation These other tools do not afford this because they lack the capacity to promote genuine collaboration on research 31 Finally <ORGANIZATION>GALGO</ORGANIZATION> allows a student to look beyond the word itself and trace contextual meaning rather than just the word A term is always connected to several different possible definitions These other tools only show the uses of a particular word and do not help a student understand that the same word can mean very different things depending on the fields and tenors of discourse It is unclear how useful it is just to see all the instances of a given word especially for students with limited knowledge of a particular work its period or even of the language in which it is written By showing the range of definitions for the keywords and allowing students to browse by one or more definitions GALGO exposes how the meanings of the keywords both recur and vary across texts Notes 1 The first four works that have been input into the database are El Abencerraje La historia de Abindarraez y la hermosa <PERSON>Jarifa La Celestina El Lazarillo</PERSON> de Tormes y de sus fortunas y adversidades and <ORGANIZATION>La Numancia</ORGANIZATION> The first five keywords are esfuerzo fuerza gentileza honra and voluntad 2 <ORGANIZATION>GALGO</ORGANIZATION> is under construction and can be accessed at http glossary mervideo us 3 The Tesoro de la lengua castellana o espa ola Treasure of the Castilian or Spanish Language by <PERSON>Sebasti n de Covarrubias</PERSON> published in 1611 can be found at http fondosdigitales us es fondos libros 765 16 tesoro de la lengua castellana o espanola and the three volume 18th century Diccionario de autoridades Dictionary of the <ORGANIZATION>Royal Spanish Academy</ORGANIZATION> is located at http web frl es DA html 4 Listen to the most recent interview with the authors and a student researcher on <ORGANIZATION>Rhode Island Latino Public Radio</ORGANIZATION> http lprnoticias com 2016 05 13 podcats galgo providence college entrevista con el dr pablo rodriguez 5 According to the Distributional Hypothesis the distributional profile DP of a word is determined by the strength of association of the word with co occurring words in the text <PERSON>Rubenstein</PERSON> and Goodenough 1965 Sch tze 1992 Pantel 2005 Works Cited <PERSON>Alonso Garc</PERSON> a and <PERSON>Caplan</PERSON> 2014 <PERSON>Alonso Garc</PERSON> a N and <PERSON>Caplan</PERSON> A Reading the World s Classics Critically A Keyword Based Approach to Literary Analysis in Foreign Language Studies Critical Inquiry in Language Studies 11 2 2014 100 120 Bowen 2012 <PERSON>Bowen</PERSON> J A Teaching Naked How Moving Technology Out of Your College Classroom Will Improve Student Learning <LOCATION>Jossey Bass San Francisco</LOCATION> 2012 <PERSON>Bowen</PERSON> and Witthaus 2013 <PERSON>Bowen</PERSON> T and <ORGANIZATION>Witthaus C Multimodal Literacies and Emerging Genres University of Pittsburgh Press Pittsburgh</ORGANIZATION> 2013 Brier 2012 Brier S Where s the Pedagogy The Role of Teaching and Learning in the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities In M K Gold ed Debates</ORGANIZATION> in the Digital Humanities 2012 http dhdebates gc cuny edu debates text 8 <PERSON>Calandra</PERSON> and Lee 2005 <PERSON>Calandra</PERSON> B and <PERSON>Lee J K</PERSON> The digital history and pedagogy project Creating an interpretative pedagogical historical website The Internet and Higher Education 8 4 2005 323 333 Carr 2010 <PERSON>Carr</PERSON> N The Shallows What the Internet is Doing to Our <ORGANIZATION>Brains W W Norton amp Co New York 2010 Carrington 2005 Carrington</ORGANIZATION> V New textual landscapes information and early literacy In J Marsh ed Popular Culture New Media and <ORGANIZATION>Digital Literacy</ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION>Early Childhood Routledge New York</LOCATION> 2005 13 27 <ORGANIZATION>Clement 2013 Clement T Text Analysis Data Mining</ORGANIZATION> and Visualizations in Literary Scholarship Literary Studies in the Digital Age An Evolving Anthology MLA Commons 2013 https dlsanthology commons mla org text analysis data mining and visualizations in literary scholarship Crane 2004 Crane G Classics and the Computer An End of the History In S <PERSON>Schreibman R Siemens amp J Unsworth</PERSON> eds A Companion to <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities Blackwell Oxford</ORGANIZATION> 2004 46 55 Drucker 2012 Drucker J Humanistic Theory and Digital Scholarship In M K Gold ed Debates in the Digital Humanities 2012 http dhdebates gc cuny edu debates text 34 Fern ndez G mez 1962 Fern ndez G mez C Vocabulario de Cervantes Pr logo de <ORGANIZATION>Rafael Lapesa Real Academia Espa</ORGANIZATION> ola <LOCATION>Madrid</LOCATION> 1962 Fyfe 2011 <PERSON>Fyfe</PERSON> P How to Not Read a Victorian Novel Journal of Victorian Culture 16 1 2011 84 88 Gee 2010 Gee J P A Situated Social Cultural Approach to Literacy and Technology In E A Baker ed The New Literacies Multiple Perspectives on Research and Practice The <ORGANIZATION>Guilford Press New York</ORGANIZATION> 2010 165 193 Giglio and Venecek 2009 <PERSON>Giglio</PERSON> and Venecek 2009 <PERSON>Giglio</PERSON> K and Venecek J The Radical Historicity of Everything Exploring Shakespearean Identity with Web 2 0 <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities Quarterly</ORGANIZATION> 3 3 2009 http www digitalhumanities org dhq vol 3 3 000063 000063 html Halliday 1978 Halliday M A K Language as Social Semiotic The <ORGANIZATION>Social Interpretation of Language and Meaning University Park Press Baltimore</ORGANIZATION> 1978 Halliday and Hasan 1989 Halliday M A K and <PERSON>Hasan</PERSON> R Language Context and Text Aspects of Language in a <ORGANIZATION>Social Semiotic Perspective Oxford University Press Oxford</ORGANIZATION> 1989 <PERSON>Halliday</PERSON> and <PERSON>Matthiessen</PERSON> 2004 Halliday M and <PERSON>Matthiessen</PERSON> C An Introduction to Functional Grammar Routledge <LOCATION>London</LOCATION> 2004 3rd ed Harpham 2005 Harpham G G Beneath and Beyond the Crisis in the Humanities New Literary History 36 1 2005 21 36 <PERSON>Hart</PERSON> et al 2005 <PERSON>Hart R Jarvis</PERSON> S <PERSON>Jennings</PERSON> W and <ORGANIZATION>Smith Howell D Political Keywords Using Language</ORGANIZATION> that Uses Us <ORGANIZATION>Oxford University Press Oxford</ORGANIZATION> 2005 Hayles 2010 <PERSON>Hayles K</PERSON> N How We Read Close Hyper Machine ADE Bulletin 150 2010 62 79 http nkhayles com how_we_read html <PERSON>Inman Berens</PERSON> 2014 <ORGANIZATION>Inman Berens K Interface Digital Pedagogy</ORGANIZATION> in the Humanities Concepts Models and Experiments MLA Commons 2014 https digitalpedagogy commons mla org keywords interface <PERSON>Jenkins</PERSON> and <PERSON>Kelley</PERSON> 2013 <PERSON>Jenkins</PERSON> H and <PERSON>Kelley</PERSON> W eds Reading in a Participatory Culture Remixing Moby <PERSON>Dick</PERSON> in the <ORGANIZATION>English Classroom Teachers College Press New York</ORGANIZATION> 2013 Jewitt 2005 <PERSON>Jewitt</PERSON> C Multimodality Reading and Writing for the 21st Century Discourse Studies in the <ORGANIZATION>Cultural Politics of Education</ORGANIZATION> 26 3 2005 315 331 <PERSON>Jewitt</PERSON> and <PERSON>Kress</PERSON> 2003 <PERSON>Jewitt</PERSON> C and <ORGANIZATION>Kress G eds Multimodal Literacy Peter Lang New York</ORGANIZATION> 2003 Kramsch 2002 Kramsch C Language and Culture A Social Semiotic Perspective ADFL Bulletin 33 2 2002 8 15 <ORGANIZATION>Kress 2003 Kress G Literacy</ORGANIZATION> in the <ORGANIZATION>New Media Age Routledge London amp New York 2003 Kress 2010 Kress G Multimodality A Social Semiotic Approach to Contemporary Communication Routledge London</ORGANIZATION> amp <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> 2010 <PERSON>Kress</PERSON> and van <PERSON>Leeuwen</PERSON> 2001 <PERSON>Kress G</PERSON> and <PERSON>van Leeuwen</PERSON> T Multimodal Discourse The Modes and Media of Contemporary Communication Arnold London 2001 Lambert 2002 <PERSON>Lambert</PERSON> J Digital Storytelling Capturing Lives Creating Community Digital Diner Press Berkeley 2002 Lapesa 1962 Lapesa R Pr logo In <PERSON>Fern</PERSON> ndez G mez <ORGANIZATION>C Vocabulario de Cervantes Real Academia Espa ola Madrid</ORGANIZATION> 1962 Liu 2012 Liu A The State of the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> A Report and a <ORGANIZATION>Critique Arts and Humanities</ORGANIZATION> in Higher Education 11 1 2 2012 8 41 Lotman 1990 Lotman Y M Universe of the Mind A Semiotic Theory of Culture I B Taurus amp Co <LOCATION>London England</LOCATION> 1990 Marsh 2005 Marsh J ed Popular Culture New Media and <ORGANIZATION>Digital Literacy</ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION>Early Childhood Routledge New York</LOCATION> 2005 Moretti 2013 <PERSON>Moretti</PERSON> F Distant Reading Verso Press <LOCATION>London England</LOCATION> 2013 <PERSON>Nicholas</PERSON> and <PERSON>Clark</PERSON> 2012 <PERSON>Nicholas D</PERSON> and <PERSON>Clark</PERSON> D Reading in the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Environment Learned Publishing</ORGANIZATION> 25 2 2012 93 98 <PERSON>Nilsson</PERSON> 2010 <PERSON>Nilsson</PERSON> M Developing voice in digital storytelling through creativity narrative and multimodality <ORGANIZATION>International Journal of Media Technology</ORGANIZATION> and Lifelong Learning 6 2 2010 148 160 Olsen 1993 1994 <ORGANIZATION>Olsen M Signs Symbols and Discourses A New Direction for Computer Aided Literature Studies Computers</ORGANIZATION> and the Humanities 27 5 6 1993 1994 309 314 O <PERSON>Halloran</PERSON> and Lim 2011 O Halloran K L and Lim F V Dimensioner af multimodal literacy Viden om L sning 10 2011 14 21 <ORGANIZATION>Pantel 2005 Pantel P Inducing</ORGANIZATION> ontological co occurrence vectors In Proceedings of the 43rd Conference of the <ORGANIZATION>Association for Computational Linguistics ACL</ORGANIZATION> 05 2005 125 132 Ramsey 2003 <PERSON>Ramsey</PERSON> S Toward an Algorithmic Criticism Literary and Linguistic Computing 18 2 2003 167 74 <PERSON>Ramsey</PERSON> and Rockwell 2012 <PERSON>Ramsey</PERSON> S and <ORGANIZATION>Rockwell G Developing</ORGANIZATION> Things Notes Toward an Epistemology of Building in the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities In M K Gold ed Debates</ORGANIZATION> in the Digital Humanities 2012 http dhdebates gc cuny edu debates text 11 <PERSON>Rubenstein</PERSON> and Goodenough 1965 <PERSON>Rubenstein</PERSON> H and <PERSON>Goodenough</PERSON> J Contextual correlates of synonymy Communications of the ACM 8 10 1965 627 633 Saif and <PERSON>Graeme</PERSON> 2006 Saif M and <ORGANIZATION>Graeme H Measuring Semantic Distance Using Distributional Profiles of Concepts Computional Linguistics</ORGANIZATION> 1 1 2006 1 34 <PERSON>Schreibman</PERSON> and <PERSON>Hanlon</PERSON> 2010 <PERSON>Schreibman</PERSON> S and <PERSON>Hanlon</PERSON> A M <ORGANIZATION>Determining Value for Digital Humanities Tools</ORGANIZATION> Report on a Survey of <ORGANIZATION>Tool Developers Digital Humanities Quarterly</ORGANIZATION> 4 2 2010 http www digitalhumanities org dhq vol 4 2 000083 000083 html Sch tze 1992 Sch tze H Dimensions of meaning In Proceedings of the 1992 ACM IEEE Conference on Supercomputing Supercomputing 92 1992 787 796 Sinclair 2003 Sinclair S Computer Assisted Reading Reconceiving Text Analysis Literary and Linguistic Computing 18 2 2003 175 184 Sinclair 2016 Sinclair S and <ORGANIZATION>Rockwell G Hermeneutica Computer Assisted Interpretation in the Humanities MIT Press Cambridge</ORGANIZATION> 2016 Walsh 2009 <PERSON>Walsh</PERSON> M Pedagogic Potentials of Multimodal Literacy In Tan Wee Hin L and <PERSON>Subramanian</PERSON> R eds Handbook of Research on <ORGANIZATION>New Media Literacy</ORGANIZATION> at the K 12 Level Issues and Challenges I and II IGI Global U S 2009 32 47 Walsh 2010 <PERSON>Walsh</PERSON> M Multimodal literacy What does it mean for classroom practice Australian Journal of Language and Literacy 33 3 2010 211 239 Williams 1983 <ORGANIZATION>Williams R Keywords A Vocabulary of Culture and Society Oxford University Press New York</ORGANIZATION> NY 1983 2nd ed 2017 11 3 XML Print Article Please enable JavaScript to view the comments powered by Disqus URL http www digitalhumanities org dhq vol 11 3 000323 000323 html Last updated Comments dhqinfo digitalhumanities org Published by The <ORGANIZATION>Alliance of Digital Humanities Organizations Affiliated</ORGANIZATION> with Literary and Linguistic Computing Copyright 2005 image Creative Commons License This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution NoDerivatives 4 0 International License</ner>
