<ner>image DHQ Logo image Digital Humanities Quarterly Logo homesubmissionsabout dhqdhq peoplecontact Current Issue 2017 11 4 Preview Issue 2018 12 1 Previous Issues 2017 11 3 2017 11 2 2017 11 1 2016 10 4 2016 10 3 2016 10 2 2016 10 1 2015 9 4 2015 9 3 2015 9 2 2015 9 1 2014 8 4 2014 8 3 2014 8 2 2014 8 1 2013 7 3 2013 7 2 2013 7 1 2012 6 3 2012 6 2 2012 6 1 2011 5 3 2011 5 2 2011 5 1 2010 4 2 2010 4 1 2009 3 4 2009 3 3 2009 3 2 2009 3 1 2008 2 1 2007 1 2 2007 1 1 Indexes Title Author image sidenavbarimg ISSN 1938 4122 Announcements Call for Reviewers Call for Submissions image button1 addthis gif DHQ Digital Humanities Quarterly Author Biographies <PERSON>Florentina Armaselu Florentina Armaselu</PERSON> is a research scientist at the Centre for Contemporary and Digital History C2DH of the <ORGANIZATION>University of Luxembourg With</ORGANIZATION> a background in Computer Science literature and linguistics her research focuses on text encoding digital scholarly editions text analysis and Human Computer Interaction <PERSON>Natalie Berkman Natalie Berkman</PERSON> is a doctoral candidate in the Department of French and Italian at <ORGANIZATION>Princeton University</ORGANIZATION> currently working on her dissertation on the mathematical methods of the Oulipo under the direction of Professor <PERSON>David Bellos An</PERSON> associated member of the <ORGANIZATION>ANR</ORGANIZATION> DifdePo she is also coordinator of the transcription team for the <LOCATION>Oulipo</LOCATION> archival transcription project Her dissertation examines various branches of mathematical thought set theory algebra combinatorics algorithms and geometry on the philosophy and production of the Oulipo and the reception of Oulipian texts She is currently working on completing one of the <ORGANIZATION>Princeton Center for Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> inaugural projects for the 2015 6 academic year which consists of digital annexes for her dissertation that she is programming herself in Python <PERSON>Rhiannon Stephanie Bettivia Rhiannon Bettivia</PERSON> is a postdoctoral research associate at the <ORGANIZATION>University of Illinois Urbana Champaign Her</ORGANIZATION> research examines the politics and discourses of the growing sub field of digital preservation and investigates new methodologies for preserving the interpretive framework for digital materials She has published in the <ORGANIZATION>International Journal of Digital Curation</ORGANIZATION> about her work on the IMLS grant Preserving Virtual Worlds II among other publications and presentations in the fields of information science digital humanities and communications She also teaches in the areas of digital preservation metadata and the role of libraries and information in society in the <ORGANIZATION>School of Information Sciences</ORGANIZATION> at the <ORGANIZATION>University of Illinois</ORGANIZATION> <PERSON>Antonis Bikakis Antonis Bikakis</PERSON> is a senior lecturer of Computing and <ORGANIZATION>Artificial Intelligence</ORGANIZATION> in the <ORGANIZATION>Department of Information Studies of University College London UCL</ORGANIZATION> and co director of its <ORGANIZATION>Knowledge Organisation and Representation Group</ORGANIZATION> His main research interests are in knowledge representation nonmonotonic reasoning argumentation multi agent systems and knowledge based systems for the Semantic Web and Ambient Intelligence He has participated in various <LOCATION>EU</LOCATION> funded and national research projects He is currently Principal Investigator in <LOCATION>CrossCult</LOCATION> a research project funded by the <ORGANIZATION>European Commission</ORGANIZATION> s Horizon 2020 initiative which uses Semantic Web and other cutting edge technology to connect digital cultural resources lying in different cultural heritage venues across <LOCATION>Europe</LOCATION> Andrew <PERSON>Bretz</PERSON> Department of English and Film Studies Contract Faculty <PERSON>Mattie Burkert Mattie Burkert</PERSON> is an Assistant Professor of English at <ORGANIZATION>Utah State University</ORGANIZATION> <PERSON>Alison Caplan Alison Caplan</PERSON> is an Assistant Professor of Spanish at <ORGANIZATION>Providence College</ORGANIZATION> focusing on Medieval and Golden Age Spanish history and literature <PERSON>Anela Chan Anela Chan</PERSON> is a Data Scientist in Analytics at the social network blogging platform Tumblr Previously she was Lead Data Scientist at the marketing tech startup Contently and a Senior Economic Analyst at the <ORGANIZATION>Federal Reserve Bank of New York Anela</ORGANIZATION> built Sonic <LOCATION>Japan</LOCATION> while undertaking the Master of <ORGANIZATION>Information Technology</ORGANIZATION> course with a specialty in Computing at the <ORGANIZATION>University of Melbourne School of Engineering</ORGANIZATION> <PERSON>Richard Chenhall Richard Chenhall</PERSON> is Associate Professor in <ORGANIZATION>Medical Anthropology</ORGANIZATION> in the <ORGANIZATION>Melbourne School of Population Health</ORGANIZATION> at the <ORGANIZATION>University of Melbourne</ORGANIZATION> In addition to scholarly articles that focus on alcohol self help groups in <LOCATION>Japan</LOCATION> and health and illness in Indigenous <LOCATION>Australia</LOCATION> his major publications include <PERSON>Benelong</PERSON> s Haven 2007 Social Determinants of Health 2007 and Sleep Around the World 2013 <ORGANIZATION>Caitlin Christian Lamb Christian Lamb</ORGANIZATION> is the Associate Archivist of <ORGANIZATION>Davidson College</ORGANIZATION> a Review Editor for dh lib and co chair of the <ORGANIZATION>Society of American Archivists Standards Committee</ORGANIZATION> <PERSON>Alex Christie Alex Christie</PERSON> is Assistant Professor in Digital Prototyping at <ORGANIZATION>Brock University s Centre for Digital Humanities His</ORGANIZATION> research draws from modernist practice to experiment with digital knowledge production including recovering manuscripts as game based reading experiences and warping historical maps to express diverse representations of space He led the <LOCATION>Pegagogy Toolkit</LOCATION> project with microgrant funding from the <ORGANIZATION>Association for Computers</ORGANIZATION> and the Humanities <PERSON>Eric Dye Eric Dye</PERSON> is a photographer graphics designer and journalist While pursuing liberal studies at <ORGANIZATION>Penn State</ORGANIZATION> <PERSON>Behrend</PERSON> he also worked at The <LOCATION>Behrend Beacon</LOCATION> as the Creative Director and Opinion Editor He is currently a Projectionist at the <LOCATION>Tom Ridge Environmental Center</LOCATION> in <LOCATION>Erie Pennsylvania</LOCATION> <PERSON>Laura Estill Laura Estill</PERSON> is an Associate Professor of English at <LOCATION>Texas</LOCATION> A amp M University Her research has appeared journals such as Digital Studies Champ Num rique Digital Literary Studies Shakespeare Quarterly and Studies in English Literature Her monograph Dramatic Extracts in Seventeenth Century English Manuscripts Watching Reading Changing Plays appeared in 2015 to positive reviews <PERSON>Calvin Fung Calvin Fung</PERSON> is currently pursuing a PhD in Creative Writing His thesis includes a creative component in the form of a Gothic novel set in <LOCATION>Hong Kong</LOCATION> and a critical component examining the way in which the cultural specificity of <LOCATION>Hong Kong</LOCATION> interacts with the Gothic genre to extend the postcolonial Gothic and Asian Gothic spectra His research interests include interdisciplinary narratology Gothic literary studies and postcolonial studies <PERSON>Nuria Alonso Garc</PERSON> a <PERSON>Nuria Alonso Garcia</PERSON> is a civically engaged educator in the fields of linguistics global studies and urban education Her research revolves around intercultural literacy and TESOL Her engaged pedagogy strives to develop service and experiential learning initiatives that address how issues of international resonance intersect with concerns experienced by local communities She has led community engagement projects in <LOCATION>Mexico</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Nicaragua</LOCATION> and engaged with learners and scholars from <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> during her Fulbright appointment at the <ORGANIZATION>Saint Petersburg State Polytechnical University Institute of Humanities</ORGANIZATION> where she is currently a visiting professor <PERSON>Dene Grigar</PERSON> writing content analysis annotation cleanup editing commenting teaching and collaboration <PERSON>Jacob Heil</PERSON> writing annotation cleanup editing contextualizing commenting and collaboration <PERSON>Charles van den Heuvel Charles van den Heuvel</PERSON> is <ORGANIZATION>Head Research of History of Science and Scholarship</ORGANIZATION> at the <ORGANIZATION>Huygens Institute</ORGANIZATION> for the History of the <LOCATION>Netherlands</LOCATION> of the <ORGANIZATION>Royal Netherlands Academy of Arts and Sciences</ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION>Amsterdam</LOCATION> Furthermore he holds the chair Digital Methods and Historical Disciplines at the <ORGANIZATION>University of Amsterdam Kate Holterhoff Kate Holterhoff</ORGANIZATION> is a Marion L Brittain Postdoctoral Fellow at the <ORGANIZATION>Georgia Institute of Technology Her</ORGANIZATION> research areas include nineteenth century British literature visual culture digital humanities and the history of science She has published articles in English Literature in Transition 1880 1920 forthcoming The Journal of Victorian Culture The Journal of the History of Biology and Victorian Network <PERSON>Patricia Hswe Patricia Hswe</PERSON> is the Program Officer for Scholarly Communications at the <ORGANIZATION>Andrew W Mellon Foundation</ORGANIZATION> In this role she helps manage and monitor the program s grant portfolio which addresses key areas such as preservation electronic publishing and access and library services <PERSON>Patricia</PERSON> holds a MSLIS from the <ORGANIZATION>University of Illinois at Urbana Champaign</ORGANIZATION> a PhD from <ORGANIZATION>Yale University</ORGANIZATION> and an AB from <ORGANIZATION>Mount Holyoke College She</ORGANIZATION> is active in the <ORGANIZATION>Association of College and Research Libraries</ORGANIZATION> and was recently elected to the <ORGANIZATION>Executive Council of the Association for Computers</ORGANIZATION> and the Humanities <PERSON>Bridget Jenkins Bridget Jenkins</PERSON> graduated from <ORGANIZATION>Penn State</ORGANIZATION> <PERSON>Behrend</PERSON> with a BA in English and Professional Writing major in the spring of 2016 She also served as the Managing Editor at her college newspaper The Behrend Beacon She is currently a Technical Recruiter for <ORGANIZATION>All Lines Technology in West Palm Beach Florida Janelle Jenstad Associate Professor University of Victoria Director Map of Early Modern London Wooseob Jeong Dean</ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION>Richel Distinguished Professor School of Library and Information Management</ORGANIZATION> founded in 1902 <ORGANIZATION>Emporia State University</ORGANIZATION> founded in 1863 <PERSON>Shannon Kelley</PERSON> English Department Assistant Professor <PERSON>Kara Kennedy Kara Kennedy</PERSON> is a PhD Candidate in English focusing on science fiction and feminism in the twentieth century as well as <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> in relation to science fiction and education <ORGANIZATION>Kimmo Kettunen National Library of Finland Centre for Digitization and Preservation</ORGANIZATION> <PERSON>Tamara Kohn Tamara Kohn</PERSON> is Associate Professor of Anthropology in the <ORGANIZATION>School of Social and Political Sciences</ORGANIZATION> and Coordinator of Gender Studies in the Faculty of Arts at <ORGANIZATION>Melbourne University Her</ORGANIZATION> research has been focused on death studies incarceration and personhood communities of practice from caring practices to moving arts ethics and the anthropology of the body and senses Her most recent publications include Death and <ORGANIZATION>Digital Media Routledge</ORGANIZATION> 2017 co authored On the Shifting Ethics and Contexts of Knowledge Production in The Ethics of Knowledge Creation Berghahn 2017 and a book chapter associated with the Sonic <LOCATION>Japan</LOCATION> project co authored with Chenhall Being in Sound in Collaborative Intimacies in Music and Dance Berghahn 2017 <ORGANIZATION>Juha Kuokkala University of Helsinki Department</ORGANIZATION> of Finnish Nordic and Finno Ugric Studies <PERSON>Ioanna Kyvernitou Ioanna Kyvernitou</PERSON> is a PhD candidate in <ORGANIZATION>Digital Arts and Humanities</ORGANIZATION> at the <ORGANIZATION>National University of Ireland Galway Her</ORGANIZATION> research explores ways of combining women s studies history of philosophy and ontology engineering in order to model information contained in early modern women s works related to philosophical issues <PERSON>Tara LaLonde Tara LaLonde</PERSON> is a GIS Specialist at <ORGANIZATION>Penn State University Libraries She</ORGANIZATION> has a Master of Science in Geography from <ORGANIZATION>Michigan State University</ORGANIZATION> and a Bachelor of Arts in Geography from <ORGANIZATION>Colgate University Prior</ORGANIZATION> to working at the <ORGANIZATION>University Libraries</ORGANIZATION> she worked in the geospatial technology industry <PERSON>Brandon T Locke Brandon Locke</PERSON> is a <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities and Social Science Specialist</ORGANIZATION> in the Department of History at <ORGANIZATION>Michigan State University</ORGANIZATION> and is Director of the Lab for the <ORGANIZATION>Education and Advancement in Digital Research LEADR Laura L fberg Department of Linguistics and English Language Lancaster University</ORGANIZATION> UK <PERSON>Simon Mahony Simon Mahony</PERSON> is Principal Teaching Fellow and Programme Director of the MA MSc in <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> at the <ORGANIZATION>Department of Information Studies University College London UCL</ORGANIZATION> and Associate Director for Teaching at the <ORGANIZATION>UCL Centre for Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> UCLDH He teaches a range of technical and non technical modules and has current research interests in the application of new technologies to the study of the ancient world using new web based mechanisms and digital resources to build and sustain learning communities collaborative an innovative working He is also active in the field of distance learning a member of the <ORGANIZATION>University of London s Centre for Distance Education</ORGANIZATION> an Associate Fellow at the <ORGANIZATION>Institute of Classical Studies School of Advance Study University of London</ORGANIZATION> and one of the founding organisers of the Digital Classicist <PERSON>Aaron Mauro Dr Aaron Mauro</PERSON> is Assistant Professor of <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> and English at <ORGANIZATION>Penn State</ORGANIZATION> <PERSON>Behrend He</PERSON> is the director of the <ORGANIZATION>Penn State Digital Humanities Lab</ORGANIZATION> and teaches on topics relating to digital culture computational text analysis and scholarly communication His articles on U S literature and culture have appeared in Modern Fiction Studies Mosaic and Symploke among others He has also published on issues relating to digital humanities in both <ORGANIZATION>Digital Studies and Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> Quarterly <PERSON>Jim McGrath Jim McGrath</PERSON> is currently a postdoctoral fellow in <ORGANIZATION>Digital Public Humanities</ORGANIZATION> at the <ORGANIZATION>John Nicholas Brown Center for Public Humanities and Cultural Heritage Brown University</ORGANIZATION> He is on Twitter JimMc_Grath <PERSON>Kim McLean Fiander</PERSON> Assistant Teaching Professor <ORGANIZATION>University of Victoria Director of Pedagogy and Outreach Map of Early Modern London Kathryn R McPherson Professor of English Utah Valley University Brad Mering Brad Mering</ORGANIZATION> is a Web Developer specializing in applications designed for teaching and researching in the humanities <PERSON>Kate Miffitt Kate Miffitt</PERSON> is Assistant Director of the <ORGANIZATION>Office of Digital Learning</ORGANIZATION> in the <ORGANIZATION>College of Arts amp Architecture</ORGANIZATION> at the <LOCATION>Pennsylvania</LOCATION> State University Her work includes identifying and developing new online programs and enhancing teaching and learning with technology with a focus on arts and humanities pedagogies <PERSON>Emily Christina Murphy</PERSON> Dr <PERSON>Emily Christina Murphy</PERSON> is a postdoctoral fellow with the Linked Modernisms Project at the <ORGANIZATION>University of Victoria</ORGANIZATION> From 2013 2015 she was instructor and Assistant Director at the <ORGANIZATION>Field School in Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> at the <ORGANIZATION>Bader International Study Centre UK Queen s University Canada She</ORGANIZATION> teaches introductory topics across the DH training network and undergraduate and graduate courses in modernist literature social networks in literature and digital humanities practice Her published writing includes articles on <PERSON>Samuel Beckett</PERSON> and a digital monograph on Canadian women journalists in the Spanish Civil War with the archival recovery project <LOCATION>Canada</LOCATION> and the Spanish Civil War Eetu M kel Assistant Professor in <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities University of Helsinki James O Sullivan James O Sullivan</ORGANIZATION> is <ORGANIZATION>Lecturer in Digital Arts amp Humanities at University College Cork National University of Ireland He</ORGANIZATION> has previously held faculty positions at the <ORGANIZATION>University of Sheffield</ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION>Pennsylvania State University</ORGANIZATION> His work has been published in a variety of interdisciplinary journals including <ORGANIZATION>Digital Scholarship</ORGANIZATION> in the <ORGANIZATION>Humanities Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> Quarterly <PERSON>Leonardo</PERSON> and Hyperrhiz New Media Cultures He is the co editor of Reading Modernism with Machines <PERSON>Palgrave Macmillan</PERSON> 2016 <PERSON>James</PERSON> is Associate Director of the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities Summer Institute</ORGANIZATION> as well as Chair of the DHSI Colloquium Further information on <PERSON>James</PERSON> and his work can be found at josullivan org <PERSON>Miriam</PERSON> Pe a <ORGANIZATION>Pimentel Lecturer</ORGANIZATION> at the <ORGANIZATION>Faculty of Philosophy and Literature UNAM Sarah Pickle Sarah Pickle UNC</ORGANIZATION> 2005 is the assessment librarian at the <LOCATION>Claremont Colleges Library</LOCATION> In that role she designs and coordinates projects related to organizational effectiveness and planning at the Library She came to <LOCATION>Claremont</LOCATION> after serving as the <ORGANIZATION>Council on Library and Information Resources Social Science Data Curation Fellow</ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION>Penn</LOCATION> State Libraries She began her fellowship in 2014 after working for two years as an analyst at the not for profit organization Ithaka S R there her research focused on the efforts academic and cultural heritage institutions are making to create and sustain digital resources and services for scholars today Prior to joining Ithaka S R she completed her PhD in comparative literature at <ORGANIZATION>Cornell University</ORGANIZATION> <PERSON>Nathan Piekielek Nathan Piekielek</PERSON> is the Geospatial Services Librarian at The <LOCATION>Pennsylvania</LOCATION> State University He works in the <ORGANIZATION>University Libraries Research Hub</ORGANIZATION> where he supports the use of geospatial technologies across the university <PERSON>Sarah Potvin</PERSON> discovering gathering writing cleanup editing theorizing collaboration commenting and contextualizing <PERSON>Daniel Powell</PERSON> writing content analysis project management annotation cleanup editing commenting community building and collaboration <PERSON>Heather Ross Heather Dohn Ross</PERSON> holds a BS and MS in Experimental Psychology from <ORGANIZATION>Syracuse University She</ORGANIZATION> is the Manager of the <PERSON>Donald W Hamer</PERSON> Center for Maps and Geospatial Information <PERSON>Albert Rozo Albert Rozo</PERSON> is the Preservation Data Specialist in the <ORGANIZATION>Preservation Conservation and Digitization Department</ORGANIZATION> at <ORGANIZATION>Penn State University Libraries Prior</ORGANIZATION> to working at the Library <PERSON>Albert</PERSON> worked in a variety of positions in the Chemistry Entomology and Information Technology Departments at <ORGANIZATION>Penn State</ORGANIZATION> <PERSON>Albert</PERSON> is a Licensed Architect in the <LOCATION>State of Illinois</LOCATION> He has a BS in Architecture and is currently working towards an MS in <ORGANIZATION>Geographic Information Systems Teemu Ruokolainen Language</ORGANIZATION> technology consultant for <ORGANIZATION>Digital Collections</ORGANIZATION> project <PERSON>Alex Saum Pascual Alex Saum Pascual</PERSON> is Assistant Professor of Spanish at the <ORGANIZATION>University of California Berkeley</ORGANIZATION> where she teaches Contemporary Spanish Literature and Culture 20th and 21st Centuries and <ORGANIZATION>Electronic Literature Digital Humanities She</ORGANIZATION> is also part of the <ORGANIZATION>Executive Committee of the Berkeley Center for New Media Her</ORGANIZATION> academic work has been published in <LOCATION>Spain Mexico</LOCATION> and the <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> Her digital artwork has been exhibited in galleries and art festivals in the <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> and abroad <PERSON>Danica Savonick Danica Savonick</PERSON> is a PhD candidate in English and a Futures Initiative Fellow at the <ORGANIZATION>CUNY Graduate Center</ORGANIZATION> and a Teaching Fellow at <ORGANIZATION>Queens College Her</ORGANIZATION> dissertation The <ORGANIZATION>Promise of Aesthetic Education On Pedagogy Praxis and Social Justice</ORGANIZATION> analyzes the feminist and antiracist pedagogies of <PERSON>Adrienne Rich Audre Lorde June Jordan</PERSON> and <PERSON>Toni Cade Bambara</PERSON> all of whom taught in the SEEK educational opportunity program at the <ORGANIZATION>City University of New York</ORGANIZATION> in the late 1960s and 1970s Her research interests include 20th century and contemporary literary studies pedagogy and social justice <PERSON>Anelise Hanson Shrout Anelise Hanson Shrout</PERSON> is an assistant professor of history at <ORGANIZATION>California State University Fullerton Prior</ORGANIZATION> to <PERSON>CSUF Shrout</PERSON> was a postdoctoral fellow in digital Studies at <ORGANIZATION>Davidson College</ORGANIZATION> <PERSON>Shannon R Smith Shannon R Smith</PERSON> is Assistant Professor of English Literature at the <ORGANIZATION>Bader International Study Centre UK Queen s University Canada From</ORGANIZATION> 2013 2015 she served as the Director of the <ORGANIZATION>BISC</ORGANIZATION> s <ORGANIZATION>Field School</ORGANIZATION> in the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities Her</ORGANIZATION> research is concerned with histories of nineteenth and twentieth century communication and print production technologies the Internet and World Wide Web and the intersection between <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> maker culture and participatory art She has also published articles on literary theory and Victorian popular theatre sport and urban spaces <PERSON>Elizabeth Stainforth Elizabeth Stainforth</PERSON> is a <ORGANIZATION>Visiting Research Fellow</ORGANIZATION> in the School of Fine Art History of Art and <ORGANIZATION>Cultural Studies University of Leeds UK Her</ORGANIZATION> research investigates digital heritage cultures and the contemporary significance of memory for cultural heritage in the wake of digital technologies She has published in the journals Museum and <ORGANIZATION>Society Cultural Trends</ORGANIZATION> and The <ORGANIZATION>Journal of Curatorial Studies</ORGANIZATION> among others and is one of the editors of parallax journal She also works for <ORGANIZATION>Leeds University Library</ORGANIZATION> where she has been involved in projects with the Digital Content and Repositories Team Special Collections and the <ORGANIZATION>Stanley</ORGANIZATION> amp <PERSON>Audrey Burton</PERSON> Gallery <PERSON>Carolyn Stevens Carolyn S Stevens</PERSON> is Professor of Japanese Studies and Director of the Japanese Studies Centre at <ORGANIZATION>Monash University Her</ORGANIZATION> recent major publications include Japanese Popular Music Culture Authenticity and <ORGANIZATION>Power Routledge 2008 Disability in Japan Routledge</ORGANIZATION> 2013 and The Beatles in <LOCATION>Japan</LOCATION> 2018 as well as the co edited volumes Sound Space and Sociality in Modern <LOCATION>Japan</LOCATION> 2014 and Internationalising Japan 2014 She is currently Editor in Chief of the interdisciplinary journal Japanese Studies <PERSON>Lisa Tagliaferri Lisa Tagliaferri</PERSON> holds a PhD in Comparative Literature from the Graduate Center of the <ORGANIZATION>City University of New York</ORGANIZATION> an MSc in Computing and <ORGANIZATION>Information Systems</ORGANIZATION> from the <ORGANIZATION>University of London</ORGANIZATION> and an MA from <ORGANIZATION>Binghamton University Lisa</ORGANIZATION> s research focuses on early modern literature and digital pedagogy and she currently works with the <ORGANIZATION>Mellon</ORGANIZATION> funded <ORGANIZATION>CUNY Humanities Alliance</ORGANIZATION> <PERSON>Marinella Testori Marinella Testori</PERSON> is a Digital Humanist with specialism in linguistic annotation and lexicography for Latin Since 2010 she has been collaborating as Linguistic Annotator of the <ORGANIZATION>Index Thomisticus Treebank Project</ORGANIZATION> http itreebank marginalia it and since 2017 as Lexicographer at the <ORGANIZATION>CIRCSE Catholic University of Milan Italy She</ORGANIZATION> received two <ORGANIZATION>MM AA in Humanities and Historical Sciences</ORGANIZATION> at the <ORGANIZATION>Catholic University of Milan</ORGANIZATION> a Biblical Diploma at the <ORGANIZATION>Pontifical University of the Holy Cross</ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION>Rome</LOCATION> and a postgraduate degree in Text Informatics and Digital Scholarly Edition at the <ORGANIZATION>University of Arezzo Siena Italy</ORGANIZATION> She is currently working on her Ph D dissertation regarding corpus linguistics methods applied to the language of <PERSON>Thomas Aquinas</PERSON> at the <ORGANIZATION>Department of Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> at <ORGANIZATION>King s College</ORGANIZATION> <LOCATION>London Adriana</LOCATION> lvarez S nchez Associate Profesor at the <ORGANIZATION>Faculty of Philosophy and Literature UNAM</ORGANIZATION> URL http www digitalhumanities org dhq vol 11 3 bios html Last updated Comments dhqinfo digitalhumanities org Published by The <ORGANIZATION>Alliance of Digital Humanities Organizations Affiliated</ORGANIZATION> with Literary and Linguistic Computing Copyright 2005 image Creative Commons License This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution NoDerivatives 4 0 International License</ner>
