<ner>image DHQ Logo image Digital Humanities Quarterly Logo homesubmissionsabout dhqdhq peoplecontact Current Issue 2017 11 3 Preview Issue 2017 11 4 Previous Issues 2017 11 2 2017 11 1 2016 10 4 2016 10 3 2016 10 2 2016 10 1 2015 9 4 2015 9 3 2015 9 2 2015 9 1 2014 8 4 2014 8 3 2014 8 2 2014 8 1 2013 7 3 2013 7 2 2013 7 1 2012 6 3 2012 6 2 2012 6 1 2011 5 3 2011 5 2 2011 5 1 2010 4 2 2010 4 1 2009 3 4 2009 3 3 2009 3 2 2009 3 1 2008 2 1 2007 1 2 2007 1 1 Indexes Title Author image sidenavbarimg ISSN 1938 4122 Announcements Call for Reviewers Call for Submissions image button1 addthis gif DHQ Digital Humanities Quarterly 2017 Volume 11 Number 3 2017 11 3 XML Discuss Comments The MoEML Pedagogical Partnership Program <PERSON>Janelle Jenstad</PERSON> lt jenstad_at_uvic_dot_ca gt <ORGANIZATION>University of Victoria</ORGANIZATION> <PERSON>Kim McLean Fiander</PERSON> lt krdmf_at_uvic_dot_ca gt <ORGANIZATION>University of Victoria</ORGANIZATION> <PERSON>Kathryn R McPherson</PERSON> lt kmcpherson_at_uvu_dot_edu gt <ORGANIZATION>Utah Valley University</ORGANIZATION> Abstract Since 2014 <ORGANIZATION>The Map of Early Modern London MoEML</ORGANIZATION> has partnered with professors and students around the world in a unique collaboration between a digital humanities DH project and humanities classrooms The model we have developed addresses a sustainability challenge for DH projects provides professors with a way of meeting administrative demands for engaged learning and gives students a high stakes research based learning opportunity with the potential for an open access peer reviewed publication The MoEML Pedagogical Partnership Project emerged from a confluence of problems and opportunities One longstanding problem for DH practitioners is project based how do we sustain the projects already begun Another problem emerges as DH moves out of the big tent and sets up camp in humanities classrooms at smaller non R1 institutions Also for scholars not trained in the technologies that drive many DH projects crossing the analog digital divide might be daunting and discourage them from contributing to DH projects To address these challenges the MoEML Pedagogical Partnership takes Research Based Learning <ORGANIZATION>RBL</ORGANIZATION> models and turns them into high profile publication opportunities mobilizing ubiquitous social networking and communication technologies to connect the project with the new demographic of student contributors This essay will highlight how digital projects and digi curious professors can collaborate to develop innovative pedagogical practices that provide projects with content enliven professors pedagogy and invite students to acquire scholarly research skills gain digital literacy and engage in an interdisciplinary and international collaboration We argue that DH projects can be used innovatively and effectively in the classroom to promote <ORGANIZATION>RBL</ORGANIZATION> At the same time DH projects open access ones in particular can provide a home both for humanities research and for the fruits of digital pedagogy across a wide range of institutional settings Introduction 1 Since 2014 The Map of Early Modern <LOCATION>London</LOCATION> has partnered with professors and students around the world in a unique collaboration between a digital humanities DH project and humanities classrooms The model we have developed addresses a sustainability challenge for DH projects provides professors with a way of meeting administrative demands for engaged learning and gives students a high stakes research based learning opportunity with the potential for an open access peer reviewed publication The MoEML Pedagogical Partnership Project emerged from a confluence of problems and opportunities One longstanding problem for DH practitioners is project based how do we sustain the projects already begun Another problem emerges as DH moves out of the big tent and sets up camp in humanities classrooms 1 A complaint about DH is that it requires infrastructure and support and is therefore inaccessible to the have nots of the mainstream humanities <PERSON>Grusin</PERSON> 2014 Even if newcomers do have the resources to build something new thereby adding to the number of projects requiring curation and care must they do so in order to be doing DH Another problem faces potential contributors to DH projects crossing the analog digital divide can be daunting for scholars not trained in the technologies that drive many DH projects Projects and contributors share the need to disseminate and mobilize scholarship Academic faculty are increasingly enjoined to publish in open access fora which increases the need for reputable digital venues We also need to capture the original work of students for whom the processes of scholarly publishing regardless of medium can be alienating 2 To address these challenges the MoEML Pedagogical Partnership takes Research Based Learning <ORGANIZATION>RBL</ORGANIZATION> models and turns them into high profile publication opportunities mobilizing ubiquitous social networking and communication technologies to connect the project with the new demographic of student contributors For collaborators in classrooms around the world MoEML s challenges become opportunities Similarly challenges in the humanities become opportunities for MoEML This essay will highlight how digital projects and digi curious professors can collaborate to develop innovative pedagogical practices that provide projects with content enliven professors pedagogy and invite students to acquire scholarly research skills gain digital literacy and engage in an interdisciplinary and international collaboration We argue that DH projects can be used innovatively and effectively in the classroom to promote <ORGANIZATION>RBL</ORGANIZATION> At the same time DH projects open access ones in particular can provide a home both for humanities research and for the fruits of digital pedagogy across a wide range of institutional settings The Problems DH Project Sustainability 3 In the seventeen years since MoEML s inception as an intranet pedagogical tool the project has developed multiple resources that are far from completion the first is a descriptive Gazetteer of over one thousand streets sites administrative units and other features the second is a Library of texts that are crucial to our understanding of early modern literary <LOCATION>London</LOCATION> but are rarely anthologized or have never been edited at all As the MoEML team turned its attention to building the best possible platform adding a digital edition of the Agas map with built in drawing tools enabling GIS capabilities linking to <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> Maps working with other projects to geolocate their data and compiling finding aids and bibliographies the core resources of the site remained unfinished This problem is not unique to MoEML 2 <ORGANIZATION>Jenstad</ORGANIZATION> s students at the <ORGANIZATION>University of Windsor</ORGANIZATION> anticipated as long ago as 2002 that finishing MoEML would require the world to help Two prescient students <PERSON>Michael Davis</PERSON> and <PERSON>Tara Drouillard</PERSON> suggested that <PERSON>Jenstad</PERSON> invite contributions from other classrooms an idea that she found inspiring but unachievable in 2002 Engaged Learning and the Knowledge Mobilization Challenge 4 DH projects not only need to determine how to sustain themselves but are also expected by funding bodies and university administrators to make their work accessible to the wider public Understandably public funding agencies such as <ORGANIZATION>SSHRC Social Sciences and Humanities Research Council</ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION>Canada</LOCATION> or the <ORGANIZATION>NEH National Endowment for the Humanities</ORGANIZATION> in the <LOCATION>US</LOCATION> want scholars to give something back to taxpayers whose money supports their projects Digital Humanists might be more comfortable than other humanists with online open access publications but simply putting research on the web is not enough Furthermore professors of all stripes are increasingly being asked to mobilize knowledge make it public and quantify its impact while also engaging students in meaningful research In the twenty years since the <ORGANIZATION>Boyer Commission</ORGANIZATION> s report was published we have seen calls for research intensive courses capstone courses and undergraduate research scholarships across the disciplines and in institutions of all sizes It has been imposed by well meaning administrators on faculty members without in some cases much guidance about how to invite students into the research process or how to mobilize research for the public good We are not accustomed to expecting original research from undergraduate students even though we can offer them access to primary texts archival materials and tools that were unimaginable even ten years ago Even with these new resources some of us find it hard to imagine innovative ways to get our undergraduates involved in an historic research model that has generally been conducted by lone scholars working in an archive and then writing up their findings 3 An obvious solution to this challenge is to get more scholars involved in <ORGANIZATION>RBL</ORGANIZATION> and DH work How can we reach across to our fellow teachers especially those lacking technological skillsets and invite them to contribute their expertise to a digital project The Solution 5 For over ten years <PERSON>Jenstad</PERSON> incubated the idea put forward by her students in 2002 Certain material conditions had to pertain before she could develop the <ORGANIZATION>Pedagogical Partnership</ORGANIZATION> she envisioned grant funding a team of research assistants and a collaborator <PERSON>McLean Fiander</PERSON> But the key impetus to launch the Partnership came from faculty members outside DH who had been charged with doing undergraduate research in the classroom and mobilizing student scholarship A 2013 exchange on <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> and email between <PERSON>Peter Herman</PERSON> at <ORGANIZATION>San Diego State University SDSU</ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON>Jenstad</PERSON> at the <ORGANIZATION>University of Victoria UVic</ORGANIZATION> catalyzed the transformation of the 2002 Windsor students idea into the reality of MoEML s current Pedagogical Partnership <PERSON>Herman</PERSON> wrote that he was teaching a very small seminar the following semester that was supposed to focus on undergraduate research He wanted to go beyond Early English Books Online EEBO which he had been using successfully in the undergraduate classroom <PERSON>Herman</PERSON> 2015 and asked <PERSON>Jenstad</PERSON> if she had any innovative ideas about using MoEML in some way The timing was ideal With <PERSON>McLean Fiander</PERSON> having recently joined the MoEML team we had conceived the idea of starting a pilot project whereby we team up with professors in other locations supply teaching materials and have the students contribute to MoEML under the close supervision of their professor on site <PERSON>Jenstad</PERSON> wrote to <PERSON>Herman</PERSON> that We are keen to honour our pedagogical origins while upholding scholarly standards We think it s a win win win win proposition MoEML needs contributors and reviewers Because MoEML is rapidly growing beyond my capacity to edit every entry submitted I need to delegate some of the work Your student gets a publication for his her CV or graduate school application You would be credited as Guest Editor and would have an innovative teaching partnership to add to your teaching dossier Jenstad 2013 <PERSON>Herman</PERSON> s response that the project was exactly what the administrators around here want <PERSON>Herman</PERSON> 2013b confirmed that such a partnership had the potential to meet a new demand in academia 6 In its current form the partnership is an innovative scalable extensible model for teachers student researchers and digital humanities projects MoEML provides teaching materials for the module research guidance and a high profile publication opportunity for the class Professors work closely with students in their classes to produce a publishable encyclopedia entry edit an early modern text and or learn to transcribe and encode text MoEML gains an edited externally sourced contribution and builds a base of educated users who may well contribute in the future Calling on the crowd is one way to complete large projects Managing the crowd and maintaining standards have always been the challenges however Causer and <PERSON>Wallace</PERSON> 2012 In this partnership the professor functions like the Guest Editor of a journal issue responsible for vetting the content before it comes to the MoEML team in this way MoEML distributes the management of the crowd and delegates a certain amount of quality control The DH Part of the Solution 7 Including a MoEML module in a course does not necessarily involve teaching DH directly but it can provide DH skills and model DH values outside a formal DH curriculum It allows partners to teach robust research skills while using digital resources and or writing for the digital environment The MoEML module teaches student participants to write for a different medium the web Because we cite preferentially from open access resources students at large institutions learn to look beyond subscription resources while students from smaller institutions without journal and database subscriptions find that they are not disadvantaged in the research process Thus the partnership promotes the new models of dissemination pioneered by DH practitioners open access Creative Commons licensing new models of peer review and brings attention to projects that may not be indexed in library catalogues The high visibility of the module invites students to do their best work The complexity of the projects demands collaboration a hallmark of DH Different people bring different skills to the table Some students will be wizards with certain aspects of technology that may well be daunting for their professors Thus the module compresses and occasionally inverts hierarchies another hallmark of both DH work and <ORGANIZATION>RBL</ORGANIZATION> The RBL Part of the Solution 8 In its 1998 white paper Reinventing Undergraduate Education A Blueprint for <ORGANIZATION>America s Research Universities the Boyer Commission</ORGANIZATION> on Educating Undergraduates in the <ORGANIZATION>Research University</ORGANIZATION> recommended that <ORGANIZATION>RBL</ORGANIZATION> become the model of learning at R1 universities Boyer 1998 4 <ORGANIZATION>RBL</ORGANIZATION> entails inviting students into a community of learners where the instructor and the students are all pursuing an unanswered question together Lambert 2009 <PERSON>Smith</PERSON> and Rust 2011 The professor is neither the sage on the stage nor the guide on the side but a fellow investigator who offers mentorship to an apprentice investigator <ORGANIZATION>RBL</ORGANIZATION> offers students a high stakes learning opportunity gives them tools to ask and answer legitimate questions cultivates a spirit of collaboration and allows them to take ownership of the knowledge they produce Brew 2006 Brew and Jewell 2012 Model <ORGANIZATION>RBL</ORGANIZATION> opportunities include lab work fieldwork internships capstone courses undergraduate research awards research scholarships and course modules Lambert 2009 RBL is a natural fit for the <ORGANIZATION>Sciences and Social Sciences</ORGANIZATION> disciplines with teams working in laboratory settings or doing fieldwork regularly Walkington et al 2011 In the humanities DH projects and laboratories have the potential to offer <ORGANIZATION>RBL</ORGANIZATION> opportunities MoEML began in 1999 as an <ORGANIZATION>RBL</ORGANIZATION> exercise and has inspired and hosted further RBL projects since then 5 Reimagining <ORGANIZATION>RBL</ORGANIZATION> through DH Pedagogy 9 MoEML stands at the intersection of two distinct pressures to provide <ORGANIZATION>RBL</ORGANIZATION> opportunities and to respond to the impact of the digital revolution upon humanities research questions The pedagogical partnership reimagines the apprentice researcher model of <ORGANIZATION>RBL</ORGANIZATION> and the project based model of DH For good reason <ORGANIZATION>RBL</ORGANIZATION> tends to happen at R1 institutions and DH tends to happen at places with centres both are research and resource intensive A typical objection to <ORGANIZATION>RBL</ORGANIZATION> is that it is difficult to practice in small institutions that do not have extensive library technical or infrastructural resources Critics have said the same of DH Pannapacker 2013 The two objections to <ORGANIZATION>RBL</ORGANIZATION> and DH have tended to be mutually reinforcing In UVic s Maker Lab in the Humanities dir Jentery Sayers for example RAs develop Kits for Culture 6 However such opportunities are not course based and depend upon a funded lab for support At MoEML we provide comparable opportunities to students undertaking Directed Readings for course credit or <PERSON>Jamie Cassels</PERSON> Undergraduate Research Awards scholarships to conduct original research with a faculty member Again however these are elite opportunities predicated on competitive funding lab project space and supervisorial good will 10 Our own project is well supported at UVic by the <ORGANIZATION>Humanities Computing and Media Centre HCMC</ORGANIZATION> and we have enjoyed generous SSHRC funding 2012 2016 The pedagogical partnership permits MoEML to become a virtual lab shared by all our partners They use our bibliography gazetteer praxis guidelines encoding protocols and mapping tools In addition we are available to provide guidance on research agendas Just as <ORGANIZATION>RBL</ORGANIZATION> is usually an instance of a student picking a small aspect of the researcher s larger research question our pedagogical partners and their students can develop a subset of research questions within the broader framework of the research questions that MoEML addresses 11 The digital revolution also makes <ORGANIZATION>RBL</ORGANIZATION> more feasible across a wider range of institutions In the humanities <ORGANIZATION>RBL</ORGANIZATION> might entail working with primary materials linked to professors research projects Such materials lend themselves to digitization and are in fact being digitized at a rapid rate because they tend to be housed in libraries which are rightly leading the charge in digitizing the very kinds of data that humanities scholars generally analyze books letters records images art 7 Our fieldwork used to take place in libraries now it takes place on the internet MoEML itself provides many open access resources but we also point people preferentially to other open access resources MoEML and the Pedagogical Partnership Methodology 12 The MoEML Pedagogical Partnerships make four key assumptions Research based learning is now possible at any institution not just the former R1 institutions thanks to the burgeoning of digital resources in particular open access ones Providing students with high stakes publishing opportunities will motivate them to produce their best work Their best work is often an original contribution to scholarship 8 The imperatives of knowledge mobilization and publicly funded education demand that we capture students original research and share it within and beyond the scholarly community 13 Broadly speaking the MoEML module has two phases The first phase teaching assigning and assessing occurs during the term at our partner institutions As noted by the Student Collaborators Bill of Rights a professor who assigns a MoEML module must primarily consider the student s own intellectual growth <PERSON>Di Pressi</PERSON> et al n d rather than the needs of the project MoEML is not involved in the grading which has to conform to the partner institution s assessment standards Once the Partnership is established and before the course begins the project and the professor discuss the nature of the contribution The contribution needs to help students achieve the learning outcomes for the course In keeping with <ORGANIZATION>RBL</ORGANIZATION> practices the contribution must be relevant to the professor s own research questions and expertise It must also fit the project s needs for MoEML the pressing needs are encyclopedia articles for the Placeography essays on topics of general interest to MoEML users and editions of texts for the Library The project supplies some teaching materials During the term the students research the assigned topic and write an encyclopedia article or create an edition under the close supervision of the professor who acts as an on site MoEML Guest Editor 14 For our 2014 pilot of the Pedagogical Partnership we teamed up with <PERSON>Herman</PERSON> at <ORGANIZATION>SDSU</ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON>Kathryn R McPherson</PERSON> at <ORGANIZATION>Utah Valley University Both</ORGANIZATION> professors chose to have the entire class work together to complete a single MoEML Encyclopedia article that needed content <PERSON>Herman</PERSON> was assigned the Blackfriars Theatre and <PERSON>McPherson</PERSON> s the Curtain Theatre MoEML provided a blurb about the Partnership for their syllabi suggested forms of assessment that had worked for <PERSON>Jenstad</PERSON> in the past provided a comprehensive online guide for student researchers visited their classes in person and or by <ORGANIZATION>Skype</ORGANIZATION> regularly checked in with them via email sent sources and helped with refining topics developing models for group work and reviewing an early draft in <PERSON>Herman</PERSON> s case 15 The second phase preparing the submission for MoEML publication occurs after the course is over and grades are submitted Not all students want to continue working on a project after the course is finished although many have done so which means that they will not experience the full cycle of academic feedback revision and publication Nevertheless their work is still subject to the peer review process through the mediation of the professor credited as Guest Editor who has to revise the students work after the students have moved on Depending on the extent of the revisions required the Guest Editor may effectively co author the contribution Most academic writing is better because of the suggestions and interventions of peer reviewers editors and copyeditors people who are often uncredited MoEML consults the Guest Editor about how credit should be apportioned and described in contribution metadata MoEML then reviews encodes and publishes the article The Results A Winning Model 16 We hoped that this model would benefit all the participants the Guest Editors professors the students and the project Professors would get an innovative teaching experience to include on their professional dossiers They would be able to engage their students in meaningful research Perhaps more importantly professors who had been tasked with incorporating digital tools and methods in the classroom would now have a methodology They would still be rooted in their own scholarly domain and subject area as they taught scholarly research skills to their students but they would also get to offer their students pathways into digital scholarship via the MoEML module In effect the Partnership would offer them one of the easy ways to dip their toe s into the field of digital scholarship Koh 2014 Furthermore they would now be free to experiment with classroom power dynamics allowing students who might be particularly technologically savvy to take leadership roles Indeed MoEML would provide a solution to some of the problems that digital pedagogues have historically faced 9 We hoped that MoEML could model the kind of non hierarchical collaborative work that bridges the erroneous distinctions drawn between pedagogy and research Konkol 2015 The Student Collaborators Bill of Rights notes that At their best these partnerships are a way for students to learn new skills and benefit from mentorship while more seasoned scholars can learn from junior scholars ideas skills subject knowledge and perspectives <PERSON>Di Pressi</PERSON> et al n d 17 Ideally students would learn that they are not only consumers of knowledge but can also be producers or creators of knowledge Konkol 2015 They would feel part of something that is bigger than themselves While mastering scholarly research methods such as using online databases academic journals and checking and citing sources properly they would come to feel like scholars and the experience would push them to take their research skills to the next level Having a venue like MoEML would provide them with an audience to write for and show them that there can be real purpose to scholarly writing since their work would have a genuine utility for other scholars Their work researching for MoEML would be formative especially for those who planned to go on to graduate school with the intention of entering the profession They would not only learn more about the early modern world but also become better researchers and collaborators 18 Finally the hope was that the project would acquire vetted scholarly content that would help to sustain a pedagogical resource used by thousands around the world While expanding our content we could achieve greater quality assurance by having Guest Editors vet contributions This method would also take some of the strain off our in house editors Refinements Lessons Learned Improvements 19 MoEML and partners have tested this model in a variety of ways public feedback extension of the model and role switching During the pilot term Spring 2014 we sought feedback from scholars and potential contributors via demonstrations most notably at the <ORGANIZATION>Shakespeare Association of America SAA Digital Salon</ORGANIZATION> social media <ORGANIZATION>Facebook Twitter</ORGANIZATION> and our own on site News feed and on site visits <PERSON>McLean Fiander</PERSON> did a MoEML Road Show in southern <LOCATION>California</LOCATION> visiting <PERSON>Herman</PERSON> s class in person while there We have since given conference papers presented in panel sessions organized a <ORGANIZATION>Modern Language Association MLA</ORGANIZATION> panel and run a workshop at the SAA Feedback from Professors 10 20 Informal feedback from <ORGANIZATION>Pedagogical Partners</ORGANIZATION> has been highly or wholly positive <PERSON>Amy Tigner</PERSON> at the <ORGANIZATION>University of Texas Arlington</ORGANIZATION> reported the following after her graduate students completed the MoEML module We have learned so much doing this project and the students remain excited and engaged The collaborative aspect has meant that they have really helped one another and the overall documents are better <PERSON>Meg Roland</PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION>Marylhurst University</ORGANIZATION> whose undergraduate study abroad students wrote about the <PERSON>London Wall</PERSON> said that her students had become passionate researchers Upon starting the MoEML module <PERSON>Shannon Kelley</PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION>Fairfield University</ORGANIZATION> also a contributor to this issue of DHQ wrote I am really excited to dig into this project with my new <PERSON>Shakespeare</PERSON> course and the administrators at my university are thrilled too after completing the module she wrote I have only positive things to say A happy by product of the MoEML Partnerships is that we are starting to see interconnections form between the <ORGANIZATION>Pedagogical Partners</ORGANIZATION> who cross review each other s work and who are developing their own collaborations including plans to participate on roundtables and panels at future conferences <ORGANIZATION>Case Studies Utah Valley University and Washington College</ORGANIZATION> 21 <PERSON>McPherson</PERSON> and another early partner <PERSON>Kathryn Moncrief</PERSON> at <ORGANIZATION>Washington College</ORGANIZATION> a small private liberal arts college have reflected at length on their experiences in public fora which has helped MoEML identify and implement improvements Like most new ventures the Partnership has room to grow beyond its strong start <ORGANIZATION>Utah Valley University</ORGANIZATION> 22 <PERSON>McPherson</PERSON> s experience was key to understanding the strengths and weaknesses of the pilot Partnership <PERSON>McPherson</PERSON> s class at <LOCATION>UVU</LOCATION> was an ideal venue for testing the hypothesis that a partnership between a major DH project and a non R1 institution could create a research based learning opportunity UVU is a large 30K student open enrollment university that doubles as a community college Its focus on Engaged Learning was recognized in 2008 with the official Carnegie designation of Elective Community Engagement which recognizes collaboration between institutions of higher education and their larger communities for the mutually beneficial exchange of knowledge and resources in a context of partnership and reciprocity <PERSON>McPherson</PERSON> teaches in a large English Department with a moderate number of majors 40 faculty and approximately 500 majors divided between Literary Studies Creative Writing Writing Studies and English Education The Shakespeare course <ORGANIZATION>ENGL</ORGANIZATION> 463R in which <PERSON>McPherson</PERSON> deployed the MoEML module is required for all Literary Studies and Creative Writing students recommended for English Education students and typically taken late in junior or during senior year Class size varies between 15 and 25 students 23 Playing to her own research strengths as <ORGANIZATION>RBL</ORGANIZATION> requires <PERSON>McPherson</PERSON> designed the course to interrogate Original Practices The concept of performing <PERSON>Shakespeare</PERSON> according to original performance practices or under original performance conditions was variously familiar to UVU students due to the Grassroots Shakespeare Center begun in 2009 by two of <PERSON>McPherson</PERSON> s former students The troupe visited <PERSON>McPherson</PERSON> s class and performed scenes from The Taming of the Shrew near the end of the term <PERSON>McPherson</PERSON> had students undertake in class performance exercises using materials prepared by <PERSON>Ralph Cohen</PERSON> and the American <LOCATION>Shakespeare Center</LOCATION> and made frequent use of comparison clips of modern films and <PERSON>Shakespeare</PERSON> s Globe performances For the Engaged Learning component of the course <PERSON>McPherson</PERSON> had her students research and write an article about the Curtain Theatre for MoEML She considered this exercise her first DH project The module allowed the students to mobilize new findings from the discovery and excavation of the Curtain Theatre site in <LOCATION>Shoreditch</LOCATION> in summer 2012 which was serendipitous since archeological evidence has been crucial to Original Practices research Working in groups <PERSON>McPherson</PERSON> s students addressed five topics Early Modern Neighborhood and Site Theatre Architecture Playing Companies and <ORGANIZATION>People Repertory</ORGANIZATION> and Writers and Modern Site and Archaeology The resulting essay is now published on the MoEML site 11 24 <PERSON>McPherson</PERSON> s <ORGANIZATION>MLA</ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION>SAA</ORGANIZATION> reports about the MoEML Partnership made specific recommendations Her comments targeted the acquisition of research skills the transition to collaborative work and the challenges of writing for a new medium MoEML s actions or comments are included parenthetically Students at non elite schools need more support for using databases such as EEBO MoEML has since published a series of How to guides written by undergraduate students working with <PERSON>Kristen Abbott Bennett</PERSON> at <ORGANIZATION>Stonehill College</ORGANIZATION> another non R1 school grappling with digital research tools 12 Students need more than models provided by their reading for understanding the conventions of scholarly writing In response MoEML wrote a Writing for the Web guide Students need to be drilled regarding the thorough use of documentation and citation precisely because the stakes are high in this kind of public scholarship MoEML s citation guide is currently appended to the end of its style guide the project make its innovative citation practices more visible Precise orientation to citing early modern texts via signature and gathering needs to be stressed MoEML can take a leading role here by providing links to videos at the <ORGANIZATION>British Library Folger Shakespeare Library</ORGANIZATION> and elsewhere A mid term draft should be required to ensure that students are not procrastinating For <PERSON>Herman</PERSON> the MoEML team performed a mid term external review to introduce students to the concept of peer review although an external review can complicate the internal assessment process Conferences outside of class with each team of students would help to foster collaboration and smooth out any interpersonal issues As we learn to work collaboratively in our discipline generally we can all learn from <ORGANIZATION>DH Washington College</ORGANIZATION> 25 <PERSON>Moncrief</PERSON> became interested in the way the MoEML module fosters metaliteracy <PERSON>Moncrief</PERSON> s Renaissance Drama class of twenty junior and senior level students worked collaboratively to write an article on the Rose Theatre for MoEML the class was divided into the same sort of topic groupings as <PERSON>McPherson</PERSON> s class <PERSON>Moncrief</PERSON> teamed up with scholar librarian <PERSON>Michele Santamaria</PERSON> to write an article about the metacognitive effects of the MoEML module They detailed how metaliteracy was intrinsic to the experience of undergraduate Renaissance Drama students embarking upon collaborative research nested within various cooperative ventures <PERSON>Santamaria</PERSON> and <PERSON>Moncrief</PERSON> 2015 13 They viewed the MoEML Partnership as creating an ideal opportunity for the students to improve both digital and social media skills while also allowing them to develop their independence as scholars a key to enhancing their metaliteracy While only two of the four research teams appeared to flourish in the team setting the students generally reported a high level of pride in contributing to MoEML and expressed a strong belief in the capacity for undergraduates to engage in meaningful research <PERSON>Santamaria</PERSON> and <PERSON>Moncrief</PERSON> reported that the students came to see themselves as authors of information and they concluded that learners benefit tremendously from collaborative research based learning that depends on them working across several domains of metaliteracy <PERSON>Santamaria</PERSON> and <PERSON>Moncrief</PERSON> 2015 Student feedback 26 We sought student feedback via an end of term anonymous assessment modelled on the UVic Course Experience Survey and an instrument designed by the UVic Learning and Teaching Centre 14 We used a <ORGANIZATION>Likert Scale</ORGANIZATION> to invite students to strongly disagree disagree remain neutral agree or strongly agree with various statements 15 The results bear out many of our expectations Among 51 respondents from four different undergraduate classes comprised primarily of third and fourth year English majors students by and large thought that the process made them a better researcher 4 31 5 Students also deeply believed that all undergraduates should have the opportunity to engage in similar high stakes research 4 33 5 They sometimes struggled to choose among and deploy sources even though a comprehensive research guide for students is provided on the MoEML site Students reported that using the MoEML Guide for Student Researchers 16 both challenged them and enriched their experience rating its helpfulness at 3 65 out of 5 27 All in all students reported a high level of pride 4 63 out of 5 said they were proud to contribute to a widely used online scholarly resource One student reported that My favorite thing about the MoEML module was how it engaged our class in legitimate literary research while making use of cutting edge technology Old books and new computers it s the future Another said the best part of the module was the satisfaction of accomplishing this daunting project I can accomplish much more than I thought I could They reported that the MoEML module encouraged them to think about proper research terms primary sources and research engines which sources are more valuable the importance of historicising and how to bring these important aspects of culture and academia into modern conversation and consumption via the internet They learned to consider the validity of information how to pare down the abundance of it and how to cross check sources 28 When asked in what specific ways did you grow and develop as a researcher students revealed the following I learned to be more organized and work with a group of people that have different strengths and weaknesses I learned how to find information that is useful I got into the habit of keeping research notes which helped with my thesis work I learned how to do real research and how to examin e the text in deep meaningful ways using historical context and intensive reasoning and logic These important lessons have carried into aspects of my life I have never considered 29 When asked to reflect on how the MoEML module might be useful for them when applying for a job or graduate school one respondent said I have experience in participating in a <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> project which was successful and allowed people to work and interact w ith one another digitally Another student who worked as a research assistant with MoEML during the Partnership reported that There is something completely inspiring and motivating in knowing that my work is being accessed assessed and cited by students and researchers worldwide What the project learned 30 Due to the rapid uptake of the Partnership MoEML found itself with more contributions in the workflow than the team could process quickly At the time of writing January 2016 MoEML has had sixteen Pedagogical Partners from four countries and a variety of institutions 17 The project has published thirteen articles with five more in draft at the encoding stage and a further 28 assigned or in revisions Research assistants in <LOCATION>Victoria</LOCATION> invested time checking facts tagging people places dates and sources finding images and sometimes performing further research As MoEML moves forward with future Partnerships the project team must use its limited resources wisely To this end MoEML has already implemented and continues to work on a series of fixes The new Teaching splash page 18 on the site provides partners with a clear overview of their role the module MoEML s submission criteria and the resources available to Guest Editors and students on and off site MoEML now insists that contributions from Partnerships include project specific identifiers for people places and dates 19 Making such identifications are part of the critical work to be done by the researcher in many cases MoEML RAs would have to replicate the research to make the identification Pedagogical Partnerships have helpfully shown where our contributor guidelines needed expansion and clearer organization it remains to be seen if students would benefit from customized guidelines pitched at their level MoEML needs to fine tune the peer review process so that the work is spread out across a wider range of reviewers When its current grant funding comes to an end in April 2016 MoEML will need to assess the viability of the Partnerships Without funding the project can still support a few experienced partners Even with renewed grant funding MoEML will move to a competitive application model Word of mouth alone has brought more partners than MoEML can accommodate although advertising via a CFP site and various discipline specific listservs and websites would be an obvious course of action when the process becomes competitive What We All Learned Ethical Matters 31 Partnerships do not always result in publishable content for the project Some submissions did not meet the standard for publication a decision usually taken by the Guest Editor but sometimes deferred to the project team Not all students want to contribute <PERSON>Janni Aragon</PERSON> Director of <ORGANIZATION>Technology Integrated Learning</ORGANIZATION> at UVic attended one of MoEML s workshops and pointed out that students need an out As teachers we cannot require students to share their work in public fora They may have personal or professional reasons for wanting their work in the course to be a terminal exercise seen only by the professor Partners need be aware of ethical implications and legal regulations at their home institutions They may need to have students sign waivers They may need to have alternative assignments ready for students who do not wish to participate Whether or not the work results in a publishable contribution the partnership is a pedagogical success because the students have developed highly mobile skills in research writing and sometimes encoding 32 We all became acutely aware of the mismatch between the speedy passage of students through courses and the significantly less speedy pace of scholarly publication Professors had to remain in contact with students for months after the end of the course students were understandably impatient with the process or simply not available to participate in post course revisions Scholars are used to the longer timelines of published research For the professors this work is part of their research and or teaching portfolios they are willing to put in time to bring the project to completion For students who are not going on to graduate studies or becoming academics there is little incentive to continue working on the MoEML contribution However students who stay in the academy or who go on to higher level training see their work for the MoEML partnership as a launchpad to a next level independent study 33 The working conditions of contingent academics affected the partnership A number of our partners have been limited term or adjunct instructors <ORGANIZATION>Frost Bennett Contingent</ORGANIZATION> faculty are often less able to propose DH or <ORGANIZATION>RBL</ORGANIZATION> courses may have limited access to institutional resources and are unlikely to have a lab space or dedicated technical support Opening up our project to contingent faculty means we open up their opportunities to participate in DH research Given the challenges they face in career continuity we can provide a permanent and visible home for their work Such partners seem to be gaining recognition for their participation in our partnership Because they are actively on the job market most of the time it becomes incumbent on us to fast track the work they and their students do Expanding and Extending the Model 34 The model is extensible to various pedagogical settings and other types of assignments Some partners have had their students collectively write a single article on a place of major significance Until the playhouses have all been written up those locations will be popular choices for teachers of Renaissance Drama <PERSON>Herman</PERSON> chose the <ORGANIZATION>Blackfriars McPherson</ORGANIZATION> the Curtain Moncrief the Rose Bishop the Theatre <PERSON>Donna Woodford Gormley</PERSON> the <LOCATION>Globe Kirilka Stavreva Middle Temple Hall</LOCATION> and so on <PERSON>Woodford Gormley</PERSON> and <PERSON>Stavreva</PERSON> spread the work across two classes in subsequent terms thus making two groups of students de facto collaborators across time and courses Other partners especially those with graduate students have assigned smaller topics to individual students <ORGANIZATION>Briony Frost</ORGANIZATION> s MA students at the <ORGANIZATION>University of Exeter</ORGANIZATION> each tackled one location along a processional route and <PERSON>Tigner</PERSON> s graduate students contributed multiple individual essays on waterside locations for a course on <PERSON>Shakespeare</PERSON> and Early Modern Urban Rural Nature <PERSON>Ian MacInnes</PERSON> at <ORGANIZATION>Albion College</ORGANIZATION> placed two summer research scholarship students with MoEML in Summer 2015 one student <PERSON>Kate Casebeer</PERSON> elected to encode her own contribution using the MoEML Praxis guidelines normally used only by our internal team members <PERSON>Roland</PERSON> at <ORGANIZATION>Marylhurst University</ORGANIZATION> worked a module on <ORGANIZATION>London Wall</ORGANIZATION> into a Study Abroad course where her students traced the route of the Roman era wall during their trip 20 Encyclopedia articles are not the only types of assignments MoEML can accommodate One of <PERSON>Tracey Hill</PERSON> s students at <ORGANIZATION>Bath Spa University</ORGANIZATION> transcribed a pageant book for the anthology of mayoral shows For <PERSON>Jennifer Drouin</PERSON> s graduate level <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> course at the <ORGANIZATION>University of Alabama</ORGANIZATION> MoEML designed an Encoding Partnership whereby students encoded proclamations for the Library as part of their introduction to the Text Encoding Initiative <PERSON>TEI Jenstad</PERSON> is currently experimenting with partnering up two classes in different locations to try double keying diplomatic transcriptions in an effort to teach descriptive bibliography transcription and encoding via an international partnership 21 MoEML has a prospective Partnership in 3D modelling for which the project will supply ground surveys and architectural information and the <ORGANIZATION>Pedagogical Partner</ORGANIZATION> will teach students to interpret the surveys and use Blender and or Google Sketch Up to create models of some buildings in <LOCATION>London</LOCATION> MoEML will then embed the models in Encyclopedia pages 22 35 Participants in our workshops have given valuable feedback wondering aloud or in writing how to implement such a partnership for their own projects embed such a module in a course or seek out other projects with whom to partner We would like to see further expansion of this model not necessarily by growth at MoEML but via uptake by other projects A key limitation on MoEML s expansion of the <ORGANIZATION>Pedagogical Partnership</ORGANIZATION> is the availability of grant funding since project team members check encode and upload content in house essentially functioning as a publisher without the infrastructure of a university press Other digital projects with different types of content different content management models and registration tools e g the capacity to capture data via web interfaces or to register contributors as Wiki users may be able to accommodate more contributors <PERSON>Jenstad</PERSON> tested the extensibility of the Encoding Partnership by having her graduate course on Textual Studies and <ORGANIZATION>Methods of Research</ORGANIZATION> partner with the Database of Victorian Periodical Poetry run by UVic professor <PERSON>Alison Chapman</PERSON> 23 Students transcribed poems from digital surrogates followed the project s guidelines and downloaded an encoding package prepared by the project s programmer Many projects need help with transcriptions markup updating bibliographies reviewing collecting and entering data writing encyclopedia entries surfacing and describing materials and creating finding aids Data created by one project might be available for visualization or analysis by another project or using another tool with the results potentially augmenting what is already available on the project s site Projects in need of such help might consider pedagogical partnerships like ours 36 Professors looking for real opportunities for their students might consider asking projects if contributions would be welcome We suggest that such professors look for projects with a Contribute link and or Contributor Guidelines an irregular publication cycle i e one not locked into Issues or Releases a variety of roles that students can perform evidence of past student contributions although this evidence is not essential since a project may never have thought of mobilizing student scholarship and of course a digital presence It helps to know a colleague on the project as <PERSON>Herman</PERSON> knew Jenstad One possible pitch is to say Would you be willing to consider contributions from students if I were to vet them first Above all it is important that the project provide an opportunity for students to exercise skills that they would need to learn in the course anyway If students need to learn palaeography then a manuscript transcription project or letters project such as Early Modern Manuscripts Online or Early Modern Letters Online could be an appropriate project partner Inspired by their experience as Partners with <PERSON>MoEML McPherson</PERSON> and <PERSON>Moncrief</PERSON> have implemented a Pedagogical Partnership in their new edition of <ORGANIZATION>Shakespeare s Life and Times</ORGANIZATION> SLT 2 0 for the Internet Shakespeare Editions an ideal scenario that has mainly Junior students writing for Freshmen Sophomores and Juniors 37 To make such partnerships work everyone has to benefit We suggest that a Project needs the following a clearly identified contribution as opposed to an offer to help reassurance that the partnership will not result in additional work for the project or a sense that the project s investment will pay off in terms of a wider user base stakeholders who care about its content and a future highly qualified contributor and a mechanism for ensuring quality The last of these is no trifling matter Ideally quality control would come in the shape of a digital curator or gatekeeper 38 <ORGANIZATION>Potential Pedagogical Partners</ORGANIZATION> i e the professors who function as Guest Editors need some or all of the following suggestions for possible contributions that will serve the learning objectives of the course and fill current gaps in the project s structure a module with clear boundaries that will fit inside the context of a course structure teaching and management tips guidelines for the students to follow when writing and submitting their contributions research guidelines assessment rubrics full credit for their work on the site an institutional letter of support and a reminder to check their university s regulations about ethics and disclaimers 39 Students need credit in the form of their name appearing on the page or linked from it ample guidance from the professor the feeling that they are making a valuable contribution thorough explanations of how to do new things opportunities to share their expertise and an out should they wish not to publish their work 24 40 While the <ORGANIZATION>MoEML Pedagogical Partnership</ORGANIZATION> model has room for improvement it has been successful thus far because all parties have benefitted from the experience <ORGANIZATION>Public Humanities</ORGANIZATION> 41 MoEML s Pedagogical Partnership also reaches beyond the classroom and builds an expansive scholarly community created by what <PERSON>Lanclos</PERSON> and White call Resident practices Networked practices provide an opportunity for individuals to make their identity broadly visible without the mediation of traditional publishers or their institution These modes of online engagement have been described as Resident in that they involve the individual being present or residing to a certain extent online This is in contrast to Visitor modes of engagement where the individual leaves no online social trace These new Resident forms of agency and online participation are repositioning institutions within a larger more open knowledge production landscape Individuals are increasingly aware via the opportunities provided by Resident practices on the web that they do not have to sacrifice as much personal agency to the institution to gain professional credibility as they might have done in a pre Web era <LOCATION>Lanclos</LOCATION> and White 2015 MoEML engages in this kind of Resident practice by opening up research communities and allowing students to reside in and contribute to a scholarly digital space where their research can be and has been accessed by scholars and the interested public alike Because the Partnership acknowledges the capacity of students with proper guidance to perform rigorous and original research and because it publishes this work on an accessible public platform it captures research that might not otherwise see the light of day simply because it was conducted by an undergraduate student 42 Another pedagogical resource that often remains hidden is the course syllabus The MoEML teaching resource page shares a number of course syllabi from our Partners so that other instructors might benefit from those who have gone before them The teaching page includes a series of How to Guides including the Student Research Guide How to Write for the Web and guides for using various digital resources the latter writing by <PERSON>Bennett</PERSON> s students at <ORGANIZATION>Stonehill College Upon</ORGANIZATION> learning of the MoEML Pedagogical Partnership <PERSON>Josh Magsam</PERSON> of The Shakespeare Standard reported It s wonderful to see a strong commitment to sharing teaching resources and partnering with other instructors to enhance awareness of the project I think joint projects and crowd sourced projects such as this hybrid pedagogy if you will represent some of the most vital and critical teaching work being done in the field Magsam 2014 43 MoEML fosters a scholarly community beyond the individual classroom too Our Partner <PERSON>Roland</PERSON> recently wrote to tell us that she took her students to a seniors center at the Provost s request so that they could talk about their work on the MoEML project One of the senior citizens was a retired Blue Badge Guide from <LOCATION>London</LOCATION> She asked to read the class s article on <ORGANIZATION>London Wall</ORGANIZATION> and ended up catching a few errors and making a number of helpful suggestions to improve the content As <PERSON>Roland</PERSON> put it what a great surprise that was to have her be an additional reader it just shows the value of getting this kind of work out into the community Roland 2016 Conclusion 44 The editors of this issue of DHQ generously invoked the MoEML Pedagogical Partnership in their call for papers Having been held up as a model of critical skills development we would like to conclude by reflecting on the extent to which our Partnerships engage in what DHQ issue editors <PERSON>Murphy</PERSON> and <PERSON>Smith</PERSON> characterized as a multidimensional reimagining of where undergrads sit in the field and how we conceive of their students role in the shifting knowledge economies produced by digital scholarship In producing digital content our partnering students develop the usual critical skills of English majors but also begin thinking about other things such as platforms infrastructures and how knowledge is made The Partnership teaches students to be highly aware users of i e Visitors to digital resources both subscription and open access At the same time it lowers the technological barriers that often stand between humanities scholars in general students and faculty alike and the digital projects created largely by so called digital humanists The Partnership enables students to see themselves as producers of digital resources and to become Residents of the digital terrain We democratize DH when we open up this subject position to students The digital space can welcome student contributors simply because it casts a bigger net around original research opening up MoEML pages to students does not mean taking away publishing opportunities from others The biggest impediment to publishing student work is time time spent on peer review copyediting and the additional demands of encoding The MoEML team and the Guest Editors can invest this time in student learning because the benefits are mutual 45 The Partnership expands the range of possibilities for doing DH We can invite students into a project like MoEML without hiring them as Research Assistants They do not have to apprentice as RAs nor do they have to acquire encoding or programming skills In fact working digitally does not mean only or even necessarily digitizing encoding or programming It includes thinking critically about the impact of medium upon readership the ways we convey information the types of sources we use and how we connect to the larger web of knowledge by citation and or links Putting XML ids into submissions demands that students think about concepts that have been driven by and are required by new forms of digital scholarship Quoting a toponym from a source is not enough students have to think about what that toponym represents and point to a stable shared reference point They become implicitly aware of the need for authority names linked open data and identifiers DOIs XML ids and URIs They start to think about humanities research findings as data and information as a network At the same time the Partnership does not preclude opportunities to acquire skills in digital mapping and text encoding if students wish Professors and students who are technologically savvy or willing to learn can adjust the module to teach various combinations of DH skills and research skills 46 A lot of what we do in the academy is scaffolded learning that builds towards the masterpiece the complete work that demands mastery of all the skills required of a particular scholarly output The capstone project the MA thesis and the PhD dissertation are the traditional forms of the masterpiece Like <ORGANIZATION>RBL</ORGANIZATION> MoEML s Partnership asks the undergraduate to produce a masterpiece earlier in the game The student works with others to take a research problem to its logical conclusion which is published in an environment where the answer reaches a readership beyond the instructor in the course The sheer scope of the user base of an open access digital project is highly motivating to the student The scholarly injunctions become immediate and pressing to be exhaustive to acknowledge prior and current voices in the scholarly conversation to consult all available sources of information to use many types of sources outside their home libraries and home disciplines and to master the form and richness required for the venue 47 We began this paper talking about how the MoEML Partnership emerged from a confluence of problems and opportunities While Pedagogical Partnerships are not in the long run an efficient way of generating content for MoEML the project has benefitted tremendously from the influx of fresh voices the growing community of students and professors who have a digital Residence in MoEML the corrections they have made to neighbouring pages their suggestions for new places and their feedback on the Contributor Guidelines The Guest Editors have welcomed the opportunity to embrace a new pedagogy that meets new institutional demands brings high profile attention to their institutions and engages students in scholarly publication Many of the Partners have been featured in their campus magazines and local media which has in turn been good for the project The full benefit to the students remains to be seen It is certain that some of them found the prospect of producing publishable work daunting at the outset and ultimately not all the articles were publishable which is a reality of academic life The model will be truly successful if it becomes a habitual way that students interact with and improve the digital resources we all use in our scholarly lives We fully expect to see many of them stake a greater claim in the digital sphere in the years ahead Notes 1 We refer of course to the theme of the 2011 <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> conference at <ORGANIZATION>Stanford Big Tent Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> 2 See the position papers in Done Finishing Projects in the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> a special cluster in <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities Quarterly</ORGANIZATION> 3 2 2009 edited by <PERSON>Matthew Kirschenbaum</PERSON> Note that it is not a problem of mission creep for MoEML which was designed from its inception to be large and was created with hundreds of empty placeholder pages 3 The essays in <PERSON>Hackel</PERSON> and <PERSON>Moulton</PERSON> s Teaching Early Modern Literature from the Archives respond to the challenge of getting students involved in archival research <PERSON>Hackel</PERSON> and <PERSON>Moulton</PERSON> 2015 4 The <ORGANIZATION>Boyer Commission</ORGANIZATION> s Blueprint uses the designation R1 a now deprecated category in the Carnegie Classification of Institutions of Higher Education There is no single equivalent term in the new ontology which is more granular and less value laden We will use the still popular R1 designation for polemical purposes See <PERSON>Garde Hansen</PERSON> and Calvert 2007 105 106 for a description of the somewhat later <LOCATION>UK</LOCATION> adoption of <ORGANIZATION>RBL</ORGANIZATION> practices 5 See for example two <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> directed readings hosted by MoEML DHUM 491 Remediating Bills of Mortality http mapoflondon uvic ca DHUM491_2015 htm and DHUM 491 <ORGANIZATION>Georeferencing London Books</ORGANIZATION> http mapoflondon uvic ca DHUM491_2014 htm 6 Maker Lab in the <ORGANIZATION>Humanities Dir Jentery Sayers University of Victoria</ORGANIZATION> http maker uvic ca 7 See Wosh et al 2012 for analysis of how the digital revolution enables the teaching of digital skills in an archives and public history curriculum Like us they have found that students bring different levels of technological expertise to the new array of <ORGANIZATION>RBL</ORGANIZATION> projects that are enabled by the digital revolution 8 It has certainly been <PERSON>Jenstad</PERSON> s experience that students can produce original research results particularly if they are working with little known texts or newly surfaced materials Within the project environment too as <PERSON>Jenstad</PERSON> and <PERSON>Takeda</PERSON> describe RAs do much more than acquire the technical skills to carry out the Director s agenda they create new technologies in response to real humanities problems like how to deal with the profusion of conflicting calendrical systems in the early modern period <LOCATION>Jenstad</LOCATION> and <PERSON>Takeda</PERSON> forthcoming 9 <ORGANIZATION>Konkol</ORGANIZATION> outlines these problems Konkol 2015 10 Other feedback on the Pedagogical Partnership is available here http mapoflondon uvic ca feedback htm 11 http mapoflondon uvic ca CURT2 htm 12 See How to Guides here http mapoflondon uvic ca teaching htm 13 See <PERSON>Moncrief</PERSON> and <PERSON>Santamaria</PERSON> s useful diagram reflecting the nested levels of collaboration between students and their peers and students and the teachers as well as between the two teachers professor and librarian and finally between these two groups students and teachers with an international community of humanities scholars contributing to MoEML <PERSON>Santamaria</PERSON> and <PERSON>Moncrief</PERSON> 2015 14 As we are not psychometricians we drew on the expertise of our institution s learning and teaching centre Our main goal was to capture any information that might help us tweak the model 15 The current edition of our survey is available online at SurveyMonkey The survey for instructors is at https www surveymonkey com r RXYRYHY and the one for students is at https www surveymonkey com r RPYB6WL 16 http mapoflondon uvic ca research_guidelines htm 17 See http mapoflondon uvic ca pedagogical_partnership htm for a current list 18 http mapoflondon uvic ca teaching htm 19 http mapoflondon uvic ca prepare_contribution htm prepare_contribution_entities 20 See Exploring Londinium at <PERSON>Meg Roland</PERSON> s blog A Passionate Geography Romancing King <PERSON>Arthur</PERSON> s Roman War Sept 3 2014 http passionategeography com 2014 09 03 exploring londinium 21 The <ORGANIZATION>Pedagogical Partners</ORGANIZATION> are <PERSON>Jenstad</PERSON> at UVic and <PERSON>Kristin Abbott Bennett</PERSON> at <PERSON>Stonehill McLean Fiander</PERSON> is representing MoEML since <PERSON>Jenstad</PERSON> cannot partner with her own project 22 <PERSON>John Bonnett</PERSON> at <ORGANIZATION>Brock University</ORGANIZATION> proposed this partnership He has long had students work with archival documents to recreate historical buildings in the <LOCATION>Niagara</LOCATION> region 23 See <PERSON>Alison Chapman</PERSON> s description of the project on the <ORGANIZATION>Victorian Poetry Network</ORGANIZATION> website at http web uvic ca vicpoet database of victorian periodical poetry 24 While we are certainly attuned to the need to pay student research assistants a fair wage for their labour we do not view the MoEML Partnership as unfairly incorporating student labor into the classroom as <PERSON>Spencer Keralis</PERSON> has recently written about in Milking the Deficit Internship 2016 This shift he argues makes student labor invisible to the institution in terms of counting the costs of digital projects But more importantly this student labor is largely uncredited and unpaid Keralis 2016 MoEML s Partnership model insists on crediting each student by name and on acknowledging the considerable work of the Guest Editor Furthermore the students get academic credit within their individual courses for the MoEML module work they do Finally MoEML does not get free labor because the Partnership demands a significant contribution from the project too Works Cited <PERSON>Boyer</PERSON> 1998 The <ORGANIZATION>Boyer Commission</ORGANIZATION> on Education Undergraduates in the <ORGANIZATION>Research University Reinventing Undergraduate Education A Blueprint for America s Research Universities Stoney Brook</ORGANIZATION> NY 1998 http eric ed gov id ED424840 Brew 2006 <ORGANIZATION>Brew Angela Research and Teaching Beyond the Divide Basingstoke Palgrave Macmillan</ORGANIZATION> 2006 Brew and <PERSON>Jewell</PERSON> 2012 <PERSON>Brew Angela</PERSON> and <PERSON>Evan Jewell</PERSON> Enhancing quality learning through experiences of research based learning implications for academic developments <ORGANIZATION>International Journal for Academic Development</ORGANIZATION> 17 1 2012 47 58 DOI 10 1080 1360144X 2011 586461 Caprio 2014 Caprio Mark J Student Publishing Future Scholars as Change Agents <ORGANIZATION>OCLC Systems and Services International Digital Library Perspectives</ORGANIZATION> 30 3 2014 144 57 Carnegie Classification n d <ORGANIZATION>Carnegie Classification of Institutions of Higher Education Online</ORGANIZATION> n d Available at http carnegieclassifications iu edu <PERSON>Causer</PERSON> and <PERSON>Wallace</PERSON> 2012 <PERSON>Causer Tim</PERSON> and <PERSON>Valerie Wallace</PERSON> Building a Volunteer Community Results and Findings from <ORGANIZATION>Transcribe Bentham Digital Humanities Quarterly</ORGANIZATION> 6 2 2012 http www digitalhumanities org dhq vol 6 2 000125 000125 html Di Pressi et al n d <PERSON>Di Pressi Haley</PERSON> et al A Student Collaborators Bill of Rights Online n d Available at http www cdh ucla edu news events a student collaborators bill of rights <ORGANIZATION>EMLO Early Modern Letters Online Online n d University of Oxford Available</ORGANIZATION> at http emlo bodleian ox ac uk EMMO Early Modern Manuscripts Online Online n d <ORGANIZATION>Folger Shakespeare Library Available</ORGANIZATION> at http transcribe folger edu <PERSON>Garde Hansen</PERSON> and Calvert 2007 <PERSON>Garde Hansen Joanne</PERSON> and <PERSON>Ben Calvert</PERSON> Developing a Research Culture in the Undergraduate Curriculum Active Learning in Higher Education 8 2 2007 105 16 DOI 10 1177 1469787407077984 <PERSON>Grusin</PERSON> 2014 <PERSON>Grusin Richard</PERSON> The <ORGANIZATION>Dark Side of Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> Dispatches from Two Recent MLA Conventions Differences A <ORGANIZATION>Journal of Feminist Cultural Studies</ORGANIZATION> 25 1 2014 79 92 DOI 10 1215 10407391 2420009 Haaf et al 2013 <PERSON>Haaf Susanne Frank Wiegand</PERSON> and <PERSON>Alexander Geyken</PERSON> Measuring the Correctness of Double Keying Error Classification and Quality Control in a Large Corpus of <ORGANIZATION>TEI Annotated Historical Text Journal</ORGANIZATION> of the Text Encoding Initiative 4 2013 Web https jtei revues org 739 <PERSON>Hackel</PERSON> and <PERSON>Moulton</PERSON> 2015 <PERSON>Hackel Heidi Brayman</PERSON> and <PERSON>Ian Frederick Moulton</PERSON> eds Teaching Early Modern English Literature from the <ORGANIZATION>Archives New York Modern Language Association 2015 Herman 2013a Facebook Messages</ORGANIZATION> to <PERSON>Janelle Jenstad</PERSON> September 20 23 2013 <PERSON>Herman</PERSON> 2013b Email to <PERSON>Janelle Jenstad</PERSON> September 22 2013 Herman 2015 <PERSON>Herman Peter</PERSON> C Opening Up The Roaring Girl and the Woman Question with EEBO Teaching Early Modern English Literature from the Archives Ed <PERSON>Heidi Brayman Hackel</PERSON> and <PERSON>Ian Frederick Moulton</PERSON> <ORGANIZATION>New York Modern Language Association</ORGANIZATION> 2015 133 44 Hunter 2015 Hunter Andrea The <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities and Democracy Canadian Journal of Communication</ORGANIZATION> 40 2015 407 23 Jenstad 2013 Email to <PERSON>Peter Herman</PERSON> September 22 2013 Jenstad and <PERSON>Takeda</PERSON> forthcoming <PERSON>Jenstad Janelle</PERSON> and <PERSON>Joseph Takeda</PERSON> Making the <ORGANIZATION>RA Matter Pedagogy Interface and Practices Making Humanities Matter</ORGANIZATION> <PERSON>Ed Jentery Sayers</PERSON> U of <LOCATION>Minnesota</LOCATION> P forthcoming Katkin 2003 Katkin Wendy The <ORGANIZATION>Boyer Commission</ORGANIZATION> Report and Its Impact on undergraduate Research New Directions for Teaching and Learning 93 Spring 2003 19 38 Kelly 2015 Kelly <PERSON>Erin</PERSON> E Online Emblems in the Classroom Teaching Early Modern English Literature from the Archives Ed <PERSON>Heidi Brayman Hackel</PERSON> and <PERSON>Ian Frederick Moulton</PERSON> <ORGANIZATION>New York Modern Language Association</ORGANIZATION> 2015 191 200 Keralis 2016 Keralis Spencer Milking the Deficit Internship Disrupting the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> MLA 2016 Position Paper Jan 6 2016 Available at http www disruptingdh com milking the deficit internship Kirschenbaum 2009 Kirschenbaum Matthew Done Finishing Projects in the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities Digital Humanities Quarterly</ORGANIZATION> 3 2 2009 http digitalhumanities org dhq vol 3 2 000037 000037 html Kirschenbaum 2010 <ORGANIZATION>Kirschenbaum Matthew What is Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> and What is it Doing in English Departments ADE Bulletin 150 2010 https mkirschenbaum files wordpress com 2011 01 kirschenbaum_ade150 pdf Koh 2014 <ORGANIZATION>Koh Adeline Introducing Digital Humanities Work</ORGANIZATION> to Undergraduates An Overview Hybrid Pedagogy A <ORGANIZATION>Digital Journal of Learning Teaching</ORGANIZATION> and Technology Aug 14 2014 http www hybridpedagogy com journal introducing digital humanities work undergraduates overview <ORGANIZATION>Konkol 2015 Konkol Margaret Public Archives New Knowledge and Moving Beyond the Digital Humanities Digital Pedagogy Distinction Hybrid Pedagogy A Digital Journal</ORGANIZATION> of Learning Teaching and Technology Sept 8 2015 http www hybridpedagogy com journal public archives and new knowledge Lambert 2009 Lambert 2009 <PERSON>Lambert Cath Pedagogies</PERSON> of participation in higher education a case for research based learning <ORGANIZATION>Pedagogy Culture amp Society</ORGANIZATION> 17 3 2009 Lanclos and White 2015 <PERSON>Lanclos Donna</PERSON> and <PERSON>David White</PERSON> The Resident Web and its Impact on the <ORGANIZATION>Academy Hybrid Pedagogy A Digital Journal</ORGANIZATION> of Learning Teaching and Technology Oct 8 2015 http www hybridpedagogy com journal resident web and impact on academy Magsam 2014 Magsam Josh Personal email correspondence with <PERSON>Kim McLean Fiander</PERSON> Feb 28 2014 Pannapacker 2011 <PERSON>Pannapacker William Pannapacker</PERSON> at <ORGANIZATION>MLA Digital Humanities Triumphant The Chronicle</ORGANIZATION> of Higher Education Jan 8 2011 http chronicle com blogs brainstorm pannapacker at mla digital humanities triumphant 30915 Pannapacker 2013 <ORGANIZATION>Pannapacker William Stop Calling It Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> And 9 other strategies to help liberal arts colleges join the movement The <ORGANIZATION>Chronicle</ORGANIZATION> of Higher Education Feb 18 2013 http chronicle com article Stop Calling It Digital 137325 Pannapacker2012 Pannapacker <PERSON>William Pannapacker</PERSON> at <ORGANIZATION>MLA</ORGANIZATION> The Come to DH Moment The Chronicle of Higher Education Jan 7 2012 http chronicle com blogs brainstorm pannapacker at the mla 2 the come to dh moment 42811 Roland 2016 <PERSON>Roland Meg Personal</PERSON> email correspondence with <PERSON>Katie Tanigawa</PERSON> Jan 27 2016 <PERSON>Santamaria</PERSON> and <PERSON>Moncrief</PERSON> 2015 <PERSON>Santamaria Michele R</PERSON> and <PERSON>Kathryn M Moncrief</PERSON> <ORGANIZATION>Metacognition Meets Research Based Learning</ORGANIZATION> in the Undergraduate Renaissance Drama Classroom Metaliteracy in Practice Ed <PERSON>Trudi E Jacobson</PERSON> and <PERSON>Thomas P Mackey</PERSON> ALA Editions New York 2015 113 33 <PERSON>Smith</PERSON> and Rust 2011 <PERSON>Smith Pete</PERSON> and <PERSON>Chris</PERSON> Rust The potential of research based learning for the creation of truly inclusive academic communities of practice <ORGANIZATION>Innovations in Education and Teaching International</ORGANIZATION> 48 2 2011 115 25 Walkington et al 2011 <PERSON>Walkington Helen Amy L Griffin Lisa Keys Mathews Sandra K Metoyer Wendy E Miller Richard Baker</PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION>Derek France Embedding Research Based Learning Early</ORGANIZATION> in the <ORGANIZATION>Undergraduate Geography Curriculum Journal of Geography</ORGANIZATION> in Higher Education 35 3 2011 315 30 Wosh et al 2012 <PERSON>Wosh Peter J Cathy Moran Hajo</PERSON> and <PERSON>Esther Katz</PERSON> <ORGANIZATION>Teaching Digital Skills</ORGANIZATION> in an Archives and <ORGANIZATION>Public History Curriculum Digital Humanities Pedagogy Practices Principles</ORGANIZATION> and Politics Open Book Publishers 2012 79 96 2017 11 3 XML Print Article Please enable JavaScript to view the comments powered by Disqus URL http www digitalhumanities org dhq vol 11 3 000302 000302 html Last updated Comments dhqinfo digitalhumanities org Published by The <ORGANIZATION>Alliance of Digital Humanities Organizations Affiliated</ORGANIZATION> with Literary and Linguistic Computing Copyright 2005 image Creative Commons License This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution NoDerivatives 4 0 International License</ner>
