<ner>image DHQ Logo image Digital Humanities Quarterly Logo homesubmissionsabout dhqdhq peoplecontact Current Issue 2017 11 4 Preview Issue 2018 12 1 Previous Issues 2017 11 3 2017 11 2 2017 11 1 2016 10 4 2016 10 3 2016 10 2 2016 10 1 2015 9 4 2015 9 3 2015 9 2 2015 9 1 2014 8 4 2014 8 3 2014 8 2 2014 8 1 2013 7 3 2013 7 2 2013 7 1 2012 6 3 2012 6 2 2012 6 1 2011 5 3 2011 5 2 2011 5 1 2010 4 2 2010 4 1 2009 3 4 2009 3 3 2009 3 2 2009 3 1 2008 2 1 2007 1 2 2007 1 1 Indexes Title Author image sidenavbarimg ISSN 1938 4122 Announcements Call for Reviewers Call for Submissions image button1 addthis gif DHQ Digital Humanities Quarterly 2017 Volume 11 Number 3 2017 11 3 XML Discuss Comments Media Visualization of Book Cover Images Exploring Differences among Bestsellers in Different Countries <PERSON>Wooseob Jeong</PERSON> lt wjeong1_at_emporia_dot_edu gt <ORGANIZATION>Emporia State University Abstract Interest</ORGANIZATION> in the role of book cover images in readers reading experience and book marketing has been long standing This study attempts to compare book covers from different countries with a media visualization tool called ImagePlot The top 100 bestselling books from 13 <ORGANIZATION>Amazon</ORGANIZATION> com s international sites were identified and their cover images were downloaded Using ImagePlot median values of brightness hue and saturation for each image in the data set were extracted and analyzed Along with one way <ORGANIZATION>ANOVA</ORGANIZATION> tests and the resulting graphs from <ORGANIZATION>SPSS</ORGANIZATION> ImagePlot outputs show differences in these graphical properties of bestsellers cover images in different countries From the outputs with all the book cover images displayed on a single canvas screen hidden patterns emerged and findings were clearly confirmed This study makes a contribution by providing connection between research interests in book cover images and media visualization techniques for further research Introduction 1 Contrary to the real meaning of the English idiom <PERSON>Don</PERSON> t judge a book by its cover research interest in book covers has been steady ranging from the personal book selection process to the marketing of trade books For example there is an edited scholarly monograph titled Judging a Book by Its Cover <PERSON>Matthews</PERSON> amp <ORGANIZATION>Moody</ORGANIZATION> 2007 discussing book covers important roles At Goodreads com which is a general forum of readers more than 400 lists related to book covers have been generated by its users which indicates readers long standing interests in the topic In fact the importance of cover images was clearly identified from the late 19th century although 1930 s Penguin Books paper revolution is generally considered as the beginning of the interest in book covers McCleery 2007 Since the 19th century book bindings were commonly decorated on their covers or dust jackets to reflect the content of the book which is a modern development Pearson 2013 and around the same time the growing interests in children s book publishing started to emphasize the importance of book covers to attract the readers eye and to promote the books for sales Immel 2013 2 Despite active research activities on book covers however most studies are based on individual book cover images often with different cover images of a single title over time and in different countries A new method called media visualization can help to overcome this limitation allowing researchers to explore various properties of images in a collection or to compare among multiple image collections 3 This study compares book covers from different countries using media visualization methods to explore characteristics of individual image groups and differences if any among the different image groups Literature Review Visualization of Image Collection for Effective Image Retrieval 4 There have been numerous research projects aimed at providing useful tools for visualization of large image collections for both retrieval and exploration purposes Two approaches are noticeable in the existing literature on visualization of image collections user interaction and semantics 5 In terms of interactive approaches <PERSON>Nguyen</PERSON> and Worring 2005 2008 tested their interactive system with 10 000 <ORGANIZATION>Corel</ORGANIZATION> images with emphasis on overview visibility and structure preservation <PERSON>Nguyen</PERSON> amp Worring 2005 <PERSON>Nguyen</PERSON> amp Worring 2008 <PERSON>Bruneau Picarougne</PERSON> and Gelgon 2010 proposed an interactive system which allows feedback on the clustering process <PERSON>Bruneau</PERSON> et al 2010 <PERSON>Zheng Gomi</PERSON> and <PERSON>Itoh</PERSON> 2014 proposed ImageCube designed for the browsing of image collections associated with multidimensional datasets With 15 participants they tested the interactive system with an automobile catalog dataset published on the Web Zheng et al 2014 Worring Rooji and <PERSON>Rijn</PERSON> 2007 created a prototype that visualizes the network of images by graph based representations and found that the nearest neighbor network can have a positive effect on the interaction effort Worring et al 2007 <PERSON>Yang</PERSON> et al 2006 proposed a scalable semantic image browser which allows interactive visual exploration <PERSON>Yang</PERSON> et al 2006 Fan et al 2009 introduced JustClick an interactive system to enable personalized image recommendation via exploratory search from large scale collections of Flickr images Fan et al 2009 Their experiments on large scale image collections 1 5 billion Flickr images with diverse semantics 4000 image topics have obtained very positive results <PERSON>Camargo Caicedo</PERSON> and <PERSON>Gonzalez</PERSON> 2013 proposed a framework for the construction of an image collection exploration system based on kernel methods with mathematically strong basis of image representation summarization visualization and interaction Carmargo et al 2013 <PERSON>Gao</PERSON> et al 2009 developed an interactive system to filter junk images from keyword based <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> Images search results by mixture of kernels to generate more accurate image clustering <PERSON>Gao</PERSON> et al 2009 <PERSON>Janecek</PERSON> and Pu 2003 implemented a prototype of an interactive focus context visualization which integrates WordNet to utilize relevant semantic information such as metadata and ontologies <PERSON>Janecek</PERSON> amp Pu 2003 6 In terms of semantic approaches many of the literatures cited above were based on textual information of images as well as graphical properties of images Fan et al 2009 Carmargo et al 2013 <PERSON>Yang</PERSON> et al 2006 <PERSON>Gao</PERSON> et al 2009 <PERSON>Janecek</PERSON> amp Pu 2003 Media Visualization 7 Media visualization is different from information visualization According to Manovich 2014 information visualization shows the metadata about the media while media visualization shows the actual data Manovich 2014 If standard information visualization translates data into pictures media visualization translate pictures into pictures Media visualization offers one solution to a fundamental question of digital humanities how to bring together macro and micro distant reading and close reading reading the actual artifacts and reading larger patterns abstracted from very large sets of these artifacts Manovich 2014 8 <PERSON>Manovich</PERSON> has been one of the leading researchers in media visualization His lab developed a visualization tool called ImagePlot by creating many custom macros based on imageJ software which was developed and distributed freely by the <ORGANIZATION>National Institutes of Health NIH Manovich</ORGANIZATION> succinctly summarizes the value of media visualization in the following Step away and you can see larger patterns across a whole data collection Step closer and you can study the details of individual images Manovich 2014 9 These techniques are aimed at scholars working in a number of disciplines including art art history film and media studies who need to analyze large image collections in their work which led to a new interdisciplinary field called Cultural Analytics <PERSON>Yamaoka</PERSON> et al 2011 As an exemplary study <PERSON>Manovich Douglass</PERSON> and Zepel 2012 downloaded one million scanned manga pages from a web site and visualized the whole data by ImagePlot to explore the characteristics of particular manga collections <PERSON>Manovich</PERSON> et al 2012 Importance of Book Cover Image Cover Images in Book Marketing and Promotion 10 Cover art and blurbs are the No 7 reason for buying a book according to reports from the <ORGANIZATION>National Endowment</ORGANIZATION> for the Arts <PERSON>Greco</PERSON> et al 2013 <PERSON>Matthews</PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION>Moody 2007</ORGANIZATION> compiled chapters about the role of book covers in marketing and other aspects into a monograph <PERSON>Matthews</PERSON> amp <ORGANIZATION>Moody 2007 Yampbell 2005</ORGANIZATION> examined 5 covers over 10 years for Weetzie Bat by <PERSON>Francesca Lia Block</PERSON> and concluded that publishers are altering the paratext particulary covers spines and sizes to charm teen readers Yampbell 2005 <PERSON>Regina Sierra Carter</PERSON> 2012 examined different versions of cover images of YA Young Adults books about minority or mixed race characters and concluded that appropriate cover art is necessary because it helps to match the inside story to the story the cover portrays <PERSON>Carter</PERSON> 2012 As seen in the example of a Portuguese translated version of <PERSON>Shariff</PERSON> s book altering book cover images without the author s knowledge can be frustrating <PERSON>Shariff</PERSON> 20913 Croker 2012 suggested that if publishing and authorial populations were involved in more conscious collaboration like <PERSON>Lewis Carroll</PERSON> the paratext could contribute to the enhancement of the reading experience Croker 2012 After examining the text and images of The Beat Goes On book jacket Goldsmith Gross and <PERSON>Carruth</PERSON> 2012 found that although the information on the jacket conveys a strong and accurate sense of the narrative still the front and back covers do not mention the disease which may make the subject matter less clear <PERSON>Goldsmith</PERSON> et al 2012 Cover Images in Book Selection Process 11 For decades in the past the role of cover images in readers book selection has been actively studied and the majority of studies have focused on younger readers from elementary and middle schools <PERSON>Reutzel</PERSON> and <LOCATION>Gali</LOCATION> 1998 observed 18 elementary school children for their book selection behaviors and found that looking at the cover is one of the common book selection elements in children s book selection processes <ORGANIZATION>Reutzel</ORGANIZATION> amp <LOCATION>Gali</LOCATION> 1998 Based on interviews with 36 children grades one through four <PERSON>Carter</PERSON> 1988 found that structural elements including cover information title and picture had much more influence on children s book selection than any other schema used by children to choose reading material Carter 1988 Wendelin and <PERSON>Zinck</PERSON> 1983 conducted a survey with responses from 688 fifth through eighth grade students and found that factors such as the description of a book on the book jacket or back cover and the content of the first page apparently weigh heavily in the decisions to read or not to read a book <ORGANIZATION>Hawkins Wendelin</ORGANIZATION> amp <PERSON>Zinck</PERSON> 1983 However still 8 said they choose a book by the picture on the cover in the first place <PERSON>Kragler</PERSON> and <PERSON>Nolley</PERSON> 1996 observed that 23 of the 17 fourth grade students in a class said they chose a book based on its physical characteristics such as a good looking book cover while 27 chose a book because others in the class had read it or told them it was a good book Kragler amp Nolley 1996 12 In a study with 96 first through fifth grade students on the <ORGANIZATION>ICDL International Children s Digital Library Reuter</ORGANIZATION> 2007 found that 39 6 said cover images influenced their book selection Reuter 2007 Mohr 2006 interviewed 122 first graders and found 25 indicated topic as primary element that influenced their book selection process while only 7 preferred front cover Mohr 2006 Moss and <PERSON>Hendershot</PERSON> 2002 conducted a two year ethnographic case study with 48 sixth graders for their nonfiction trade book selection for reading <PERSON>Moss</PERSON> amp Hendershot 2002 48 reported that visual aspects of the text influenced their book choices whether a picture on the cover or photographs inside the book <PERSON>Swartz</PERSON> and <PERSON>Hendricks</PERSON> 2000 conducted a book selection process study with 31 middle school students with special needs <PERSON>Swartz</PERSON> amp <PERSON>Hendricks</PERSON> 2000 15 of the 31 students said they picked a book because of the pictures on the cover or illustrations in the book From a study with 25 eighth graders <PERSON>Rinehart Gerlach</PERSON> and Wisell 1998 found that these adolescent readers were able to draw important clues from <ORGANIZATION>BOB</ORGANIZATION> back of the book summaries titles and cover illustrations although more emphasis is on BOB rather than cover illustrations <PERSON>Rinehart</PERSON> et al 1998 Based on anonymous observation methods Cunningham 2011 conducted studies on how children find books for leisure reading at bookstores and public libraries and confirmed that the primary basis for the good not good decision is the appearance of the cover <PERSON>Cunningham</PERSON> 2011 13 The role of cover images in book selection has been studied for the adult population as well Spiller 1980 found 27 of public library users mostly adults in the survey with 500 respondents thought that the visual impact of the cover design influenced them to pick up the book in the first instance although the cover alone would not afford enough information Spiller 1980 Researchers at the <ORGANIZATION>University of Waikato</ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION>New Zealand</LOCATION> studied their college students browsing and book selection process and found the cover images play an important role <PERSON>Vanderschantz</PERSON> et al 2011 Timpany et al 2012 <PERSON>Hinze</PERSON> et al 2012 <PERSON>Cunningham</PERSON> et al 2013 <PERSON>Vanderschantz</PERSON> and Timpany 2013 examined a sample of 840 books from their university library s collection for their physical properties of the cover use of a dust jacket type of binding and the contents of the cover background color most predominant color the imagery used and the use of typography based on the Library of <ORGANIZATION>Congress Classification System Vanderschantz amp Timpany</ORGANIZATION> 2013 They concluded that understanding of the design parameters and their variations across different subject areas can assist with accurately conveying the content of a book to the reader as the initial impression of the outside of a book can have an effect on whether the reader delves further into the content Purpose of Study 14 The purpose of this study is utilizing a media visualization method by <PERSON>ImagePlot</PERSON> to find if there is any difference in brightness hue and saturation of cover images of bestseller books from different countries and to identify any patterns among the differences and if so what the characteristics of the differences may be <ORGANIZATION>Methdology Data Collection</ORGANIZATION> 15 In mid April 2014 from <LOCATION>Amazon</LOCATION> com s 13 international sites the cover images of the top 100 bestsellers were collected The 13 international sites include <ORGANIZATION>Australia Brazil Canada China France Germany India Italy Japan Mexico Spain United Kingdom</ORGANIZATION> and <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> A few books did not display their cover images Table 1 shows the number of images in each country s data set with each country s country code Some images have white borders around actual cover images or Look Inside icons but due to time constraints those images were not cropped but used in the data process as they were <ORGANIZATION>Country Number of Images Country Number of Images Australia</ORGANIZATION> AU 100 <LOCATION>Italy</LOCATION> IT 100 <LOCATION>Brazil</LOCATION> BR 100 <LOCATION>Japan</LOCATION> JP 94 <LOCATION>Canada</LOCATION> CA 100 <LOCATION>Mexico</LOCATION> MX 100 <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> CN 100 <LOCATION>Spain</LOCATION> ES 99 <LOCATION>France</LOCATION> FR 100 <LOCATION>United Kingdom UK</LOCATION> 100 <LOCATION>Germany</LOCATION> DE 100 <LOCATION>United States US</LOCATION> 99 <LOCATION>India</LOCATION> IN 99 Table 1 Number of Images by Country Data Processing 16 The collected images were saved in a designated folder for each country By ImageMeasure macro median values of hue brightness and saturation for each image were extracted and saved in a corresponding data file for each country For the overall visualization and analysis all the images regardless of their country origins were collected in a separate folder Their hue brightness and saturation values were measured again and saved into another data file In this file the Internet country code was assigned for each data entry Visualization Tool ImagePlot 17 ImagePlot was developed by <PERSON>Manovich</PERSON> and his lab colleagues with various macros It is primarily based on ImageJ software developed by and freely distributed from NIH With the ImageMeasure txt macro median values of brightness hue and saturation of each image in the data set was automatically obtained Brightness Median is the median of grey scale values for the pixels in an image Saturation Median is the median of saturation which means purity of color for each pixel in an image and Hue Median is the median of color values of all pixels in an image 18 In ImagePlot all the values measured are converted into 0 255 scale ImagePlot Documentation For brightness measurements color images are internally converted to greyscale using this formula gray red green blue 3 If an image is pure black Brightness_Median will be 0 if an image is pure white it will be 255 Low Saturation_Median value indicates that image colors are mostly desaturated a high value indicates that most colors are close to being pure very saturated The 0 255 scale may lead to some confusion particularly for hue values since hue values are normally represented as degree of a circle 0 to 360 from yellow to red with green blue and purple in the middle Therefore when the hue values are represented in a linear form such as X axis or Y axis the interpretation requires extra caution Data Analysis 19 For the overall image collection 3 sets of visualization outputs were rendered by ImagePlot brightness by country hue by country and saturation by country For the differences among countries one way ANOVA analysis was conducted with means and standard deviations stdev of the measured median values of brightness hue and saturation Bar graphs of the result were generated by the <ORGANIZATION>SPSS</ORGANIZATION> software For combined analysis 3 sets of bivariate graphs were generated for each country s collection by ImagePlot brightness vs hue brightness vs saturation and saturation vs hue The output bivariate graphs were compared among countries for further analysis Results Differences in brightness hue and saturation by countries <ORGANIZATION>ANOVA</ORGANIZATION> 20 A one way ANOVA test was conducted by <ORGANIZATION>SPSS</ORGANIZATION> with the median values and standard deviation values of each image for its brightness hue and saturation The results showed that both the median values and the standard deviations are significantly different statistically p lt 05 among countries for all three of the properties 21 Graphical displays of the results can provide more intuitive observation For example a graph based on the mean values for each country shows how bright or dark the books from a country are in general However it may not show how much different each group s images are in brightness In that sense a graph based on standard deviations is useful Figures 1 2 and 3 show the graphical displays of means and standard deviations for brightness hue and saturation respectively The X axis means each country represented by its Internet country domain name Brightness by Country 22 Figure 1 shows that while the book cover images from <LOCATION>Australia</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Brazil</LOCATION> have relatively dark low value in brightness colors they have a wide range of brightness larger standard deviation Meanwhile Chinese books are the brightest among countries with the most homogeneous level of brightness the smallest in standard deviation Japanese books are quite bright as well but with modest variation image Figure 1 Brightness by Country mean vs stdev Hue by Country 23 For hue values a line graph can display different color tones in general among countries For example as seen in the first graph in Figure 2 the books from the <LOCATION>United Kingdom</LOCATION> use much higher value of hue than those from <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> However since hue is based on 360 degree circular measurements for RGB red green and blue values the mean value may not have intuitive indicators Rather the standard deviation values may have more useful information For example from the second graph in Figure 2 it is reasonable to conclude that books from <LOCATION>United Kingdom United States Spain India Italy France</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Germany</LOCATION> have more consistent or homogeneous color schemes than others image Figure 2 Hue by Country mean vs standard deviation Saturation by Country 24 Figure 3 shows that the majority of the books in the data do not have highly saturated colors Chinese Japanese and Australian books have the least saturated colors while French Indian British and American books have the most saturated colors Chinese and Mexican books have the largest standard deviations in saturation while Italian British and American books have the least image Figure 3 Saturation by Country mean vs stdev Differences in brightness hue and saturation by countries <ORGANIZATION>Media Visualization</ORGANIZATION> 25 While the graphics based on the means of median values show some useful information still a bigger picture needs to be examined for a full description of the differences and the outputs from ImagePlot provides more in depth but still easy to identify representation of the book cover images among countries It is also worthwhile to remember that the values for hue are not numeric because red green and blue color are arbitrarily assigned to 0 120 and 240 in a 360 degree color wheel and then later 0 255 into <PERSON>ImagePlot</PERSON> data file 26 The three graphs in Figures 4 5 and 6 show the different brightness hue and saturation of each book cover image from the data by country respectively All the books in the data set were represented on the individual graph with actual images of the covers with the size of 50 by 50 pixels The X axis shows each country represented by its Internet country domain name and the Y axis shows brightness hue and saturation on a scale of 0 255 For brightness and saturation the lower the Y value the darker or the less saturated each image is For hue Y values represent from lower to higher yellow green blue purple red colors 27 In this method since all the actual book cover images are displayed on a graph it is easy to identify patterns throughout the whole data For example Chinese and Japanese books do not have many dark images on their covers and French German Indian and British books have more red purple colors on their covers Most book covers do not have highly saturated colors but Japanese books distinctively do not have highly saturated colors on their covers It also seems that books from <LOCATION>Brazil</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Germany</LOCATION> use either highly saturated colors or lowly saturated colors not middle range saturated colors image Figure 4 Brightness by Country image Figure 5 Hue by Country image Figure 6 Saturation by Country Bivariate Analysis Media Visualization Polar vs Non polar display 28 There are two options for visualization in ImagePlot polar vs non polar Since ImagePlot converted all the values into 0 255 scale regardless of their natural scale for example 0 360 for hue each option has its advantages and disadvantages The polar option seems fancier than the non polar one but the difficulty of interpretation depends on which variables are used For example in Figure 7 it is more intuitive to use the polar display because hue red green and blue colors is easily identified in counterclockwise direction from the right side while the center represents darker and the periphery represents brighter colors However in Figure 8 since neither saturation nor brightness involves a circular data point a polar display option has little value Rather a simple x y coordinate can deliver easier interpretation in this case X axis for brightness and Y axis for saturation In general a non polar display is easier to understand while a polar display may have an advantage if hue is involved image Figure 7 Brightness vs Hue for Brazilian Bestsellers image Figure 8 Brightness vs Saturation for Canadian Bestsellers Brightness vs Hue 29 Figure 9 shows four ImagePlot outputs for brightness and hue in the image data sets from four countries <LOCATION>China Japan United Kingdom</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> X axis is for brightness the higher the value the brighter the image and Y axis for hue from lower value to higher representing yellow green blue purple and red These outputs show that Chinese and Japanese book covers are mostly brightest and less colorful while British and American book covers are not only various in color but also diverse in brightness image Figure 9 Brightness X axis vs Hue Y axis Brightness vs Saturation 30 Figure 10 shows four ImagePlot outputs for brightness and saturation in the image data sets from four countries <LOCATION>China Japan France</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>India</LOCATION> X axis is for brightness the higher the value the brighter the image and Y axis for saturation the higher the value the more saturated In terms of brightness French and Indian books have more dark colors on their covers than Chinese and Japanese books They also have more saturated colors on their covers than Chinese and Japanese books meaning Chinese and Japanese book cover images have more white black or gray elements in their colors image Figure 10 Brightness X axis vs Saturation Y axis Saturation vs Hue 31 From the previous sections on Brightness vs Hue and Brightness vs Saturation it is clear that Chinese and Japanese books distinctively have brighter and less saturated colors In this section of Hue vs Saturation rather subtle distinctions are explored without Chinese or Japanese books image Figure 11 Saturation X axis vs Hue Y axis 32 Figure 11 shows four ImagePlot outputs for hue and saturation in the image data sets from four countries <LOCATION>Germany Italy Mexico</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Spain</LOCATION> X axis is for saturation and Y axis for hue From these graphs it is reasonable to conclude that German and Italian books have more red purple colors on their covers than Mexican and Spanish books more blue colors on Mexican and Spanish book covers as well while Mexican and Spanish books have more saturated colors relatively than German and Italian books Discussion Differences among countries and cultures 33 In the previous section <ORGANIZATION>ANOVA</ORGANIZATION> tests and their graphical outputs along with the media visualizations by <PERSON>ImagePlot</PERSON> showed that there are clear differences among the cover images of bestselling books in different countries in terms of their brightness hue and saturation values The differences are clear enough to allow us to draw a cautious but reasonable generalization regarding cultural difference in book cover images For example between East Asian culture and Anglo American culture there are distinctive differences in brightness hue and saturation East Asian book covers tend to have brighter colors fewer red purple colors and fewer saturated colors than Anglo American books covers These differences may reflect different consumer preferences in book cover images which gives a good insight for global book translation business In other words when publishers translate Anglo American books into East Asian languages they may have to consider changing their book covers to have brighter and less colorful images The opposite suggestion should be made for the other direction of translation for example translation of Chinese or Japanese books into English Possibility of combining book selection process and media visualization 34 Since book cover images have been proven to be an important element in readers book selection it is natural to devise visualization tools for the book selection process For example Thudt Hinrichs and Carpendale 2012 developed an interactive visualization system to allow serendipitous book discoveries by providing cover images based on various metadata including keywords publication and content dates length and author names Thudt et al 2012 In their system the cover color circle focuses on this aesthetic quality of books by providing an overview of cover colors as they occur in the book selection With more refined and richer metadata such as users preference and their searching or reading history this kind of approach can generate more sophisticated interactive book selection or book recommendation systems Potentials of media visualization in information science 35 Information science has a long and strong tradition of information visualization such as bibliometrics and social network analysis Media visualization can enrich this tradition by enabling more cultural and historical artifacts data to be analyzed with flexible graphical analysis technique Since media visualization allows direct display of images of artifacts or still shots of video with all the data displayed on a big canvas screen it can reveal unknown patterns which may not be visible if we only use a small number of cases <PERSON>Manovich</PERSON> et al 2012 The patterns can be identified by time by geographical locations or other variables Numerous digital collections of cultural heritage have been developed and available worldwide in the past several decades Media visualization tools can make a significant contribution in research on those collections via easy to use analysis techniques Study limitation and future research direction 36 Unlike <PERSON>Manovich</PERSON> and his colleagues massive study with 1 million manga pages <PERSON>Manovich</PERSON> et al 2012 this study used only 100 images per each country It would be more desirable if a much larger data set is used Including more countries would be better as well particularly if cultural differences are pursued Even if changing cover images when translated into other languages or countries is common in many cases the original cover images are used in multiple countries It would be interesting to see how much the result may differ if only unique cover images are included However if time is considered as a variable it is also necessary to consider the fact that even in the same country a book may change its cover images numerous times for marketing purposes 37 As mentioned before some cover images have their white borders but the borders were not removed due to time limits for this manuscript The white borders and Look Inside icons may influence the measurement of brightness hue or saturation values of each image although the overall impact on the final data analysis is thought to be minimal considering the fact that only median values are included in the analysis 38 Expansion of this study into other image collections is natural For example jacket images of music CD or DVD collections can be easily analyzed by the same technique used in this study The analysis can be conducted in multiple ways including by time or location Conclusion 39 In their qualitative content analysis with 69 finalist titles for the 2010 Governor General s Literary Awards <PERSON>Pecoskie</PERSON> and Desrochers 2013 suggested that peritextual information including items on book covers can provide great values to the areas of readers advisory and research <PERSON>Pecoskie</PERSON> amp Desrochers 2013 Media visualization may reveal valuable patterns and findings often hidden for further understanding of peritextual information s role in reading experiences and marketing It is believed that this study makes a contribution by providing connection between research interests in book cover images and media visualization technique for further investigation In practical application aspects it also contributes in the book business particularly in the area of translation and marketing of books in different countries with different cover images Works Cited <PERSON>Beheshti</PERSON> amp Large 2013 <PERSON>Beheshti</PERSON> J amp Large J A Eds 2013 The information behavior of a new generation children and teens in the 21st century <PERSON>Rowman</PERSON> amp <PERSON>Littlefield Berry</PERSON> 2012 <PERSON>Berry</PERSON> D M Ed 2012 Understanding digital humanities <PERSON>Palgrave Macmillan Bruneau</PERSON> et al 2010 <PERSON>Bruneau</PERSON> P Picarougne F amp Gelgon M 2010 Interactive unsupervised classification and visualization for browsing an image collection Pattern Recognition 43 2 485 493 Carmargo et al 2013 <PERSON>Camargo J E Caicedo</PERSON> J C amp <PERSON>Gonzalez</PERSON> F A 2013 A kernel based framework for image collection exploration <ORGANIZATION>Journal of Visual Languages amp Computing</ORGANIZATION> 24 1 53 67 <PERSON>Carter</PERSON> 1988 Carter M A 1988 How children choose books Implications for helping develop readers <LOCATION>Ohio</LOCATION> Reading Teacher 22 15 21 Carter 2012 <PERSON>Carter</PERSON> R S 2012 YA literature the inside and cover story YALSA s third annual Young Adult Literature Symposium November 2 4 <ORGANIZATION>St Louis</ORGANIZATION> http www yalsa ala org jrlya 2013 04 ya literature the inside and cover story Croker 2012 Croker B 2012 The vestibule of the text exploration of paratext In Aundreta C F and Pattenden F Eds Exploring visual literacy inside outside and through the frame <ORGANIZATION>Inter Disciplinary Press United Kingdom Cunningham</ORGANIZATION> 2011 Cunningham S J 2011 Children in the physical collection Implications for the digital library Proceedings of the <ORGANIZATION>American Society for Information Science and Technology</ORGANIZATION> 48 1 1 10 Cunningham et al 2013 <PERSON>Cunningham S J Alqurashi H Hinze</PERSON> A Vanderschantz N Timpany C amp Heese R 2013 Browsing and book selection in the physical library shelves Working Paper Series 02 2013 Fan et al 2009 Fan <PERSON>J Keim</PERSON> D A <PERSON>Gao Y Luo</PERSON> H amp Li Z 2009 JustClick Personalized image recommendation via exploratory search from large scale Flickr images Circuits and Systems for Video Technology IEEE Transactions on 19 2 273 288 <PERSON>Gao</PERSON> et al 2009 <PERSON>Gao Y Peng J Luo</PERSON> H <PERSON>Keim</PERSON> D A amp Fan J 2009 An interactive approach for filtering out junk images from keyword based <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> search results Circuits and Systems for Video Technology IEEE Transactions on 19 12 1851 1865 <PERSON>Goldsmith</PERSON> et al 2012 <PERSON>Goldsmith</PERSON> A Y Gross M amp <PERSON>Carruth</PERSON> D 2012 The Cover Story What the Book Jacket of <ORGANIZATION>Adele Minchin</ORGANIZATION> s Young Adult Novel The Beat Goes On Communicates about HIV AIDS http www yalsa ala org jrlya 2012 04 the cover story what the book jacket of adele minchins young adult novel the beat goes on communicates about hivaids <PERSON>Greco</PERSON> et al 2013 <PERSON>Greco</PERSON> A N <PERSON>Milliot</PERSON> J amp Wharton R M 2013 The book publishing industry <ORGANIZATION>Routledge Hawkins Wendelin amp Zinck 1983 Hawkins Wendelin K amp Zinck</ORGANIZATION> R 1983 How students make book choices Reading horizons 23 2 2 <PERSON>Hinze</PERSON> et al 2012 <PERSON>Hinze</PERSON> A McKay D Vanderschantz N Timpany C amp <PERSON>Cunningham</PERSON> S J 2012 June Book selection behavior in the physical library implications for ebook collections In Proceedings of the 12th ACM IEEE CS joint conference on <ORGANIZATION>Digital Libraries</ORGANIZATION> pp 305 314 ACM ImagePlot Documentation ImagePlot Documentation Retrieved from http lab softwarestudies com p imageplot html Immel 2013 <PERSON>Immel</PERSON> A 2013 Children s Books In Suarez M F amp <PERSON>Woudhuysen</PERSON> H R Eds The Book A Global History 220 230 <PERSON>Janecek</PERSON> amp Pu 2003 <PERSON>Janecek</PERSON> P amp Pu P 2003 January Searching with semantics An interactive visualization technique for exploring an annotated image collection In On The Move to Meaningful Internet Systems 2003 OTM 2003 Workshops pp 185 196 Springer <LOCATION>Berlin</LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION>Heidelberg Kragler amp Nolley</ORGANIZATION> 1996 Kragler S amp <PERSON>Nolley</PERSON> C 1996 Student choices Book selection strategies of fourth graders Reading Horizons 36 4 5 Manovich 2014 <PERSON>Manovich</PERSON> L 2014 Visualization Methods for Media Studies in Vernallis Carol <PERSON>Amy Herzog</PERSON> and <PERSON>John Richardson</PERSON> eds The Oxford Handbook of Sound and Image in <ORGANIZATION>Digital Media Oxford University Press</ORGANIZATION> 2014 Manovich et al 2012 <ORGANIZATION>Manovich L Douglass J amp Zepel</ORGANIZATION> T 2012 How to compare one million images 249 278 In Berry D M Ed Understanding digital humanities <PERSON>Matthews</PERSON> amp <ORGANIZATION>Moody 2007 Matthews N amp Moody N</ORGANIZATION> Eds 2007 Judging a book by its cover fans publishers designers and the marketing of fiction <ORGANIZATION>Ashgate Publishing Ltd</ORGANIZATION> McCleery 2007 <PERSON>McCleery</PERSON> A 2007 The paperback revolution Tauchnitz Albatross and <ORGANIZATION>Penguin</ORGANIZATION> 3 17 In Matthews N amp <ORGANIZATION>Moody N Eds</ORGANIZATION> Judging a book by its cover fans publishers designers and the marketing of fiction <PERSON>Mohr</PERSON> 2006 <PERSON>Mohr</PERSON> K A 2006 Children s choices for recreational reading A three part investigation of selection preferences rationales and processes <ORGANIZATION>Journal of Literacy Research</ORGANIZATION> 38 1 81 104 Moss amp Hendershot 2002 Moss B amp <PERSON>Hendershot</PERSON> J 2002 Exploring sixth graders selection of nonfiction trade books The Reading Teacher 6 17 <PERSON>Nguyen</PERSON> amp Worring 2005 Nguyen G amp Worring M 2005 Similarity based visualization of image collections Int l Worksh on Audio Visual Content and <ORGANIZATION>Information Visualization in Digital Libraries Nguyen</ORGANIZATION> amp Worring 2008 Nguyen G P amp Worring M 2008 Interactive access to large image collections using similarity based visualization Journal of Visual Languages amp Computing 19 2 203 224 Pearson 2013 <PERSON>Pearson</PERSON> D 2013 Bookbinding In Suarez M F amp <PERSON>Woudhuysen</PERSON> H R Eds The Book A Global History 245 257 Pecoskie amp Desrochers 2013 Pecoskie J J amp Desrochers N 2013 Hiding in plain sight Paratextual utterances as tools for information related research and practice <ORGANIZATION>Library amp Information Science Research</ORGANIZATION> 35 3 232 240 Reuter 2007 Reuter K 2007 Assessing aesthetic relevance Children s book selection in a digital library Journal of the <ORGANIZATION>American Society for Information Science and Technology 58 12 1745 1763 Reutzel</ORGANIZATION> amp <LOCATION>Gali</LOCATION> 1998 Reutzel D R amp <LOCATION>Gali</LOCATION> K 1998 The art of children s book selection A labyrinth unexplored Reading Psychology An International Quarterly 19 1 3 50 <PERSON>Rinehart</PERSON> et al 1998 <PERSON>Rinehart</PERSON> S D <PERSON>Gerlach</PERSON> J M Wisell D L amp <PERSON>Welker</PERSON> W A 1998 Would I like to read this book Eighth graders use of book cover clues to help choose recreational reading <ORGANIZATION>Literacy Research and Instruction</ORGANIZATION> 37 4 263 280 <PERSON>Shariff</PERSON> 20913 Shariff S 2013 Defining the line on cyber bullying how youth encounter and distribute demeaning information 195 211 In <PERSON>Beheshti</PERSON> J and Large A Eds 2013 The information behavior of a new generation children and teens in the 21st century Scarecrow Press Lanham Spiller 1980 <PERSON>Spiller</PERSON> D 1980 The provision of fiction for public libraries <ORGANIZATION>Journal of Librarianship</ORGANIZATION> and Information Science 12 4 238 266 <PERSON>Suarez</PERSON> amp <PERSON>Woudhuysen</PERSON> 2013 Suarez M F amp <PERSON>Woudhuysen</PERSON> H R Eds 2013 The Book A <ORGANIZATION>Global History Oxford University Press Swartz amp Hendricks 2000 Swartz M K amp Hendricks C G 2000 Factors</ORGANIZATION> that influence the book selection process of students with special needs <ORGANIZATION>Journal of Adolescent amp Adult Literacy</ORGANIZATION> 608 618 Thudt et al 2012 Thudt A <ORGANIZATION>Hinrichs U amp Carpendale</ORGANIZATION> S 2012 May The bohemian bookshelf supporting serendipitous book discoveries through information visualization In Proceedings of the SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems pp 1461 1470 ACM Timpany et al 2012 Timpany C Alqurashi H <PERSON>Hinze</PERSON> A Cunningham S J amp Vanderschantz N 2012 Shared browsing and book selection in an academic library Working Paper Series 05 2012 <PERSON>Vanderschantz</PERSON> amp Timpany 2013 Vanderschantz N amp Timpany C 2013 Who says you can t judge a book by its cover International Journal Of the Book 10 4 1 17 Vanderschantz et al 2011 Vanderschantz N <PERSON>Hinze</PERSON> A Cunningham S J Timpany C amp <PERSON>McKay</PERSON> D 2011 How to take a book off the shelf Learning about ebooks from using a physical library In Proceedings of OZCHI 2011 Workshops Programme Nov 28 amp 29 <LOCATION>Canberra Australia</LOCATION> CHISIG Vernallis et al 2014 Vernallis C <PERSON>Herzog</PERSON> A amp <PERSON>Richardson</PERSON> J Eds 2014 The Oxford Handbook of Sound and Image in <ORGANIZATION>Digital Media Oxford University Press Worring</ORGANIZATION> et al 2007 Worring M de Rooij O amp van <PERSON>Rijn</PERSON> T 2007 September Browsing visual collections using graphs In Proceedings of the international workshop on Workshop on multimedia information retrieval pp 307 312 ACM <PERSON>Yamaoka</PERSON> et al 2011 <PERSON>Yamaoka S Manovich</PERSON> L <PERSON>Douglass</PERSON> J amp <PERSON>Kuester</PERSON> F 2011 Cultural analytics in large scale visualization environments Computer 44 12 39 48 <ORGANIZATION>Yampbell 2005 Yampbell</ORGANIZATION> C 2005 Judging a book by its cover Publishing trends in young adult literature The Lion and the <ORGANIZATION>Unicorn</ORGANIZATION> 29 3 348 372 <PERSON>Yang</PERSON> et al 2006 <PERSON>Yang J Fan J Hubball D Gao Y Luo H Ribarsky</PERSON> W amp Ward M 2006 October Semantic image browser Bridging information visualization with automated intelligent image analysis In Visual Analytics Science And Technology 2006 IEEE Symposium On pp 191 198 IEEE <PERSON>Zheng</PERSON> et al 2014 <PERSON>Zheng Y Gomi</PERSON> A amp <PERSON>Itoh</PERSON> T 2014 ImageCube An Image Browser Featuring a Multi Dimensional Data Visualization Natural Science Report <ORGANIZATION>Ochanomizu University</ORGANIZATION> 64 2 21 32 2017 11 3 XML Print Article Please enable JavaScript to view the comments powered by Disqus URL http www digitalhumanities org dhq vol 11 3 000332 000332 html Last updated Comments dhqinfo digitalhumanities org Published by The <ORGANIZATION>Alliance of Digital Humanities Organizations Affiliated</ORGANIZATION> with Literary and Linguistic Computing Copyright 2005 image Creative Commons License This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution NoDerivatives 4 0 International License</ner>
