<ner>image Page Header Open Journal Systems Journal Help User Username Password Remember me Journal Content Search Search Scope All Authors Title Abstract Index terms Full Text Browse By Issue By Author By Title Other Journals Font Size Current Issue image Atom logo image RSS2 logo image RSS1 logo Article Tools image Abstract image Print this article image Indexing metadata image How to cite item image Email this article Login required image Email the author Login required About The Authors <PERSON>Rodrigo Sandoval Almaz</PERSON> n image orcid <ORGANIZATION>Autonomous University of the State of Mexico Mexico</ORGANIZATION> Associate professor on the political sciences faculty at the <ORGANIZATION>Autonomous University of the State of Mexico</ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION>Toluca Mexico</LOCATION> <PERSON>David Valle Cruz</PERSON> image orcid <ORGANIZATION>Autonomous University of the State of Mexico Mexico Lecturer</ORGANIZATION> in the Engineering Faculty and <ORGANIZATION>Bussiness School</ORGANIZATION> at the <ORGANIZATION>Autonomous State University of Mexico</ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION>Toluca City</LOCATION> Home About Login Register Search Current Archives Announcements SUBMISSIONS Home gt Volume 23 Number 4 2 April 2018 gt <PERSON>Sandoval Almaz</PERSON> n image First Monday image Towards an understanding of Twitter networks The case of the state of <LOCATION>Mexico</LOCATION> by <PERSON>Rodrigo Sandoval Almazan</PERSON> and <PERSON>David Valle Cruz</PERSON> image Abstract The purpose of this research is to provide some understanding of Twitter Networks using the data from the Twitter discussion generated on the State of the Union from Governor <PERSON>Eruviel Avila</PERSON> in 2015 and 2016 We analyzed and compared Network Links from tweets of two years using <PERSON>Netlytic</PERSON> as a mining text tool This research presents two contributions 1 the links analysis perspective of social media and 2 we proposes a methodology to assess the impact of online social media and government promotion Our findings suggest that citizens use social media platforms to interact with politicians in offices and supports the argument about networked individualism in which analyzed Twitter accounts reveal many citizens opinions and retweets related to the governor s use of YouTube for his State of the Union speech Decision makers can use this study to improve communication with their customers public and allocate resources effectively for better public services Finally the last trend has tried to understand content analysis by wording There is a lack of research about network links their quality and users that are part of such network to understand in an integrated perspective the impact of social media <ORGANIZATION>Contents Introduction Literature</ORGANIZATION> review Methodology Results and findings Conclusions bookmark p1 Introduction Providing the State of the Union address via YouTube by the Governor of the State of <LOCATION>Mexico</LOCATION> <PERSON>Eruviel Avila Villegas</PERSON> broke a long tradition of Mexican governors once delivering a long speech in a big ceremony with special guests Since 2015 <PERSON>Eruviel Avila</PERSON> has been using online social media such as <ORGANIZATION>Facebook Twitter Instagram</ORGANIZATION> and YouTube to send his messages This particular event was divided into two stages The first was held on 29 September 2015 EruvielTV where he gave a short message via streaming starting at 20 00 hrs The second stage was an open dialogue through social media accounts Eruviel Twitter com eruviel_avila called EruvielAnswersYou EruvielTeResponde and a panel with journalists students and leaders The purpose of this paper is to compare the networks created by the State of the Union addresses of <PERSON>Eruviel Avila</PERSON> in the past two years 2015 2016 The use of social media in public administration can be defined by two paths 1 in order to legitimate actions of the agency <PERSON>DePaula</PERSON> and Dincelli 2016 and 2 to promote actions and behavior changes related to the purposes and goals of the agency <PERSON>Graham</PERSON> et al 2015 A similar path has been followed by politicians and publicists that use social media platforms to persuade and spread public information or to promote self images with comments or quotations that could be dispersed around their networks <PERSON>Fox</PERSON> and <PERSON>Ramos</PERSON> 2012 <PERSON>Sandoval Almaz</PERSON> n 2015 However in both cases politicians and public administration rarely use online social media <ORGANIZATION>OSM</ORGANIZATION> to establish bidirectional communications with citizens or to create conversations <PERSON>Grimmelikhuijsen</PERSON> and Meijer 2015 Usually <ORGANIZATION>OSM</ORGANIZATION> are used without any knowledge about their impacts limitations or advantages for most public officials <PERSON>Sandoval Almaz</PERSON> n and <PERSON>Gil Garc</PERSON> a 2013 Many government officers use their official Twitter accounts as a complementary communication channel of a more complex strategy to promote a politician s image or different government actions However there are insufficient studies to understand the overall effects and uses of <ORGANIZATION>OSM</ORGANIZATION> in government Guillam n et al 2016 <PERSON>Oliveira</PERSON> and Welch 2013 Research on elections for example Freelon 2014 <PERSON>Kaplan</PERSON> and Haenlein 2010 and the legitimacy of governments <PERSON>Grimmelikhuijsen</PERSON> and Meijer 2015 <PERSON>Hyun</PERSON> and <PERSON>Kim</PERSON> 2015 have been mostly descriptive and general What if we can go deeper into networks and understand what kind of users are linked to a particular network Our research does not analyze specifically the meaning of words sentiments or number of tweets it is instead based on the creators of links individuals behind <ORGANIZATION>Twitter</ORGANIZATION> accounts In order to answer our research questions we selected a political event that used social media for diffusion and tested our assumptions We used the case of the State of the Union speech delivered by the governor of the state of <LOCATION>Mexico</LOCATION> over two years first in September 2015 and then in September 2016 He gave his annual State of the Union speech using <ORGANIZATION>YouTube</ORGANIZATION> and promoted it through <ORGANIZATION>Twitter and Facebook In</ORGANIZATION> advance we speculated that followers or government supporters would send most of the tweets We assumed that support for the governor might come from unconditional accounts or perhaps robots We had a number of questions that we would like to investigate in our research What kind of users are linked to the annual State of the Union speech by the governor of the state of <LOCATION>Mexico</LOCATION> How are online social media tools used to promote the event How would we measure links through their authors image bookmark p2 Literature review According to <PERSON>Verba</PERSON> and <PERSON>Nie</PERSON> 1987 political participation is usually conceptualized along four dimensions voting campaign activity contacting officials and collective activities <PERSON>McLeod</PERSON> et al 1999 as well as Boulianne 2009 and <PERSON>Bakker</PERSON> and Vresse 2011 support the notion that the Internet promotes political participation in several ways <PERSON>McLeod</PERSON> et al 1999 surveyed 389 individuals in order to understand civic participation by analyzing television news Their findings revealed a modest indirect impact using this technology to promote political participation Boulianne 2009 found that the use of Internet that affects online news with strong evidence against the Internet having a negative effect on engagement <PERSON>Bakker</PERSON> and <PERSON>Vresse</PERSON> s 2011 contribution to the debate of the Internet s impact on political participation was derived from a national survey They found positive relationships between online communication and non information uses of the Internet <PERSON>Dimitrova</PERSON> and Bystrom 2013 found that social media had no effects on participation in the <LOCATION>Iowa</LOCATION> caucuses On the other hand <PERSON>Xenos</PERSON> et al 2014 analyzed youth political engagement in the U S U K and <LOCATION>Australia</LOCATION> and found that young people were politically engaged by their use of social media <PERSON>Corrigall Brown</PERSON> and <PERSON>Wilkes</PERSON> 2014 findings established that media exposure affected voting because it increased political knowledge Again <PERSON>Dimitrova</PERSON> et al 2014 using panel surveys stated that digital media forms had appreciable effects on political participation More recent meta analysis studies suggested that social media use had generally a positive relationship with engagement and social capital as well as political participation and civic engagement <PERSON>Skoric</PERSON> et al 2016 Wojcieszak and <PERSON>Mutz</PERSON> 2009 found in chat rooms that deliberation could occur in groups incidentally not deliberately Shirky 2011 outlined political activism using text messaging and online social networks based on cases from the <LOCATION>Philippines Moldova</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Iran</LOCATION> Gerbaudo 2012 complemented <PERSON>Shirky</PERSON> s findings with the use of online social media for political mobilization cyberactivism using Twitter and <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> emerged with the Spanish movement of Indignados anti austerity movement and Arab Spring movements <PERSON>Mitchelstein</PERSON> and <PERSON>Boczkowski</PERSON> 2010 proposed three limitations regarding news on the Internet 1 The assumption of a division between printed broadcasted and online media 2 The notion that analysis should treat media and social practices separately and 3 Inclination to focus on ordinary and extraordinary patterns of the phenomena bookmark 1a 1 Ceron 2015 presented a distinction between news and political trust which were highly associated with social media <PERSON>Moeller</PERSON> et al 2014 stated that actively participating in the communication process of political information online has the strongest impact on internal efficacy Internal efficacy in turn is found to be a significant predictor of first time voters bookmark 2a 2 <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> is essentially one of the most studied social media platforms Effing et al 2011 supported the notion that social media tools could be linked to participation They found that in national elections in the <LOCATION>Netherlands</LOCATION> that politicians with higher social media engagement got relatively more votes within most political parties bookmark 3a 3 <ORGANIZATION>Tufekci</ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON>Wilson</PERSON> 2012 examined interactions during <LOCATION>Egypt</LOCATION> s Arab Spring demonstrating how people learned about the movement using <ORGANIZATION>Facebook Conroy</ORGANIZATION> et al 2012 analyzed the use of <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> for political engagement using a survey of undergraduate students They found that online political participation was strongly correlated with off line political activities <PERSON>Carlisle</PERSON> and <PERSON>Patton</PERSON> 2013 compared political engagement of <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> users and found that individual political activity was not as extensive as predicted <PERSON>Toledo Bastos</PERSON> and colleagues 2013 analyzed the use of political hashtags in Twitter and gatekeepers Park s 2013 research on <ORGANIZATION>Twitter</ORGANIZATION> opinion leaders found that mobilization was mediated with opinion leadership and frequency of use Bode and <PERSON>Dalrymple</PERSON> 2016 surveyed political Twitter users finding that they were engaged in politics in general and less trusting on the mainstream media In terms of social media participation by local governments a preliminary study examined practical social media usage in the U K De Saulles 2011 Bons n et al 2012 studied Spanish municipalities noting that social media use was still in its infancy Effing et al 2013 developed a model to analyze social media participation in local politics They suggested four constructs <ORGANIZATION>Social Media Choice Social Media Use Sense of Community</ORGANIZATION> and Community Engagement Research by S ez Mart n et al 2014 found that social media had an impact on the development of smart cities using Twitter and <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> to promote citizen participation Mossberger and colleagues 2013 examined the use of social networks in 75 of the largest U S cities from 2009 to 2011 During that period they found that the adoption of <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> skyrocketed from just 13 percent in 2009 to nearly 87 percent in 2011 and similarly the use of Twitter increased from 25 percent to 87 percent Firmstone and <PERSON>Coleman</PERSON> 2015 examined three of the largest cities in the <ORGANIZATION>U K</ORGANIZATION> interviewing 20 elected politicians council strategists and communication specialists to understand different motivations to engage and communicate with citizens They found that social media played an important role in defining and reconfiguring the role of citizens within local governance <PERSON>Bons</PERSON> n and colleagues 2015 analyzed 75 local governments in 15 countries most media types used by local governments were links and phones According to <PERSON>Skoric</PERSON> et al 2016 the use of social media has a positive relationship with engagement developing social capital civic engagement and political participation <PERSON>Hofmann</PERSON> and colleagues 2013 examined 15 941 posts and 19 290 comments on <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> pages for 25 of the largest German cities social network sites SNS were used to promote communication between governments and citizens <PERSON>DePaula</PERSON> and Dincelli 2016 analyzed 1 472 posts of 53 distinct municipal departments in 16 U S cities they found that most of the content was used for favorable publicity Collaboration or networking activity was adopted less than 10 of the time <PERSON>Moss</PERSON> et al 2015 examined the use of analytic tools for social media in two British cities noting how these tools affected the use of social media <PERSON>Graham</PERSON> et al 2015 studied 300 municipalities in the U S and found that social media use affected the ability of city officials to control crises In <LOCATION>Turkey Sobaci</LOCATION> and Karkin 2013 revealed that social media was used mostly for self promotion and political marketing <PERSON>Ceron</PERSON> and d Adda 2016 investigated the Italian general election examining information published on official Twitter accounts of Italian parties Their results demonstrated that a negative campaign has positive effects <PERSON>Boulianne</PERSON> s findings 2016 suggested that online news has a minimal effect on civic and political engagement However <PERSON>Boulianne</PERSON> concluded that by building civic awareness among youth online news may be able to address participation inequalities between younger and older citizens <PERSON>Diehl</PERSON> et al 2016 examined Twitter and political campaigns finding that social interaction and news seeking behaviors on social media may lead to diverse networks exposure to dissenting political opinion and changing political views A direct relationship between organizational institutional and environmental factors with governmental use of social media was demonstrated in <LOCATION>Spain</LOCATION> Criado et al 2017 <PERSON>Haro de Rosario</PERSON> et al 2018 demonstrated that <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> was preferred to Twitter as a means of participation in local government issues Factors such as transparency level of activity in social media and interactivity were relevant to citizen engagement In <LOCATION>Mexico</LOCATION> more governments have been adopting these technologies to interact with citizens <PERSON>Sandoval Almaz</PERSON> n <PERSON>Gil Garc</PERSON> a et al 2011 <PERSON>Sandoval Almaz</PERSON> n and <PERSON>Gil Garc</PERSON> a 2013 researched <ORGANIZATION>Twitter and Facebook</ORGANIZATION> in local governments describing a consistent adoption of these platforms between 2010 and 2012 They presented a content analysis of two cases <LOCATION>Sinaloa</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Yucat</LOCATION> n noting the emerging implementation of social media in local governments Based on the diffusion of the innovations theory <PERSON>Valle Cruz</PERSON> and <PERSON>Sandoval Almaz</PERSON> n 2015 analyzed data from Twitter and <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> accounts for 32 Mexican local governments over the years 2010 to 2014 describing how social media was implemented on governmental actions image bookmark p3 Methodology State of the Union speech on Twitter The state of <LOCATION>Mexico</LOCATION> is one of the central states of <LOCATION>Mexico</LOCATION> surrounding <LOCATION>Mexico City</LOCATION> the country s capital The last census reported more than 15 million inhabitants in the state It has been ruled by the traditional political party <ORGANIZATION>Revolutionary Institutional Party PRI</ORGANIZATION> since the Mexican Revolution in the past century It is the former state ruled by actual President <PERSON>Enrique</PERSON> Pe a <ORGANIZATION>Nieto Every</ORGANIZATION> year on September the governor of the state delivers his annual State of the Union speech For the last two years the governor has used YouTube and Twitter to promote this speech For 2015 we collected a sample of 1 529 tweets during 24 26 September For 2016 we collected a sample of 877 tweets during 29 30 September We analyzed these tweets separately in order to understand links between the governor s followers citizens and media then we compared results for the two years We downloaded the total sample of tweets using the hashtag EruvielTeResponde Eruviel the governor Answers You because it was the hashtag advertised during the campaign to promote the State of the Union speeches We collected this information using the Netlytic software based on the <PERSON>Fruchterman Reingold</PERSON> algorithm <PERSON>Fruchterman</PERSON> and Reingold 1991 Accordingly we did not exclude or include any tweet we use the whole sample collected from the Twitter API Research design Online social media methodologies analyze qualitative data such as content analysis semantics but also quantitative data as descriptive statistics of use replication and conversation They also compare different platforms such as <ORGANIZATION>Twitter Facebook</ORGANIZATION> or YouTube and emergent ones like Periscope or WhatsApp The purpose of this research was to understand the number of links and connections to the governor s network created for his annual State of the Union speeches using online social media tools For this purpose we developed our methodology in two main stages 1 data collection in 2015 2 data collection in 2016 Data collection in 2015 We used a Twitter mining tool developed by <PERSON>Netlytic</PERSON> org collecting 1 529 tweets without duplicates and or RT then we analyzed Who mentions whom For our analysis we chose the top five clusters that collected the largest number of Twitter accounts and nodes transforming the data into CSV reading as an Excel file Then we analyzed each cluster manually and categorized <ORGANIZATION>Twitter</ORGANIZATION> author accounts into five groups <ORGANIZATION>PRI</ORGANIZATION> groups <ORGANIZATION>Partido Revolucionario Institucional Institutional Revolutionary Party</ORGANIZATION> followers identified by logo or political position Communication and media groups media accounts or freelance journalists Citizen groups by personal accounts or NGO Twitter accounts identified with more than 10 followers and at least one recent tweet to distinguish them from robots Government groups accounts of public officials or agencies from the local government identified by the name of an agency and compared to lists extant on government public directories and Others those that did not match aforementioned categories but were not robots identified with at least two recent tweets and 20 followers At the end of the analysis we found 570 Twitter accounts from different authors We eliminated retweets and other redundancies or duplicates from the 1 529 analyzed tweets during a two day period for data collection The two days were 24 before the speech and the actual date of the State of the Union address We decided that these two days saw more tweets Intentionally we did not set a boundary for each cluster Netlytic created it by the organizational perspective we chose Who mentions whom but we could had the tweets organized in a different way Who replies to whom According to <LOCATION>Netlytic</LOCATION> every cluster was organized on Who mentions whom criteria with every node grouped according to these relationships For example in cluster 1 the main node was the governor s personal Twitter account it was bigger than the rest in terms of connections to the center Cluster 2 was related to another node around the account manzur_jose He was the vice governor with a centrality value of 78 The third node was centralized by the account pdtegerman a politician and mayor in the State of <LOCATION>Mexico</LOCATION> The centrality value of this cluster was 26 The fourth node gathered the accounts around ricardoalemanmx a local journalist with a centrality value of 12 Finally the last cluster was centralized by the account el_viejopaulino a citizen with a centrality value of 38 Data collection in 2016 We collected 877 tweets without duplicates and or RT We analyzed Who mentions whom and chose the top five clusters that grouped the largest amount of <ORGANIZATION>Twitter</ORGANIZATION> accounts and nodes We analyzed each cluster manually and categorized Twitter author accounts into the same five groups as 2015 At the end of the analysis we found 771 Twitter accounts from different authors We eliminated retweets and other redundancies or duplicates from the 877 analyzed tweets during a two day period of data collection The two days were parallel to those selected in 2015 As in 2015 we did not set a boundary for each cluster with Netlytic organizing according to a Who mentions whom perspective In cluster 1 the governor s personal Twitter account had a centrality value of 24 Cluster 2 was related to another node around the account evielpm undersecretary of social and human development of the Mexican Federal Government with a centrality value of 12 The third node was centralized by the account memomonroyg a politician The centrality value of this cluster was 328 The fourth node gathered the accounts around tapiafernanda a journalist with a centrality value of 149 Finally the last cluster was centralized by the account prawanaa a citizen account with a centrality value of 20 image bookmark p4 Results and findings What kind of users were linked to the case study annual Governor s State of the Union speech using online social media tools to promote it Table 1 illustrates network properties Gruzd 2016 for each year Diameter was 26 for 2015 and diameter was 9 for 2016 representing the longest distance between two network participants Density represents how close participants are within a network with the closest density is 1 the most close knit community conversation Density in the two years was very low meaning that participants were not connected to each other in the network Reciprocity is measured by the number of reciprocal connections in relation to the total number of connections in the network In two years reciprocity was low meaning that most of the conversations were only one sided Centralization measures the average degree centrality of all nodes within a network For 2015 tweets were a little more centralized than 2016 However we had decentralized networks meaning that information flowed more freely between participants Modularity helps to determine whether clusters represent different communities in a network The values for the two years were greater than 0 5 so the groups did not overlap and did not consist of a core group of nodes The network of 2016 had more separated groups in other words different kinds of groups compare Figures 1 and 2 bookmark tab1 Table 1 Network properties clusters 2015 2016 Property 2015 2016 Diameter 26 9 <ORGANIZATION>Density</ORGANIZATION> 0 001644089736 0 001544282757 <ORGANIZATION>Reciprocity</ORGANIZATION> 0 018598884066 0 015523932729 Centralization 0 164344149278 0 231074523882 Modularity 0 595682571112 0 736640795477 bookmark fig1 image <PERSON>Eruviel</PERSON> s clusters summary 2015 Figure 1 <ORGANIZATION>Eruviel</ORGANIZATION> s clusters summary 2015 Note Larger version of figure available here bookmark fig2 image <PERSON>Eruviel</PERSON> s clusters summary 2016 Figure 2 <ORGANIZATION>Eruviel</ORGANIZATION> s clusters summary 2016 Note Larger version of figure available here Our first assumption was that government officials and political party supporters were leading the Twitter authorship accounts This assumption was correct according to our data <ORGANIZATION>PRI</ORGANIZATION> presented 130 accounts and government officials 54 A total of 184 accounts of unconditional supporters for the governor were found in Twitter see Figure 3 bookmark fig3 image Network links and supporters in the case study Figure 3 Network links and supporters in the case study Note Larger version of figure available here Another assumption was that citizens would be a minority in participation for this Twitter promotion of the State of the Union address However citizens represented the largest number of accounts in our sample numbering 192 a few more than government officials and <ORGANIZATION>PRI</ORGANIZATION> combined see Figure 3 Communication and media accounted for 90 Twitter accounts below the political party accounts but above the number of accounts for government officials Finally the other category that grouped accounts with no precise authorship ranked third in the number of accounts with a total of 104 Twitter accounts in our sample <PERSON>Eruviel</PERSON> s network of 2015 was centralized while the 2016 network was not see Figures 1 and 2 The 2015 network was denser than <PERSON>Eruviel</PERSON> s network of 2016 and had more reciprocity than the 2016 network Figure 1 This could be explained because the 2015 State of the Union speech was more widely disseminated Centralization and modularity of the 2016 network were visibly larger than 2015 The 2016 network was not centralized around <PERSON>Eruviel</PERSON> s network was more dispersed and memomonroyg was the biggest cluster Figure 2 In 2015 the eruviel_avila cluster was the largest This memomonroyg node was an official in local government in charge of communications In both 2015 and 2016 we found anomalies inside the network In the 2015 network this anomaly could be explained by citizens against the governor Figure 1 In 2016 the anomaly was due to an overall lack of dissemination Figure 2 of the State of the Union address with another politician memomonroyg becoming the focus of attention These anomalies altered network properties From the cluster groups gathered by Netlytic relations are shown in Figure 3 Political parties group around the node of the second cluster as well as communication and media categoriues Citizens were dispersed but predominantly collected in the first one The use of Twitter to encourage the diffusion of government information seems to have been successful A number of citizens without perceived political affiliations commented and interacted with government and party officials as a result of the governor s State of the Union address Citizens represented the largest number of authors in our sample 192 34 percent <ORGANIZATION>Party</ORGANIZATION> and government officials accounted for 184 authors in the sample see Figure 3 These characteristics related to network properties see Table 1 Our clusters analysis of authors see Figure 1 described a more intense relation on Cluster 1 This cluster was directly related to the governor s Twitter account rather than the official account of the government of the state of <LOCATION>Mexico</LOCATION> This feature could be explained over a perceived lack of credibility for government information in <LOCATION>Mexico Kavanaugh</LOCATION> and colleagues 2014 found support for this notion during the presidential election in <LOCATION>Mexico</LOCATION> in 2012 This approach of tweeting the personal account of the governor reflected individual decisions to avoid contact with the government The political party <ORGANIZATION>PRI</ORGANIZATION> largely maintained conversations within its own private cluster We assumed that citizens would be less interested in the State of the Union address from the governor than political officials or party supporters However citizens were engaged and interested in the addresses as reflected in Twitter traffic The image of the governor was altered thanks to social media This conclusion is different from that found by <PERSON>Dimitrova</PERSON> and <PERSON>Bystrom</PERSON> 2013 on the political effects of social media Political awareness and democratic accountability was evolving due to the use of social media Arnold 2012 Mergel 2014 More citizens were using social media platforms to participate criticize and collaborate with their governments More citizens were aware of government innovation in using technological tools to promote a given event image bookmark p5 Conclusions The first purpose of this paper was to understand links in social networks as represented by Twitter traffic with a second purpose to develop an appropriate methodology Further research is needed for a number of reasons The content of tweets was not examined in this study Our findings stated that most of the users in the network were citizens however we are unaware of how many citizens endorsed the State of the Union addresses The behavior of social media is dependent on the dissemination of information In 2015 we discovered a larger and more centralized network because of dissemination in different media In 2016 the network was smaller and more dispersed We need to better understand the factors influencing network size Different behaviors appeared inside the network as anomalies We need to better understand these anomalies dissecting factors that led to their development over time Broadly our findings suggest that citizens use social media platforms to interact with politicians in office These findings support notions introduced by <PERSON>Rainie</PERSON> and Wellman 2012 about networked individualism It appeared that a number of citizens expressed opinions via <LOCATION>Twitter</LOCATION> over the governor s use of YouTube for his State of the Union addresses This idea of networked individualism was supported by <PERSON>Pieper</PERSON> and <PERSON>Pieper</PERSON> 2015 <PERSON>Carlisle</PERSON> and <PERSON>Patton</PERSON> 2013 and <PERSON>Margetts</PERSON> et al 2015 A significant limitation to this study was that it focused on the state of <LOCATION>Mexico</LOCATION> for a mere 48 hours A longitudinal study with other objects of analysis local county or federal level governments would be more accurate Future research will follow several paths A combination of methods will be used in order to have a more integrated view of tweets Content analysis of tweets will determine their support or rejection of the governor and specific points in his addresses Additionally there will be an effort to understand policy implications of Twitter commentary by citizens We hope that this preliminary study will suggest new paths of research to understand the motivations of public officials and users in their use of social media Additionally we expect that practitioners developing communications strategies will better understand how social media platforms can be used in a more focused fashion image End of article bookmark author About the authors <PERSON>Rodrigo Sandoval Almaz</PERSON> n is an assistant professor in the <ORGANIZATION>Political Sciences and Social Sciences Department</ORGANIZATION> at the <ORGANIZATION>Autonomous State University of Mexico</ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION>Toluca City</LOCATION> Dr <PERSON>Sandoval Almaz</PERSON> n is the author or co author of articles in <ORGANIZATION>Government Information Quarterly Information Polity Electronic Journal of Electronic Ggovernment Journal of Information Technology for Development Journal of Organizational Computing and Electronic Commerce and International Journal of E Politics</ORGANIZATION> His research interests include electronic government open government and social media in government <PERSON>Proffesor Sandoval Almaz</PERSON> n has a Bachelor s degree in political science and public administration a Master s in management focused on marketing and a Ph D in management with information systems Web www rodrigosandoval mx E mail rsandovala at uaemex dot mx <PERSON>David Valle Cruz</PERSON> is a lecturer in the economics faculty and <ORGANIZATION>Bussiness School</ORGANIZATION> at the <ORGANIZATION>Autonomous State University of Mexico</ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION>Toluca City Professor Valle Cruz</LOCATION> research interests are in emergent technologies data mining and artificial intelligence in government E mail davacr at uaemex dot mx Notes bookmark 1 1 <PERSON>Mitchelstein</PERSON> and <PERSON>Boczkowski</PERSON> 2010 p 1 085 bookmark 2 2 Moeller et al 2014 p 689 bookmark 3 3 Effing et al 2011 p 25 References J R Arnold 2012 Political awareness corruption perceptions and democratic accountability in <LOCATION>Latin America Acta Politica</LOCATION> volume 47 number 1 pp 67 90 doi https doi org 10 1057 ap 2011 21 accessed 27 March 2018 <PERSON>Toledo Bastos</PERSON> and colleagues 2013 <PERSON>Tufekci</PERSON> and <PERSON>Wilson</PERSON> 2012 <PERSON>Valle Cruz</PERSON> and <PERSON>Sandoval Almaz</PERSON> n 2015 <PERSON>Verba</PERSON> and <PERSON>Nie</PERSON> 1987 Wojcieszak and <PERSON>Mutz</PERSON> 2009 <PERSON>Xenos</PERSON> et al 2014 T P <PERSON>Bakker</PERSON> and C H de Vreese 2011 Good news for the future Young people Internet use and political participation <ORGANIZATION>Communication Research</ORGANIZATION> volume 38 number 4 pp 451 470 doi https doi org 10 1177 0093650210381738 accessed 27 March 2018 L Bode and K E Dalrymple 2016 Politics in 140 characters or less Campaign communication network interaction and political participation on <ORGANIZATION>Twitter Journal of Political Marketing</ORGANIZATION> volume 15 number 4 pp 311 332 doi https doi org 10 1080 15377857 2014 959686 accessed 27 March 2018 E Bons n S <PERSON>Royo</PERSON> and M Ratkai 2015 Citizens engagement on local governments Facebook sites An empirical analysis The impact of different media and content types in <LOCATION>Western Europe</LOCATION> Government Information Quarterly volume 32 number 1 pp 52 62 doi https doi org 10 1016 j giq 2014 11 001 accessed 27 March 2018 E <PERSON>Bons</PERSON> n L Torres S <PERSON>Royo</PERSON> and F Flores 2012 Local e government 2 0 Social media and corporate transparency in municipalities Government Information Quarterly volume 29 number 2 pp 123 132 doi https doi org 10 1016 j giq 2011 10 001 accessed 27 March 2018 S Boulianne 2016 Online news civic awareness and engagement in civic and political life <ORGANIZATION>New Media amp Society</ORGANIZATION> volume 18 number 9 pp 1 840 1 856 doi https doi org 10 1177 1461444815616222 accessed 27 March 2018 S Boulianne 2009 Does Internet use affect engagement A meta analysis of research Political Communication volume 26 number 2 pp 193 211 doi https doi org 10 1080 10584600902854363 accessed 27 March 2018 J E <PERSON>Carlisle</PERSON> and R C Patton 2013 Is social media changing how we understand political engagement An analysis of <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> and the 2008 presidential election Political Research Quarterly volume 66 number 4 pp 883 895 doi https doi org 10 1177 1065912913482758 accessed 27 March 2018 A Ceron 2015 Internet news and political trust The difference between social media and online media outlets <ORGANIZATION>Journal of Computer Mediated Communication</ORGANIZATION> volume 20 number 5 pp 487 503 doi https doi org 10 1111 jcc4 12129 accessed 27 March 2018 A <ORGANIZATION>Ceron</ORGANIZATION> and G d Adda 2016 E campaigning on Twitter The effectiveness of distributive promises and negative campaign in the 2013 Italian election <ORGANIZATION>New Media amp Society</ORGANIZATION> volume 18 number 9 pp 1 935 1 955 doi https doi org 10 1177 1461444815571915 accessed 27 March 2018 M <ORGANIZATION>Conroy J T Feezell</ORGANIZATION> and M Guerrero 2012 <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> and political engagement A study of online political group membership and offline political engagement Computers in Human Behavior volume 28 number 5 pp 1 535 1 546 doi https doi org 10 1016 j chb 2012 03 012 accessed 27 March 2018 C <PERSON>Corrigall Brown</PERSON> and R Wilkes 2014 Media exposure and the engaged citizen How the media shape political participation <ORGANIZATION>Social Science Journal</ORGANIZATION> volume 51 number 3 pp 408 421 doi http dx doi org 10 1016 j soscij 2014 03 009 accessed 27 March 2018 J I Criado F <PERSON>Rojas Mart</PERSON> n and <PERSON>J R Gil Garc</PERSON> a 2017 Enacting social media success in local public administrations An empirical analysis of organizational institutional and contextual factors <ORGANIZATION>International Journal of Public Sector Management</ORGANIZATION> volume 30 number 1 31 47 doi https doi org 10 1108 IJPSM 03 2016 0053 accessed 27 March 2018 M De Saulles 2011 Social media and local government in <LOCATION>England</LOCATION> Who is doing what In M <PERSON>Klun</PERSON> M Decman and T <PERSON>Jukic</PERSON> editors Proceedings of the 11th European Conference on <ORGANIZATION>eGovernment Reading Academic Publishing Ltd</ORGANIZATION> pp 187 192 N <PERSON>DePaula</PERSON> and E Dincelli 2016 An empirical analysis of local government social media communication Models of e government interactivity and public relations dg o 16 Proceedings of the 17th <ORGANIZATION>International Digital Government Research Conference on Digital Government Research</ORGANIZATION> pp 348 356 doi http dx doi org 10 1145 2912160 2912174 accessed 27 March 2018 T <PERSON>Diehl</PERSON> B E Weeks and H <PERSON>Gil</PERSON> de Z iga 2016 Political persuasion on social media Tracing direct and indirect effects of news use and social interaction <ORGANIZATION>New Media amp Society</ORGANIZATION> volume 18 number 9 pp 1 875 1 895 doi https doi org 10 1177 1461444815616224 accessed 27 March 2018 D V <PERSON>Dimitrova</PERSON> and D Bystrom 2013 The effects of social media on political participation and candidate image evaluations in the 2012 <LOCATION>Iowa</LOCATION> caucuses American Behavioral Scientist volume 57 number 11 pp 1 568 1 583 doi https doi org 10 1177 0002764213489011 accessed 27 March 2018 D V <PERSON>Dimitrova</PERSON> A <PERSON>Shehata J Str</PERSON> mb ck and L W Nord 2014 The effects of digital media on political knowledge and participation in election campaigns Evidence from panel data <ORGANIZATION>Communication Research</ORGANIZATION> volume 41 number 1 pp 95 118 doi https doi org 10 1177 0093650211426004 accessed 27 March 2018 R <PERSON>Effing J van Hillegersberg</PERSON> and T W C Huibers 2013 Social media participation and local politics A case study of the <ORGANIZATION>Enschede Council</ORGANIZATION> in the <LOCATION>Netherlands</LOCATION> In M A <PERSON>Wimmer</PERSON> E Tambouris and A Macintosh editors Electronic participation Lecture Notes in Computer Science volume 8075 <LOCATION>Berlin</LOCATION> Springer Verlag pp 57 68 doi https doi org 10 1007 978 3 642 40346 0_6 accessed 27 March 2018 R <PERSON>Effing J van Hillegersberg</PERSON> and T Huibers 2011 Social media and political participation <ORGANIZATION>Are Facebook Twitter</ORGANIZATION> and YouTube democratizing our political systems In E Tambouris A Macintosh and H de Bruijn editors Electronic participation Lecture Notes in Computer Science volume 6847 <LOCATION>Berlin</LOCATION> Springer Verlag pp 25 35 doi https doi org 10 1007 978 3 642 23333 3_3 accessed 27 March 2018 J Firmstone and S Coleman 2015 Public engagement in local government The voice and influence of citizens in online communicative spaces <ORGANIZATION>Information Communication amp Society</ORGANIZATION> volume 18 number 6 pp 680 695 doi https doi org 10 1080 1369118x 2014 986180 accessed 27 March 2018 R L <PERSON>Fox</PERSON> and <PERSON>J Ramos</PERSON> editors 2012 iPolitics Citizens elections and governing in the new media era <ORGANIZATION>New York Cambridge University Press</ORGANIZATION> D Freelon 2014 Tweeting to power The social media revolution in American politics by <PERSON>Jason Gainous</PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION>Kevin M Wagner Political Communication</ORGANIZATION> volume 31 number 3 pp 502 505 doi https doi org 10 1080 10584609 2014 923280 accessed 27 March 2018 T M <PERSON>J Fruchterman</PERSON> and E M Reingold 1991 Graph drawing by force directed placement <ORGANIZATION>Journal of Software Practice</ORGANIZATION> and Experience volume 21 number 11 pp 1 129 1 164 doi https doi org 10 1002 spe 4380211102 accessed 27 March 2018 P Gerbaudo 2012 Tweets and the streets Social media and contemporary activism <LOCATION>London</LOCATION> Pluto Press M W <PERSON>Graham E J Avery</PERSON> and S Park 2015 The role of social media in local government crisis communications <ORGANIZATION>Public Relations Review</ORGANIZATION> volume 41 number 3 pp 386 394 doi https doi org 10 1016 j pubrev 2015 02 001 accessed 27 March 2018 S <PERSON>G Grimmelikhuijsen</PERSON> and A J Meijer 2015 Does Twitter increase perceived police legitimacy <ORGANIZATION>Public Administration Review</ORGANIZATION> volume 75 number 4 pp 598 607 doi https doi org 10 1111 puar 12378 accessed 27 March 2018 A Gruzd 2016 Netlytic at https netlytic org accessed 27 March 2018 M D <PERSON>Guillam</PERSON> n A M R os B Gesuele and C Metallo 2016 Factors influencing social media use in local governments The case of <LOCATION>Italy</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Spain</LOCATION> Government Information Quarterly volume 33 number 3 pp 460 471 doi https doi org 10 1016 j giq 2016 06 005 accessed 27 March 2018 A <ORGANIZATION>Haro de Rosario A S ez Mart</ORGANIZATION> n and M del <PERSON>Carmen Caba</PERSON> P rez 2018 Using social media to enhance citizen engagement with local government Twitter or <ORGANIZATION>Facebook New Media amp Society</ORGANIZATION> volume 20 number 1 pp 29 49 doi https doi org 10 1177 1461444816645652 accessed 27 March 2018 S <PERSON>Hofmann</PERSON> D Beverungen M R ckers and J Becker 2013 What makes local governments online communications successful Insights from a multi method analysis of <ORGANIZATION>Facebook Government Information Quarterly</ORGANIZATION> volume 30 number 4 pp 387 396 doi https doi org 10 3233 IP 2012 0269 accessed 27 March 2018 K D <PERSON>Hyun</PERSON> and <PERSON>J Kim</PERSON> 2015 The role of new media in sustaining the status quo Online political expression nationalism and system support in <ORGANIZATION>China Information Communication amp Society</ORGANIZATION> volume 18 number 7 pp 766 781 doi https doi org 10 1080 1369118x 2014 994543 accessed 27 March 2018 A M <PERSON>Kaplan</PERSON> and M Haenlein 2010 Users of the world unite The challenges and opportunities of social media Business Horizons volume 53 number 1 pp 59 68 doi https doi org 10 1016 j bushor 2009 09 003 accessed 27 March 2018 A L <PERSON>Kavanaugh</PERSON> S D <PERSON>Sheetz</PERSON> R <PERSON>Sandoval Almaz</PERSON> n J C <PERSON>Tedesco</PERSON> and E A Fox 2014 Media use during conflicts Information seeking gratifications amp efficacy during 2012 Mexican elections dg o 14 Proceedings of the 15th Annual International Conference on <ORGANIZATION>Digital Government Research</ORGANIZATION> pp 205 214 doi http doi acm org 10 1145 2612733 2612738 accessed 27 March 2018 H <PERSON>Margetts</PERSON> P <PERSON>John S Hale</PERSON> and T Yasseri 2015 Political turbulence How social media shape collective action <ORGANIZATION>Princeton N J Princeton University Press</ORGANIZATION> J M <PERSON>McLeod</PERSON> D A <PERSON>Scheufele</PERSON> and P Moy 1999 Community communication and participation The role of mass media and interpersonal discussion in local political participation Political Communication volume 16 number 3 pp 315 336 doi https doi org 10 1080 105846099198659 accessed 27 March 2018 I Mergel 2014 Social media adoption Toward a representative responsive or interactive government dg o 14 Proceedings of the 15th Annual International Conference on <ORGANIZATION>Digital Government Research</ORGANIZATION> pp 163 170 doi http doi acm org 10 1145 2612733 2612740 accessed 27 March 2018 E <PERSON>Mitchelstein</PERSON> and P J <PERSON>Boczkowski</PERSON> 2010 Online news consumption research An assessment of past work and an agenda for the future <ORGANIZATION>New Media amp Society</ORGANIZATION> volume 12 number 7 pp 1 085 1 102 doi https doi org 10 1177 1461444809350193 accessed 27 March 2018 J Moeller C de Vreese F <PERSON>Esser</PERSON> and R <PERSON>Kunz</PERSON> 2014 Pathway to political participation The influence of online and offline news media on internal efficacy and turnout of first time voters American Behavioral Scientist volume 58 number 5 pp 689 700 doi https doi org 10 1177 0002764213515220 accessed 27 March 2018 <ORGANIZATION>G Moss H Kennedy S Moshonas</ORGANIZATION> and C Birchall 2015 Knowing your publics The use of social media analytics in local government Information Polity volume 20 number 4 pp 287 298 doi https doi org 10 3233 IP 150376 accessed 27 March 2018 K <PERSON>Mossberger Y Wu</PERSON> and <PERSON>J Crawford</PERSON> 2013 Connecting citizens and local governments Social media and interactivity in major U S cities Government Information Quarterly volume 30 number 4 pp 351 358 doi https doi org 10 1016 j giq 2013 05 016 accessed 27 March 2018 G H M <PERSON>Oliveira</PERSON> and E W Welch 2013 Social media use in local government Linkage of technology task and organizational context Government Information Quarterly volume 30 number 4 pp 397 405 doi https doi org 10 1016 j giq 2013 05 019 accessed 27 March 2018 C S Park 2013 Does Twitter motivate involvement in politics Tweeting opinion leadership and political engagement Computers in Human Behavior volume 29 number 4 pp 1 641 1 648 doi https doi org 10 1016 j chb 2013 01 044 accessed 27 March 2018 A K <PERSON>Pieper</PERSON> and M Pieper 2015 Political participation via social media A case study of deliberative quality in the public online budgeting process of <ORGANIZATION>Frankfurt Main Germany 2013 Universal Access</ORGANIZATION> in the <ORGANIZATION>Information Society</ORGANIZATION> volume 14 number 4 pp 487 503 doi https doi org 10 1007 s10209 014 0353 4 accessed 27 March 2018 L <PERSON>Rainie</PERSON> and B Wellman 2012 Networked The new social operating system <ORGANIZATION>Cambridge Mass MIT Press</ORGANIZATION> A S ez Mart n A <PERSON>Haro de Rosario</PERSON> and C Caba Perez 2014 A vision of social media in the Spanish smartest cities Transforming Government People Process and Policy volume 8 number 4 521 544 doi https doi org 10 1108 TG 03 2014 0010 accessed 27 March 2018 R <PERSON>Sandoval Almaz</PERSON> n 2015 Using Twitter in political campaigns The case of the <ORGANIZATION>PRI</ORGANIZATION> candidate in <LOCATION>Mexico</LOCATION> International Journal of E Politics volume 6 number 1 pp 1 15 doi https doi org 10 4018 IJEP 2015010101 accessed 27 March 2018 R <PERSON>Sandoval Almaz</PERSON> n and <PERSON>J R Gil Garc</PERSON> a 2013 Social media in state governments Preliminary results about the use of <ORGANIZATION>Facebook and Twitter</ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION>Mexico</LOCATION> In Z Mahmood editor E government implementation and practice in developing countries <LOCATION>Hershey Pa</LOCATION> IGI Global pp 128 146 doi https doi org 10 4018 978 1 4666 4090 0 ch006 accessed 27 March 2018 R <PERSON>Sandoval Almaz n J R Gil Garc</PERSON> a L F <PERSON>Luna Reyes</PERSON> D E <PERSON>Luna</PERSON> and G Diaz Murillo 2011 The use of Web 2 0 on Mexican state Websites A three year assessment <ORGANIZATION>Electronic Journal of e Government</ORGANIZATION> volume 9 number 2 pp 107 121 C Shirky 2011 The political power of social media Technology the public sphere and political change Foreign Affairs at https www foreignaffairs com articles 2010 12 20 political power social media accessed 27 March 2018 M M Skoric Q <PERSON>Zhu D Goh</PERSON> and N Pang 2016 Social media and citizen engagement A meta analytic review <ORGANIZATION>New Media amp Society</ORGANIZATION> volume 18 number 9 pp 1 817 1 839 doi https doi org 10 1177 1461444815616221 accessed 27 March 2018 M Z Sobaci and N Karkin 2013 The use of Twitter by mayors in <LOCATION>Turkey</LOCATION> Tweets for better public services <ORGANIZATION>Government Information Quarterly</ORGANIZATION> volume 30 number 4 pp 417 425 doi https doi org 10 1016 j giq 2013 05 014 accessed 27 March 2018 M <PERSON>Toledo Bastos R L Galdini Raimundo</PERSON> and R Travitzki 2013 Gatekeeping Twitter Message diffusion in political hashtags <ORGANIZATION>Media Culture amp Society</ORGANIZATION> volume 35 number 2 pp 260 270 doi https doi org 10 1177 0163443712467594 accessed 27 March 2018 Z Tufekci and C <PERSON>Wilson</PERSON> 2012 Social media and the decision to participate in political protest Observations from <ORGANIZATION>Tahrir Square Journal of Communication</ORGANIZATION> volume 62 number 2 pp 363 379 doi https doi org 10 1111 j 1460 2466 2012 01629 x accessed 27 March 2018 D <PERSON>Valle Cruz</PERSON> and R <PERSON>Sandoval Almaz</PERSON> n 2015 Social media governments from innovators to laggards The case of Mexican local governments with diffusion of innovations theory dg o 15 Proceedings of the 16th Annual International Conference on <ORGANIZATION>Digital Government Research</ORGANIZATION> pp 250 255 doi https doi org 10 1145 2757401 2757413 accessed 27 March 2018 S <PERSON>Verba</PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION>N H Nie 1987 Participation in America Political democracy</ORGANIZATION> and social equality <ORGANIZATION>Chicago University of Chicago Press</ORGANIZATION> M E Wojcieszak and D C <PERSON>Mutz</PERSON> 2009 Online groups and political discourse Do online discussion spaces facilitate exposure to political disagreement <ORGANIZATION>Journal of Communication</ORGANIZATION> volume 59 number 1 pp 40 56 doi https doi org 10 1111 j 1460 2466 2008 01403 x accessed 27 March 2018 M Xenos A Vromen and B D Loader 2014 The great equalizer Patterns of social media use and youth political engagement in three advanced <ORGANIZATION>democracies Information Communication amp Society</ORGANIZATION> volume 17 number 2 pp 151 167 doi https doi org 10 1080 1369118X 2013 871318 accessed 27 March 2018 Editorial history Received 2 March 2018 accepted 14 March 2018 image Licencia Creative Commons Towards an understanding of Twitter networks The case of the state of <LOCATION>Mexico</LOCATION> por <PERSON>Rodrigo Sandoval Almaz</PERSON> n and <PERSON>David Valle Cruz</PERSON> se distribuye bajo una <ORGANIZATION>Licencia Creative Commons Atribuci n CompartirIgual</ORGANIZATION> 4 0 <ORGANIZATION>Internacional Towards</ORGANIZATION> an understanding of Twitter networks The case of the state of <LOCATION>Mexico</LOCATION> by <PERSON>Rodrigo Sandoval Almaz</PERSON> n and <PERSON>David Valle Cruz</PERSON> First Monday Volume 23 Number 4 2 April 2018 http firstmonday org ojs index php fm article view 8760 6972 doi http dx doi org 10 5210 fm v23i4 8760 image Bookmark and Share A Great Cities Initiative of the <ORGANIZATION>University of Illinois at Chicago University Library First</ORGANIZATION> Monday 1995 2018 ISSN 1396 0466</ner>
