<ner>image DHQ Logo image Digital Humanities Quarterly Logo homesubmissionsabout dhqdhq peoplecontact Current Issue 2017 11 3 Preview Issue 2017 11 4 Previous Issues 2017 11 2 2017 11 1 2016 10 4 2016 10 3 2016 10 2 2016 10 1 2015 9 4 2015 9 3 2015 9 2 2015 9 1 2014 8 4 2014 8 3 2014 8 2 2014 8 1 2013 7 3 2013 7 2 2013 7 1 2012 6 3 2012 6 2 2012 6 1 2011 5 3 2011 5 2 2011 5 1 2010 4 2 2010 4 1 2009 3 4 2009 3 3 2009 3 2 2009 3 1 2008 2 1 2007 1 2 2007 1 1 Indexes Title Author image sidenavbarimg ISSN 1938 4122 Announcements Call for Reviewers Call for Submissions image button1 addthis gif DHQ Digital Humanities Quarterly 2017 Volume 11 Number 3 2017 11 3 XML Discuss Comments Methods of quality quality of methods What does <PERSON>Roberto Busa</PERSON> have to communicate to digital humanists in the 21st century From hermeneutics to performativity <PERSON>Marinella Testori</PERSON> lt testorimarinella_at_gmail_dot_com gt King s College <LOCATION>London</LOCATION> Abstract Despite being also known as the Father of <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> owing to his pioneering contribution to the application of informatics to the whole ensemble of texts by the medieval philosopher and theologian <PERSON>Thomas Aquinas</PERSON> 1225 1274 the Jesuit Italian priest <PERSON>Roberto Busa</PERSON> 1913 2011 has still not been fully appreciated with regard to his development of a hermeneutic informatics <PERSON>Busa</PERSON> 1999 5 Indeed this may represent a key concept to clarify what makes a difference between the common usage of computers in order to speed up procedures and high quality practices enhancing the role of informatics in shaping human interaction with machines In other terms <PERSON>Busa</PERSON> s interpretation of informatics may impact not only on the way in which digital resources and tools are developed but also on the epistemological reflection about <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities In</ORGANIZATION> this paper by drawing from many of his texts I will outline how this innovative hermeneutics is explained by <PERSON>Busa</PERSON> in terms of language dynamisms potentially leading to the development of what <PERSON>Johanna Drucker</PERSON> has described as a humanistic informed theory of the making of technology <PERSON>Drucker</PERSON> 2012 87 1 In his article titled What is humanities computing and what is not <PERSON>John Unsworth</PERSON> suggests looking at humanities computing as a practice of representation Unsworth which he has articulated according to six propositions among which are those concerning humanities computing as a way of reasoning and humanities computing as shaped by the need for human communication The basis for these suggestions outlined in 2002 may be found in the article What is a Knowledge Representation by <PERSON>Randall Davis Howard Shrobe</PERSON> and <PERSON>Peter Szolovits</PERSON> which appeared around a decade before in <ORGANIZATION>Al Magazine</ORGANIZATION> and in the light of which <PERSON>Unsworth</PERSON> has developed his considerations in this contribution in fact the authors have reasoned about the features of knowledge representation which among others they have defined as a set of ontological commitments a medium for efficient computation and a medium of human expression <PERSON>Davis Shrobe</PERSON> and Szolovits 1993 2 It is worth noticing that with their discussion <PERSON>Davis</PERSON> and colleagues have anticipated the current debates regarding what digital humanities is and more specifically the boundary between a generic widespread use of computers to do things and computer applications adding value to academic research in humanistic disciplines because of their capability of representing human knowledge more effectively Interestingly in the second half of the twentieth century <PERSON>Roberto Busa</PERSON> 1913 2011 the groundbreaking developer of the <ORGANIZATION>Index Thomisticus</ORGANIZATION> 1 a linguistic corpus for <PERSON>Thomas Aquinas</PERSON> texts already proposed ideas with the potential to enlighten and steer the contemporary discussion in the field Although <PERSON>Busa</PERSON> is known for having been one of the early pioneers to bring problems in language together with computing machinery his contribution to the development of a hermeneutic informatics 2 is not so appreciated and recognised There is the risk of pigeonholing his work under constraining labels or confining it only to specific sectors for example computing techniques applied to ancient languages It appears to me significant instead that since he worked on the development of a linguistic corpus <PERSON>Busa</PERSON> established in this way a vital connection between humanities computing and the reflection on language 3 In this article I am going to outline the salient ideas put into practice by <PERSON>Busa</PERSON> by discussing some of his contributions as a common thread It is not a coincidence that in 1998 <PERSON>Busa</PERSON> admonished that Informatics is already an ocean <PERSON>Busa</PERSON> 1999 so we need to be careful not to get lost For this reason I also propose many quotations from <PERSON>Busa</PERSON> s texts as a deliberate choice to let the reader know many worthy reflections provided by the scientist that are not so well known so as to stimulate a debate At the same time I will be pointing out how my current experience of work on <PERSON>Busa</PERSON> s legacy is leading me to move ahead with the development of new perspectives requiring further consideration Methods of quality <PERSON>Roberto Busa</PERSON> and the computing in the humanities 4 In his keynote speech From Punched Cards to Treebanks 60 Years of <ORGANIZATION>Computational Linguistics</ORGANIZATION> at the <ORGANIZATION>Eighth International Workshop</ORGANIZATION> on Treebanks and Linguistic Theories Milan 2009 <PERSON>Busa</PERSON> sketched three main typologies of informatics currently in use documentaristic informatics comprising all the informatic services allowing efficient information retrieval editorial informatics referring to the wide range of multimedia devices for reading books watching films browsing the Internet and hermeneutic informatics considering the computerized text analysis or language hermeneutics i e interpretation of all our ways of questioning the whys of language <PERSON>Busa</PERSON> 1999 5 This latter was the informatic typology to which <PERSON>Busa</PERSON> devoted his inexhaustible attention during all his life The focus on language according to him is strictly required by the nature of the relationships between man and computers which interact by means of specific programming codes Moreover the computer allows and exigently demands as its specific capacities an exhaustive detailed deep quantitative knowledge derived from huge amounts of natural texts <PERSON>Busa</PERSON> 1999 6 As a consequence it is arguable that computers and human beings technological devices and humanities are not competitors or antagonists but they are potential allies insofar as they both are human expressions <PERSON>Busa</PERSON> 1999 6 Nevertheless what do we really know about the language our language on which human communication is based and by which it is conveyed Are we really aware of the intrinsic logic the inner dynamism and the psychological implications which are put in motion every time we communicate <PERSON>Roberto Busa</PERSON> defined the language that is unknown <PERSON>Busa</PERSON> 1999 6 3 as signifying that establishing an interaction with the computer machine implies a more profound level of language awareness than that to which we are accustomed This raising of consciousness is necessary to introduce consolidated philological and linguistic methods to the new qualitative dimensions <PERSON>Busa</PERSON> 1980 made available by informatics In the light of this applying computer methods to the humanities can help us to be more humanistic than before <PERSON>Busa</PERSON> 1980 89 because it leads us first to an inner journey through rational paths triggered by language expression This conviction mirrors the current debate regarding the necessity of an epistemological reflection on the making of the digital humanities for example <PERSON>Stephen Ramsay</PERSON> and <PERSON>Geoffrey Rockwell</PERSON> have recently stated that the understanding of underlying theoretical claims is the sine qua non of humanistic enquiry <PERSON>Ramsay</PERSON> and Rockwell 2012 <PERSON>Roberto Busa</PERSON> would have certainly confirmed this vision and reasserted that these underlying theoretical claims primarily involve language dynamisms and linguistic issues More specifically these underlying implications concern the meaning the semantics of words and sentences which is not attainable by a mere quantitative production of a certain amount of data <PERSON>Busa</PERSON> claimed that we do not speak in words but in sentences A sentence has a global meaning which is not the pure sum of the values of its single components The heart of this problem is whether we are able to formalise the global meaning of sentences with something less than the whole sentence itself in other words whether we can succeed in identifying in each sentence something which can be taken as characteristic of its global meaning <PERSON>Busa</PERSON> 1980 88 Quality of methods <PERSON>Roberto Busa</PERSON> and the hermeneutics of informatics 5 According to <PERSON>Busa</PERSON> s experience a high quality methodology in computing for the humanities should be focused on an accurate reflection on communication because man and computer interact with the help of sophisticated languages which differ from common grammar and syntax and require constant development <PERSON>Charles L Isbell</PERSON> et al have confirmed the language oriented nature of the interaction established by human beings with the machine and suggested a reciprocal shaping power of the language on the outside reality the computer and vice versa of the external world the computer to the language itself <PERSON>Isbell</PERSON> et al 2009 4 A more conscious remark of this communicative essence may contribute to illuminating a controversial point in computing for the humanities as <PERSON>Johanna Drucker</PERSON> has pointed out the challenge is to shift humanistic study from attention to the effects of technology from readings of social media games narrative personae digital texts images environments to a humanistic informed theory of the making of technology Drucker 2012 With respect to this question <PERSON>Busa</PERSON> s message is that the development of an informed theory of the making of technology cannot elude a renewed unremitting consideration of language features and issues which in a kind of virtuous circle are positively related to the effects of technology on our life In this sense the fruit sprouting from the hermeneutic informatics to which <PERSON>Busa</PERSON> referred in his last keynote speech From Punched Cards to <PERSON>Treebanks</PERSON> mentioned previously is what I propose to indicate as a language based hermeneutics of informatics Moving ahead of <PERSON>Busa</PERSON> from hermeneutics to performativity 6 This type of theoretical approach along with the scepticism <PERSON>Busa</PERSON> expressed regarding possibilities for a machine to fully develop it Busa 1990 5 clears an unexpected irreplaceable space for the human role in fact although the computer has even improved the quality of methods in philological analysis because its brute physical rigidity demands full accuracy full completeness full systematicity <PERSON>Busa</PERSON> 1980 88 investigating the meaning of a discourse as well as the mind processes involved requires that man instructs the machine to work at this level 7 <PERSON>Busa</PERSON> found in the so called arbor <LOCATION>Porphyrii</LOCATION> the Porphyrian tree suggested by the ancient philosopher Porphyry to explain the Aristotelian Categories 6 an effective way of representing how the human way of reasoning works This is perfectly interpreted by the trees which constitute a treebank a linguistic corpus characterised by a specific focus on the relationships between words and sentences <PERSON>Busa</PERSON> was aware of the difference among the Porphyrian trees expressing a graduated scalarity of similarities and differences <PERSON>Busa</PERSON> 2009 7 among genres and species and the treebanks illustrating relations of real and true dependency <PERSON>Busa</PERSON> 2009 from a linguistic point of view nevertheless he asserts that dependency trees provide a syntax extracted inductively from computerised texts and workable by the computer according to its boundless capacities <PERSON>Busa</PERSON> 2009 that is a pedagogically powerful means for clarifying our interior logic and way of thinking and consequently of communicating 8 8 Building a treebank for the syntactic and semantic annotation of the 11 million words constituting the Index <PERSON>Thomisticus</PERSON> as it is currently being performed by the <ORGANIZATION>Research Group</ORGANIZATION> committed to <PERSON>Busa</PERSON> s legacy with the Index Thomisticus Treebank Project 9 is thus a method of quality par excellence not only for the enhancement of linguistic properties in a text but also for casting light on some mental paths connected with language My current experience as annotator of the IT TB in fact has been increasingly persuading me about what I propose to define as the performative nature of linguistic annotation While working in <PERSON>Busa</PERSON> s footsteps I have been practically experiencing first hand the insights he advanced in From Punched Cards to Treebanks 60 Years of Computational Linguistics and at the same time I have been realizing how these insights can lead us ahead of what <PERSON>Busa</PERSON> himself could not have completely foreseen The most intriguing fact of annotation of a treebank is that it enables the human annotator to deal with a living branching and constantly evolving tree Making a tree live by establishing relations between words until it has reached its accomplished form is the amazing vocation I have discovered since in the very act of annotating I can make the text live It really represents a kind of making of language to recall the title of the book by <PERSON>Mike Beaken</PERSON> The Making of Language Beaken 2011 in which is proposed an alternative view of looking at the origins of language rooted not so much in biological features rather than in cultural and technological developments Treebanks in my vision represent one of these contemporary worth exploring and pursuing developments made available by the advancements of linguistics not only for modern but also for no longer spoken languages Conclusions 9 Language based models of interpreting and building a language along with the development of new technologies in the field of computing applied to the humanities may represent theoretically and practically valid methods of contributing to the above quoted challenges explained by <PERSON>Unsworth</PERSON> and <PERSON>Davis</PERSON> Despite being software embedded in fact these models and related technologies may be able to overcome the inherent limitations e g strong object orientation of mere computational approaches not capturing the performative value of human acts of linguistic expression In addition owing to our language shaped minds they may offer a remedy to that universal lament about the fragmentation of knowledge <PERSON>Busa</PERSON> 2009 that <PERSON>Busa</PERSON> ascertained because the human hunger for syntheses derived from microanalysis continues to surge up and not only in technologies but also in linguistics philosophy psychology and theology <PERSON>Busa</PERSON> 2009 in other words in the context of general human knowledge Notes 1 See the website http www corpusthomisticum org it index age 2 This expression was used by <PERSON>Roberto Busa</PERSON> himself in his keynote speech From Punched Cards to Treebanks 60 Years of Computational Linguistics in Proceedings of the <ORGANIZATION>Eighth International Workshop</ORGANIZATION> on Treebanks and Linguistic Theories 4 5 December 2009 <PERSON>Milan Busa</PERSON> 2009 The full text of the intervention is not available in the Proceedings but it can be acquired through the C I R C S E Centro Interdisciplinare di Ricerche per la Computerizzazione dei Segni dell Espressione at the <ORGANIZATION>Catholic University of Milan Italy</ORGANIZATION> http centridiricerca unicatt it circse_index html rdeLocaleAttr en 3 Language that unknown is a literal translation from Italian The meaning is that generally we do not have a full conscious awareness of the language in all its components 4 The computing machine or artifact is typically manipulated through some language that provides a combination of symbolic representation of the features objects and states of interest as well as a visualization of transformations and interactions that can be directly compared and aligned with those in the world The centrality of the machine makes computing models inherently executable or automatically manipulable and in part distinguishes computing from mathematics Therefore the computationalist acts as an intermediary between models machines and languages and prescribes objects states and processes 5 Language is living open and continually evolving It is in tune with everything that is beautiful and new Consequently the epistemological methodologies of mathematical and physical sciences which measure quantifiable physical entities are not sufficient to dominate and grasp the logic of the signs we use to communicate knowledge 6 For a first general information regarding the Porphyrian Tree see https en wikipedia org wiki Porphyrian_tree See also what is proposed about Transcendentals and Predication in <PERSON>Goris</PERSON> and <PERSON>Aertsen</PERSON> 2013 7 The word scalarity appears in the original text but the most proper term here would be scale 8 Dependency trees are very useful and very educative They train us in an internal speleology on our own logic which in each of us is the spiritual centre of our own personal consistency and dignity Knowing yourself is a process that is never really exhausted 9 The website of the <ORGANIZATION>Index Thomisticus Treebank Project</ORGANIZATION> is http itreebank marginalia it Works Cited Beaken 2011 Beaken Mike 2011 The Making of <ORGANIZATION>Language Edinburgh Dunedin Academic Busa</ORGANIZATION> 1980 <PERSON>Busa Roberto</PERSON> 1980 The Annals of Humanities Computing The <ORGANIZATION>Index Thomisticus Computers</ORGANIZATION> and the Humanities 14 83 90 <PERSON>Busa</PERSON> 1990 <PERSON>Busa Roberto</PERSON> 1990 Informatics and <ORGANIZATION>New Philology Computers</ORGANIZATION> and the Humanities 24 339 343 Busa 1999 <PERSON>Busa Roberto</PERSON> 1999 Picture a Man Busa Award Lecture Debrecen Hungary 6 July 1998 Literary and Linguistic Computing 14 5 9 <PERSON>Busa</PERSON> 2009 <PERSON>Busa Roberto</PERSON> From Punched Cards to Treebanks 60 Years of Computational Linguistics In Proceedings of the <ORGANIZATION>Eighth International Workshop</ORGANIZATION> on Treebanks and Linguistic Theories 4 5 December 2009 Milan Edited by <PERSON>Marco Passarotti Adam Przepi rkowski Savina Raynaud</PERSON> and <PERSON>Frank Van Eynde</PERSON> http convegni unicatt it meetings_Proceedings_TLT8 pdf <PERSON>Davis Shrobe</PERSON> and Szolovits 1993 <PERSON>Davis Randall Howard Shrobe</PERSON> and <PERSON>Peter Szolovits</PERSON> What is a Knowledge Representation 1993 AI Magazine 14 17 33 http groups csail mit edu medg ftp psz k rep html Drucker 2012 <PERSON>Drucker Johanna</PERSON> Humanistic Theory and Digital Scholarship 2012 In Debates in the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> edited by <ORGANIZATION>Matthew K Gold Minneapolis London University of Minnesota Press</ORGANIZATION> http dhdebates gc cuny edu debates text 34 <PERSON>Goris</PERSON> and <PERSON>Aertsen</PERSON> 2013 <PERSON>Goris Wouter</PERSON> and <PERSON>Aertsen</PERSON> Jan 2013 Medieval Theories of Transcendentals The <ORGANIZATION>Stanford Encyclopedia of Philosophy</ORGANIZATION> edited by <PERSON>Edward N Zalta</PERSON> http plato stanford edu entries transcendentals medieval <PERSON>Isbell</PERSON> et al 2009 <PERSON>Isbell Charles L Lynn Andrea Stein Robb Cutler Jeffrey Forbes Linda Fraser John Impagliazzo Viera Proulx Steve Russ Richard Thomas</PERSON> and Yan Xu 2009 Re Defining Computing Curricula by Re Defining Computing SIGCSE Bulletin 41 4 195 207 http www cc gatech edu isbell papers p195 isbell pdf <PERSON>Ramsay</PERSON> and Rockwell 2012 Ramsay <PERSON>Stephen</PERSON> and <PERSON>Geoffrey Rockwell</PERSON> 2012 Developing Things Notes toward an Epistemology of Building in the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities In Debates</ORGANIZATION> in the <ORGANIZATION>Digital Humanities</ORGANIZATION> edited by <ORGANIZATION>Matthew K Gold Minneapolis London University of Minnesota Press</ORGANIZATION> http dhdebates gc cuny edu debates part 3 <ORGANIZATION>Unsworth Unsworth John What is Humanities Computing</ORGANIZATION> and What is Not http computerphilologie uni muenchen de jg02 unsworth html 2017 11 3 XML Print Article Please enable JavaScript to view the comments powered by Disqus URL http www digitalhumanities org dhq vol 11 3 000329 000329 html Last updated Comments dhqinfo digitalhumanities org Published by The <ORGANIZATION>Alliance of Digital Humanities Organizations Affiliated</ORGANIZATION> with Literary and Linguistic Computing Copyright 2005 image Creative Commons License This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution NoDerivatives 4 0 International License</ner>
