<ner>image Page Header Open Journal Systems Journal Help User Username Password Remember me Journal Content Search Search Scope All Authors Title Abstract Index terms Full Text Browse By Issue By Author By Title Other Journals Font Size Current Issue image Atom logo image RSS2 logo image RSS1 logo Article Tools image Abstract image Print this article image Indexing metadata image How to cite item image Email this article Login required image Email the author Login required About The Authors Qianli Yuan Ph D student in the <ORGANIZATION>Department of Public Administration and Policy Rockefeller College of Public Affairs and Policy University at Albany SUNY Mila Gasc Research Associate Professor</ORGANIZATION> in the <ORGANIZATION>Department of Public Administration and Policy Rockefeller College of Public Affairs</ORGANIZATION> and Policy and the Associate Research Director in the <ORGANIZATION>Center for Technology</ORGANIZATION> in Government both at the <ORGANIZATION>University at Albany SUNY Home About Login</ORGANIZATION> Register Search Current Archives Announcements SUBMISSIONS Home gt Volume 23 Number 4 2 April 2018 gt <ORGANIZATION>Yuan</ORGANIZATION> image First Monday image Citizens use of microblogging and government communication during emergencies A case study on water contamination in <LOCATION>Shanghai</LOCATION> by <PERSON>Qianli Yuan</PERSON> and <PERSON>Mila Gasco</PERSON> image Abstract This study explored how citizens and governments used microblogging for communication during the water contamination incident in <LOCATION>Shanghai China</LOCATION> Based on analysis of both citizen and government microblogging posts this study showed citizens can use microblogging to engage in the emergency response in four different ways while governments mainly applied a push strategy for communication Although public organizations showed a weak sign of using a pull strategy the overall misalignment in the use of microblogging limited its benefits as an interactive platform where additional network collaboration can be developed This study contributes to understanding how citizens actually use microblogging during an emergency and how governments adapt to the observed users behavior over time Further research is needed to explore how governments can use pull or networked strategy to maximize the benefits of microblogging <ORGANIZATION>Contents Introduction Literature</ORGANIZATION> review Research design Findings Discussion Conclusion bookmark p1 Introduction Social media has been increasingly used by both governments and citizens to create opportunities for participation and collaboration in <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> Microblogging a platform allowing users to post short messages and small pieces of digital content like pictures video or audio on the Internet that frequently maintain and instantly update target audiences on their activities opinions and status <PERSON>Barnes</PERSON> et al 2010 has become particularly popular among citizens since it allows them to exchange information among a wide range of Internet users enabling many to many interactive networks Bertot et al 2012 Compared to other social media platforms microblogging is used more frequently given its characteristics immediacy ubiquity portability simplicity and availability In addition it makes access to messages open for the public at large who can read them via either desktop computers or mobile devices <PERSON>Kwon</PERSON> et al 2014 Its main attributes also allow for more reciprocity as well as for targeting specific users bookmark 1a 1 Although there are several microblogging platforms in the world Twitter is the most popular one However its use is blocked in <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> where as a result domestic microblogs like <PERSON>Weibo</PERSON> com are on the rise Ma 2013 Like Twitter they allow users to post instant messages of a maximum of 140 characters which can sometimes contain hyperlinks pictures or videos for original content Users can read respond or share microblogs posted by other users They use hashtags and mentions to make messages more likely to be found by people who are interested in them Recent years have witnessed the increasing use of <PERSON>Weibo</PERSON> com microblogging for citizens to communicate with governments currently 59 3 percent of Chinese Internet users have a microblogging account Ma 2013 bookmark 2a 2 The main features of microblogging have made it the favorite tool to use in a variety of natural and man made crisis situations from hurricanes earthquakes and floods to the riots that took place in 2011 in the <LOCATION>United Kingdom</LOCATION> and the aftermath of the 2013 <ORGANIZATION>Boston Marathon</ORGANIZATION> bombings Gasc et al 2017 <PERSON>Blum</PERSON> et al 2014 Fugate 2011 Microblogging can afford efficient and widespread information distribution as well as information collection to improve situational awareness Wukich 2015 Further its use during emergencies represents a shift in crisis communication from mere information transmission to interaction between organizations and the public <ORGANIZATION>Gasc</ORGANIZATION> et al 2017 As Wukich 2015 phrases it the public becomes a much more active and potentially empowered participant in the event as opposed to a passive receiver of responder produced messages bookmark 3a 3 The literature has echoed this trend and has addressed the use of microblogging by first responders during emergencies Yet only a few studies have focused on the use of microblogging by citizens <ORGANIZATION>Gasc</ORGANIZATION> et al 2017 Mergel 2014 Chatfield et al 2013 Meijer 2014 We believe it is an important topic because it may show how citizens actually engage with first responders and public organizations during emergencies Comparing citizens and public organizations use of microblogging allows us to further explore plausible links between public opinions and government communication Our paper addresses this gap by studying the use of microblogging and particularly of <PERSON>Weibo</PERSON> com by citizens and governments during a water contamination emergency in <LOCATION>Shanghai China</LOCATION> We focus on <PERSON>Weibo</PERSON> com as this fast paced short messaging service is the most used in <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> and therefore the most frequently adopted platform by governmental agencies and citizens alike for different events including crises and emergency situations The following research questions have guided our study 1 How do citizens use microblogging to communicate and participate online during an emergency 2 How do public agencies use microblogging for communication with citizens during an emergency The remainder of this paper is as follows the first section reviews the current literature on microblogging in the public sector and particularly in emergency management Next a detailed description of the research design is provided In the following sections we describe and discuss our main findings on citizens use of microblogging during different phases of the water contamination incident Finally we present our most important conclusions providing evidence of new approaches to the use of microblogging by citizens during emergency situations image bookmark p2 Literature review Social media applications like <ORGANIZATION>Facebook Twitter YouTube LinkedIn</ORGANIZATION> and wikis have been widely accepted by governmental agencies around the world as information and communication channels <PERSON>Mergel</PERSON> 2013a <PERSON>Warren</PERSON> et al 2014 Zheng 2013 Among them microblogging sites like Twitter have shown great potential regarding information sharing and public participation in emergency management <PERSON>Wukich</PERSON> and <PERSON>Mergel</PERSON> 2016 Reuter et al 2012 Microblogging offers citizens a broad channel to communicate with authorities and to be actively involved in an emergency Alexander 2014 Latonero and Shklovski 2011 At the same time it offers important advantages to public organizations as large scale communication tools Hughes et al 2014 <PERSON>Yates</PERSON> and <PERSON>Paquette</PERSON> 2011 However previous studies concluded that social media is differently used by citizens and governmental agencies Reuter et al 2012 <LOCATION>Houston</LOCATION> et al 2014 Prentice and <PERSON>Huffman</PERSON> 2008 Thus this section reviews usage of social media by both governments and citizens parties during emergencies In her work <PERSON>Mergel</PERSON> 2013a 2013b identifies three possible strategies regarding social media use by governmental agencies representation involvement and networking The first one is a communication strategy that suggests that governments have to be represented in all potential interaction channels Its objective is to reach audiences in those social spaces they frequent on a daily basis using a press release style that seeks for no interaction According to <PERSON>Mergel</PERSON> the resulting social media tactic can be described as a push strategy where minimal additional resources are invested into tailoring the content specifically for social media channels on active bidirectional interactions bookmark 4a 4 The engagement strategy suggests that governments and public administrations realize that their audiences want to interact with them in a more natural and informal style instead of reading governmental reports or official memoranda <PERSON>Mergel</PERSON> 2013b who refers to this strategy as a pull strategy states that it promotes bilateral interactions the engagement strategy goes beyond mere broadcasting of information to the public Instead agencies are actively trying to encourage their audiences to co create and share content in different formats with them The engagement strategy in many ways uses social media applications for their initially intended purposes to connect users with each other bookmark 5a 5 Finally the networking strategy focuses on listening to citizens This way of proceeding allows public administrations to absorb comments and to gain valuable perspectives about citizens feelings or the issues they worry about It is a highly interactive and bidirectional strategy which also allows users to reuse government information and knowledge that is the content of social media In sum in <PERSON>Mergel</PERSON> s 2013b words a networking tactic of a social media strategy therefore does not necessarily only include active interactions with the public instead it can be seen as an enhanced interaction of the public with the content an agency is producing and a snowballing of the content through the audiences own networks bookmark 6a 6 Several studies argue that governments follow both push and pull strategies in their use of social media although push strategies and particularly one to many push strategies are more prominent <PERSON>Mergel</PERSON> 2013b Reuter et al 2016 <LOCATION>Houston</LOCATION> et al 2014 As a result public organizations mainly use social media particularly microblogging as a broadcasting tool to disseminate critical information like warnings alerts and suggestions <PERSON>Sutton</PERSON> et al 2013 <PERSON>Bennett</PERSON> 2014 <PERSON>Bruns</PERSON> et al 2012 By providing broader accessibility and lower costs for rapid information dissemination <PERSON>Keim</PERSON> and Noji 2011 social media enables public organizations to reach a wide range of people affected by disasters D az et al 2014 <PERSON>Tucker</PERSON> et al 2012 and to disseminate customized information Latonero and Shklovski 2011 <PERSON>Tseng</PERSON> et al 2011 Wukich 2015 referred to this strategy of using social media during emergency as one of the three strategies information dissemination The other two additional strategies were monitoring of real time data to accrue situational awareness and engaging the public in conversations or the coordination of actions including crowdsourcing While one of these uses may be more prominent depending on the situation Wukich 2015 suggested that practitioners might maximize outcomes by using all three strategies in concert and thus implement a wider three step strategy all three strategies complement each other and enable emergency managers to effectively augment traditional communication practices bookmark 7a 7 These three uses of microblogging in emergency management have been well documented <LOCATION>Heverin</LOCATION> and <PERSON>Zach</PERSON> 2010 For example <PERSON>Landwehr</PERSON> and <PERSON>Carley</PERSON> 2014 showed the use of Twitter by the <LOCATION>Portland</LOCATION> branch of the <ORGANIZATION>National Incident Management Organization NIMO</ORGANIZATION> during the 2011 <LOCATION>Shadow Lake</LOCATION> fire to gain situational awareness about fire risk and updated messages to address citizens needs <PERSON>Sutton</PERSON> et al 2013 also showed that emergency managers can engage with citizens by using replies mentions or hashtags to encourage citizen generated content and open dialogue <LOCATION>Miorandi</LOCATION> and Maggi 2014 found that the public collaborated with governmental agencies provided language translation and drew the disaster area map through social media platforms In doing so social media became an interactive platform for crowdsourcing to connect with citizens and to integrate information from both governments and citizens <PERSON>Mergel</PERSON> 2014 Despite wide research about the potential of social media use by governments during emergency events few studies have discussed citizens communication and behavior on microblogging platforms The few which did described citizens behavior as information milling that helped them to assess risks to their own lives <PERSON>Mergel</PERSON> 2014 <PERSON>Liu</PERSON> et al 2010 <PERSON>Purohit</PERSON> et al 2014 In this respect citizens used social media as an information source to seek out information that might help them understand emergencies <PERSON>Palen</PERSON> and Liu 2007 Tseng et al 2011 Social media therefore might bridge the information gaps of traditional media reports and reduce the plight of the affected public due to a lack of information Alexander 2014 In addition citizens may use microblogging to timely convey first hand information to both first responders and other citizens <PERSON>Sutton</PERSON> et al 2008 Information conveyed to governmental agencies often includes evaluation of their emergency responses and actions which helps them adapt response strategies Alexander 2014 Reuter et al 2012 When citizens address that information to other citizens a bottom up citizen led network can emerge to timely assist each other in emergencies Poblet et al 2014 <PERSON>Alexander 2014 Palen</PERSON> and <PERSON>Liu</PERSON> 2007 As <PERSON>Sutton</PERSON> et al 2008 showed sharing doubts showing support and confirming critical situation on a microblogging platform raises awareness on the event and creates an online community which contributes to addressing those issues Citizen generated content on social media may contribute to first responders more informed decisions and may provide a more targeted response to the situation <PERSON>Purohit</PERSON> et al 2013 <PERSON>Eismann</PERSON> et al 2016 <PERSON>Palen</PERSON> et al 2010 D az et al 2014 Actually public organizations are starting to recognize the value of citizen generated content and social media and to incorporate it as a necessary instrument in the emergency response D az et al 2014 Hughes 2014 This may result in a change of the citizens role during crises an evolution from a passive service receiver <PERSON>Branicki</PERSON> and Agyei 2015 to a network member <PERSON>Panagiotopoulos</PERSON> et al 2013 who can become an active and responsible agent capable of contributing to emergency response <PERSON>Ginige</PERSON> et al 2014 However analyzing and using citizen generated information may face two challenges On one hand microblogging platforms are usually owned by third parties outside the public sector ecosystem This may result in a high level of uncertainty due to unexpected changes in the platforms and uncontrollable cybersecurity risks Public organizations also need to deal with emergent citizen behaviors characterized by the constant change of opinions and messages which often cause difficulties in both social media policies and government organizational structures <PERSON>Kavanaugh</PERSON> et al 2012 <PERSON>Mergel</PERSON> and Bretschneider 2013 Further inaccurate information disseminated by citizens may result in spreading viral rumors and false information <PERSON>Starbird</PERSON> and Palen 2011 which requires the ability to separate key information from noise and to connect citizens to right response actions <PERSON>Wukich</PERSON> and <PERSON>Mergel</PERSON> 2016 Hughes et al 2014 These challenges show how important it is to understand how citizens actually use microblogging platforms during emergencies and how that use offers a tool for first responders and governmental agencies to improve decisions and consequent impact of crisis responses Governments need to adapt to the observed users behaviors within microblogging platforms Our study aims at shedding light on this unexplored topic by answering the following questions 1 How do citizens use microblogging to communicate and participate online during emergencies 2 How do governmental agencies use microblogging to communicate with citizens image bookmark p3 Research design To investigate citizens and governments use of social media during emergency situations we examine an illustrative case of a water contamination incident in <LOCATION>Shanghai</LOCATION> that took place in 2013 Case studies are suitable to answer descriptive exploratory or explanatory questions about in depth understanding of real life contexts They provide the flexibility to explore complex and relatively unstructured and infrequent phenomena This leaves room for unexpected interesting findings that can form the basis for specific hypotheses to be tested in future research Yin 2014 <PERSON>Bennett</PERSON> and <PERSON>Elman</PERSON> 2007 Case background On 4 March 2013 a citizen spotted a few dead pig bodies on the upstream of the <LOCATION>Huangpu River</LOCATION> in <LOCATION>Shanghai</LOCATION> and posted his finding on <PERSON>Weibo</PERSON> com The original post was followed by huge media coverage The incident caught citizens attention and more citizens posted on <PERSON>Weibo</PERSON> com It raised great public concern since the <LOCATION>Huangpu River</LOCATION> is the main water source for the residents in <LOCATION>Shanghai</LOCATION> and everyone had a stake in water safety Therefore such an event triggered a wide ranged public reaction and led to a strong desire for public participation on the microblogging platform On 9 March the <LOCATION>Shanghai</LOCATION> municipal government launched a systematic emergency response While reinforcing field cleaning the local government of <LOCATION>Shanghai</LOCATION> along with the governments of <LOCATION>Jiaxing</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Zhejiang</LOCATION> started to locate the source of contamination After a three day investigation the three governments came up with inconsistent results The local government of <LOCATION>Shanghai</LOCATION> identified <LOCATION>Jiaxing</LOCATION> as the source of the water contamination while both the governments of <LOCATION>Jiaxing</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Zhejiang</LOCATION> denied this accusation The absence of conclusive explanations led later on to a wide ranged online discussion on the cause of the incident and the effectiveness of the governmental response Multiple government microblogging accounts started to post official messages to inform citizens about the incident investigation and the field cleaning process They posted information about the numbers of dead pigs and about how the investigation was progressing Seven government microblogging accounts engaged in this process The contamination incident became more visible when the central government began to intervene On 16 March a group of inspectors from the <ORGANIZATION>Department of Agriculture</ORGANIZATION> arrived in <LOCATION>Shanghai</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Jiaxing</LOCATION> to conduct further investigations Results confirmed that <LOCATION>Jiaxing</LOCATION> was the source of the water contamination The governments of <LOCATION>Jiaxing</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Zhejiang</LOCATION> were required to take responsibility to control the amount of water contamination On 24 March the <LOCATION>Shanghai</LOCATION> municipal government announced the end of the emergency response and switched to routine operations on water quality control and contamination monitoring The following table shows the four stages we identified in this water contamination incident bookmark tab1 Table 1 The evolution of the water contamination incident Stage Initial stage Early stage Later stage End Date 4 March 8 March 9 March 16 March 16 March 24 March 25 March 28 March Incident Many dead pigs suddenly appeared in the <LOCATION>Shanghai Huangpu River Shanghai</LOCATION> started to implement a comprehensive plan of emergency response The central government intervened Multiple government agencies participated in the emergency response <LOCATION>Shanghai</LOCATION> announced that the field cleaning in the <LOCATION>Huangpu River</LOCATION> was completed During this emergency incident citizens used microblogging to express their opinions on water contamination and emergency response based on the information from <PERSON>Weibo</PERSON> com governmental announcements and media reports Citizens collected and disseminated information on a continuous basis to share their own opinions and assessments about the emergency At the same time governmental agencies <LOCATION>Songjiang District</LOCATION> government <ORGANIZATION>Shanghai Municipal Shanghai Department of Agriculture Shanghai Bureau of Water and Sea Shanghai Police Department Jiaxing City Government</ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION>Jiaxing Environmental Protection Agency</ORGANIZATION> used their microblogging accounts to post official messages about this incident In total 94 messages were posted from seven microblogging accounts within a month Data collection Microblogging data was collected in two phases First we started by collecting and analyzing 1 834 messages posted by citizens between 4 March and 28 March on <PERSON>Weibo</PERSON> com Second we collected official microblogging messages by searching the accounts of seven governmental agencies who participated in the emergency response During the initial data collection we searched for messages containing water contamination in <LOCATION>Shanghai</LOCATION> dead pigs in <LOCATION>Shanghai</LOCATION> dead pigs on the <LOCATION>Huangpu River</LOCATION> and public safety emergency in <LOCATION>Shanghai</LOCATION> The search found 34 500 results which included amongst other citizens microblogging posts forwarded posts news bulletins by news agencies and announcements by other private sector organizations In order to obtain a comprehensive picture of citizens use of microblogging this study focused on microblogging messages posted by individual citizens that expressed their own opinions and comments We therefore excluded those messages posted by organizations and excluded forwarded messages as they did not contain new information This led to a set of 1 834 citizen microblogging posts stored in the custom database that showed citizens behaviors on <PERSON>Weibo</PERSON> com Next to the original microblogging text we stored the timestamp of when the message was posted day and time and the handle of the microblogging user During the second phase the same key terms were applied to search messages in the seven official accounts of governmental agencies shown in Table 2 Eventually we found seven government microblogging accounts that together posted 94 official messages about the water contamination incident between 4 28 March Those official microblogging posts were also stored in the custom database with timestamps and users information bookmark tab2 Table 2 Official government microblogging accounts Agency Official account Number of posts <ORGANIZATION>Shanghai Municipal Shanghai Broadcast 16 Shanghai Department of Agriculture Shanghai Agriculture Broadcast</ORGANIZATION> 17 <ORGANIZATION>Shanghai Bureau of Water and Sea Shanghai Water and Sea Broadcast</ORGANIZATION> 30 <ORGANIZATION>Shanghai Police Department Shanghai Railway Policy Department Broadcast</ORGANIZATION> 14 <LOCATION>Songjiang District</LOCATION> government <ORGANIZATION>Shanghai Songjiang Broadcast</ORGANIZATION> 7 <LOCATION>Jiaxing City</LOCATION> government <LOCATION>Jiaxing Broadcast</LOCATION> Official 6 <ORGANIZATION>Jiaxing Environmental Protection Agency Jiaxing Environmental Protection</ORGANIZATION> 4 Data analysis To understand both citizens reactions and government communication we coded citizen posts and government posts separately on their content Each of the 1 834 citizen posts and 94 government posts was coded manually by two different researchers using a set of pre defined codes from the existing literature on social media Wukich 2015 Liu 2016 bookmark 8a 8 Additional codes on social media during emergency situations emerged during the analysis process Those codes were later categorized and their meaning was evaluated by the researchers following a grounded theory approach Charmaz and Belgrave 2015 At this stage of conceptualization the collected data was broken down into separate sections according to different points of view and was labeled considering both its content and the pre defined codes The analysis generated 576 open codes for citizen posts Codes with similar meanings were later collapsed combined or integrated resulting in 356 codes These codes were further organized into categories according to the themes they covered Eventually 17 categories were identified that covered eight topics For government posts 234 open codes were created and nine categories were eventually identified see Appendix Those categories were non exclusive since a few posts were labeled by more than one code image bookmark p4 Findings We next report the results of our research and look into the use of microblogging by both citizens and governments We conclude that citizens used microblogging to express their own opinions in four different ways At the same time the analysis of governments posts shows that public organizations changed the content of their messages over time Citizens use of microblogging We identified four different ways in which citizens used microblogging to engage in this incident 1 to express their safety concerns 2 to deliberate on the cause of the emergency 3 to provide suggestions and 4 to make assessments of the emergency response The microblogging platform became a channel for citizens to address concerns and to share their opinions with public organizations and with fellow citizens Expressing safety concerns First citizens expressed their safety concerns due to the great uncertainty brought by the incident <ORGANIZATION>Citizens</ORGANIZATION> mainly worried about two safety issues water safety and food safety Since the <LOCATION>Huangpu River</LOCATION> is one of the main sources of drinking water in <LOCATION>Shanghai</LOCATION> water safety became the focus of public safety concerns Another focus of citizens concerns was pork food safety which was about pork food products made from dead pigs Figure 1 shows that within 72 hours 20 73 percent of the citizens were worried about water safety and 10 98 percent were concerned about pork food safety As the incident evolved the demand for field response decreased while concerns about the source of water contamination increased This increase probably resulted from inconclusive government explanations about the origin of the emergency Later concerns about accountability became the fourth concern as citizens started to ask about entities that needed to be held responsible for this incident By the end most of the citizens 24 19 percent were concerned about pig farming safety bookmark fig1 image Evolution of citizens concerns on microblogging Figure 1 Evolution of citizens concerns on microblogging Note Larger version of figure available here Deliberating on the origin of the emergency During the incident citizens were confused by inconclusive explanations about the source of contamination that the governments of <LOCATION>Shanghai</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Jiaxing</LOCATION> provided They therefore used microblogging to discuss the origin of water contamination and explored several options Some citizens argued that farmers illegal dumping of dead pigs in the upstream area was one of the causes that led to water contamination Many citizens shared this view based on the news about how the labels of some dead pigs showed they were raised and cultivated in the farms in <LOCATION>Jiaxing City</LOCATION> I think there has been pig disease in <LOCATION>Jiaxing</LOCATION> since January Some farmers just dumped those dead pigs into the river bookmark 9a 9 Nowadays so many immoral merchants They dared to dump those pigs into the river My judgment these pigs are from <LOCATION>Jiaxing</LOCATION> bookmark 10a 10 Other citizens argued that poor management of pig agriculture in <LOCATION>Jiaxing</LOCATION> was the root of the water contamination incident behind illegal dumping <ORGANIZATION>Citizens</ORGANIZATION> wanted the government of <LOCATION>Jiaxing</LOCATION> to take responsibility for the crisis since it failed to effectively execute the policies regarding dead animal disposal Ineffective surveillance and regulation of pig agriculture could not prevent farmers from illegally disposing of the bodies I am concerned about why there are so many dead pigs Is there any hidden information bookmark 11a 11 From the beginning due to limitations in regulation water safety in the downstream area could not be fully guaranteed bookmark 12a 12 Providing suggestions <ORGANIZATION>Citizens</ORGANIZATION> used <PERSON>Weibo</PERSON> com to also provide suggestions and recommendations on how to address the crisis Governmental agencies were first suggested to increase resources to speed up the cleaning process Figure 2 shows that 7 32 percent of the online citizens strongly suggested that more resources including personnel had to be allocated to speed up the cleaning process and to reduce the contamination in the <LOCATION>Huangpu River</LOCATION> To protect water safety public agencies were suggested to enhance real time monitoring of water quality By the end of the incident 4 84 percent of the citizens mentioned water safety control and it was the only suggestion during the final stage Another important recommendation had to do with controlling the source of water contamination About 15 85 percent of citizens suggested governments focusing on inhibiting dead pig dumping in the upper reaches by punishing illegal farmers Recovery is not the key It is a temporary solution The key is to crack down on the source and shut down the illegal pig farms bookmark 13a 13 governmental agencies should investigate and put a heavy penalty on agricultural enterprises which committed a crime bookmark 14a 14 bookmark fig2 image Public suggestions on microblogging Figure 2 Public suggestions on microblogging Note Larger version of figure available here Assessing emergency response During this incident citizens provided feedback and assessment on emergency response through microblogging based on their own understanding and feelings Overall public feedback to government emergency response changed from positive to negative Initially citizens expected governments as main responsible entities for emergency response to deal with the emergency effectively However as the incident evolved they continued to question the efficiency and effectiveness of the government response At the beginning 16 87 percent of the citizens provided suggestions and appealed to governmental agencies for more response actions By the end of the incident about 51 61 percent of the citizens criticized government information release accountability and on site investigation about 32 26 percent of the citizens questioned the authenticity of government statements and the effectiveness of government response They gradually felt disappointed at the governments ability and less than 10 percent of the citizens continued to provide recommendations The focus of citizens criticism changed over time At the beginning about 17 07 percent of the public stated that the field cleaning up had been ineffective to reduce water contamination Yet this criticism on field response decreased as the local government of <LOCATION>Shanghai</LOCATION> announced it would initiate a systematic emergency response However criticism regarding water quality food safety accountability and the origin of the contamination increased over time indicating the public s dissatisfaction with how the government released information challenging both information authenticity and transparency of government Further the lack of accountability was an issue of great concern and about 9 50 percent of the citizens referred to it Although questions about the origin of the contamination and the way information being disclosed de escalated over time complaints about accountability did not bookmark fig3 image Public assessment of emergency response Figure 3 Public assessment of emergency response Note Larger version of figure available here Government communication through microblogging Both the governments of <LOCATION>Shanghai</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Jiaxing</LOCATION> communicated with citizens through their official microblogging accounts As the incident evolved the number of official posts increased to address various issues about the water contamination crisis and emergency response actions The content of those posts also evolved as the incident unfolded and covered main public concerns mentioned earlier Yet we identified a delay in government communication public organizations posted later in time in comparison to citizens Government microblogging posts over time The first official message was posted at 2 00 p m on 4 March from the microblogging account Jiaxing Environment Protection It shortly stated Have dispatched staff to check This official message was not followed by other official posts until 8 March when another government microblogging account <ORGANIZATION>Shanghai Railway Policy Department Broadcast</ORGANIZATION> posted an official announcement about the water contamination incident Other two official accounts <LOCATION>Shanghai Songjiang Broadcast</LOCATION> and <ORGANIZATION>Shanghai Agriculture Broadcast</ORGANIZATION> forwarded this message later that day A lot of dead pigs appeared in the <LOCATION>Huangpu River</LOCATION> Recently many dead pigs appeared in the area of the <LOCATION>Huangpu River</LOCATION> protected for drinking water source The contamination came from the illegal pig farms from the upper stream area according to the preliminary investigation Up until the 5th the relevant agencies have collected 45 pig corpses To avoid harm to drinking water quality the relevant agencies will further put effort into contamination cleaning and water quality inspection http t cn zYnTZDy In the beginning governmental agencies posted only six messages before they initiated a systematic response plan The number of official posts increased gradually as their emergency response actions unfolded until the end of the incidents Governmental agencies posted most microblogging messages 62 posts during the later stage In comparison to the number of citizens posts over time governments posted fewer official messages in the early stage They also started to post later in time The mismatch between the incident evolution and the evolution of the numbers of posts shows a certain delay in starting online communication addressed to citizens bookmark fig4 image Numbers of government and citizen microblogging posts over time Figure 4 Numbers of government and citizen microblogging posts over time Note Larger version of figure available here Government microblogging content The content of government official microblogging posts also evolved over time During the early stage the content of government official posts mainly covered issues about field response 37 74 percent pork food quality inspection 22 64 percent and water quality monitoring 22 64 percent Other issues covered but with less emphasis were the investigation about the origin of the crisis 11 32 percent and pig farming 5 66 percent Yet Figure 5 shows that only a small part of the content of the governments posts coincided with the content posted by citizens including both public concerns and suggestions Some 13 90 percent of the citizens criticized governments accountability yet none of the official posts during the early stage touched on that issue This mismatch in terms of content between government and citizen posts may indicate that during the early stage governmental agencies were not really addressing citizens concerns and were not really promoting bilateral interactions Instead they were reaching audiences using microblogging as a press release tool bookmark fig5 image Content of government and citizen posts during the early stage Figure 5 Content of government and citizen posts during the early stage Note Larger version of figure available here During the later stage the official microblogging messages were posted in a more systematic way The content of government posts covered field responses 28 79 percent investigation of the origin of the crisis 26 89 percent and accountability 15 53 percent Figure 6 shows that the content of government posts was more aligned with the content of citizens posts in later stages This increasing coincidence may imply that governmental agencies started to look for a certain bilateral interaction with citizens by addressing their concerns and suggestions Posts about the origin of the crisis and accountability increased while posts about pork food quality inspection decreased In focusing on the former topics governments showed a delayed but real interest in addressing citizens concerns Yet there was still a gap between citizens focus and governments posts For example during this later stage only 11 74 percent of government posts addressed water quality issues in comparison to 23 22 percent of citizen posts Compared to the previous stage governmental agencies seemed to adjust the focus of their messages bookmark fig6 image Content of government and citizen posts during the later stage Figure 6 Content of government and citizen posts during the later stage Note Larger version of figure available here Formats of government microblogging The way content was posted on the microblogging platform showed little interaction with citizens indicating the use of a push strategy see Discussion In addition Table 3 shows that over 70 percent of the government posts exceeded the 140 characters limitation Those posts usually provided a hyperlink to another Web site or to a PDF file containing detailed information about water quality progress on field response source of the contamination and accountability issues Governmental agencies followed one typical template for official summaries and messages Title agencies names response actions They compiled all government response actions into a long Web page or PDF file with little effort to integrate the information These posts were less interactive and only a few of them highlighted issues or concerns brought up by citizens such as water quality and the origin of the crisis bookmark tab3 Table 3 Format of government microblogging Type of microblogs Description Frequency Percentage Text microblogs Microblogs that contains only text of 140 characters 17 18 08 Microblogs with photos <PERSON>Microblogs</PERSON> that include both text and pictures from crisis scene 9 9 57 Microblogs with Web site links Microblogs that include links to other Web sites with government reports 37 39 36 Long microblogs with PDF files Microblogs that include a link to a PDF file with full information 31 32 98 In addition governmental agencies used official language to write those messages They used technical vocabulary to describe the incident For instance information regarding water quality in the government posts often included residual chlorine turbidity and total number of bacteria Also posts about pig disease inspection included the word porcine circovirus Although governmental agencies were accustomed to those terms in their daily operations those words and phrases made less sense to ordinary citizens with little background knowledge In this regard official microblogging posts did not make emergency response information more understandable disseminating information in a less interactive way image bookmark p5 Discussion The main objective of this article was to examine how citizens and governmental agencies used microblogging during a water contamination incident in <LOCATION>Shanghai China</LOCATION> Regarding citizens we have identified four different ways of engaging in the crisis through microblogging 1 expressing public concerns 2 providing suggestions 3 deliberating on the cause of the incident and 4 assessing emergency response As previous work has shown citizens actively expressed their feelings and opinions through microblogging and participated in the emergency response processes engaging in a milling process <PERSON>Palen</PERSON> and Liu 2007 Tseng et al 2011 Mergel 2014 During the water contamination incident in <LOCATION>Shanghai</LOCATION> citizens messages were not only addressed to public organizations but also to peer citizens <PERSON>Currie</PERSON> 2009 indicating the existence of an incipient rhetorical arena <PERSON>Frandsen</PERSON> and <PERSON>Johansen</PERSON> 2017 <PERSON>Coombs</PERSON> and Holladay 2014 where crisis responses emanate from different types of actors including the public In <PERSON>Coombs</PERSON> and <PERSON>Holladay</PERSON> s 2014 words The rhetorical arena considers the voices of any actors trying to communicate about the crisis as crisis communicators From this perspective multiple voices can attempt to influence crisis publics not just the one organizational voice A rhetorical arena opens around a crisis Various actors enter into this arena by engaging in communication about a crisis or potential crisis bookmark 15a 15 Further the use of the microblogging platform <PERSON>Weibo</PERSON> com in this case resulted in a digital environment where peer discussion or a many to many model co existed rather than replaced the one to many model encouraged by traditional media <LOCATION>Wukich</LOCATION> and <PERSON>Mergel</PERSON> 2015 However and despite the potential to increase situational awareness citizens in this incident did not play a role as active information providers Poblet et al 2014 <PERSON>Branicki</PERSON> and Agyei 2015 Most of their posts included citizens subjective feelings and opinions about the incident instead of specific more objective information related to the situation It is worth though to note that feelings about the crisis were quite similar and reflected citizens main concerns suggestions and evaluation during the duration of the incident We believe that this specific content is the result of citizens that were not directly affected by the water contamination nor had sufficient access to the effected area D az et al 2014 They had therefore little first hand information and were less capable of contributing to situational awareness In any case citizens opinions and feelings showed what their concerns and insights about the water contamination incident were and what they wanted emergency response to focus on <ORGANIZATION>Citizens</ORGANIZATION> became evaluators that provided feedbacks to first responders turning <PERSON>Weibo</PERSON> com into a bottom up channel <PERSON>Purohit</PERSON> et al 2013 Reuter et al 2012 Regarding public organizations use of the microblogging platform we observe a push strategy The objective of such a strategy is to reach audiences in those social spaces frequently on a daily basis other than traditional ones According to <PERSON>Mergel</PERSON> 2013b in a push strategy minimal additional resources are invested into tailoring content specifically for social media channels on active bidirectional interactions This push strategy was predominant during the early stage of the crisis although the content of government posts was somewhat more coincident with public concerns and suggestions in a later stage suggesting the presence of an incipient pull or engagement strategy <PERSON>Mergel</PERSON> 2013a 2013b that is one that promotes bilateral interactions Still the one to many approach was the one adopted by public organizations over the course of the crisis <PERSON>Sutton</PERSON> et al 2013 <PERSON>Bennett</PERSON> 2014 In this respect both the governments of <LOCATION>Shanghai</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Jiaxing</LOCATION> had an online presence and used their official accounts to broadcast emergency information to citizens They chose less interactive formats with technical vocabulary making <PERSON>Weibo</PERSON> com a top down communication channel between citizens and government organizations As a result despite citizens use of the microblogging platform in the water contamination incident public organizations considered them as mere passive receivers of information and hardly provided a direct response to public opinions <PERSON>Branicki</PERSON> and Agyei 2015 particularly at the beginning of the crisis We therefore argue that this misalignment in the use of <PERSON>Weibo</PERSON> com limited the benefits of microblogging as an interactive platform reproducing a top down relationship with no room for additional network collaboration <PERSON>Panagiotopoulos</PERSON> et al 2013 Surprisingly as previously noticed towards the end of the crisis there were weak signs of a pull strategy and governments started to include some content that addressed citizens concerns and needs of information Hughes 2014 Latonero and Shklovski 2011 We conclude that these slight changes may show not only a change in the communication strategy and use of <PERSON>Weibo</PERSON> com but also in the potential influence of citizens messages on government communication strategies Further research is needed to exactly explore how and to what extent citizens interaction on the microblogging platform resulted in an improved and more targeted online communication strategy D az et al 2014 <PERSON>Tseng</PERSON> et al 2011 Jennex 2010 Ginige et al 2014 Finally our study shows that there are still many challenges that need to be addressed in the use of microblogging by both citizens and public organizations during emergency situations <PERSON>Wukich</PERSON> and <PERSON>Mergel</PERSON> 2016 Hughes et al 2014 We have already referred to the misalignment in the use of <PERSON>Weibo</PERSON> com Further it was not easy for governmental agencies to analyze citizen posts in real time since their content included feelings and opinions which were highly unstructured and constantly changing Previous works have already referred to this challenge which is even more difficult to overcome when a traditional top down communication approach is adopted <PERSON>Kavanaugh</PERSON> et al 2012 In this regard governmental agencies should improve their capacity for data mining to detect public opinions locate and identify citizen concerns and further adapt to the observed user behavior within a given microblogging platform Hughes et al 2014 Lastly our findings seem to suggest a lack of coordination amongst governmental agencies in sending homogeneous messages as suggested by <PERSON>Pechta</PERSON> et al 2010 and <PERSON>Wukich</PERSON> and <PERSON>Steinberg</PERSON> 2013 which should be further explored in future studies image bookmark p6 Conclusion Our study on the water contamination incident in <LOCATION>Shanghai China</LOCATION> explored two research questions We showed that citizens used microblogging to engage during the emergency in four different ways while government organizations mainly applied a push strategy on the microblogging platform Although there were weak signs of a pull strategy used by public organizations the misalignment between public organizations and citizens use of social media in resolving the crisis limited the benefits of microblogging as a bidirectional communication channel Further it generate doubt over its potential to become a networked platform where all actors can produce and reuse online information and knowledge contributing to an emergency Our findings have a number of practical implications On one hand microblogging is not just another communication channel Despite its benefits it adds complexity to crisis management and requires crisis responders to further explain their actions online Microblogging changes the ecosystem of communication and governmental agencies should be aware of the need to manage crises both off line and online On the other hand our study shows that changing concerns of citizens throughout a crisis will find their expression on social media Using the combination of sentiment and content analysis channels such as <PERSON>Weibo</PERSON> com are therefore excellent indicators for changes in the type of concerns and information requirements that enable governments to adjust communication strategies and to address more accurate and needs oriented messages Finally our findings make evident the need to further unleash the full potential of microblogging and social media generally speaking during emergency situations by both citizens and governmental agencies going beyond communication and enhancing coordination and collaboration The creation of a community around an incident which could foster collaboration and peer to peer communications rather than top down or bottom up strategies could be an interesting idea that deserves further attention In addition to the latter our results raise questions that need further research On one hand what explains the limited and uncoordinated use of microblogging by public organizations Many works studying government use of social media around the globe show as our study that the predominant strategy is the push strategy What hinders transition then to a pull or networked strategy On the other how can public organizations change to maximize the benefits of using microblogging Or in other words how can the content gap be addressed Finally how far our observations also hold for other forms of crises and other social media platforms are questions that require further attention image End of article bookmark author About the authors <PERSON>Qianli Yuan</PERSON> is a Ph D student in the <ORGANIZATION>Department of Public Administration and Policy Rockefeller College of Public Affairs and Policy University at Albany SUNY</ORGANIZATION> His research focuses on open innovation open government data and co production through social media <PERSON>Qianli Yuan</PERSON> obtained his Master s degree of public administration at the <ORGANIZATION>School of International Relations and Public Affairs Fudan University</ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> E mail qlyuan1990 at outlook dot com <PERSON>Mila Gasc</PERSON> is a Research Associate Professor in the <ORGANIZATION>Department of Public Administration and Policy Rockefeller College of Public Affairs</ORGANIZATION> and Policy and the Associate Research Director in the <ORGANIZATION>Center for Technology</ORGANIZATION> in Government both at the <ORGANIZATION>University at Albany SUNY</ORGANIZATION> Before joining the <ORGANIZATION>University</ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION>Albany</LOCATION> Dr <PERSON>Gasc</PERSON> served as a senior researcher at the <ORGANIZATION>Institute of Governance and Public Management</ORGANIZATION> currently known as <ORGANIZATION>ESADEgov Center for Public Governance</ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION>Institute of Innovation and Knowledge Management</ORGANIZATION> both at <ORGANIZATION>ESADE Business amp Law School</ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION>Spain</LOCATION> Prior to that she was a senior analyst at the <ORGANIZATION>International Institute on Governance of Catalonia</ORGANIZATION> and a professor in the <ORGANIZATION>Rovira Virgili University</ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION>Pompeu Fabra University</ORGANIZATION> both in <LOCATION>Spain</LOCATION> E mail mgasco at ctg dot albany dot edu Acknowledgments We want to thank multiple funding agencies for their generous support that made this research possible <ORGANIZATION>China National Social Science Foundation Project</ORGANIZATION> ID 11CGL091 <ORGANIZATION>Shanghai Science and Technology Commission Project</ORGANIZATION> ID 11CGL091 Notes bookmark 1 1 <PERSON>Kommers</PERSON> and Isaias 2012 p 193 bookmark 2 2 In May 2017 <PERSON>Weibo</PERSON> com reached 340 million active monthly users http www bbc com news technology 39947442 bookmark 3 3 Wukich 2015 p 132 bookmark 4 4 <ORGANIZATION>Mergel</ORGANIZATION> 2013b p 128 bookmark 5 5 Ibid bookmark 6 6 <PERSON>Mergel</PERSON> 2013b p 129 bookmark 7 7 Wukich 2015 p 284 bookmark 8 8 Following Procter et al 2013 we decided to manually analyze and classify posts The authors argue that automated sentiment analysis is not yet sufficiently reliable to be used as a substitute for human interpretation of message content Hence as Procter et al 2013 did our methodology combines in ways that are complementary techniques that make use of relatively unsophisticated computational tools with conventional qualitative methods for media analysis bookmark 9 9 liyujing 1 the original post in Chinese bookmark 10 10 the original post in Chinese bookmark 11 11 the original post in Chinese bookmark 12 12 <PERSON>Simon</PERSON> the original post in Chinese bookmark 13 13 the original post in Chinese bookmark 14 14 the original post in Chinese bookmark 15 15 <PERSON>Coombs</PERSON> and Holladay 2014 p 42 References <PERSON>David E Alexander</PERSON> 2014 Social media in disaster risk reduction and crisis management <ORGANIZATION>Science and Engineering Ethics</ORGANIZATION> volume 20 number 3 pp 717 733 doi https doi org 10 1007 s11948 013 9502 z accessed 14 March 2018 <PERSON>Stuart J Barnes Martin</PERSON> B hringer <PERSON>Christian Kurze</PERSON> and <PERSON>Jacqueline Stietzel</PERSON> 2010 Towards an understanding of social software The case of Arinia HICSS 10 Proceedings of the 2010 43rd <ORGANIZATION>Hawaii International Conference on System Sciences</ORGANIZATION> pp 1 9 doi https doi org 10 1109 HICSS 2010 406 accessed 14 March 2018 <PERSON>Andrew Bennett</PERSON> and <PERSON>Colin Elman</PERSON> 2007 Case study methods in the international relations subfield Comparative Political Studies volume 40 number 2 pp 170 195 doi https doi org 10 1177 0010414006296346 accessed 14 March 2018 <PERSON>DeeDee M Bennett</PERSON> 2014 How do emergency managers use social media platforms <ORGANIZATION>Journal of Emergency Management</ORGANIZATION> volume 12 number 3 pp 251 256 and at http www wmpllc org ojs 2 4 2 index php jem article view 374 accessed 14 March 2018 doi http dx doi org 10 5055 jem 2014 0178 accessed 14 March 2018 <PERSON>John Carlo Bertot Paul T Jaeger</PERSON> and <PERSON>Justin M Grimes</PERSON> 2012 Promoting transparency and accountability through ICTs social media and collaborative e government Transforming Government People Process and Policy volume 6 number 1 pp 78 91 doi https doi org 10 1108 17506161211214831 accessed 14 March 2018 <PERSON>Jeffrey R Blum Alexander Eichhorn Severin Smith Michael Sterle Contala</PERSON> and <PERSON>Jeremy R Cooperstock</PERSON> 2014 Real time emergency response Improved management of real time information during crisis situations <ORGANIZATION>Journal</ORGANIZATION> on Multimodal User Interfaces volume 8 number 2 pp 161 173 doi https doi org 10 1007 s12193 013 0139 7 accessed 14 March 2018 <PERSON>Layla J Branicki</PERSON> and <PERSON>Doreen</PERSON> A Agyei 2015 Unpacking the impacts of social media upon crisis communication and city evacuation In <PERSON>John Preston Jane M Binner Layla Branicki Tobias Galla Nick Jones James King Magdalini Kolokitha</PERSON> and <PERSON>Michalis Smyrnakis</PERSON> editors City evacuations An interdisciplinary approach <LOCATION>Berlin</LOCATION> Springer Verlag pp 21 37 doi https doi org 10 1007 978 3 662 43877 0_2 accessed 14 March 2018 <PERSON>Axel Bruns Jean Burgess Kate Crawford</PERSON> and <PERSON>Frances Shaw</PERSON> 2012 qldfloods and QPSMedia Crisis communication on Twitter in the 2011 <LOCATION>South East Queensland</LOCATION> floods Methodology at https eprints qut edu au 48241 accessed 14 March 2018 <PERSON>Kathy Charmaz</PERSON> and <PERSON>Linda Liska Belgrave</PERSON> 2015 Grounded theory In <PERSON>George Ritzer</PERSON> editor <ORGANIZATION>Blackwell Encyclopedia of Sociology Hoboken N</ORGANIZATION> <PERSON>J Wiley Blackwell</PERSON> doi http dx doi org 10 1002 9781405165518 wbeosg070 pub2 accessed 14 March 2018 <PERSON>Akemi Takeoka Chatfield Hans J Jochen Scholl</PERSON> and Uuf Brajawidagda 2013 Tsunami early warnings via Twitter in government Net savvy citizens co production of time critical public information services Government Information Quarterly volume 30 number 4 pp 377 386 doi https doi org 10 1016 j giq 2013 05 021 accessed 14 March 2018 W <PERSON>Timothy Coombs</PERSON> and <PERSON>Sherry Jean Holladay</PERSON> 2014 How publics react to crisis communication efforts Comparing crisis response reactions across sub arenas <ORGANIZATION>Journal of Communication Management</ORGANIZATION> volume 18 number 1 pp 40 57 doi https doi org 10 1108 JCOM 03 2013 0015 accessed 14 March 2018 <PERSON>Donya Currie</PERSON> 2009 Special report Expert round table on social media and risk communication during times of crisis Strategic challenges and opportunities <ORGANIZATION>Washington D C American Public Health Association Paloma D</ORGANIZATION> az <PERSON>Ignacio Aedo</PERSON> and <PERSON>Sergio Herranz</PERSON> 2014 Citizen participation and social technologies Exploring the perspective of emergency organizations In Chihab Hanachi Fr d rick B naben and Fran ois Charoy editors Information systems for crisis response and management in <LOCATION>Mediterranean</LOCATION> countries Lecture Notes in Business Information Processing LNBIP volume 196 <LOCATION>Berlin</LOCATION> Springer Verlag pp 85 97 doi https doi org 10 1007 978 3 319 11818 5_8 accessed 14 March 2018 <PERSON>Kathrin Eismann Oliver Posegga</PERSON> and <PERSON>Kai Fischbach</PERSON> 2016 Collective behaviour social media and disasters A systematic literature review ECIS Proceedings at http aisel aisnet org ecis2016_rp 104 accessed 14 March 2018 <PERSON>Finn Frandsen</PERSON> and <PERSON>Winni Johansen</PERSON> 2017 Organizational crisis communication A multivocal approach Thousand Oaks Calif Sage Craig Fugate 2011 Understanding the power of social media as a communication tool in the aftermath of disasters Hearing before the Ad Hoc Subcommittee on Disaster Recovery and <ORGANIZATION>Intergovernmental Affairs of the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs United States Senate</ORGANIZATION> 112th Congress First Session 5 May at https www gpo gov fdsys pkg CHRG 112shrg67635 content detail html accessed 14 March 2018 <PERSON>Mila Gasc Petra Saskia Bayerl Sebastian Denef</PERSON> and <PERSON>Babak Akhgar</PERSON> 2017 What do citizens communicate about during crises Analyzing Twitter use during the 2011 <LOCATION>UK</LOCATION> riots Government Information Quarterly volume 34 number 4 pp 635 645 doi https doi org 10 1016 j giq 2017 11 005 accessed 14 March 2018 <PERSON>Athula Ginige Luca Paolino Marco Romano Monica Sebillo Genoveffa Tortora</PERSON> and <PERSON>Giuliana Vitiello</PERSON> 2014 Information sharing among disaster responders An interactive spreadsheet based collaboration approach <ORGANIZATION>Computer Supported Cooperative Work CSCW</ORGANIZATION> volume 23 numbers 4 6 pp 547 583 doi https doi org 10 1007 s10606 014 9207 0 accessed 14 March 2018 <PERSON>Thomas Heverin</PERSON> and <PERSON>Lisl Zach</PERSON> 2010 Microblogging for crisis communication Examination of Twitter use in response to a 2009 violent crisis in the <LOCATION>Seattle Tacoma Washington</LOCATION> area Proceedings of the Seventh International ISCRAM Conference pp 1 5 J <PERSON>Brian Houston Joshua Hawthorne Mildred F Perreault Eun Hae Park Marlo Goldstein Hode Michael R Halliwell Sarah E Turner McGowen Rachel Davis Shivani Vaid Jonathan A McElderry</PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION>Stanford</ORGANIZATION> A Griffith 2014 Social media and disasters A functional framework for social media use in disaster planning response and research Disasters volume 39 number 1 pp 1 22 doi https doi org 10 1111 disa 12092 accessed 14 March 2018 Amanda L Hughes 2014 Participatory design for the social media needs of emergency public information officers Proceedings of the Eleventh International ISCRAM Information Systems for Crisis Response and Management Conference pp 727 736 and at http iscramlive org ISCRAM2014 papers p90 pdf accessed 14 March 2018 Amanda L Hughes Lise A A St <PERSON>Denis Leysia Palen</PERSON> and <PERSON>Kenneth M Anderson</PERSON> 2014 Online public communications by police amp fire services during the 2012 Hurricane Sandy CHI 14 Proceedings of the SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in <ORGANIZATION>Computing Systems</ORGANIZATION> pp 1 505 1 514 doi https doi org 10 1145 2556288 2557227 accessed 14 March 2018 <PERSON>Murray</PERSON> E Jennex 2010 Implementing social media in crisis response using knowledge management <ORGANIZATION>International Journal of Information Systems for Crisis Response and Management</ORGANIZATION> volume 2 number 4 pp 20 32 doi https doi org 10 4018 jiscrm 2010100102 accessed 14 March 2018 <PERSON>Andrea L Kavanaugh Edward A Fox Steven D Sheetz Seungwon Yang Lin Tzy Li Donald J Shoemaker Apostol Natsev</PERSON> and Lexing Xie 2012 Social media use by government From the routine to the critical Government Information Quarterly volume 29 number 4 pp 480 491 doi https doi org 10 1016 j giq 2012 06 002 accessed 14 March 2018 <PERSON>Peter M Landwehr</PERSON> and <PERSON>Kathleen M Carley</PERSON> 2014 Social media in disaster relief Usage patterns data mining tools and current research directions In <PERSON>Wesley W Chu</PERSON> editor Data mining and knowledge discovery for big data Methodologies challenges and opportunities Studies in Big Data SBD volume 1 <LOCATION>Berlin</LOCATION> Springer Verlag pp 225 257 doi https doi org 10 1007 978 3 642 40837 3_7 accessed 14 March 2018 <PERSON>Mark Latonero</PERSON> and <PERSON>Irina Shklovski</PERSON> 2011 Emergency management Twitter and social media evangelism <ORGANIZATION>International Journal of Information Systems for Crisis Response and Management</ORGANIZATION> volume 3 number 4 pp 196 212 doi https doi org 10 4018 jiscrm 2011100101 accessed 14 March 2018 <PERSON>Shuhua Monica Liu</PERSON> 2016 Chinese netizens collective deliberation on bystander controversies and the role of micro blogging dg o 16 Proceedings of the 17th International Digital Government Research Conference on <ORGANIZATION>Digital Government Research</ORGANIZATION> pp 425 434 doi https doi org 10 1145 2912160 2912181 accessed 14 March 2018 <PERSON>Sophia B Liu Anahi Ayala Iacucci</PERSON> and <PERSON>Patrick Meier</PERSON> 2010 Ushahidi <LOCATION>Haiti</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Chile</LOCATION> Next generation crisis mapping American <ORGANIZATION>Congress</ORGANIZATION> on Surveying and Mapping <ORGANIZATION>ACSM</ORGANIZATION> Bulletin 246 <PERSON>Liang Ma</PERSON> 2013 The diffusion of government microblogging Evidence from Chinese municipal police bureaus <ORGANIZATION>Public Management Review</ORGANIZATION> volume 15 number 2 pp 288 309 doi https doi org 10 1080 14719037 2012 691010 accessed 14 March 2018 <PERSON>Albert Jacob Meijer</PERSON> 2014 New media and the coproduction of safety An empirical analysis of Dutch practices <ORGANIZATION>American Review of Public Administration</ORGANIZATION> volume 44 number 1 1 pp 17 34 doi https doi org 10 1177 0275074012455843 accessed 14 March 2018 Ines Mergel 2014 Social media practices in local emergency management Results from central <ORGANIZATION>New York Syracuse University Institute of National Security and Counterterrorism Moynihan Institute of Global Affairs</ORGANIZATION> at http sotechem syr edu wp content uploads 2014 11 SoTechEM_Executive_Report mwedit111914 pdf accessed 14 March 2018 I <PERSON>Mergel</PERSON> 2013a A framework for interpreting social media interactions in the public sector <ORGANIZATION>Government Information Quarterly</ORGANIZATION> volume 30 number 4 pp 327 334 doi https doi org 10 1016 j giq 2013 05 015 accessed 11 October 2017 <PERSON>Ines Mergel</PERSON> 2013b Social media adoption and resulting tactics in the U S federal government <ORGANIZATION>Government Information Quarterly</ORGANIZATION> volume 30 number 2 pp 123 130 doi https doi org 10 1016 j giq 2012 12 004 accessed 14 March 2018 <PERSON>Ines Mergel</PERSON> and <PERSON>Stuart Bretschneider</PERSON> 2013 A three stage adoption process for social media use in government <ORGANIZATION>Public Administration Review</ORGANIZATION> volume 73 number 3 pp 390 400 doi https doi org 10 1111 puar 12021 accessed 14 March 2018 <PERSON>Daniele Miorandi</PERSON> and <PERSON>Lorenzo Maggi</PERSON> 2014 Programming social collective intelligence Technology and <ORGANIZATION>Society Magazine</ORGANIZATION> volume 33 number 3 pp 55 61 doi https doi org 10 1109 MTS 2014 2345206 accessed 14 March 2018 <PERSON>Leysia Palen</PERSON> and <PERSON>Sophia B Liu</PERSON> 2007 Citizen communications in crisis Anticipating a future of <ORGANIZATION>ICT</ORGANIZATION> supported public participation CHI 07 Proceedings of the SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems pp 727 736 doi https doi org 10 1145 1240624 1240736 accessed 14 March 2018 Leysia Palen <PERSON>Kenneth M Anderson Gloria Mark James Martin Douglas Sicker Martha Palmer</PERSON> and <PERSON>Dirk Grunwald</PERSON> 2010 A vision for technology mediated support for public participation amp assistance in mass emergencies amp disasters ACM BCS 10 Proceedings of the 2010 ACM BCS Visions of <ORGANIZATION>Computer Science Conference</ORGANIZATION> article number 8 <PERSON>Panagiotis Panagiotopoulos Julie Barnett</PERSON> and <PERSON>Laurence Brooks</PERSON> 2013 Social media and government responsiveness The case of the <LOCATION>UK</LOCATION> food standards agency In Maria A <PERSON>Wimmer Marijn Janssen</PERSON> and <PERSON>Hans J Scholl</PERSON> editors Electronic government <LOCATION>Berlin</LOCATION> Springer Verlag pp 310 321 doi https doi org 10 1007 978 3 642 40358 3_26 accessed 14 March 2018 <PERSON>Laura</PERSON> E <ORGANIZATION>Pechta Dale C Brandenburg</ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON>Matthew W Seeger</PERSON> 2010 Understanding the dynamics of emergency communication Propositions for a four channel model <ORGANIZATION>Journal of Homeland Security</ORGANIZATION> and Emergency Management volume 7 number 1 doi https doi org 10 2202 1547 7355 1671 accessed 14 March 2018 <PERSON>Marta Poblet Esteban Garc</PERSON> a Cuesta and Pompeu Casanovas 2014 Crowdsourcing tools for disaster management A review of platforms and methods In Pompeu Casanovas <PERSON>Ugo Pagallo Monica Palmirani</PERSON> and <PERSON>Giovanni Sartor</PERSON> editors AI approaches to the complexity of legal systems Lecture Notes in Computer Science LNCS volume 8929 <LOCATION>Berlin</LOCATION> Springer Verlag pp 261 274 doi https doi org 10 1007 978 3 662 45960 7_19 accessed 14 March 2018 <PERSON>Sara Prentice</PERSON> and <PERSON>Ethan Huffman</PERSON> 2008 Social media s new role in emergency management Emergency management and robotics for hazardous environments <ORGANIZATION>Idaho National Laboratory INL</ORGANIZATION> CON 07 13552 at https inldigitallibrary inl gov sites sti sti 3931947 pdf accessed 14 March 2018 <PERSON>Rob Procter Farida Vis</PERSON> and <PERSON>Alex Voss</PERSON> 2013 Reading the riots on Twitter methodological innovation for the analysis of big data <ORGANIZATION>International Journal of Social Research Methodology</ORGANIZATION> volume 16 number 3 pp 197 214 doi https doi org 10 1080 13645579 2013 774172 accessed 14 March 2018 Hemant Purohit Andrew <PERSON>Hampton Valerie L Shalin Amit</PERSON> P <PERSON>Sheth John Flach</PERSON> and <PERSON>Shreyansh Bhatt</PERSON> 2013 What kind of conversation is Twitter Mining psycholinguistic cues for emergency coordination Computers in Human Behavior volume 29 number 6 pp 2 438 2 447 doi https doi org 10 1016 j chb 2013 05 007 accessed 14 March 2018 Christian Reuter <PERSON>Alexandra Marx</PERSON> and <PERSON>Volkmar Pipek</PERSON> 2012 Crisis management 2 0 Towards a systematization of social software use in crisis situations <ORGANIZATION>International Journal of Information Systems for Crisis Response and Management</ORGANIZATION> volume 4 number 1 pp 1 16 doi https doi org 10 4018 jiscrm 2012010101 accessed 14 March 2018 Christian Reuter <PERSON>Thomas Ludwig Marc Andr Kaufhold</PERSON> and <PERSON>Thomas Spielhofer</PERSON> 2016 Emergency services attitudes towards social media A quantitative and qualitative survey across <ORGANIZATION>Europe International Journal of Human Computer Studies</ORGANIZATION> volume 95 pp 96 111 doi https doi org 10 1016 j ijhcs 2016 03 005 accessed 14 March 2018 <PERSON>Kate Starbird</PERSON> and <LOCATION>Leysia Palen</LOCATION> 2011 Voluntweeters Self organizing by digital volunteers in times of crisis CHI 11 Proceedings of the SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in <ORGANIZATION>Computing Systems</ORGANIZATION> pp 1 071 1 080 doi https doi org 10 1145 1978942 1979102 accessed 14 March 2018 <PERSON>Jeannette Sutton Leysia Palen</PERSON> and <PERSON>Irina Shlovski</PERSON> 2008 Backchannels on the front lines Emergent uses of social media in the 2007 Southern <LOCATION>California</LOCATION> wildfires Proceedings of the Fifth <ORGANIZATION>ISCRAM Information Systems</ORGANIZATION> for Crisis Response and Management Conference pp 624 632 <PERSON>Jeannette Sutton Emma Spiro Carter</PERSON> Butts <PERSON>Sean Fitzhugh Britta Johnson</PERSON> and <PERSON>Matt Greczek</PERSON> 2013 Tweeting the spill Online informal communications social networks and conversational microstructures during the Deepwater Horizon oilspill <ORGANIZATION>International Journal of Information Systems for Crisis Response and Management</ORGANIZATION> volume 5 number 1 pp 58 76 doi https doi org 10 4018 jiscrm 2013010104 accessed 14 March 2018 <PERSON>Shu Fen Tseng Wei Chu Chen</PERSON> and <PERSON>Chien Liang Chi</PERSON> 2011 Online social media in a disaster event Network and public participation In <PERSON>Hocine Cherifi Jasni Mohamad Zain</PERSON> and Eyas El Qawasmeh editors Digital information and communication technology and its applications <ORGANIZATION>Communications in Computer and Information Science CCIS</ORGANIZATION> volume 167 <LOCATION>Berlin</LOCATION> Springer Verlag pp 256 264 doi https doi org 10 1007 978 3 642 22027 2_22 accessed 14 March 2018 S <PERSON>Tucker V Lanfranchi</PERSON> N Ireson A <PERSON>Sosa G Burel</PERSON> and F Ciravegna 2012 Straight to the information I need Assessing collational interfaces for emergency response Proceedings of the Ninth international ISCRAM Information Systems for Crisis Response and Management Conference at http www iscramlive org ISCRAM2012 proceedings 164 pdf accessed 14 March 2018 <PERSON>Anne Marie Warren Ainin Sulaiman</PERSON> and <PERSON>Noor Ismawati Jaafar</PERSON> 2014 Social media effects on fostering online civic engagement and building citizen trust and trust in institutions Government Information Quarterly volume 31 number 2 pp 291 301 doi https doi org 10 1016 j giq 2013 11 007 accessed 14 March 2018 Clayton Wukich 2015 Social media use in emergency management <ORGANIZATION>Journal of Emergency Management</ORGANIZATION> volume 13 number 4 pp 281 294 and at http www wmpllc org ojs 2 4 2 index php jem article view 200 0 accessed 14 March 2018 doi http dx doi org 10 5055 jem 2015 0242 accessed 14 March 2018 <PERSON>Clayton Wukich</PERSON> and <PERSON>Ines Mergel</PERSON> 2016 Reusing social media information in government Government Information Quarterly volume 33 number 2 pp 305 312 doi http dx doi org 10 1016 j giq 2016 01 011 accessed 14 March 2018 <PERSON>Clayton Wukich</PERSON> and <PERSON>Alan Steinberg</PERSON> 2013 Nonprofit and public sector participation in self organizing information networks Twitter hashtag and trending topic use during disasters Risk Hazards amp Crisis in Public Policy volume 4 number 2 pp 83 109 doi http dx doi org 10 1002 rhc3 12036 accessed 14 March 2018 <PERSON>Dave Yates</PERSON> and <PERSON>Scott Paquette</PERSON> 2011 Emergency knowledge management and social media technologies A case study of the 2010 Haitian earthquake <ORGANIZATION>International Journal of Information Management</ORGANIZATION> volume 31 number 1 pp 6 13 doi https doi org 10 1016 j ijinfomgt 2010 10 001 accessed 14 March 2018 <PERSON>Robert K Yin</PERSON> 2014 Case study research Design and methods Fifth edition Thousand Oaks Calif Sage Lei Zheng 2013 Social media in Chinese government Drivers challenges and capabilities Government Information Quarterly volume 30 number 4 pp 369 376 doi https doi org 10 1016 j giq 2013 05 017 accessed 14 March 2018 bookmark app Appendix Coding categories and topics bookmark tab4 Table 4 <ORGANIZATION>Citizens</ORGANIZATION> posts code category Topic Code category Example Water safety Suggestions on water safety control Although there is little influence on water quality future impact is still uncertain Hope government can keep water clean Questions about water quality More than ten thousand dead pigs in the <LOCATION>Huangpu River How</LOCATION> can government say water quality is the same as if not better than late year Inquiry about water quality What about water quality monitoring How to improve water quality Concern about water safety <LOCATION>Shanghai</LOCATION> citizens need to pay special attention to water safety Source of contamination Questions about the source They admitted dead pigs were from <LOCATION>Jiaxing</LOCATION> and because of cold weather yesterday however they refuse to admit today How confusing Inquiry about the source Governments are all about field response and cleaning How about where those dead pigs come from How many are there in the source Do governments of <LOCATION>Shanghai</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Jiaxing</LOCATION> begin to investigate Pig farming Reflection on pig farming management This is a huge production scandal Where are the pigs from More importantly have local governments fulfilled responsibility to manage and supervise pig farming industry Questions about pig epidemic disease Are those pigs dead because of certain disease Food safety Concern about food safety <LOCATION>Shanghai</LOCATION> citizens need to be careful about pork products I suggest everyone do not eat pork in the near future <LOCATION>Field</LOCATION> response Suggestions on field response Very scary Speed up the cleaning process and build precautions Criticism on slow government field response Government is wasting time and energy to do just cleaning without controlling the source Investigation Suggestions on government investigation Government need to find who is dumping dead pigs Where are those public agencies responsible for that Criticism on unclear government investigation Governments explanation is clear about why so many dead pigs appeared Information disclosure Criticism on public information disclosure They are talking about nonsense in the official posts Accountability Suggestions on accountability It is a temporary solution The key is to crack down on the source and shut down the illegal pig farms Criticism on government insufficient accountability So many government agencies so many public employees yet there is no effective supervision and management Why do they have to wait to act after something bad happened Inquiry about accountability Can most of the pigs were dead because of cold weather be sufficient to explain the cause Who needs to be held accountable bookmark tab5 Table 5 Government posts code category Topic Code category Example Water safety Water quality monitoring According to current reports from <ORGANIZATION>Environment Protection Agency and Department of Water</ORGANIZATION> there is no pollution in the drinking water Source of contamination Investigation on the source of dead pigs The contamination came from the illegal pig farms from the upper stream area according to the preliminary investigation Investigation on the cause of death The pigs were dead because of cold weather not pig disease Pig farming Pig disease inspection The positive rate of porcine circovirus virus was detected from a sample and all the other samples were negative According to reports porcine circovirus disease does not belong to zoonotic disease Pig farming information The <ORGANIZATION>Zhejiang Provincial Department of Agriculture</ORGANIZATION> has said that no swine fever in <LOCATION>Zhejiang</LOCATION> more than frozen to death <ORGANIZATION>Food safety Pork</ORGANIZATION> food quality inspection A special inspection on the supermarket farmers market pork retail shop has been carried out At present did not find the source of unknown pig products listed on sale Field response Progress on dead pig collection By 3 p m 809 pigs were collected from the <LOCATION>Huangpu River</LOCATION> Progress on dead pig elimination The city in recent days stepped up to carry out dead pig collection and harmless disposal in the upper reaches of the <LOCATION>Huangpu River Accountability Penalty</LOCATION> on those who are responsible Eight pig farmers indicated by ear tags were given the following punishment of 3 000 yuan Editorial history Received 2 March 2018 accepted 14 March 2018 image Creative Commons License This paper is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution 4 0 <ORGANIZATION>International License Citizens</ORGANIZATION> use of microblogging and government communication during emergencies A case study on water contamination in <LOCATION>Shanghai</LOCATION> by <PERSON>Qianli Yuan</PERSON> and <PERSON>Mila Gasc</PERSON> First Monday Volume 23 Number 4 2 April 2018 http firstmonday org ojs index php fm article view 8367 6662 doi http dx doi org 10 5210 fm v23i4 8367 image Bookmark and Share A Great Cities Initiative of the <ORGANIZATION>University of Illinois at Chicago University Library First</ORGANIZATION> Monday 1995 2018 ISSN 1396 0466</ner>
