<ner>According to police a 4 year old boy in <LOCATION>Pennsylvania</LOCATION> was beaten to death by his mother and her boyfriend over a sp https t co GOUOPMkU6h Millions of recalled cars still may be on the road with unfixed issues https t co bMfIGgO85i https t co q3YHSCzgPB During Facebook CEO <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> s testimony <PERSON>Sen Ted Cruz R TX</PERSON> said he believes many Americans are deeply c https t co pIVRP4Ghc5 <PERSON>Bill Cosby</PERSON> s retrial took a far more combative turn Tuesday than the first go round as his lawyers launched a scat https t co 575prQSDW0 Federal investigators are looking into the 2016 non disclosure agreement adult film star <PERSON>Stormy Daniels</PERSON> signed and https t co Yq8e1z1ENs A police officer shot and killed a man who was waving a pellet gun and threatening patrons inside a casino early Tu https t co UeUEkSQCm6 <ORGANIZATION>Senate</ORGANIZATION> Minority Leader <PERSON>Charles Schumer</PERSON> is warning President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> not to fire special counsel <PERSON>Robert Mueller</PERSON> after https t co wYyuahk5Y2 A possible tornado was reported near <LOCATION>Fort Lauderdale Hollywood International Airport</LOCATION> on Tuesday afternoon https t co exE1JV7DoE It may not feel like spring but these rows of rainbow tulips in <LOCATION>Washington</LOCATION> beg to differ https t co HlzxffHCOU <LOCATION>Sacramento</LOCATION> police have issued their first written policy on when officers can turn off body cameras after two offic https t co H4MH3SNZ2u Gold Star families who lost loved ones in military service are helping someone else put their life back together https t co 9PDTLKP1OF Facebook CEO <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> made his long awaited appearance before <ORGANIZATION>Congress</ORGANIZATION> and apologized for the privacy scanda https t co PgOYonsDN6 Before he was paralyzed this couple dreamed of running the <LOCATION>Boston Marathon</LOCATION> together Yesterday a week before Mar https t co zrNM5oNuS1 President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> sought the ouster of special counsel <PERSON>Robert Mueller</PERSON> in early December but ultimately backed down t https t co scSDx9XRZ0 President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> is getting closer to a decision on how the U S will respond to the apparent chemical weapons attac https t co <ORGANIZATION>LlsGRk0rju Associated Press</ORGANIZATION> photographer <PERSON>Andrew Harni</PERSON> got a clear shot of <PERSON>Zuckerberg</PERSON> s notes as he left the table during a bre https t co zcjxoDSV7k <ORGANIZATION>White House Press</ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON>Sarah Sanders</PERSON> did not know whether <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> s personal lawyer <PERSON>Michael Cohen</PERSON> still represen https t co d41NfnzUSj The Alabama Crimson Tide this year s <ORGANIZATION>NCAA</ORGANIZATION> football champions visited with President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> on the <ORGANIZATION>White House</ORGANIZATION> Sout https t co ssDUWcIkpv When asked if app developer <PERSON>Aleksandr Kogan</PERSON> gave user data to other firms besides <LOCATION>Cambridge Analytica Zuckerberg</LOCATION> s https t co eb1wQKPI1Y SenCapito If somebody leaves <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> and then rejoins and asks <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> can you recreate my past your answer w https t co rjYo6yLD9e Here s what everybody has been trying to tell you today and I say this gently Your user agreement sucks The purpo https t co Zm2QTkA7cL RT CBSEveningNews We re on the air in the East JeffGlor is live from Studio 57 in <LOCATION>NYC Thanks</LOCATION> for being with us <ORGANIZATION>OriginalReporting CBSE</ORGANIZATION> I think we clearly view it as a mistake that we didn t inform people and we did that based on false information th https t co xPZMbhSDET If you don t want to share something don t share it Go on there and say I don t want to allow third party engine https t co X1wlGevl79 SenGaryPeters Yes or no does <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> use audio obtained from mobile devices to enrich personal information abou https t co tYhOmm1kbt Senator <PERSON>Heller</PERSON> Do you consider the 87 million users victims MZ Senator I think yes I mean they did not want https t co ROa45NEQqk SenDeanHeller Have you ever collected the content of phone calls or messages through any <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> application or https t co QPm6XLSn7h Yesterday <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> sent out a notification to 87 million users that information was given to <ORGANIZATION>Cambridge Analytica</ORGANIZATION> w https t co fDaGR3U67X In general unless law enforcement has a very clear subpoena or ability or reason to get access to information we https t co ZDGtetqH9B Senator the most important thing that I care about right now is making sure that no one interferes in the various https t co PzhLBHO0of Senator <PERSON>Sullivan</PERSON> Dorm room to global behemoth only in <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> Would you agree with that You couldn t do this https t co PgvlOaaGpi When asked if <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> would cooperate with ICE <PERSON>Zuckerberg</PERSON> says we would not proactively do that https t co 46BnJ6ZjaA I don t think sitting here today that we have specific knowledge of other efforts by those nation states but in g https t co EjXXA0opZc We re going to have more than 20 000 people working on security and content review by the end of this year Zucke https t co q9nIBmnnG4 Sen Sasse Do social media companies hire consulting firms to help them figure out how to get more dopamine feedba https t co oJRq3ZoRdW <ORGANIZATION>Sen Sasse Do</ORGANIZATION> you worry about social media addiction as a problem for <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> s teens MZ At <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> spec https t co AkXgctbVJi Sen Coons Isn t it <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> s job to protect users amp amp why do you shift the burden to users to flag inappropriate https t co J6xEDQDKBI You do have control and complete control over the information <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> Well senator this is how the s https t co RIGOGawup0 <PERSON>Zuckerberg</PERSON> on data you choose to put it there You can take it down at any time amp amp you completely control the t https t co <ORGANIZATION>ZDOYxrHHoz Facebook</ORGANIZATION> stock jumps almost 5 higher as <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> testifies before <ORGANIZATION>Congress</ORGANIZATION> https t co zE31K6Ii52 https t co BoyQWcncIX <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> In order to create a service where everyone has a voice we also need to make sure that people ar https t co T8MRAe6BNU <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> Senator I think that the terms of service are what they are but the service is really defined by https t co cLGqLchjTT MORE <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> CEO <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> to continue his <LOCATION>Capitol Hill</LOCATION> testimony after a five minute recess follow <ORGANIZATION>CBS</ORGANIZATION> Ne https t co MLL30XeOLj <ORGANIZATION>Sen Ted Cruz Does Facebook</ORGANIZATION> consider itself to be a neutral public forum <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> We consider ourselve https t co ozK6azxI4J Sen Blumenthal D CT Has anyone been fired on that app review team <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> Senator not because of https t co Zw1jQZ0Bba Mark Zuckerberg There is a very common misconception about <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> that we sell data to advertisers And we do n https t co bFfW5S4XQa <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> I think the big mistake that we made looking back on this is viewing our responsibility as just b https t co <PERSON>Y7yOGh6lcm Sen Durbin</PERSON> I think that maybe what this is all about Your right to privacy The limits of your right to privacy https t co vD2hq0ytKY Sen Durbin Would you be comfortable sharing with us the name of the hotel you stayed in last night <PERSON>Zuckerberg</PERSON> https t co CVyBTbsEYB Sen Blunt Do you collect user data through cross device tracking <PERSON>Zuckerberg</PERSON> Senator I believe we do link pe https t co yddpxMXeu4 Sen Graham Do you think the average consumer understands what they are signing up for <PERSON>Zuckerberg</PERSON> I don t think https t co bXLhFsoykM Sen Graham Do you embrace regulation <PERSON>Zuckerberg</PERSON> I think the real question as the internet becomes more importan https t co nzZxXMxKfE Sen Graham Is Twitter the same as what you do <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> It overlaps with portions of what we do Gra https t co L4VLpLZ0yv Sen <PERSON>Graham</PERSON> Is there an alternative to <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> in the private sector <PERSON>Zuckerberg</PERSON> Yes senator The average Am https t co TMfg0dx1v6 Mark Zuckerberg Let me clarify that I m actually not aware of a subpoena I believe that there may be but I kno https t co eZ3WVosMk7 Sen <PERSON>Leahy</PERSON> I assume that <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> has been served the subpoenas from the special counsel s office Is that correct https t co wgBZrh5hBH Sen Wicker R MS There have been reports that <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> can track users internet browsing history even after th https t co UhjOn7d9ch Sen <PERSON>Maria Cantwell</PERSON> D WA Do you believe European regulations should be applied here in the U S <PERSON>Zuckerberg</PERSON> https t co E2iXIxX2HC Zuckerberg Data privacy and foreign interference and elections are certainly topics that we ve discussed at the b https t co R2NjvkNYFN Sen Hatch If a version of <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> will always be free how do you sustain a business model in which users don https t co FNkd6tPsIn Sen Hatch You said in 2010 that <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> would always be free Is that still your objective <PERSON>Zuckerberg</PERSON> https t co RJj6lfesH5 <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> As of the time we learned about <ORGANIZATION>Cambridge Analytica</ORGANIZATION> s activity in 2015 they weren t an adverti https t co YeSXta9uYd Sen Feinstein How many accounts has <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> removed <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> Of accounts pegged back to the <ORGANIZATION>IRA</ORGANIZATION> we https t co PRVoekcaiY <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> Just last week we were able to determine that a number of Russian media organizations that were https t co qE2Xc4U5kv Zuckerberg The nature of these attacks though is that there are people in <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> whose job it is to try to exp https t co 2Hs7v6bMxd What is <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> doing to prevent foreign actors from interfering in U S elections This is one of my top prior https t co FoKb5AxddW <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> on monitoring hate speech on FB By the end of this year we are going to have 20 000 people worki https t co b8bOiSmtov Sen <PERSON>John Thune</PERSON> R SD After more than a decade of promises to do better how is today s apology different Why s https t co P1htDk67ul Zuckerberg In 2015 we took down the app and we demanded that both the app developer and <ORGANIZATION>Cambridge Analytica</ORGANIZATION> del https t co lihNVdAJYu Sen Nelson Therefore you consider my personally identifiable data the company s data is that it <PERSON>Zuckerberg</PERSON> https t co IZEKwygbrj Mark Zuckerberg Even though some people don t like ads people really don t like ads that aren t relevant th https t co AccmiH9qCh I believe it s important to tell people exactly how the information that they share on <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> is going to be use https t co bI9t8bvKkG <ORGANIZATION>Sen Chuck Grassley R IA</ORGANIZATION> to <PERSON>Zuckerberg</PERSON> Why doesn t <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> disclose to its users all the ways the data might b https t co 4C49bZxSJu we are going to be investigating many apps tens of thousands of apps And if we find any suspicious activity https t co tMK9P149QU It will take some time to work through all the changes we need to make across the company but I m committed to ge https t co U27l1c2dRR <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> s <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> It is not enough to just give people a voice We need to make sure that people are not https t co gYfHUcMvTz We didn t take a broad enough view of our responsibility and that was a big mistake <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> says in his https t co 3yyFlv8EQM Zuckerberg It is clear now that we didn t do enough to prevent these tools from being used for harm as well That https t co Q56xrAdANH <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> CEO <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> We face a number of important issues around privacy safety and democracy And you w https t co 9bTlAnh3un You want to do the right thing You want to enact reforms <PERSON>Sen Bill Nelson</PERSON> says to <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> CEO <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> https t co 8f3iR4mHwC Let me just cut to the chase If you and other social media companies do not get your act in order none of us are https t co Hf2IuI3ymB The potential for further growth and innovation based on collection of data is limitless However the potential f https t co FyVgAgb3dk In many ways you and the company you ve created represent the American Dream Sen <PERSON>John Thune</PERSON> says At the same https t co f7yksq1Hcb The fact that those 87 million people may have technically consented to making their data available doesn t make m https t co nl9kIvkwp2 In many respects <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> s incredible reach is why we re here today <PERSON>Sen John Thune</PERSON> R <LOCATION>South Dakota</LOCATION> says in o https t co LTwgLC9pvK WATCH LIVE <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> CEO <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> faces grilling from <ORGANIZATION>Senate</ORGANIZATION> lawmakers as the social media giant is under fi https t co jimFOEwwwi A <ORGANIZATION>White House</ORGANIZATION> official mocked <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> s penchant for phony bologna hoodies and dungarees but suits a https t co COSof0Yn8K SOON Facebook CEO <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> is set to testify before a joint hearing of the <ORGANIZATION>Senate Judiciary and Commerce Co</ORGANIZATION> https t co <PERSON>SweuhEbpjy James Comey</PERSON> hearing nearly 3 hours <PERSON>Anita Hill</PERSON> hearing 8 hours <PERSON>Hillary Clinton</PERSON> hearing 11 hours How long https t co EPyxUe2sCO <PERSON>Seth Meyers</PERSON> and <PERSON>Alexi Ashe</PERSON> welcome son born in their apartment building lobby https t co wp2R8v84QL https t co XxTN07cXwT With due respect <LOCATION>Pres Trump America</LOCATION> has been around for over two and a half centuries An investigation of your https t co aeDBFoHOv3 How to check if your <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> data was shared with <ORGANIZATION>Cambridge Analytica</ORGANIZATION> https t co S1enURefcQ https t co JWmpspoS8L An advocacy group placed 100 life sized cutouts of <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> CEO <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> on the <LOCATION>Capitol Lawn</LOCATION> ahead of his te https t co arTrBMJWLQ Conservative TV host s show canceled after he threatens to sexually assault Parkland shooting survivor <PERSON>David Hogg</PERSON> w https t co ocLC6ZCPRI WATCH President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> ignores shouted questions from reporters on Monday s <ORGANIZATION>FBI</ORGANIZATION> raid of <PERSON>Michael Cohen</PERSON> s residence https t co CdyygsGFbJ MOMENTS AGO President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> hosts the emir of <LOCATION>Qatar</LOCATION> at the <LOCATION>White House</LOCATION> amid crisis in region https t co SKeOkV6Qyn A 10 year old boy is telling the story of his escape from a tragic school bus crash that killed four adults and 23 https t co g5r11mBLvI On the heels of the worst scandal in its 14 year history <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> is introducing a bounty for people who report in https t co SHBKHU7RQD A study has found that contrary to popular belief old people can churn out just as many new brain cells as young https t co VxLadiTdas Former Secretary of <ORGANIZATION>State</ORGANIZATION> <PERSON>Madeleine Albright</PERSON> is warning of a looming worldwide political threat https t co nwa2JZ0FYF MORE <PERSON>Tom Bossert</PERSON> was forced out from his position as <ORGANIZATION>Homeland Security Adviser CBS News</ORGANIZATION> <PERSON>Margaret Brennan</PERSON> repor https t co Qk5r3NX4QY <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> has been around for over two and a half centuries An investigation of your personal attorney is not an at https t co 7X7bApok5N Facebook CEO <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> is testifying in front of <ORGANIZATION>Senate</ORGANIZATION> lawmakers today where he s expected to take the blam https t co 1uCrMktmgI Last night POTUS said the <ORGANIZATION>FBI</ORGANIZATION> raid was a disgrace part of a witch hunt an attack on our country and mentioned https t co SRjRwbRkf9 HAPPENING NOW Sen Chuck <PERSON>Schumer</PERSON> is calling for legislation to protect Special Counsel <PERSON>Robert Mueller</PERSON> https t co L75hU3DW5d Stocks rise after Chinese President <PERSON>Xi Jinping</PERSON> vows to lower trade barriers https t co UwL7w5snhu https t co 5v6rWUcpmV Homeland Security Adviser <PERSON>Tom Bossert</PERSON> to resign from <ORGANIZATION>White House</ORGANIZATION> at the request of President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> s <ORGANIZATION>National Secur</ORGANIZATION> https t co Yx3MJmIyz5 Hard numbers 70 Around 70 of Cubans have never known a <LOCATION>Cuba</LOCATION> led by anyone other than a <PERSON>Castro</PERSON> 63 It took https t co Q3LiYLU5Hj As we hear the latest testimony from <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> CEO <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> take a closer look at the global impact his rema https t co IkQ9LFG2wZ JUST IN President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> s Homeland Security Adviser <PERSON>Tom Bossert</PERSON> is leaving the <ORGANIZATION>White House</ORGANIZATION> The President is grat https t co L98wrI6n3V Facebook CEO <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> testifies to <ORGANIZATION>Senate</ORGANIZATION> committees Tuesday Here s how to watch https t co X7EeTFbmOG https t co zBjfHeyCYv President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> calls off trip to <LOCATION>South America</LOCATION> to focus on <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> https t co lrxh371mzr https t co LCMeQhQENi Sen <PERSON>John Thune</PERSON> on data privacy It s time for <ORGANIZATION>Congress</ORGANIZATION> to exercise some oversight https t co 4GHmABny6q https t co QGZqFUFyxL Notable U S and <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> goods missing from tariff lists showing how far both countries might be willing to go or w https t co 2u6FYa4qwr NEW President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> will no longer go on upcoming <LOCATION>South America</LOCATION> trip <ORGANIZATION>White House</ORGANIZATION> says president will remain in t https t co dkqc4EggoK A 7 year old girl from <LOCATION>Texas</LOCATION> broke the world record as the youngest female to climb Mt Kilimanjaro She did it in https t co MPXiLvkya1 RT CBSThisMorning I think <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> is the most undemocratic president I have ever seen in American history Former Sec of State <PERSON>Madel PReedGolf</PERSON> clinched the 2018 Masters tournament over the weekend It s the first major victory for the 27 year old https t co OMJ8crz55D I think part of the issues here is first of all he s attacked the free press which is central to having democrac https t co VnDP0sNv4N Venus and <PERSON>Serena Williams</PERSON> are joining the Billie Jean King Leadership Initiative to push for equal pay across all j https t co O9q5kmufFc Some leaders are grabbing power by identifying with one group And then also excluding the individual rights of https t co 35aQ3ltHx9 Former Secretary of <ORGANIZATION>State</ORGANIZATION> <PERSON>Madeleine Albright</PERSON> is warning of a looming worldwide political threat She argues in her https t co 40u54I0So8 Here are this morning s headlines from around the globe on CBSThisMorning https t co YA2vBFROQr Former Secretary of <ORGANIZATION>State</ORGANIZATION> madeleine <PERSON>Albright</PERSON> and Masters champion PReedGolf are both in the <ORGANIZATION>Toyota</ORGANIZATION> green room and https t co sQnM2tXRsF When a dance studio went up in flames on Monday the young students inside jumped out of the second story window to https t co U6rQ3AVYKG Sen <PERSON>Tammy Duckworth</PERSON> is now the first U S Senator to give birth while in office Before she gave birth to <PERSON>Maile Pe</PERSON> https t co 9NDs5ATOct <ORGANIZATION>Fox News</ORGANIZATION> host <PERSON>Sean Hannity</PERSON> accepts <PERSON>Jimmy Kimmel</PERSON> s apology even if it seemed forced https t co XLwebHrDEK https t co wgCTFhs8yH <ORGANIZATION>CBS News</ORGANIZATION> will bring you <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> s opening statement on <LOCATION>Capitol Hill</LOCATION> today during a special report at 2 15 p https t co pOjbWr6owV Republican SenJohnThune of <LOCATION>South Dakota</LOCATION> is Chairman of the <ORGANIZATION>Commerce Science and Transportation</ORGANIZATION> committee He wor https t co AKPZxu6IHI Facebook CEO <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> will testify before half of the <ORGANIZATION>U S Senate</ORGANIZATION> today In prepared remarks <PERSON>Zuckerberg</PERSON> tal https t co 36XEkktLLr President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> says <ORGANIZATION>FBI</ORGANIZATION> raids targeting his personal attorney <PERSON>Michael Cohen</PERSON> mean attorney client privilege is https t co NZpNyk1OUK Here are this morning s headlines on CBSThisMorning https t co OVI1sj3E4T Facebook CEO <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> s testimony could lead to new calls for oversight from <ORGANIZATION>Congress</ORGANIZATION> The company faces out https t co n6AdyedtU4 Some <ORGANIZATION>National Guard</ORGANIZATION> members have started arriving at the U S <LOCATION>Mexico</LOCATION> border with more expected https t co YnW411sEEk Canadian officials are apologizing for misidentifying two of the victims in the deadly bus crash involving a junior https t co NEyblHOO2K Here are three things you should know this morning 1 <PERSON>Kim Jong</PERSON> Un preps for POTUS 2 Distracted driving surges 3 Eq https t co pzM06VMsUK Does it matter what kind of gas was used in the latest <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> attack If the Syrian government used chlorine gas ins https t co qKsconFsJg The daughter of a former Russian spy poisoned by a nerve agent is at a secure location after being released from th https t co hqBuMV9sRH President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> says he will respond forcefully to what he calls the atrocious use of chemical weapons by the <LOCATION>Syr</LOCATION> https t co oYd3LkJ3Sa <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> s President <PERSON>Xi Jinping</PERSON> may be starting to pull back from a trade confrontation with President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> promisin https t co a1NbQazIz6 <ORGANIZATION>CBS News</ORGANIZATION> will bring you live coverage of Facebook CEO <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> s <LOCATION>Capitol Hill</LOCATION> testimony Find it on our stre https t co 7Cm5xMxUcg Some are criticizing The Simpsons for the show s sad response in a controversy over the Apu character https t co 1ApckXlFTQ WIRED editor in chief and <ORGANIZATION>CBS News</ORGANIZATION> contributor nxthompson interviewed <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> CEO <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> last month ab https t co CAnFilsZIf Facebook CEO <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> will testify in front of a joint hearing of the <ORGANIZATION>Senate Judiciary and Commerce Committe</ORGANIZATION> https t co VHK9exwwSm A raid on the offices of President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> s personal attorney <PERSON>Michael Cohen</PERSON> would have had to clear a number of le https t co vojjJcGJxq Pres <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> tore into special counsel <PERSON>Robert Mueller</PERSON> after the <ORGANIZATION>FBI</ORGANIZATION> raided the offices <PERSON>Michael Cohen</PERSON> Some of the ev https t co pYzuW9OgWp <ORGANIZATION>CBS News</ORGANIZATION> poll Americans say they were not surprised to learn that outside companies were accessing personal data o https t co bdipcj9esX <LOCATION>Illinois</LOCATION> SenDuckworth just became the first senator to give birth while in office Before she had her baby girl https t co h81K6cyLnC <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> files complaint with <ORGANIZATION>World Trade Organization</ORGANIZATION> over U S steel tariffs https t co AQkv1uRVwz https t co rNfV8DBYpE RT CBSThisMorning THIS MORNING nxthompson on <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> s testimony SenJohnThune on securing <PERSON>Zuckerberg</PERSON> s testimony Former S Former Secretary of <ORGANIZATION>State</ORGANIZATION> <PERSON>Madeleine Albright</PERSON> calls herself an optimist who worries a lot Ahead she ll be in https t co 3KGxq3m4zW Coming up CBSThisMorning chats with WIRED s Editor in Chief nxthompson about the high stakes for <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> CEO https t co uVR3GxzUXd Is <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> making concessions in the trade standoff with President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> https t co trUqFWJuYQ https t co NilTRJF1K5 Ahead on CBSThisMorning PreedGolf will join us at the table in Studio 57 to talk about his breakthrough PGATOUR https t co 15EW9uJUTD Poisoned Russian ex spy s daughter <PERSON>Yulia Skripal</PERSON> released from hospital <PERSON>Sergei Skripal</PERSON> hopefully able to be disch https t co PNYrWeatpp Two months shy of her birthday a 7 year old girl climbed Mt Kilimanjaro in memory of late father and broke the https t co 2INVgdPBRa Attorney says <PERSON>Geoffrey Rush</PERSON> is barely eating after sexual misconduct allegation https t co JQI9e8FLPz https t co RozbrjoIBO <LOCATION>Colorado</LOCATION> man gets life without parole after 2nd conviction in wife s 2001 murder https t co ZMVAudiG89 https t co 5avdd9budF The <PERSON>Simpsons</PERSON> chided for sad response in <LOCATION>Apu</LOCATION> controversy https t co GrRiD6fAX3 https t co GDUH78Yde5 Fugitive who confessed killing mother friend on <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> found dead https t co nYVnh68LHm https t co wqkD5h4j1l 8 promises from <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> after <ORGANIZATION>Cambridge Analytica</ORGANIZATION> https t co 2wF1oOeSdX https t co uSU6wecRM3 <PERSON>Darren Criss Lea Michele</PERSON> of Glee announce joint tour https t co k3ewzoTW2s https t co ooyzpRutm6 Still Standing Sir <PERSON>Elton John</PERSON> talks stellar career and farewell tour https t co AZTi8UKwjJ https t co 41ANk46qYN Man fatally struck by high speed train in <LOCATION>Florida</LOCATION> police say https t co 6kddQOOTtw https t co 6426ORLHYG <PERSON>Roger Stone</PERSON> says <PERSON>Paul Manafort</PERSON> will never roll over on <ORGANIZATION>Trump</ORGANIZATION> https t co aL5a9eQPTb https t co Csl1ZvAkDj Poisoned Russian ex spy s daughter <PERSON>Yulia Skripal</PERSON> released from hospital reports say https t co jBmJjxRGqp https t co C9L75TNWYd Eating a <ORGANIZATION>Carolina Reaper</ORGANIZATION> chili pepper sends man to the hospital with thunderclap headaches https t co LPLulGybOA https t co afkbTmAeQs <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> making concessions in trade standoff with <ORGANIZATION>Trump</ORGANIZATION> https t co 1JTgRpDLZp https t co TT7hB7Qsnf Exonerated death row inmate tells his story at <ORGANIZATION>Legacy Museum</ORGANIZATION> https t co w4ImerG9Ru https t co JbSShPK4vn <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> s prepared remarks before <ORGANIZATION>Congress</ORGANIZATION> released https t co I8WXeaqxy0 https t co jwVlkRJ7Pc At least 23 children killed when school bus plunges into gorge in <LOCATION>India</LOCATION> https t co d7PI7BB0I0 https t co ojZolYdw2N Women can t be paid less than men based on previous job salary appeals court rules https t co bchAAVhk4w https t co zLFQSsjwtz <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> calls raid on his lawyer <PERSON>Michael Cohen</PERSON> s office a disgrace and witch hunt https t co feDvhiRL2P https t co qSxtsrl157 Police arrest aide to NYC mayor <PERSON>Bill de Blasio</PERSON> on weapons charges https t co JE4IzrjhOH https t co <ORGANIZATION>PVLAwrooHI Boston Marathon</ORGANIZATION> other races say trans women can compete as women https t co hnrWcfqHWK https t co xtBKSZuL8m Grandmother of starved teen sentenced to 20 years in prison in her death https t co IOpfcXw521 https t co R2KjdimVMN Federal deficit to hit 1 trillion earlier than expected https t co 8JfTf3JAuc https t co 0dnuwlHV0Z Why cereal companies are returning to sugar https t co j2XoJPkB1O https t co l3xepbtF7r Small plane crashes onto <LOCATION>Arizona</LOCATION> golf course https t co 1b5zgV8a0v https t co HafNgf3uCP Attorney says <PERSON>Geoffrey Rush</PERSON> is barely eating after sexual misconduct allegation https t co BQYooovsoA https t co xTMzXC4zXo Fugitive who confessed killing mother friend on <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> found dead https t co q9pjKrcZpn https t co vbOCgTipfk Dozens of students hurt when bus roof sheared off in overpass crash https t co 4xxjY14zlV https t co XRFDvhC907 Search for missing autistic boy takes grim turn as father is arrested https t co zV4UFKQicg https t co LNfzcuehGp Perimeter fencing boosts security at <ORGANIZATION>Dallas Police Department</ORGANIZATION> substations https t co owXfZuDIGb https t co BzHSKTCXCh Canadian hockey bus crash Victims identified as son of former <ORGANIZATION>NHL</ORGANIZATION> player respected coach https t co q3Ad391QwI https t co PbqFL5Fvbu <LOCATION>Texas</LOCATION> girl 7 climbs Mt Kilimanjaro to honor late father breaks world record https t co vqUTSRGgoq https t co noCJAPtMjO <PERSON>Mattis</PERSON> on possible airstrike against <PERSON>Assad</PERSON> I don t rule out anything right now https t co hv1IpXQICd https t co QF49JfUqE8 <PERSON>Roger Stone</PERSON> says <PERSON>Paul Manafort</PERSON> will never roll over on <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> https t co dKZAyVX6Vx https t co ojpNY6eBSO Exonerated death row inmate tells his story at <ORGANIZATION>Legacy Museum</ORGANIZATION> https t co 82EZB8eJDW https t co bJx4UC8WVF At least 23 children and four adults were killed in <LOCATION>India</LOCATION> when a school bus plunged into a deep gorge in the <LOCATION>Himala</LOCATION> https t co ZmDNXXUgFd <ORGANIZATION>EPA IG</ORGANIZATION> will review former <ORGANIZATION>EPA</ORGANIZATION> official <PERSON>Samantha Dravis</PERSON> employment records https t co ARzJaFLKDc https t co ANSNGI3xTh Dozens of students hurt when bus roof sheared off in overpass crash https t co 1l6F1YxC29 https t co BYUYezKLTD At least 23 children killed when school bus plunges into gorge in <LOCATION>India</LOCATION> https t co wPiFpvXQG8 https t co wMOYFQuB8m <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> is displaying advertisements for well known American corporations on group pages operated by overseas wild https t co epRSPWHDKp <ORGANIZATION>Green Bay Packers</ORGANIZATION> wide receiver <PERSON>Trevor Davis</PERSON> was arrested after falsely claiming to have explosives while checking https t co 7sH8Nvk2OF Eating a <ORGANIZATION>Carolina Reaper</ORGANIZATION> chili pepper sends man to the hospital with thunderclap headaches https t co CdthpYNCud RT CBSThisMorning TOMORROW ON CBSThisMorning PReedGolf will join us at the table in Studio 57 to talk about his breakthrough <PERSON>PGATOUR Bill Cosby</PERSON> paid nearly 3 4 million to the woman he is charged with sexually assaulting a prosecutor revealed to j https t co SIk9CaKAL6 TOMORROW PReedGolf will be on CBSThisMorning to talk about his breakthrough TheMasters win https t co <ORGANIZATION>GeLAUbzcp4 Facebook</ORGANIZATION> CEO <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> met one on one with a series of key lawmakers on Monday in what could be the most imp https t co uFacEcwFv4 House Minority Leader <PERSON>NancyPelosi</PERSON> slams President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> s attacks on special counsel <PERSON>Robert Mueller</PERSON> saying it s https t co miX1suw3Jz Survivors in the town of <LOCATION>Douma</LOCATION> outside the Syrian capital of <LOCATION>Damascus</LOCATION> smelled strongly of chlorine a chemical that https t co 30Z8B37Ok2 In a meeting with military advisers President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> complained about the <ORGANIZATION>FBI</ORGANIZATION> raid of his lawyer <PERSON>Michael Cohen</PERSON> s of https t co rFfGuio2nM For the past 24 years <PERSON>Wang Mingqing</PERSON> has been searching for his daughter that he lost at his roadside fruit stand https t co XBb20D0Wcj When a truck slammed into the <ORGANIZATION>Humboldt Broncos</ORGANIZATION> bus Friday killing 15 team members and injuring more than a dozen https t co kY46szdWWO Last week people across the country heard stories about strange zombie like raccoons terrorizing a town in northe https t co Frs4k40bTV This is American history Great grandson of lynching victim faces the past https t co uT8QXzR6iv https t co lgD48aNwsC Facebook CEO <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> is ready to tell <ORGANIZATION>Congress</ORGANIZATION> he s sorry He faces a grilling tomorrow and Wednesday over https t co k10ujbnF0v Medics describe smelling chlorine on survivors of apparent chemical attack in <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> that killed 40 https t co t7i7sTOubs This raid reveals there is now a second criminal investigation into the president s inner circle and that it like https t co Hhe7qjsuqR CBSNews Why don t I just fire special counsel <PERSON>Robert Mueller</PERSON> Well I think it s a disgrace going on We ll see https t co CiozXILXKF RT CBSEveningNews A remarkable memorial opens later this month in <LOCATION>Alabama</LOCATION> dedicated to the memory of victims of lynching The National CBSNews POTUS lashes out at Attorney General <PERSON>Jeff Sessions</PERSON> saying he made a terrible mistake when he recused https t co OX0VL4zlWw CBSNews It s frankly a real disgrace It s an attack on our country POTUS says of <ORGANIZATION>FBI</ORGANIZATION> search on <PERSON>Cohen</PERSON> https t co 31HrzyJ5o0 NEW President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> talks about <ORGANIZATION>FBI</ORGANIZATION> raid on his personal attorney <PERSON>Michael Cohen</PERSON> POTUS calls it a disgraceful s https t co NXf2LybiTa RT CBSEveningNews COMING UP TONIGHT We ll have more on today s <ORGANIZATION>FBI</ORGANIZATION> raid on the office of the president s personal attorney The pre <ORGANIZATION>Fox News</ORGANIZATION> host <PERSON>Laura Ingraham</PERSON> returns from a one week vacation tonight to The <ORGANIZATION>Ingraham Angle</ORGANIZATION> a show that now has https t co 4ilJ5QrtFz Senator <PERSON>Tammy Duckworth</PERSON> D IL has just become the first senator in U S history to give birth while in office https t co jG29miWa49 <ORGANIZATION>FBI</ORGANIZATION> agents stormed not only <PERSON>Michael Cohen</PERSON> s office but also his <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> residence seizing documents and other ma https t co kmb7rIlN1i <LOCATION>Los Angeles</LOCATION> is painting some of its roads white and the reasons why are pretty cool literally https t co BOh7mk3KNH Whether this is related to the special counsel <PERSON>Mueller</PERSON> investigation or the <PERSON>Stormy Daniels</PERSON> case it looks like t https t co mK9HYlN66B NEW The decision by the <ORGANIZATION>US Attorney s Office</ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> to conduct their investigation using search warrants is https t co W3P2jNWtLH MORE It is unclear whether this is stemming from the <PERSON>Mueller</PERSON> investigation whether it has anything to do with th https t co B8Tn8dX26z We did learn that the seizure by <ORGANIZATION>FBI</ORGANIZATION> and law enforcement was under a court authorized warrant that was obtained in https t co hDtpV7saE4 MORE Law enforcement agents conducted searches today at the <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> office and <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> residence of <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> person https t co yxNf1Qoeil MORE Federal prosecutors in <LOCATION>Manhattan</LOCATION> obtained search warrant for <PERSON>Michael Cohen</PERSON> s office after special counsel in https t co EX9UTJPiRi NEW <ORGANIZATION>FBI</ORGANIZATION> agents raid office of <PERSON>Michael Cohen Pres Trump</PERSON> s personal lawyer according to <ORGANIZATION>New York Times</ORGANIZATION> report https t co gpvCqz388d U S Ambassador <PERSON>Nikki Haley</PERSON> speaks at <ORGANIZATION>UN Security Council</ORGANIZATION> emergency meeting in wake of suspected chemical attack in https t co MnnI2tTN6A Sen <PERSON>Tammy Duckworth D IL</PERSON> became the first sitting U S senator to give birth while holding office with the deli https t co <ORGANIZATION>KLjDFjxvAV U N Security Council</ORGANIZATION> holds emergency meeting after suspected chemical attack in <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> https t co 8AoewaCf7J https t co 6Dpp0lPDwR Four teens charged with throwing a sandbag from a <LOCATION>Toledo</LOCATION> overpass and causing the death of a car passenger have bee https t co 7LNjKtX21z <PERSON>Saddam Hussein</PERSON> s statue toppled over 15 years ago today becoming one of the most iconic moments of the <LOCATION>Iraq</LOCATION> war https t co 4tUb83yfeR I m not going to get ahead once again of any actions that he U S may or may not take but I think the president h https t co m7LHjrJmoM Reporter Did chief of staff <PERSON>John Kelly</PERSON> recommend that <ORGANIZATION>EPA</ORGANIZATION> administrator <PERSON>Pruitt</PERSON> be fired PressSec I m not go https t co DA7Ts9i09R He s asked the department of agriculture to protect our farmers and will present a plan on specifics of that short https t co dV8XxHwqP9 The point of view that matters most here at the <LOCATION>White House</LOCATION> as you well know is the president s <PERSON>PressSec</PERSON> says https t co YYwlKcrZpM We re still there and I think that it is outrageous to say that the president has green lit actions that have tak https t co 0gHMGtbcrF I can only speak on behalf of this government For questions on that I would refer you outside At this time the https t co 5mXmVK5agz WATCH NOW <ORGANIZATION>White House</ORGANIZATION> briefing underway as U S considers possible military retaliation over suspected chemical at https t co QYIafgxKtA The <ORGANIZATION>Giants</ORGANIZATION> added a special player to their roster on Sunday an 8 year old girl named <PERSON>Hailey</PERSON> who threw out the fi https t co 8sHveDxHpt SenDuckworth gives birth to baby girl becomes first U S senator to give birth while in office https t co 0ydTqqQao3 <LOCATION>Arizona</LOCATION> Gov <PERSON>Doug Ducey</PERSON> says 225 <ORGANIZATION>National Guard</ORGANIZATION> members are heading to the <LOCATION>Mexico</LOCATION> border to back President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> s https t co ye5BCOJ12L Lawyers representing President <PERSON>Donald Trump</PERSON> s family hotel business appealed to <LOCATION>Panama</LOCATION> s president for help days be https t co Y5AWfsMHMt Fox News <PERSON>Sean Hannity</PERSON> says he will address comments by <ORGANIZATION>ABC</ORGANIZATION> late night comic <PERSON>Jimmy Kimmel</PERSON> on his show Monday night https t co lgp4llLFPb Hockey player s body misidentified in bus crash Canadian officials say https t co rVRHxEiaXV https t co fhUKF4Iwzw CBSNews Reporter Would you like to see executives from <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> and Twitter and other tech companies come testify https t co cBQv3EWrPr On defensive amid <ORGANIZATION>Cambridge Analytica</ORGANIZATION> controversy <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> announces an independent election research commission https t co pzJfe0uVwa CBSNews My sense is that he takes it seriously because he knows that there is going to be a hard look at regulati https t co Z6AyGIziEk MOMENTS AGO Sen <PERSON>Bill Nelson</PERSON> D FL discusses meeting with <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> CEO <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> ahead of his congressional https t co R7JfdgovvL Topless protestor charges <PERSON>Bill Cosby</PERSON> with Women s Lives Matter painted on her chest https t co V6Mg4WIXcC https t co Bi15PvmamV Former manager says he warned <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> about potential privacy risks in 2012 https t co 8ZNoas1iFj https t co M6NqfugA48 <PERSON>Tony Robbins</PERSON> if you talk to more SURVIVORS and less sexist businessmen maybe you ll understand what we want https t co KiBOv1rlhq <PERSON>Pres Trump</PERSON> confers with military on suspected gas attack in <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> https t co 25vr1d7xPe https t co TrdrCYuFAp Nothing is off the table in response to <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> POTUS says The generals will figure it out over the next 24 hou https t co BNkvf136oZ If during the course of the negotiation with <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> they want to hit farmers because they think that hits me I w https t co lq3DYQIjaR POTUS says he and Chinese President <PERSON>Xi Jinping</PERSON> are very good friends but with that being said <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> is takin https t co JqXrCEbwu5 If it is <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> if it is <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> if it is <LOCATION>Iran</LOCATION> if it is all of them together we will figure it out and we will https t co fTnAdlmlwt The <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> brothers business trip to <LOCATION>Dubai</LOCATION> just cost taxpayers 73 000 https t co weCZigp3SC https t co LDtwGvlsgB WATCH We are studying that situation extremely closely We are meeting with our military and everyone else that w https t co lgm7XcH3vN Remains of <ORGANIZATION>Navy</ORGANIZATION> seaman killed in <LOCATION>Pearl Harbor</LOCATION> attack identified military says https t co WU0H6VSOp8 https t co tUipUHTsYD Toddler hit in the head by oxygen canister on <ORGANIZATION>American Airlines</ORGANIZATION> flight https t co h86MMLUcMT https t co 1tT2fWiOX6 Still Standing Sir <PERSON>Elton John</PERSON> talks stellar career and farewell tour on CBSThisMorning https t co f4FpOifCGH https t co N89MZFt61d Asked about potential airstrikes against <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> s <PERSON>Assad</PERSON> regime <ORGANIZATION>U S Defense</ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON>James Mattis</PERSON> replied I don https t co ER57YHYwNW First look at the 2019 <ORGANIZATION>Chevy Camaro General Motors</ORGANIZATION> has taken extraordinary measures to keep the reboot of the clas https t co WC0PBfqIVp Apple co founder protests <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> by closing his account https t co Qbz1SSmfrn https t co sorVxVlqmI Dozens of students hurt when bus roof sheared off in overpass crash https t co IiFLHDLT0u https t co NoMlbo0mN7 Republicans return to work with <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> agenda in mind scrambling to compile a to do list to satisfy a president the https t co qP7KZjEu7q After pulling <ORGANIZATION>Facebook ads Mozilla</ORGANIZATION> exec says trust isn t being earned https t co Boo2oRO2Z9 https t co XiwijxW0nd <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> says to hell with it about staff advice AP https t co xG62YDP4d3 https t co JXzrtfllrT President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> seeks to ease fears about trade war with <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> https t co AVB1SflRFT https t co elYHUMvYkj Music icon <PERSON>Elton John</PERSON> has nine 1 hits and has won 5 Grammys an Oscar and a Tony After touring the world for near https t co cYJfd2mH7V Self help guru <PERSON>Tony Robbins</PERSON> asks for forgiveness after making controversial comments about MeToo movement https t co pW57b4UUgF Facebook CEO <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> will testify before 3 <ORGANIZATION>Congressional</ORGANIZATION> committees in 2 hearings this week on how his comp https t co XAW1qLYaPY Here s a look at some of this morning s headlines on CBSThisMorning https t co v5AuJ1FIfW First on CBSThisMorning a look at the 2019 Chevy Camaro before its public debut <ORGANIZATION>General Motors</ORGANIZATION> has taken extraor https t co Eu6SMklbv9 Captain <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> is now the Masters champion <PERSON>Patrick Reed</PERSON> 27 has won his first major title at the Masters in Au https t co vvQIt7Ai4i A new memorial in <LOCATION>Montgomery Alabama</LOCATION> features a tribute honoring thousands of victims of lynching The memorial is https t co rMwwqAL4tf U S officials say President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> will wait for Monday s emergency meeting of the <ORGANIZATION>U N Security Council</ORGANIZATION> before dec https t co 6VQsjm7ySK Missiles struck an air base in central <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> early Monday but the <ORGANIZATION>Pentagon</ORGANIZATION> quickly denied claims from Syrian state https t co oAXBXxenos Here s a look at some of this morning s headlines on CBSThisMorning https t co MLnHneRJq0 Facebook CEO <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> prepares to testify to <ORGANIZATION>congress</ORGANIZATION> this week <ORGANIZATION>Cambridge Analytica</ORGANIZATION> improperly obtained pri https t co ojHgr3qtLo <PERSON>Chuck McCann</PERSON> the zany comic who hosted a children s television show in the 1960s before branching out as a charact https t co pf8IrSi2Ak Self help guru <PERSON>Tony Robbins</PERSON> is apologizing for comments he made criticizing the Me Too movement At one of his ev https t co ft7E7qZgRs Here are three things you should know this morning 1 <ORGANIZATION>U S National Guard on Mexico Border</ORGANIZATION> 2 Gas prices surge 3 Bl https t co FCNW0XzrCg <LOCATION>Iran</LOCATION> U S would regret violating nuke deal in less than a week https t co MLTlaJGkDU https t co PGlQxhswQP Opening statements are expected to begin Monday in <PERSON>Bill Cosby</PERSON> s sexual assault re trial The first trial ended last https t co H8SBPK067X An investigation is underway into the deadly fire at <LOCATION>New York City</LOCATION> s <LOCATION>Trump Tower</LOCATION> One 67 year old man was killed an https t co bWRPaa8IhZ A vigil was held to mourn victims of a devastating bus crash in <LOCATION>Saskatchewan Canada</LOCATION> Fifteen people were killed wh https t co E0Pk8FZXrZ 44 people are injured after a bus full of high school students crashed in <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> The group was being picked up a https t co t3lNytN75o Facebook CEO <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> will testify Tuesday before <ORGANIZATION>Congress</ORGANIZATION> on how his company handles its users data Lawma https t co 3HKwkCu838 <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> has suspended another data collecting firm on Monday Cubeyou reportedly acted a lot like <ORGANIZATION>Cambridge Anal</ORGANIZATION> https t co <ORGANIZATION>GINx04Btbi White house</ORGANIZATION> officials say <LOCATION>North Korea</LOCATION> has confirmed that dictator <PERSON>Kim Jong Un</PERSON> is ready to discuss removing all nucl https t co zwZF3DAd90 U S officials say President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> will wait for Monday s U N meeting before deciding on a U S response to appare https t co 04P4VFyB6X International outrage and threats of retaliation follow the latest apparent chemical weapons attack by <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> s gove https t co fOHrbhCNMh U N to hold dual meetings about alleged chemical attack in <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> https t co GxoWNhP6hr https t co fvUJoFRXDZ <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> will give testimony to 3 congressional committees in two hearings <PERSON>Sandy Parakilas</PERSON> led the team at https t co mzMtnm8R9n Commentary <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> s <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> quandary The president wants to get out of <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> but he also wants to punish the animal https t co jKqzfUu6C4 The international community is vowing to respond after the Syrian government allegedly carried out another deadly c https t co 9Y6h9mqWFf U S denies missile strike in <LOCATION>Syria Russia</LOCATION> says <LOCATION>Israel</LOCATION> did it https t co kRbMm7ZN49 https t co VLXCz8zDLU <ORGANIZATION>Howard University</ORGANIZATION> sit in ends after record 9 days https t co atXWIAoa27 https t co <ORGANIZATION>CaFW7YDIVs Transcript Treasury</ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON>Steven Mnuchin</PERSON> on Face the Nation April 8 2018 https t co UBqcSb6Cg3 https t co oBBjZbelMp Transcript Sen <PERSON>John Kennedy</PERSON> on <ORGANIZATION>Face the Nation</ORGANIZATION> April 8 2018 https t co rwYbEb11EH https t co br8Cm9MbDn Who is <PERSON>Steve Spurrier</PERSON> https t co TSmuwDTq9G https t co xIvrtgiaq2 <LOCATION>Iran</LOCATION> U S would regret violating nuke deal in less than a week https t co ADxcfiDA09 https t co vKqbq7EQxX What has <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> learned from <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> s data controversy https t co B4s7aW9cUb https t co 10ifIl7403 <ORGANIZATION>AG</ORGANIZATION> Sessions orders zero tolerance policy on illegal border crossings https t co kvomKDHPPz https t co ds6QpfDm83 <PERSON>Al Sharpton</PERSON> and Parkland shooting survivor announce June rally against gun violence https t co XwivxaMyAj https t co sO9OWoEsYi Nine <LOCATION>West</LOCATION> declares bankruptcy as retailer failures continue https t co JjDpyMmy9t https t co Fy1hz9aHku Will <ORGANIZATION>Blake Farenthold</ORGANIZATION> reimburse taxpayers for 84K harassment settlement https t co FTdcr7v4Kj https t co uaYVTKBqdj <PERSON>Jimmy Kimmel</PERSON> apologizes for gay joke amid feud with <PERSON>Sean Hannity</PERSON> https t co cTsfPlAQfx https t co rKFVAyYNk0 <ORGANIZATION>House Oversight Committee</ORGANIZATION> reviewing <PERSON>Scott Pruitt</PERSON> condo agreement https t co MxutbCKt9P https t co llok4WMTlL <LOCATION>Miami</LOCATION> dad arrested after 8 year old son brings loaded gun to school in book bag https t co MrvudqGcYv https t co KXkAy6cclm <PERSON>Chuck McCann</PERSON> comic and actor dies at 83 https t co PHsCpUHCZU https t co 1ASSxKiZny Baby delivered after pregnant woman is shot in head in <LOCATION>Ohio</LOCATION> https t co 3pcoOdAAyM https t co 1jZjojle47 <PERSON>Tina Fey</PERSON> brings her Mean Girls to <LOCATION>Broadway</LOCATION> https t co kDnPu0si7B https t co <ORGANIZATION>I4nA5uShCO Facebook</ORGANIZATION> suspends another data analytics firm AggregateIQ https t co hMdIUzp7YO https t co 3PoJHszLW2 Doctors warn of second wave of the flu https t co pRL0psS6jK https t co 9TClNHXHvm Man arrested for <LOCATION>Indianapolis</LOCATION> knife attack that injured 3 https t co KCNY0VL7Uj https t co 19Wy9FKJwE Criminal minds Inside the head of a man authorities believe to be a killer https t co GGlwhl5zeb https t co cz4pO3qWEW Ahead of <PERSON>Zuckerberg</PERSON> s testimony Sen <PERSON>John Kennedy</PERSON> says privacy is too big for <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> to fix https t co MGupDd6E6o Doors from <LOCATION>New York City</LOCATION> s famed <ORGANIZATION>Chelsea Hotel</ORGANIZATION> head to auction https t co T9HeArjO9W https t co RHIkPxGKV9 YouTube shooting spotlights creators frustrations with monetization policy changes https t co c9DH9kBU5n https t co 19Uzxkmwrv 2 soldiers killed in helicopter crash at <LOCATION>Fort Campbell</LOCATION> https t co Ep0hDfUDDd https t co ZMSTvituIP Taxes Is there a better way https t co zHUYIIJ6aF https t co JeiFq3voYW President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> begins initial preparation for possible interview with special counsel <PERSON>Robert Mueller</PERSON> https t co qQ027hBR06 <PERSON>Joe Kennedy III</PERSON> on his legacy and future https t co JOPW9BI4iY https t co GinCwKX8Px U N to hold dual meetings about alleged <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> chemical attack https t co ZwpVuIUuVP https t co 7gZh09W5rW Earthquakes in northwest <LOCATION>Oklahoma</LOCATION> include magnitude 4 6 https t co u1CJ3heu2f https t co WdX5umk8zd <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> says <ORGANIZATION>DOJ</ORGANIZATION> is slow walking congressional document requests https t co HQnAUAxi3c https t co 5sPiBvWYzi Homeland Security to compile database of journalists media influencers https t co CTCdfZH5Kk https t co dhwk0YFiVX U S not conducting air strikes <ORGANIZATION>Pentagon</ORGANIZATION> says after apparent chemical attack by Syrian regime https t co POuLtDQHi2 Almanac A multitude of sunspots https t co CXInyLG2k4 https t co EAlVPpuePs Road collapses in <LOCATION>Pittsburgh</LOCATION> prompting evacuations https t co J0q2o3Ywgm https t co AY9EzvqkEN We are sealing up our southern border <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> speaks on <ORGANIZATION>National Guard</ORGANIZATION> deployment https t co iEOhJq2BW1 https t co HNvjLyKxWa Facebook to notify users if their data was shared with <ORGANIZATION>Cambridge Analytica</ORGANIZATION> https t co aAFaqpv9uU https t co Ovut8dG2Ad Assault weapons ban doesn t violate 2nd Amendment judge says https t co wEtX6WXu2o https t co n0McjoetaM Allegiant Air plane skids off snowy runway at <LOCATION>South Dakota</LOCATION> airport https t co YENSn92Sr5 https t co Qd4fl7cKuY Family outraged after video of toddler frightened by the <ORGANIZATION>Easter Bunny</ORGANIZATION> goes viral https t co oMStMha1bq https t co S3C9uOCbMv Should you clone your dog https t co Hua2HHb4gN https t co NjxvlaHyoP <PERSON>Laura Ingraham</PERSON> due back at <ORGANIZATION>Fox News</ORGANIZATION> following backlash https t co t9ZNtP4RUH https t co LAURdce9LF I m not going to be a <PERSON>Gabby Giffords</PERSON> Congressman pulls out gun at constituent meeting https t co AHKWxqA4BG https t co IunLKRjLAo Police search for man accused of killing 3 with assault rifle in <LOCATION>Illinois</LOCATION> https t co YCsXm4Csis https t co YDCQMNDeN4 Treasury Secretary <PERSON>Steve Mnuchin</PERSON> on trade war with <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> It could be but I don t expect it at all https t co 4VYugogLLn Charter bus shooting leaves 3 dead in <LOCATION>Rockford Illinois</LOCATION> suspect at large https t co OIiNAKNELo https t co FIN549WBGF 60Minutes goes inside the 142 year old <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> institution that s produced some of the funniest people in show bu https t co AMeudJ6mPK <PERSON>Oprah</PERSON> reports on the <LOCATION>Alabama</LOCATION> memorial dedicated to thousands of African American men women and children lynched https t co 01EMKDazWn Russian operatives launched a widespread cyberattack against state voting systems during the 2016 presidential elec https t co QW9Tsjtpxf <LOCATION>Trump Tower</LOCATION> fire is second 2018 blaze in sprinkler free residential tower https t co czbnznwLDr https t co hVnTmAftrF WATCH Nun runs 10K race in her habit But this feat is nothing for Sister <PERSON>Mary Beth Lloyd</PERSON> who has run races up to https t co FskTuQpgub U S confirms <LOCATION>North Korea</LOCATION> s <PERSON>Kim Jong</PERSON> Un willing to talk denuclearization official says https t co 4V6ujZMHS0 https t co n3kj6J9e34 Tonight 60Minutes looks at the widespread cyberattack Russian operatives launched on U S election systems in 201 https t co KDJgBEZR9v At an illustrious university famous for taking itself seriously one student magazine s staff devotes itself to pu https t co R1Ksf6Xwnr <LOCATION>Trump Tower</LOCATION> fire victim was avid art collector who spent time with <PERSON>Andy Warhol</PERSON> but fell on hard financial times in https t co nESndzACzm WATCH A golfer fed up with winter weather in the spring decides to tee off in the snow Guess that s why they don https t co 1pH2AtGPM2 Tonight <PERSON>Oprah Winfrey</PERSON> reports on a new monument going up in <LOCATION>Montgomery Ala</LOCATION> that documents the lynchings of Afri https t co 0j7LM0pTkK WATCH 400 decorative boats set sail for the 2018 Qintong Boat Festival with more than 10 000 participants in colo https t co pMFWzzN1Im <PERSON>Bernie Taupin Elton John</PERSON> s musical collaborator for over 50 years is a man of lyrics and now art https t co kS4DpxFOSg <PERSON>Jimmy Kimmel</PERSON> apologizes for gay joke amid feud with <PERSON>Sean Hannity</PERSON> https t co NSqvyaDcjD https t co 8VDKuiI8S2 Man arrested for <LOCATION>Indianapolis</LOCATION> knife attack that injured 3 people https t co wK0mveSbgE https t co O7ESB4td8Y <PERSON>Tina Fey</PERSON> is now bringing Mean Girls her 2004 film about teen cliques to <LOCATION>Broadway</LOCATION> as a musical https t co Aql7rCffTS <PERSON>Antonio Banderas</PERSON> on playing <PERSON>Pablo Picasso</PERSON> in the new series Genius https t co lBWqzsdTDS https t co 5xplnqt0sB A suspected chemical attack in the Syrian city of <PERSON>Douma</PERSON> suffocated dozens to death opposition groups said Preside https t co LH5kgM0zZU <PERSON>Joe Kennedy</PERSON> III talks about following in the family tradition of politics his stands on healthcare reform and gun https t co Rgc72E2bvE German police detain 6 people in connection to planned knife attack at <LOCATION>Berlin</LOCATION> half marathon https t co q6ggwvT4gs https t co eAliLIGs3p What has <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> learned from <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> s data controversy https t co S1nsDwju9g https t co 9GAwnjyw34 Sen <PERSON>Ben Cardin</PERSON> calls for international response to suspected <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> chemical attack https t co SWuCk2QY0y https t co gGCpfAOICe Treasury Secretary <PERSON>Steve Mnuchin</PERSON> joined FaceTheNation to discuss the trade dispute with <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> the possibility of https t co nQ3QtFR7Cz WATCH An explosion went off in the aisle of a <LOCATION>California</LOCATION> store sending shocked customers running Police now thin https t co JSUzkUjpqc Ahead of <PERSON>Zuckerberg</PERSON> s testimony Sen <PERSON>John Kennedy</PERSON> says privacy is too big for <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> to fix https t co kgxOzy6QEF WATCH Explosives detonate underneath a frozen river sending plumes of ice flying high into the air https t co 0HeYxEVfMN Is there a better way to file your taxes Advocates say a pre filled tax return system as used in other countries https t co RMdYUv0Sad The Masters 2018 How to watch Round 4 on TV and online https t co b0XMGwexXM https t co HMjwjZ4jvJ Sen <PERSON>John Kennedy</PERSON> joined <ORGANIZATION>FaceTheNation</ORGANIZATION> to discuss <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> CEO <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> s testimony before <ORGANIZATION>Congress Cambri</ORGANIZATION> https t co 4qhvWa3hR6 A fire engulfed an apartment inside <LOCATION>Trump Tower</LOCATION> in <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> on Saturday killing one man inside and injuring 6 out https t co QNbDKaojyS President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> threatens Animal <PERSON>Assad</PERSON> and <PERSON>Putin</PERSON> over alleged chemical attack in <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> https t co QkmxBH8NOq https t co 377fZEYcAz <PERSON>Laura Ingraham</PERSON> due back at <ORGANIZATION>Fox News</ORGANIZATION> following backlash after mocking <PERSON>David Hogg</PERSON> a survivor of the <LOCATION>Florida</LOCATION> school s https t co 4Inj3qQkmX Fire at <LOCATION>Trump Tower</LOCATION> leaves 1 civilian dead 6 firefighters with minor injuries https t co wnY6sgxOPV https t co GteQf4TJY9 Dozens suffocate in suspected chemical weapon attack in <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> opposition says https t co GPqQqurhwm https t co snBl5kHDqK Worker at store where YouTube shooter bought her pistol speaks out https t co LWhVL3Z5oY https t co 3144Fr6HjD <LOCATION>Florida</LOCATION> school shooting hero blames sheriff superintendent https t co OWSJkgZlBS https t co WTtiaCyAzd <LOCATION>Puerto Rico</LOCATION> running out of time as storm season approaches <ORGANIZATION>FEMA</ORGANIZATION> says https t co PZN7tFDdmr https t co QndtU0Sivo Dozens suffocate in suspected chemical weapon attack in <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> opposition says https t co CAhEIlPpEq https t co MJfGuZljzg <PERSON>Al Sharpton</PERSON> and Parkland shooting survivor announce June rally against gun violence https t co XwivxaMyAj https t co 5K5kv5QGid Man in legal battle to annul his own death certificate https t co HRU3o9l3Dp https t co kgt5qMKo79 Rep <PERSON>Joe Kennedy</PERSON> III Arming teachers to make schools safer is absurd https t co Fmg0PWXJkC https t co Bj2K50jlcm Will <ORGANIZATION>Blake Farenthold</ORGANIZATION> reimburse taxpayers for 84K harassment settlement https t co FTdcr7v4Kj https t co wsr76ZwDIb <ORGANIZATION>Smithsonian</ORGANIZATION> celebrates 50th anniversary of 2001 A Space Odyssey https t co gJmSI2hYi1 https t co z5VUHO6PNP Heavy rain in <LOCATION>Northern California</LOCATION> may test spillway at nation s tallest dam https t co g10f10w3IO https t co JNxCDpQM9W <LOCATION>Gaza</LOCATION> buries journalist killed while covering mass protests https t co 75tRocr7K0 https t co uZ3YZBFIAe Lobbyist tied to condo rented by <ORGANIZATION>EPA</ORGANIZATION> chief <PERSON>Scott Pruitt</PERSON> speaks out https t co oCbTOrxsrN https t co FOKuHJK8eP Trade war with <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> What you need to know https t co omFRAX9rtV https t co BN46bMPo8I Teens say they re bored with their smartphones https t co E1emEaLQ9Q https t co 5lh1GqX1y8 Report Man accused of killing family told professor I think I need to kill my mom https t co 8YkFfHJoWS https t co HmLFijG8qs Road collapses in <LOCATION>Pittsburgh</LOCATION> prompting evacuations https t co J0q2o3Ywgm https t co dNPG9m3O6X <ORGANIZATION>Howard University</ORGANIZATION> sit in ends after record 9 days https t co atXWIAoa27 https t co 9gVn5Zp7jt Jury awards 3M to <ORGANIZATION>LAPD</ORGANIZATION> officer who claimed sexual harassment retaliation https t co 30VMxgpZZI https t co 0plGjinZMO <ORGANIZATION>AG</ORGANIZATION> Sessions orders zero tolerance policy on illegal border crossings https t co Rc4lx9thQj https t co o4omTXxI1M <ORGANIZATION>PetSmart</ORGANIZATION> is drawing more unwanted attention after the death of a third dog in five months at one of its more than 1 https t co gtx990MtMj <ORGANIZATION>House Oversight Committee</ORGANIZATION> reviewing <PERSON>Scott Pruitt</PERSON> condo agreement https t co LW3jPkO1mf https t co 2LRdnWzAwS <ORGANIZATION>Smithsonian</ORGANIZATION> celebrates 50th anniversary of 2001 A Space Odyssey https t co vr3IF72NIy https t co fA2mqJQeuf Mission to find a stolen wallet changes one man s life https t co pH02oCiNZ4 https t co x1nJ3mL0sz Doors from <LOCATION>New York City</LOCATION> s famed <ORGANIZATION>Chelsea Hotel</ORGANIZATION> head to auction https t co z22kMnYTuV https t co Jf6iQ5nvZ0 The 9 states where teachers have it worst https t co LG47LEkTMm https t co er86M0V9xu Even in gun country Democrats shift towards gun control https t co OZjwuMbErM https t co oaTg0N9b5S YouTube shooting spotlights creators frustrations with monetization policy changes https t co J5aI5fKXIz https t co xl76Fgx1iM President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> freezes out chief of staff <PERSON>John Kelly</PERSON> says he s tired of being told no https t co 1S4iJYxhGu https t co y1rjFWvASW Baby delivered after pregnant woman is shot in head in <LOCATION>Ohio</LOCATION> https t co qooeM004mm https t co dTjUNMlgMZ <LOCATION>Tennessee</LOCATION> may change its Constitution to say God is only source of liberty https t co VR610VMBAT https t co nNHxyjV7uQ Even in gun country Democrats shift towards gun control https t co grfx8NdvxW https t co rzcc7E5kGO <LOCATION>South Carolina</LOCATION> state <ORGANIZATION>House</ORGANIZATION> Republicans introduce bill on secession over gun rights https t co LLJl9nK6AX https t co <ORGANIZATION>WRfSjQEDCT Carolina Panthers</ORGANIZATION> linebacker <PERSON>Thomas Davis</PERSON> suspended for PED violation https t co kPj5ML2rR4 https t co SK7IDGimEu <LOCATION>Maine</LOCATION> mayor faces backlash over tweeted insult of Parkland shooting survivor https t co JFZ3Lgz7QT https t co ztX9mbZ3Aq <PERSON>Hart</PERSON> family crash Body recovered near where SUV went off cliff sheriff says https t co oLuxXTIiXH https t co tujpUrVlnI First grader discovers her new textbook was used by <PERSON>Blake Shelton</PERSON> in 1982 https t co N8Np3EuXVZ https t co b2iVE3gYhL I m not going to be a <PERSON>Gabby Giffords</PERSON> Congressman pulls out gun at constituent meeting https t co WpL6ggoYaR https t co <ORGANIZATION>AxpeeHsbef Homeland Security</ORGANIZATION> to compile database of journalists media influencers https t co utkB5pTd6q https t co mmEirlITMx <LOCATION>Trump Tower</LOCATION> fire is second 2018 blaze in sprinkler free residence https t co lqhFJLYbmo https t co vJYee4t3pB <LOCATION>Maine</LOCATION> mayor faces backlash over tweeted insult of Parkland shooting survivor https t co S3XMaVJiES https t co DBBUTIJ6mu <LOCATION>Trump Tower</LOCATION> fire Victim identified as <PERSON>Todd Brassner</PERSON> https t co U4RlYGS1pP https t co <ORGANIZATION>fU0jtFvX6x Carolina Panthers</ORGANIZATION> linebacker <PERSON>Thomas Davis</PERSON> suspended for PED violation https t co 7BzDCEFsHV https t co DqgiRuHqEZ <PERSON>Sean Hannity</PERSON> feuds with <PERSON>Jimmy Kimmel</PERSON> over <PERSON>Melania Trump</PERSON> joke https t co BtSlyNTTiy https t co IFVGMtgrwd Mission to find a stolen wallet changes one man s life https t co M2PKBnOZyd https t co lxefZwCmae <LOCATION>Miami</LOCATION> dad arrested after 8 year old son brings loaded gun to school in book bag https t co yYLtrwY2D9 https t co pPLS48WrkC <ORGANIZATION>EPA</ORGANIZATION> spent millions on security for embattled chief <PERSON>Scott Pruitt</PERSON> Report https t co hXgRXKuQME https t co 0GcRdRYXvl Teen who fell into <LOCATION>Los Angeles</LOCATION> sewer system thanks rescue crews https t co RHidw32sUF https t co IaIUiKKdvp Doors from <LOCATION>New York City</LOCATION> s famed <ORGANIZATION>Chelsea Hotel</ORGANIZATION> head to auction https t co DZoqj5DKel https t co vle0F4pGu3 <ORGANIZATION>House Oversight Committee</ORGANIZATION> reviewing <PERSON>Scott Pruitt</PERSON> condo agreement https t co tD4sryDIEz https t co qmdfrt1hay Condemned killer seen abducting young victim on camera to be resentenced https t co rLMlW7Pbyt https t co yoQ3U7kzvY Earthquakes in northwest <LOCATION>Oklahoma</LOCATION> include magnitude 4 6 https t co 05DtXXxc2e https t co 1PCEblrltg <PERSON>Steve Spurrier</PERSON> to coach <LOCATION>Orlando</LOCATION> team in new spring league <ORGANIZATION>Alliance of American Football</ORGANIZATION> https t co 2ZGESkSvlp https t co aunv2cNGX1 <LOCATION>California</LOCATION> storm <LOCATION>West Coast</LOCATION> still drenched after second rainiest day since 1849 Gold Rush https t co x3uf3JwNBu https t co ViYck8P3uk YouTube shooting spotlights creators frustrations with monetization policy changes https t co wwMxHRzu8I https t co wrogEcA0W4 Northern <LOCATION>California</LOCATION> rains raise flood concerns warnings and watches in effect https t co jeGeVqBwET https t co 0qy3wdmui3 Older adults can still grow new brain cells study finds https t co QvvbLsyHET https t co 4DnulQfJO9 UPDATE A civilian has died after a fire broke out in NYC s <LOCATION>Trump Tower</LOCATION> https t co uf0Gb8XpuC https t co jGuHCT8H5y Family outraged after video of toddler frightened by the <ORGANIZATION>Easter Bunny</ORGANIZATION> goes viral https t co YZYCniGYeM https t co RAao2tYBQE Doctors warn of second wave of the flu https t co dqBi324C6L https t co zYDcRA1h0N UPDATE The <ORGANIZATION>FDNY</ORGANIZATION> commissioner said 1 person is in critical condition and 4 firefighters suffered minor injuries in https t co kbxBCa67KM <LOCATION>Trump Tower</LOCATION> fire Fire breaks out on 50th floor <ORGANIZATION>FDNY</ORGANIZATION> says https t co kizrQ1Fzgo https t co VTiXQpbiu1 Assault weapons ban doesn t violate 2nd Amendment judge says https t co 8lXMOyntXX https t co PAjqxjdzOY First grader discovers her new textbook was used by <PERSON>Blake Shelton</PERSON> in 1982 https t co oEL3A8ztlA https t co GQDEeeyNPU I m not going to be a <PERSON>Gabby Giffords</PERSON> Congressman pulls out gun at constituent meeting https t co jgVR9eUvwj https t co 5POjyKMEeT Opioid crisis <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> shuts down drug hashtags on Instagram https t co cuIcjS6PWR https t co <ORGANIZATION>PNSly4Ea0h Homeland Security</ORGANIZATION> to compile database of journalists media influencers https t co 7UJs8adrYN https t co Qb9DZzOB2T <PERSON>Sean Hannity</PERSON> vows to bash <PERSON>Jimmy Kimmel</PERSON> until he apologizes to <PERSON>Melania Trump</PERSON> https t co F1vuC0pqdw https t co 9CHtfktEhu YouTube s changes to the way people can profit from popular videos were thrust into the spotlight last week after a https t co 7Z0NIIRNzs President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> tweeted the fire at NYC s <LOCATION>Trump Tower</LOCATION> is out https t co ALSnsTYdUq https t co e3WC9nSDOr JUST IN Firefighters are battling a fire on the 50th floor of <LOCATION>Trump Tower</LOCATION> in NYC https t co wAyaj9EdgS https t co 9Prxuj040Y Even in gun country Democrats shift towards gun control https t co HF1DMzkf88 https t co Iwzchknq1I I have some rather startling news to tell you Where is <PERSON>Marsha Brantley</PERSON> Join the investigation Saturday at 10 https t co n2AWKFs7kT UPDATE 15 dead 14 injured after Canadian junior hockey team bus crash https t co xZNf3yB2pI https t co BKc4AXIvGf We are sealing up our southern border President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> speaks out on <ORGANIZATION>National Guard</ORGANIZATION> deployment https t co hKULoPNh4D A student gravely wounded while saving his classmates lives during the <LOCATION>Florida</LOCATION> school massacre says the county she https t co fYESGFCz94 <ORGANIZATION>House Oversight Committee</ORGANIZATION> has requested and received documents related to <ORGANIZATION>EPA</ORGANIZATION> chief <PERSON>Scott Pruitt</PERSON> s renting of a con https t co 0k6oewa1MY Researchers are eager to better understand <LOCATION>Northern California</LOCATION> s atmospheric river storm so they re launching we https t co HcPJcWq3Gw A magnitude 4 6 earthquake shook <LOCATION>Oklahoma</LOCATION> and was also felt in neighboring <LOCATION>Kansas</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Missouri</LOCATION> according to the U https t co j4aR2vBFyg It s got to rip the heart out of your chest Horrific horrific accident <LOCATION>Toronto</LOCATION> MapleLeafs head coach <PERSON>Mike</PERSON> https t co BDthsMNWFJ A survivor of the <LOCATION>Florida</LOCATION> school shooting has joined the <ORGANIZATION>Rev Al Sharpton</ORGANIZATION> to announce a June rally against gun viol https t co whAqe9xgBY The driver is not in custody As part of the process of the investigation the driver was detained initially Our https t co qsilZy5XpK 15 people were sent to the hospital with a variety of injuries after deadly bus crash in <LOCATION>Canada</LOCATION> and some of the inj https t co NSUY8UPS9L A pair of <LOCATION>Pennsylvania</LOCATION> goats were rescued after they found themselves in a tricky situation https t co qlIEHXZNfu https t co uW49I7AQLl I don t have a lot to say other than the worst nightmare has happened <ORGANIZATION>Saskatchewan Junior Hockey League</ORGANIZATION> preside https t co dJ79evrMem On behalf of the entire <ORGANIZATION>Broncos</ORGANIZATION> family our deepest sympathies go to the injured and the deceased and of course https t co Tl4ZoUtS7e WATCH LIVE Canadian officials are giving an update on the hockey team bus collision that killed 14 people https t co <ORGANIZATION>UDDqKzYIBC Will Blake Farenthold</ORGANIZATION> reimburse taxpayers for 84 000 harassment settlement https t co e6GlLofO3q https t co U0IJYlbmIC Hundreds attend funeral of well known Palestinian journalist in <LOCATION>Gaza</LOCATION> who was killed while covering mass protests al https t co tE9cC3VLNb One eyewitness and resident in <LOCATION>Muenster Germany</LOCATION> says he is feeling less safe after a van crashed into a crowd of https t co AwrKr4oaKn The incident in <LOCATION>Muenster Germany</LOCATION> is being treated as terrorism but the suspect s identification has not yet been https t co Mv0gY13wvt Charter bus shooting leaves 3 dead in <LOCATION>Rockford Illinois</LOCATION> suspect at large https t co T5S7wPkiXl https t co PZE2DaR36O President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> s sons visit to <LOCATION>Dubai</LOCATION> this week has costed taxpayers a minimum of 73 000 in security costs accor https t co LG9CogwE4Y Road collapses in <LOCATION>Pittsburgh</LOCATION> prompting evacuations https t co 5zdUQN9FTB https t co X43hRg3ZbZ Police in <LOCATION>Muenster Germany</LOCATION> said a vehicle crashed into a crowd there killing several people and injuring others https t co XyDO10SOp7 2 soldiers were killed Friday in an Apache helicopter crash at <LOCATION>Fort Campbell</LOCATION> in <LOCATION>Kentucky</LOCATION> authorities say https t co <ORGANIZATION>GxmalhEIhv MORE Police</ORGANIZATION> say a suspicious object has been found in the van that ran into the crowd in <LOCATION>Muenster</LOCATION> Germany They s https t co AgqpH88ffa President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> has begun to informally prepare for a possible interview with special counsel <PERSON>Robert Mueller</PERSON> <ORGANIZATION>CBS</ORGANIZATION> N https t co XY89SBX6Ry At least 4 people including the driver are dead after a driver plowed into a crowd of people near a pub in <LOCATION>Muenst</LOCATION> https t co 5XvhBtCC7n So far we do not know if the shooter shouted anything No witnesses have said something like that What we know is https t co za7H2qWGUQ We do not know if this was a terror attack <LOCATION>Berlin</LOCATION> journalist <PERSON>Anna Noryskiewicz</PERSON> says of incident in Muenster Ger https t co FMO1WQBzvV UPDATE Around 30 people are injured and 6 are in a critical condition after a vehicle crashed into a crowd in Germ https t co klVahTCCgA I m not going to be a <ORGANIZATION>Gabby Giffords Republican U S Rep</ORGANIZATION> <PERSON>Ralph Norman</PERSON> pulls out gun at constituent meeting https t co HWmKvfno9I MORE Several dead others injured after car crashes into crowd in <LOCATION>Germany</LOCATION> police say https t co wE3EboRJqU https t co ygaBMcg4BN A tight knit Canadian community is trying to make sense of a tragedy after 14 people were killed when a truck colli https t co MVcVNWrsTq DEVELOPING A vehicle reportedly drove into pedestrians in the German city of <LOCATION>Muenster</LOCATION> local police confirmed ther https t co dx1IUPxQbN When an <LOCATION>Oklahoma</LOCATION> first grader found out she was using the same textbook as country music star blakeshelton she wa https t co f8Y05dTEB7 <ORGANIZATION>EPA</ORGANIZATION> spent millions on security for embattled chief <PERSON>Scott Pruitt</PERSON> a new report says https t co mTMFuAa0UC https t co hp8gs5GdII The <ORGANIZATION>White House</ORGANIZATION> sent mixed signals on Friday as financial markets slid from investor concern about a significant tr https t co sJBM1pP6Gr <PERSON>Steve Spurrier</PERSON> has been announced as the head coach of the inaugural team of the <ORGANIZATION>Alliance of American Football</ORGANIZATION> bas https t co aVt3GyxbKf Northern <LOCATION>California</LOCATION> rains raise flood concerns warnings and watches in effect https t co sjDHTUxp2Y https t co 8gYBsSVU6T A crash between a transport truck and a bus carrying a junior hockey team in <LOCATION>Western Canada</LOCATION> left 14 people dead and https t co cT28Z1wQVh <LOCATION>Minneapolis</LOCATION> activist shot dead on his mother s front porch https t co pR2ANQzfCh https t co 77OLIwwR9r 2018 <LOCATION>Atlantic</LOCATION> hurricane season will be slightly above average researchers say https t co y6zDG44xsO https t co Zqlr7xhBj9 <PERSON>Steve Spurrier</PERSON> to coach <LOCATION>Orlando</LOCATION> team in new spring league <ORGANIZATION>Alliance of American Football</ORGANIZATION> https t co Q624CmNL5Z https t co CUZIHJddLI Deadly violence for 2nd week on <LOCATION>Gaza Israel</LOCATION> border https t co tbFfBNWZg0 https t co U8jYWE8l5J RT CBSThisMorning What was it that drew you back into football The new rules I really liked Two and a half hour games 30 seconds Who is <PERSON>Steve Spurrier</PERSON> https t co DKlzyg6PfC https t co zdjgDAdUQr Just announced on CBSThisMorning A new professional spring football league called TheAAF reveals <ORGANIZATION>Orlando Florid</ORGANIZATION> https t co 09JR70cmfc Details emerge about teens found dead in mine shaft https t co gkUOhjtseR https t co g0uxkFUqDz Family outraged after video of toddler frightened by the <ORGANIZATION>Easter Bunny</ORGANIZATION> goes viral https t co RXYJhN0SyV https t co 2qa2MObIeB Northern <LOCATION>California</LOCATION> rains raise flood concerns warnings and watches in effect https t co OruRQXIEyx https t co yN4J8Ca1Cq Bald eagle lands on <ORGANIZATION>Mariners</ORGANIZATION> pitcher <PERSON>James Paxton</PERSON> before game https t co YloMFpvlvg https t co IZEV65Etfn What is shingles A look at the virus after <PERSON>Lin Manuel Miranda</PERSON> s diagnosis https t co V4lOfeD5E7 https t co fAvZynos0N Cops Woman accused of murdering wife called it a mistake https t co 8CWGlbH3Os https t co pchE5zHS5w Police Mom used kitchen knife to decapitate 7 year old son https t co ZDznBmhdQ5 https t co JSzxZx5c1f Police Mom used kitchen knife to decapitate 7 year old son https t co NRmjD5sMt3 https t co JxBbJtpYCp RT CBSThisMorning AHEAD on CBSThisMorning Saturday jillonmoney on potential trade war gdebenedetti talks politics CharlieEbersol L A residents complain GPS app <LOCATION>Waze</LOCATION> is creating insanity on their street https t co VmreDdKMfY https t co 9B0X0dNtmZ Deck hand saved lives as fishing boat sank captain s role under investigation https t co mZskkyNt9T https t co GRhnSVbYlJ Officer shows off stanky leg dance moves at <ORGANIZATION>Chattanooga Easter</ORGANIZATION> egg hunt https t co mUFFq5CHtq https t co hzUsxoj7UJ <PERSON>Alison Krauss Brad Paisley</PERSON> and others give <PERSON>Johnny Cash</PERSON> s poetry a second life in new album https t co oYvqYZ8zwh https t co 48KAAtPYhy Lobbyist tied to condo rented by <ORGANIZATION>EPA</ORGANIZATION> chief <PERSON>Scott Pruitt</PERSON> speaks out https t co 5LXWI7z0rq https t co n805TrAVFH Sisters in service Carrying on a century long tradition of military service https t co 4P74PYoyUB https t co b7oUXiN66o Virgin Galactic chalks up successful supersonic test flight https t co XbrLVJ7uJM Heavy rain in <LOCATION>Northern California</LOCATION> may test spillway at nation s tallest dam https t co l5VwA8B8Wr https t co WmRRqx3FBr Ex teacher cries in court as he admits fleeing with 15 year old <LOCATION>Tennessee</LOCATION> student https t co 3lY5QCBZv6 https t co iX1L1mT70O <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> says trade war is already lost and he probably won t attend <ORGANIZATION>White House</ORGANIZATION> Correspondents Dinner https t co hRu3E1WJjS <ORGANIZATION>PetSmart</ORGANIZATION> faces another dog death https t co Hmhu2woX5L https t co nd3aS1teQB <PERSON>Menendez</PERSON> brothers convicted of killing parents in 1989 reunited in prison https t co uCw4NjZfQ1 https t co d4HXdUKLPm <ORGANIZATION>ValuJet</ORGANIZATION> Flight 592 crash <ORGANIZATION>FBI</ORGANIZATION> offers 10 000 for info on fugitive in deadly 1996 crash https t co xnRIp0xUQ3 https t co 0ZJhVbGUsp Condemned killer seen abducting young victim on camera to be resentenced https t co zQPajB1bjS https t co mScQNxKQ1O Preview <PERSON>Tina Fey</PERSON> finally lives her <LOCATION>Broadway</LOCATION> dream https t co OuncjFbCUk https t co cyBSdTFXMy <ORGANIZATION>MMA</ORGANIZATION> superstar <PERSON>Conor McGregor</PERSON> charged with assault after chaos caught on video https t co SuwPJwVWkL https t co BjKfJ41x3E Man arrested after mother s body found in freezer https t co q1kBvz287U https t co lZ1Jkd8Rqu <PERSON>Daniel Day Lewis</PERSON> spotted using a flip phone https t co oenH2mR9KF https t co YAx9Nd693N Man in legal battle to annul his own death certificate https t co UKbGC4mi2m https t co uSTY9Zg9Lu Deck hand saved lives as fishing boat sank captain s role under investigation https t co Q6zc2St0nI https t co knHTiFsoFC Social worker charged with sexual misconduct at <LOCATION>Illinois</LOCATION> mental health center https t co XqYS0aACMR https t co <PERSON>RudBhiOPKq Hart</PERSON> family crash Searchers find cellphone near site of deadly SUV plunge https t co l9IecuDi1q https t co E7KpmzUbkQ Deaths reported in Canadian junior hockey team bus crash https t co cQUe637qAP https t co <PERSON>HYiUeyR8pU Trump</PERSON> freezes out chief of staff <PERSON>John Kelly</PERSON> says he s tired of being told no https t co JiRVZPHdXM https t co 5TgZgEEZX4 Deadly Thunderbirds crash marks 4th military aircraft incident this week https t co tcldjYpuFr https t co <ORGANIZATION>F6ttWnRutA Facebook</ORGANIZATION> suspends another data analytics firm AggregateIQ https t co JAsHEJSdn8 https t co i7Qufha3zv Heavy rain in <LOCATION>Northern California</LOCATION> may test spillway at nation s tallest dam https t co 4zBcppMLwy https t co sbEbxzshv7 Lobbyist tied to condo rented by <ORGANIZATION>EPA</ORGANIZATION> chief <PERSON>Scott Pruitt</PERSON> speaks out https t co bWHogSpxtK https t co mMJAO8nM2d Ex teacher cries in court as he admits fleeing with 15 year old <LOCATION>Tennessee</LOCATION> student https t co ooGOUUNITu https t co zlnezNBq0W <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> says trade war is already lost and he probably won t attend <ORGANIZATION>White House</ORGANIZATION> Correspondents Dinner https t co I8oty96yOB <PERSON>Menendez</PERSON> brothers convicted of killing parents in 1989 reunited in prison https t co H0OTrRaFiS https t co pYR96mY8JJ <ORGANIZATION>Howard University</ORGANIZATION> sit in ends after record 9 days https t co GboS7I2und https t co 9aevoSwUj6 <ORGANIZATION>ValuJet</ORGANIZATION> Flight 592 crash <ORGANIZATION>FBI</ORGANIZATION> offers 10 000 for info on fugitive in deadly 1996 crash https t co Z9eS9ftShq https t co d8shmWN8Un Condemned killer seen abducting young victim on camera to be resentenced https t co nuwfivyA5T https t co Rr60hNPbs9 A <LOCATION>Washington</LOCATION> woman accused of killing her wife and leaving her beneath a carpet in their shared bedroom told police https t co VUeDdoBHmK Woman used a large bladed kitchen knife to sever the head of her 7 year old son in rural western <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> author https t co gv6Vty2Hg6 Hopper <LOCATION>Penn</LOCATION> son of <PERSON>Sean Penn</PERSON> and <PERSON>Robin Wright</PERSON> was arrested and charged with possession of drugs in <LOCATION>Nebraska</LOCATION> https t co yqeLWcFEru Authorities in western <LOCATION>Ohio</LOCATION> say hospital staffers delivered a pregnant woman s baby after the mother was shot in th https t co SUxnlGz4VN With <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> CEO <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> set to testify a key question is when executives at the social network learned a https t co em1VHs4bky Three <LOCATION>California</LOCATION> gang members have been charged after leading police on a car chase before crashing head on into a https t co Pt5Jc1CUjx <LOCATION>Arizona</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Texas</LOCATION> announced Friday that they were preparing to deploy <ORGANIZATION>National Guard</ORGANIZATION> members to the <ORGANIZATION>U S Mexico</ORGANIZATION> bor https t co t5uHKzeBkJ <ORGANIZATION>ValuJet</ORGANIZATION> Flight 592 crash <ORGANIZATION>FBI</ORGANIZATION> offers 10 000 for info on fugitive in deadly 1996 crash https t co 8edoGU9aa2 https t co g11A7eEFcs He was living in the woods and this is when it was 30 degrees outside and he hadn t eaten in two days Mission https t co XXROrjoSID CBSNews Within 72 hours the <LOCATION>Texas</LOCATION> military department will have 250 personnel along with ground surveillance veh https t co PQ1RBNXA5w WATCH NOW Officials hold news conference as <LOCATION>Texas</LOCATION> prepares to send <ORGANIZATION>National Guard</ORGANIZATION> to U S <LOCATION>Mexico</LOCATION> border https t co 3YY2keNmFW A man went out for a hike last Sunday in the rugged hills along <LOCATION>Southern California</LOCATION> s <LOCATION>Malibu</LOCATION> coast Then he disapp https t co X7RyiqchTl Treasury Secretary <PERSON>Steve Mnuchin</PERSON> admits potential trade war with <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> stocks tumble amid fears https t co eIBf49f3N3 RT CBSEveningNews She was frantic really upset about it so it just became my mission OnTheRoadCBS introduces us to an amazing bart Traffic apps don t always take drivers on the best route In <LOCATION>Southern California</LOCATION> the GPS is taking drivers on a da https t co cGpEWRD4aC In the <LOCATION>Florida</LOCATION> there s a memorial to the 110 people who died there in the crash of a jetliner in 1996 The <ORGANIZATION>FBI</ORGANIZATION> ann https t co bZ88eNfimS A man went out for a hike last Sunday in the rugged hills along <LOCATION>Southern California</LOCATION> s <LOCATION>Malibu</LOCATION> coast and disappeared https t co a7gWh9iYXk Facebook CEO <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> announced new rules aimed at preventing further election meddling on <ORGANIZATION>Facebook Adverti</ORGANIZATION> https t co c6eOFfVgCE Chinese government is matching President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> s threats with threats of its own benstracy reports from <LOCATION>Beijing</LOCATION> https t co pfeUA0v51Z The Dow lost 572 points as investors fear a potential trade war with <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> MajorCBS has more https t co IdaiUnzJMn Federal agents seized the classified ad website https t co WVreYCKvt5 and closed it down PaulaReidCBS is followi https t co HXPgWda0u7 A <LOCATION>Florida</LOCATION> family is outraged after a day care worker recorded and shared video of their toddler s frightened reacti https t co XJdmdrYnZF The former Russian spy who was left fighting for his life after exposure to a rare nerve agent is no longer in crit https t co mToqAiSfNC Attorney General <PERSON>Jeff Sessions</PERSON> has ordered a zero tolerance policy aimed at people entering the <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> ill https t co KjXb4Gn5ZF <PERSON>Sean Hannity</PERSON> and <PERSON>Jimmy Kimmel</PERSON> are feuding after the late night host cracked a joke at first lady <PERSON>Melania Trump</PERSON> s ex https t co SfOWErjywO Rep <PERSON>Blake Farenthold</PERSON> the <LOCATION>Texas</LOCATION> Republican under scrutiny for using 84 000 in taxpayer funds to settle a sexual h https t co tbDtVSGIp8 <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> admits to secretly deleting messages CEO <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> sent through its Messenger app https t co j9eJ6HxboT For weeks residents in one <LOCATION>Ohio</LOCATION> city have been reporting zombie like raccoons that stand up on their hind legs https t co J9fFWHREFX Ahead of <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> CEO <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> s congressional testimonies next week here are six questions he still needs https t co E51CCj0iRq A federal judge dismissed a lawsuit challenging <LOCATION>Massachusetts</LOCATION> ban on assault weapons and large capacity magazines https t co cr4j7z7MoQ JUST IN Dow closes more than 500 points down as President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> threatens more tariffs on <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> escalating fears https t co AmuiAEnatC WATCH NOW <ORGANIZATION>UFC</ORGANIZATION> star <PERSON>Conor McGregor</PERSON> arraigned at <LOCATION>NYC</LOCATION> courthouse where he faces assault and criminal mischief charges https t co QrlNQFlrt5 Students at the <ORGANIZATION>University of Chicago</ORGANIZATION> have organized a protest rally in the wake of the shooting of a student who https t co nGv64Vjkuj You ve goat to be kidding A pair of goats were rescued after they found themselves in a tricky situation on a <LOCATION>Penn</LOCATION> https t co sEJocr2ckc NEW Stocks are plunging as investors fear a trade war with <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> is on the horizon The drop comes the president t https t co 6mDnqEVTms <LOCATION>South Carolina</LOCATION> state <ORGANIZATION>House</ORGANIZATION> Republicans introduce bill on secession over gun rights https t co BRkvLFSpiY https t co xIC8OqX7JY PressSec says President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> feels <PERSON>Scott Pruitt</PERSON> has done a good job at the <ORGANIZATION>EPA</ORGANIZATION> No one other than the preside https t co M43S46ENp4 Reporter Do you think anything POTUS has said or done is attributable to stock market decline The actions of th https t co WzTQg26Y3f Reporter Does President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> think trade wars are easy to win PressSec I think the president feels like if h https t co BX3RC8IXU6 Reporter Is President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> willing to fight a trade war on this PressSec We don t want it to come to that Th https t co ParaApzUUc Reporter What prompted the tariff escalation with <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> PressSec Look <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> created this problem amp amp the presid https t co B5qc7LGHhb MajorCBS What do you want to see from <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> PressSec Again what we would like to see is the totality of th https t co SLnuBXBOt6 <PERSON>Pres Trump</PERSON> wants to have a good relationship with <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> but that s going to depend on some of the actions by https t co 8CYjEXOhoj <ORGANIZATION>PressSec</ORGANIZATION> says Friday is <PERSON>H R McMaster</PERSON> s last day at the <ORGANIZATION>White House</ORGANIZATION> The president wishes him well He will miss https t co eTiIMDDuZN WATCH LIVE <ORGANIZATION>White House</ORGANIZATION> holds the daily press briefing as the U S targets <PERSON>Putin</PERSON> s inner circle with new sanctions https t co <ORGANIZATION>cOTdkLIKtJ Facebook</ORGANIZATION> announces advertisers running political or issue ads must be verified https t co pFLdvR3BKn https t co dGz0ak9Ord RT CBSThisMorning WATCH Co Founders of the 17th annual Tribeca Film Festival <PERSON>Jane Rosenthal</PERSON> and <PERSON>Robert De Niro</PERSON> sat down with MistahW <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> s communications watchdog says it has asked a court to block access to popular messaging app Telegram https t co PHewvNwr7j <LOCATION>Puerto Rico</LOCATION> is running out of time as storm season approaches <ORGANIZATION>FEMA</ORGANIZATION> says https t co b7vUDAw4FA https t co OJynXXcr20 Report Man accused of killing family told professor I think I need to kill my mom https t co SyFUdoEQVh https t co <ORGANIZATION>Pgx0ZP2VnP Hamilton</ORGANIZATION> creator <PERSON>Lin_Manuel</PERSON> says he s been diagnosed with shingles According to the <ORGANIZATION>CDC</ORGANIZATION> one in three Americans w https t co N8h6tB7XD3 The U S and Chinese governments have doubled down in an escalating trade dispute with the U S threatening to imp https t co C0djhFTtTN YouTube shooter <PERSON>Nasim Aghdam</PERSON> s gun buy did not stand out store worker says https t co vDT8CRf03z https t co RkJCiDFVET <LOCATION>Oregon</LOCATION> Gov <PERSON>Kate Brown</PERSON> says she ll tell President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> no if he asks to send <ORGANIZATION>National Guard</ORGANIZATION> troops from her state https t co RqD9RLwL84 WATCH <ORGANIZATION>MMA</ORGANIZATION> star <PERSON>Conor McGregor</PERSON> leaves a <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> precinct in handcuffs in the wake of Thursday s backstage outburst https t co 1vu2aWY1rV <PERSON>Lin Manuel Miranda</PERSON> made a joke about his health after a shingles diagnosis and now he regrets it https t co RIPgvEvhYs <ORGANIZATION>Seattle Mariners</ORGANIZATION> pitcher <PERSON>James Paxton</PERSON> kept his cool as a bald eagle landed on his shoulder before the <LOCATION>Minnesota</LOCATION> Twi https t co 2qTLkOj0gF Details emerge about <LOCATION>Utah</LOCATION> teens found dead in an abandoned mine shaft https t co RNioo4f7Ox https t co bt9MzBbsLU <ORGANIZATION>OMB</ORGANIZATION> chief <PERSON>Mick Mulvaney</PERSON> has given big pay bumps at the consumer agency he once wanted to abolish https t co Pna7OmSCl9 A woman has sued the Mormon church alleging a former missionary leader raped her in the 1980s and the church faile https t co KuDCD2apO8 The <PERSON>Menendez</PERSON> brothers who were convicted of killing their parents in their <LOCATION>Beverly Hills</LOCATION> mansion in 1989 have bee https t co BFk8ehgitS Hard numbers 81 9 81 9 of the 2 783 counties most likely to lose jobs in a U S <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> trade war voted for <PERSON>Tru</PERSON> https t co wc5PGlzr99 <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> has vowed to fight the U S at any cost as a potential trade war escalates President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> threatened 100 b https t co F6Jx65Frlt The <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> administration is targeting Russian President <PERSON>Putin</PERSON> s inner circle in new sweeping sanctions https t co FZef7LC6Ga The <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> breach shows we share too much and think too little one cybersecurity expert says https t co K6NOUjtnFx A relative of a former Russian spy and his daughter who were poisoned in <LOCATION>Britain</LOCATION> says she has not heard from them s https t co LK7C3VEBHc President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> says the trade war is already lost and he probably won t attend <ORGANIZATION>White House</ORGANIZATION> Correspondents Din https t co RkaIC4PoZ9 Businesses added 103 000 jobs in March the <ORGANIZATION>Labor Department</ORGANIZATION> reports the figure fell far short of predictions e https t co 75dEglzuha Federal authorities are offering a 10 000 reward for information leading to the capture of a fugitive airline mech https t co U8hQjdaiAI For months after a <LOCATION>Tennessee</LOCATION> woman s disappearance nobody reported her missing not even her husband But her hair https t co VVFxZ35Nd4 A new <ORGANIZATION>Smithsonian</ORGANIZATION> exhibit aims to make visitors think about our place in the universe It celebrates the 50th anniv https t co Vs598b8cMY <LOCATION>Los Angeles</LOCATION> residents complain GPS app <LOCATION>Waze</LOCATION> is creating insanity on their street https t co NEIDq8qVPp https t co UjpDeuqyoG For the Easter sisters answering the call to service felt natural The three sisters are the fourth generation of https t co zXMFo1qP7v Democratic Congressman <PERSON>Joe Kennedy III</PERSON> is criticizing the idea of arming teachers to protect schools On Sunday s https t co L4OmFzKIJH A report from <LOCATION>Michigan</LOCATION> lawmakers says <ORGANIZATION>Michigan State University</ORGANIZATION> failed to protect students and parents from former https t co O8InRLGU05 President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> said in a radio interview Friday morning that tariffs on <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> may cause a little pain but he insi https t co tB8S2gEz69 <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> s campaign to discredit claims about nerve agent attack is working in <LOCATION>Moscow</LOCATION> https t co mltM1zJ5mS https t co bgOCLgJWQa Homeowners in a <LOCATION>Los Angeles</LOCATION> neighborhood say <LOCATION>Waze</LOCATION> is creating dangers by diverting drivers to one of the city s ste https t co zqtIIurXV4 RT CBSThisMorning A record number of women are running for the <ORGANIZATION>U S House</ORGANIZATION> of reps in the upcoming midterm elections Researchers pr A new memorial in <LOCATION>Montgomery Alabama</LOCATION> reflects on one of the most difficult periods in American history when thou https t co bDNDP4FlRm President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> s face off with <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> exposes <ORGANIZATION>GOP</ORGANIZATION> weakness in rural U S https t co xSkNSUDT0S https t co iqYUyakJAb In <LOCATION>Southern California</LOCATION> an early detection system warned seismologists about a 5 3 magnitude earthquake before it h https t co YqgtSu9cYZ Flooding is a major concern across <LOCATION>Northern California</LOCATION> on Friday morning Some areas could see up to 8 inches of ra https t co SObFwrBIZp British police released a statement Thursday from <PERSON>Sergei Skripal</PERSON> s daughter <PERSON>Yulia</PERSON> in her first public comments si https t co 3VHHYZNd70 On this week s TakeoutPodcast mrdannyglover says racism is the foundation of this country https t co Y2r42CKy7z Police in <LOCATION>New York City</LOCATION> have released new video showing the moments before a deadly police shooting of a black man https t co wfwcJ0BNbp Police provided new details about the gun used in the shooting at <ORGANIZATION>YouTube</ORGANIZATION> s <LOCATION>California</LOCATION> headquarters https t co F1M070nRwS <ORGANIZATION>Facebook COO Sheryl Sandberg</ORGANIZATION> admits the company did not strengthen its security fast enough to safeguard the data o https t co hmQRyoJj3f President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> seems to be standing by <ORGANIZATION>EPA</ORGANIZATION> administrator <PERSON>Scott Pruitt</PERSON> who is fending off repeated questions over https t co Mx4PHu9N8z President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> said Thursday he did not know his personal lawyer paid 130 000 to adult film star Stormy Daniels https t co y8m6pGe3Y2 President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> says he wants to send up to 4 000 <ORGANIZATION>National Guard</ORGANIZATION> troops to the border with <LOCATION>Mexico</LOCATION> to stop illegal i https t co bLM8JmG2cr President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> is proposing even bigger tariffs 100 billion against <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> in the newest sign of a potential t https t co XmuYFNLR3i President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> freezes out chief of staff <PERSON>John Kelly</PERSON> says he s tired of being told no https t co jsty46M3pd https t co MLxKxtYY2X RT CBSThisMorning WATCH Here s a preview of what s next on CBSThisMorning https t co WsYopUReW0 <ORGANIZATION>MMA</ORGANIZATION> superstar <PERSON>Conor Mcgregor</PERSON> charged with with assault and criminal mischief after chaos at <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> s <ORGANIZATION>Barclays Cen</ORGANIZATION> https t co 2uUul7N0uX Coming up on CBSThisMorning AnthonyMasonCBS talks to <PERSON>John Carter</PERSON> Cash about a new album created from his father https t co TpHoM5tdHm <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> vows to fight the U S at any cost after President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> proposed slapping an additional 100 billion in ta https t co bvqq3iIECB Ahead on CBSThisMorning NorahODonnell introduces you to a family whose men and women celebrate more than a centu https t co UgjYSCSoqD <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> is used to promote tobacco despite policies against it study finds https t co C8R1gdbQIB https t co DtSzVDjGWE 2018 <LOCATION>Atlantic</LOCATION> hurricane season will be slightly above average researchers say https t co CQax4jHjbV https t co Vj6fBaJCvW <LOCATION>Milwaukee</LOCATION> couple sells portion of art collection to benefit housing for needy https t co 2Gj0YsXQwb https t co <ORGANIZATION>zZKGl9JVEp Facebook</ORGANIZATION> breach shows we share too much and think too little https t co cYCBAmh2al https t co DaTsPM7fcp Look at the size of this thing Great white shark interrupts <LOCATION>Australia</LOCATION> police operation https t co lONUn2k1yd https t co 5y25vZvzc8 Hefty prison sentence for Park Geun hye ex President of <LOCATION>South Korea</LOCATION> https t co zhus1G2WSC https t co LbXmRVvcSS President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> says he was unaware of Stormy Daniels payment https t co LxMV1FMmv7 https t co iNPlROagDN Co founder of manga movie powerhouse Studio Ghibli dies at 82 https t co Ls8I6UvBPw https t co ffFsFtgb0O <ORGANIZATION>MMA</ORGANIZATION> superstar <PERSON>Conor Mcgregor</PERSON> charged with assault after chaos caught on video https t co 4KLpPF6smy https t co mWWPUDTLHi Service dogs in training take a field trip <ORGANIZATION>Disneyland</ORGANIZATION> https t co vBuvfeLwPb https t co k3w82OIzFZ Dems target <ORGANIZATION>House</ORGANIZATION> seat that s been Republican for decades https t co tcZV62mfoJ https t co MbIn38wNbo <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> s new terms and data policies 4 things to check https t co vcaEvVupBz https t co EVSpg24Lfv Retired <ORGANIZATION>Adm Winnefeld</ORGANIZATION> on <ORGANIZATION>National Guard</ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION>Mexico</LOCATION> border mixed messages on U S troops in <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> https t co g55oKBbqmY <LOCATION>Illinois</LOCATION> town votes to ban assault weapons fine violators up to 1 000 per day https t co WeCtvRTiQO https t co LkzOjRa3HU Jaime King s 4 year old son hit with glass in c