<ner>Thousands of people who got a telemarketing call for Dish Network in 2010 or 2011 may be able to collect 1 200 per https t co 35K9mFNRmw Police officer pulls gun on customer over pack of Mentos video shows https t co lArdfNxfTk https t co mrJYlo9UuU The mom of 2 Native American teesn removed from a college tour by campus police says her sons are the victims of ra https t co 7VRc4kyolm Dramatic cell phone video shows water pouring into a hallway and passenger rooms of a <ORGANIZATION>Carnival Cruise</ORGANIZATION> ship after a https t co swr4jDDOUo Here are three things you should know this morning 1 First lady unveils platform 2 Changing the menu 3 <ORGANIZATION>Avengers</ORGANIZATION> f https t co P4XfWmTm7S Commentary Could <PERSON>Rudy Giuliani</PERSON> be doing it right The former <LOCATION>New York City</LOCATION> mayor should probably stop saying so https t co mQkVqSeYOK <PERSON>Vladimir Putin</PERSON> begins his 4th term as president this morning <PERSON>Putin</PERSON> was sworn in during a ceremony marking his 18th https t co FhbWZMOQM0 Police in <LOCATION>Missouri</LOCATION> believe a man stabbed to death on a busy highway may have been a victim of road rage 23 year ol https t co Vrk51YlqIJ <ORGANIZATION>CIA</ORGANIZATION> Director nominee <PERSON>Gina Haspel</PERSON> reportedly considered withdrawing She wanted to step aside to avoid a brutal conf https t co TIgUh9Naww <PERSON>Rudy Giuliani</PERSON> says he doesn t know or care when <PERSON>Pres Trump</PERSON> found out about the 130 000 payment to <ORGANIZATION>Stormy Daniels</ORGANIZATION> https t co VpfwIr5ssY <ORGANIZATION>WCBS</ORGANIZATION> LonnieQuinnTV joins CBSThisMorning to discuss the science behind the eruption in <LOCATION>Hawaii</LOCATION> https t co VFHeacordn The <LOCATION>Kilauea Volcano</LOCATION> in <LOCATION>Hawaii</LOCATION> spilled huge amounts of lava for more than 3 days amp amp nights Around 1 700 people have https t co LbxLKk2Y4z 3 month old baby dead after dog mauling in <LOCATION>Los Angeles</LOCATION> police say https t co ZqYnjLWbZD https t co NvmnsY93Yn Coming up on cbsthismorning Journalists <PERSON>James</PERSON> and <PERSON>Deborah Fallows</PERSON> discuss their book Our Towns which chronicle https t co lC7Bc6XpTK Man dead in roadside stabbing ID d as <ORGANIZATION>Missouri Air National Guard</ORGANIZATION> member https t co oldyVlyGo0 https t co FN5S6mJOUT One of <LOCATION>Hawaii</LOCATION> s largest volcanos continues to threaten homes days after a huge lava flow started oozing out of it https t co yePITYsR6a <LOCATION>Chicago</LOCATION> sees spike in gun violence as more than 50 people shot in past week https t co AzEgAaf9MX https t co 9fCYx7WL1Q Andela one of <LOCATION>Africa</LOCATION> s top tech startups has local and global impact https t co vHcaLeYhMa https t co cFMsS86IZ6 <PERSON>Alex Ferguson</PERSON> ex <ORGANIZATION>Manchester United</ORGANIZATION> manager undergoes emergency surgery for brain hemorrhage https t co btHJpM7aDQ Report <PERSON>Gina Haspel</PERSON> offered to withdraw nomination to head <ORGANIZATION>CIA</ORGANIZATION> before confirmation hearing https t co 867QdEkrzD https t co aeTTQZi2ws Small town <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> in renewal https t co 6y27BJ2pvA https t co xDBU24kgAN <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> s <PERSON>Vladimir Putin</PERSON> is addressing the Russian people after being inaugurated for his fourth term as president https t co IIptLEFEOQ <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> s <PERSON>Vladimir Putin</PERSON> is being inaugurated for this fourth term as president <ORGANIZATION>CBSN</ORGANIZATION> is carrying it vladimir puti https t co dGXi2AQKZy The rise of social media influencers https t co g90MeA42mC https t co p5gln7Ofqc Woman wins 1 2 million on 18 bet that included <ORGANIZATION>Kentucky Derby</ORGANIZATION> https t co Pt8SrypX4A https t co lsXHdG32K0 Nearly 200 horses found dead amid <ORGANIZATION>Southwest</ORGANIZATION> drought in <LOCATION>Arizona</LOCATION> https t co Ecxw5qJXJt https t co c15BgEJRJN Massive Rockefeller estate auction could fetch 1 billion https t co XLq3gDUiHy https t co zd0cIHGyko <LOCATION>Hawaii</LOCATION> s <LOCATION>Kilauea</LOCATION> volcano eruption destroys more than 30 homes https t co 6ElW0oJsKa https t co XO5ezZAydb <PERSON>Daryn Kagan</PERSON> s Mother s Day card to her daughter s first mother https t co FEg6PqhUP6 https t co 89VzBj4ys8 <ORGANIZATION>Almanac Yale</ORGANIZATION> locks https t co MdDdy66JWF https t co l7czIpoiLQ <PERSON>Kellyanne Conway</PERSON> says President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> was not aware of <ORGANIZATION>Stormy Daniels</ORGANIZATION> payments when they occurred https t co <ORGANIZATION>A1LNiyjCYa Neo Nazi Senate</ORGANIZATION> candidate kicked out of <LOCATION>California</LOCATION> GOP convention https t co cRffRGdYvD https t co wFDAsro3iW <LOCATION>Hawaii Kilauea</LOCATION> volcano eruption Lava flows toxic gas show no signs of slowing down https t co Td7fburLXr https t co EUMQGJAcmn <LOCATION>Prince Louis</LOCATION> photos <LOCATION>Kensington Palace</LOCATION> releases first official pictures of newborn https t co XFNywm0TaW https t co 6qmeVqFoxP <PERSON>Nikki Haley</PERSON> on <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> confusion and speaking her mind https t co SfGB4zJax7 https t co 5j0tLhOTso 16 year Terre Haute police veteran killed in shootout with homicide suspect https t co kZROuuyPiL https t co wfDFu1EB3s Lowrider bikes Latino street life on wheels https t co u54FJ78Xr2 https t co 87zy0psGqC The Dish Mexican chef <PERSON>Eddie Hernandez</PERSON> https t co VXcwjJ5iaN https t co 5gzzhodOxL <PERSON>Rudy Giuliani</PERSON> says President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> doesn t have to comply with a special counsel subpoena https t co U3sPRN7qGn https t co 5GGEJgknL0 Six people shot in <LOCATION>Memphis</LOCATION> found inside parked car https t co WcjfqNcFCS https t co OSGtlLtQ2k <LOCATION>North Korea</LOCATION> calls U S claims about upcoming summit misleading https t co HAr34hXEV0 https t co nT1OWyNuGJ Small town <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> in renewal https t co 7Fvh5ogxyP https t co 9nwJ7TPIbl Passage <PERSON>Judith</PERSON> and <PERSON>Gerson Leiber</PERSON> https t co H4S60MonNr https t co V0dtB6ztfA Nearly 200 horses found dead amid <ORGANIZATION>Southwest</ORGANIZATION> drought in <LOCATION>Arizona</LOCATION> https t co BbwkISGKAT https t co Nk0WqUGdM2 Boy regains consciousness after parents sign papers to donate his organs https t co 0GxH0gSdN2 https t co LHY6bQVuPg Man dead in roadside stabbing ID d as <ORGANIZATION>Missouri Air National Guard</ORGANIZATION> member https t co 0eFXneYVar https t co Je2CG9M6MY <LOCATION>Hawaii</LOCATION> s <LOCATION>Kilauea</LOCATION> volcano eruption destroys more than 30 homes https t co 561zVwpdhv https t co fPt9COOvCB Johnny Cash s boyhood home added to national historic register https t co fCynP5gHt9 https t co cA7LOm2Lq7 3 month old baby dead after dog mauling in <LOCATION>Los Angeles</LOCATION> police say https t co uCAEXFMKMl https t co jtMlkvuKvQ Woman missing in <LOCATION>New Jersey</LOCATION> since December found dead authorities say https t co TmG04CCNxt https t co werD6qHE3l <PERSON>Daryn Kagan</PERSON> s Mother s Day card to her daughter s first mother https t co c0JFpaeE0i https t co H6s7Ut0LWy We could be separated Immigrants families react after <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> administration ends protected status https t co m66p3z7yWZ 16 year old girl burned to death after rape in <LOCATION>India</LOCATION> https t co 75B0E3y3m6 https t co 5lTy0IAkcg <PERSON>Kellyanne Conway</PERSON> says President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> was not aware of <ORGANIZATION>Stormy Daniels</ORGANIZATION> payments when they occurred https t co ILdHIvty72 <LOCATION>Chicago</LOCATION> sees spike in gun violence as more than 50 people shot in past week https t co TfFD9fMvdK https t co OiYM7Sy4HL Guess where the corporate tax cut money is flowing https t co sfxR0i92Zg https t co MARjSi8cDQ This week on Sunday Morning May 6 https t co jJ37uTuuhU https t co 3hqeqSXvaf At 96 years old this World War II veteran received his college diploma 68 years after taking his last class https t co NUnyxsjG6T The mother of one of the victims fatally shot at a <LOCATION>Nashville Waffle House</LOCATION> last month accepted her daughter s diplom https t co oB1crPzwBS WATCH NOW Officials hold news conference in <LOCATION>Hawaii</LOCATION> where a volcano eruption series of earthquakes forced hundreds https t co BJwj9p8pON <LOCATION>UK</LOCATION> ambassador reveals President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> will fix the <LOCATION>Iran</LOCATION> nuclear deal without actually changing a word https t co 1ZoL3PMtKf The number of homes destroyed by <LOCATION>Hawaii</LOCATION> s <LOCATION>Kilauea</LOCATION> volcano has climbed to 21 officials say https t co HQEJDhDfLf https t co LlsMYbsEnr Renowned wildlife photographer mangelsen shows 60Minutes what goes into his iconic pictures https t co YqHjCEPfWV <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> s civil war has left over 100 000 children orphaned 60Minutes talked to two people who dropped everything t https t co 87C97Z1gYU What one city did to fight high drug prices reveals a supply chain in which just about every link can benefit when https t co SE7EZfBfVi A review of news reports collected by the nonprofit Gun Violence Archive revealed more than 30 publicly reported mi https t co lxgaRHydlJ <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> s civil war has left at least 100K children orphaned Major organizations are helping but tonight <PERSON>Scott Pel</PERSON> https t co D3RzsY628t A 13 year old boy who suffered severe brain trauma in an accident regained consciousness after his parents signed p https t co ADcuF5HMhx At 72 photographer <PERSON>Tom Mangelsen</PERSON> travels to remote and inhospitable places What he brings back are some of the m https t co S7gaS5t1cQ A bomb blast inside a mosque in <LOCATION>Afghanistan</LOCATION> that was being used as a voter registration center killed at least 14 p https t co imE2IhEs7z A 13 year old boy was given two hours to live after suffering an extreme head injury Then a day before they were https t co PXjVWm5eB8 How did the cost of one drug prescribed to treat two infants threaten to financially cripple an entire town https t co 8j2aPqADOb Ex coal CEO and <LOCATION>West Virginia</LOCATION> senate candidate <PERSON>Don Blankenship</PERSON> says he will not rule out a third party bid in the W https t co pri5zrgZ4O <ORGANIZATION>George Washington University</ORGANIZATION> constitutional law professor says it s possible that a porn star could take down a pr https t co xj1vvNXAp8 WATCH A water line break on a cruise ship cause a vacation nightmare for dozens of passengers but some people on https t co aA9bDAZxzA After a tornado hit his town one pastor found a wedding dress stuck in a tree Despite suffering damage of his own https t co <ORGANIZATION>qoqAvaPuFz Facebook</ORGANIZATION> is being accused of inadvertently helping Islamist extremists connect and recruit new members https t co dLJHyCNcb0 British ambassador to the U S says senior officials for the U K are making progress on negotiations with Presid https t co PElHUPLSwO President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> s pick to lead the <ORGANIZATION>CIA</ORGANIZATION> <PERSON>Gina Hapsel</PERSON> offered to withdraw her nomination after a <ORGANIZATION>White House</ORGANIZATION> meeting https t co PFjvjUYI1H After a tornado ripped through town a pastor found a lost wedding dress stuck in a tree Despite suffering his own https t co DnxIZO1U4v Two earthquakes hit <LOCATION>Hawaii</LOCATION> s <LOCATION>Big Island</LOCATION> on Friday adding to an already busy day with five separate eruptions on Ki https t co Gl45jBTQyi Sen <PERSON>McCain</PERSON> is doing well and reflecting at the end on a lot of different things as he recovers from procedure https t co 7cirBpZ3W5 Nearly 200 horses found dead amid <ORGANIZATION>Southwest</ORGANIZATION> drought in <LOCATION>Arizona</LOCATION> https t co nDOdKBQ3vw https t co WhPQxT1PCq <PERSON>Michael Avenatti</PERSON> attorney for <PERSON>Stormy Daniels</PERSON> chides the rope a dope defense being used by President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> s leg https t co pbl3AE76M2 <PERSON>Kellyanne Conway</PERSON> says President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> was not aware of <ORGANIZATION>Stormy Daniels</ORGANIZATION> payments when they occurred https t co Mk2xCv4CzT Social media influencers are on the rise thanks to their fashion sense and marketing savvy and millions of follow https t co iqLOvt8YmD Transcript <PERSON>Kellyanne Conway</PERSON> on FaceTheNation Sunday https t co r5NoZcjVHD https t co dg8aJRqklZ <PERSON>Nikki Haley</PERSON> on President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> confusion and speaking her mind https t co m2B09XPOsS https t co ZQgzSafKAw <PERSON>Kesha</PERSON> I feel like I took my life back via CBSSunday https t co UiAdJPDk6a https t co pqOHvOOhsq Playwright <PERSON>Mart Crowley</PERSON> on the revolutionary The Boys in the Band via CBSSunday https t co Z2rucDj5Uh https t co sz41sV9jVv Small town <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> in renewal Contrary to the narrative held by some that <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> is in decline many towns and ci https t co qLI8Biq1Fg <LOCATION>Hawaii</LOCATION> braces for long upheaval from volcano as new vents open https t co mGjfn4VctK https t co AnuihXjMIj The first official photos of Prince <PERSON>Louis</PERSON> have been revealed The adorable photos taken by his mom <PERSON>Duchess Kate</PERSON> s https t co FxgGJxCWS5 Justify wins 2018 <LOCATION>Kentucky Derby</LOCATION> get the full results list here https t co ffGFyCVcVF https t co ac8oalEXpN <LOCATION>North Korea</LOCATION> calls U S claims about upcoming summit misleading https t co 4rBwHDa4Fm https t co uJzD0TnQZ8 <ORGANIZATION>Stormy Daniels</ORGANIZATION> makes an appearance Saturday on Saturday Night Live delivering the iconic Live from <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> it https t co aptc3kFQ0i At his ranch <PERSON>John McCain</PERSON> urges <PERSON>Joe Biden</PERSON> not to walk away from politics https t co Fj5GqElvmo https t co dYgZkW9iLr Engineers are taking the most detailed look at the <LOCATION>Golden Gate Bridge</LOCATION> since it opened https t co oQJBU52AKS https t co KJEK0aYHed Top Democrat calls for investigation into <PERSON>Stormy Daniels</PERSON> payment https t co txYvKxJt13 https t co sPBLRfmbnN Many Americans are lonely and Gen Z most of all study finds https t co 1yGGZ7GdPT https t co 9sU88dCQyb Royal wedding <PERSON>Meghan Markle</PERSON> s parents and <PERSON>Diana</PERSON> s sisters to have roles https t co Y5bCYmZyot https t co a3Q4dOyuQH <LOCATION>North Korea</LOCATION> calls U S claims about upcoming summit misleading https t co Nh59EjYiOp https t co H7Rsldo1Yd Human feces found on high school track on a daily basis suspect is a school superintendent https t co mEbTOOdIDb <ORGANIZATION>New York Mets</ORGANIZATION> cutting ties with pitcher <PERSON>Matt Harvey</PERSON> after he refuses demotion to minors https t co V2ivdO7gJT https t co pqgPlrOqhF Massive Rockefeller estate auction could fetch 1 billion https t co XLq3gDUiHy https t co SFMQ8J0M1j <LOCATION>Hawaii</LOCATION> volcano eruption Residents warned about sulfur dioxide exposure https t co el3qC2xkXU https t co hBw562apX8 Man who opened fire on <LOCATION>Sutherland Springs</LOCATION> shooter honored at <ORGANIZATION>NRA</ORGANIZATION> convention https t co G0t7sGuURN https t co ovPweOf1NB Farm worker stumbles upon enormous sinkhole in <LOCATION>New Zealand</LOCATION> https t co AJxodVernb https t co JKIpmUbBeG Video captures man jumping on school bus in middle of <LOCATION>Massachusetts Turnpike</LOCATION> https t co HSoP5jiMbk https t co xV3cJnBUYz Mom found dead with 3 kids in N D home may have struggled with finances https t co Sp6ryGsltg https t co 8R1syE3VHS Police called on two Native American students taking college tour https t co NOrcXwPFLg https t co S2yZuqT0Ht <ORGANIZATION>Amazon</ORGANIZATION> plays hardball with <LOCATION>Seattle</LOCATION> over eat the rich tax https t co aQkN2kXsnx https t co 09M68WVO7u Rescuers to submit bill for hiker reported missing then found at luxury hotel https t co C7B6FhQQpy https t co r3fI8dmGpZ <LOCATION>Iran</LOCATION> trolls President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> insists it will not renegotiate nuclear deal https t co IPLLc8fOUj https t co uL14eLGiVY Son of American detained in <LOCATION>North Korea</LOCATION> speaks out https t co u6PBGuQ3pX https t co CyGRkov2Tu U S freezes funding for <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> s White Helmets https t co AbkwY6vzCK https t co QDUAKTgfj0 <PERSON>Diana Alvarez</PERSON> case Missing girl s mother sobs as suspect is charged with murder https t co 2suiA3pw7j https t co lJux9SeEwB <ORGANIZATION>CIA</ORGANIZATION> director nominee <PERSON>Gina Haspel</PERSON> gets sudden full court media press from <ORGANIZATION>White House</ORGANIZATION> https t co hUQSDujxez https t co hfsMOY8QZZ Palace reportedly worried about sex scene in Lifetime movie <PERSON>Harry</PERSON> amp amp <PERSON>Meghan</PERSON> https t co IwQCzPQ2lm https t co XRB7aaUGNO <PERSON>Michael Skakel</PERSON> case <ORGANIZATION>Court</ORGANIZATION> throws out conviction of <PERSON>Kennedy</PERSON> cousin https t co YhGibZyRks https t co yNjehUcmIa <ORGANIZATION>Southwest</ORGANIZATION> captain initially wanted to land crippled plane at different airport https t co wOIQ9tyUHb https t co GBjnDf4R9e <PERSON>Marcia Gay Harden</PERSON> on The Seasons of My Mother I didn t want her legacy to be Alzheimer s https t co tYtRInWYE6 <PERSON>James Comey</PERSON> weighs in on dangerous <PERSON>Giuliani</PERSON> comments <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> probe https t co E70wgym493 https t co 402wVP408n President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> signs order to protect religious freedom establishes new <LOCATION>White House</LOCATION> faith initiative https t co LY4qzOq8hp Severe weather blamed for at least 3 deaths in <LOCATION>Midwest Canada</LOCATION> https t co ivFASjxU0d https t co LOoOJ2etsU Why <PERSON>Samira Wiley</PERSON> almost passed on The Handmaid s Tale https t co yOfml12xir https t co 0PpSB4r4wg Teen s gift brings classmate to tears https t co hotmQ39gSp https t co pXTdzWL6kZ Trial opens for football player who killed cheerleader ex through her bedroom window https t co OUMt1Sqb4D https t co 9QP3QOE97s <LOCATION>California</LOCATION> now has the world s 5th largest economy https t co esA8LKe072 https t co N7ds3pF8Ej Stormy Daniels appears on Saturday Night Live https t co rM6q2aoXhD https t co <ORGANIZATION>LZIuBFoVgn Apple</ORGANIZATION> stock price hits new high after <PERSON>Warren Buffett</PERSON> reveals bigger stake https t co Ixzs2HKGYX https t co jLHIzcmMsQ <LOCATION>Iowa</LOCATION> abortion bill signed into law by Gov <PERSON>Kim Reynolds</PERSON> https t co bO0IZHxNwg https t co D6uxoQRERr <PERSON>Rudy Giuliani</PERSON> on <ORGANIZATION>Fox News</ORGANIZATION> insists <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> did not violate campaign finance laws https t co 4cioaB375F https t co gjZaxzVM6c More charges filed against dad accused of shackling some of his 13 children https t co JuLfxU4Cml https t co ckN8hu9HMG Dramatic video shows owner of animal sanctuary dragged away by lion https t co DZTwwpSABw https t co fFMWxQVFxP The fuzzy math of adding work requirements for food stamps https t co CsYfnLmIT6 https t co iIWp8ZTC99 Justify wins 2018 <LOCATION>Kentucky Derby</LOCATION> full results list https t co t7LySYAM2O https t co tOzFDFKgAC <LOCATION>Florida</LOCATION> woman wakes up with flying cockroach in her ear https t co DjPE2NJjBj https t co p7WUhNl0cZ <ORGANIZATION>NASA</ORGANIZATION> launches InSight lander toward <LOCATION>Mars</LOCATION> https t co 0T8CGKPNps https t co TLM4WoLSlN President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> booked himself for his first TV interview in months sources tell <ORGANIZATION>CBS News</ORGANIZATION> https t co 74CaKk4Csj https t co qR0moopjFg Fentanyl deaths now outpace prescription painkiller overdoses study finds https t co Z7kd5SFyth https t co jVjljtVhdS Johnny Cash s boyhood home added to national historic register https t co TAxq7codR1 https t co RMcFaHRGyj Launch of new naval command reflects concerns over Russian presence in <LOCATION>Atlantic</LOCATION> region https t co M8iEfCKXz8 https t co <ORGANIZATION>PvuHM2kS3Y Cambridge Analytica</ORGANIZATION> ordered to release data on an American voter report says https t co AzoO2p7SFm https t co k8ETddLk6A <LOCATION>New Orleans</LOCATION> mayor <PERSON>Mitch Landrieu</PERSON> looks back on his eight years in office https t co IR8p8p0WTh https t co VOVlvQHbs2 Neo <ORGANIZATION>Nazi Senate</ORGANIZATION> candidate kicked out of <LOCATION>California</LOCATION> GOP convention https t co qBNZnHP69Y https t co 6WKW2VQCyE Wells Fargo settles shareholder lawsuits for 480 million https t co yzEd5mQ2OH https t co wSICOtDvHc Woman who kidnapped newborn and raised child as her own apologizes https t co zPlGZcKUfv https t co fKA9gSVWdn Sweeping arrests amid anti <PERSON>Putin</PERSON> protests across <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> https t co 21KCXG7jgY https t co IzcgvMbcP5 <PERSON>Junot Diaz</PERSON> withdraws from writers festival after allegations https t co sLDkBk1G6j https t co WzsKVLU0Ig Two top <ORGANIZATION>FBI</ORGANIZATION> officials who worked with <PERSON>James Comey</PERSON> leave the bureau report says https t co th7VYb9px3 https t co wD1tIvC9Q7 <PERSON>Warren Buffett</PERSON> s <ORGANIZATION>Berkshire Hathaway</ORGANIZATION> makes a huge bet on <ORGANIZATION>Apple</ORGANIZATION> https t co vXrgq7AoxJ https t co r8cM6pnkTU <LOCATION>Prince Louis</LOCATION> photos <LOCATION>Kensington Palace</LOCATION> releases first official pictures of newborn https t co ZNaBstaNTt https t co kIakVh6duF Tourist found dead in <LOCATION>India</LOCATION> over a month after she went missing https t co 7AqnF7y9Ha https t co K5i2AMBkWO <PERSON>Joe Biden Lindsey Graham</PERSON> visit <PERSON>John McCain</PERSON> while he recovers from surgery https t co W7gD9kTSX0 https t co g7NEYnvfYH My neck s bleeding Young mom s gruesome injury confounds first responders https t co EzUvCIZL6X https t co 55AKo1pPqj Video Cuffed defendant runs from court flips over 2nd story railing https t co mwnJk2d7UE https t co 0o5UcO7H1y It burns man <LOCATION>Georgia</LOCATION> man says during execution for killing prison guard https t co jly8VPpaYi https t co Z6SK5FrLDl Nurse charged after allegedly exposing patients to Hep C with needles she used for drugs https t co ByfJLHzr9L https t co y1Gs4szZGA <LOCATION>Hawaii Kilauea</LOCATION> volcano eruption Lava flows toxic gas show no signs of slowing down https t co mTFnIRT9JN https t co RgWklVehHc <PERSON>Alex Ferguson</PERSON> ex <ORGANIZATION>Manchester United</ORGANIZATION> manager undergoes emergency surgery for brain hemorrhage https t co JqKeefPVGO Rodan Fields hit with suit over eyelash enhancer https t co DkhribohMv https t co DQKootH9iI The big seven races that will probably decide who controls the <ORGANIZATION>Senate</ORGANIZATION> https t co JPtL0ahOwk https t co cfYwn02Ljp 16 year Terre Haute police veteran killed in shootout with homicide suspect https t co 1swvd8otqr https t co aP9jblj1lu With just about two weeks until the big day <PERSON>Meghan Markle</PERSON> and Prince <PERSON>Harry</PERSON> are putting the finishing touches on th https t co rjPikUWh6t The Kentucky Derby gets underway soon at the historic <LOCATION>Churchill Downs</LOCATION> in <LOCATION>Louisville Kentucky</LOCATION> Here s how you can w https t co GOxxs8xaDs Russians angered by the impending inauguration of <PERSON>Vladimir Putin</PERSON> to a new term as president protested Saturday in s https t co HbjM9y9PEK The <ORGANIZATION>114th Kentucky Derby</ORGANIZATION> will go down as the wettest on record as the <ORGANIZATION>National Weather Service</ORGANIZATION> announces there is a https t co NLJtBu4sQM <LOCATION>Florida</LOCATION> woman wakes up with flying cockroach in her ear Feeling a roach in the throes of death lodged in a very https t co 7zucgyZ1CA Man who opened fire on <LOCATION>Sutherland Springs</LOCATION> shooter honored at <ORGANIZATION>NRA</ORGANIZATION> convention https t co KHHKJUIl3a https t co yokBgfqwoT It burns man <LOCATION>Georgia</LOCATION> man says during execution for killing prison guard https t co aI6sDyuulE https t co o5pWgQAU9T Those joining the festivities at <ORGANIZATION>Churchill Downs</ORGANIZATION> on Saturday will experience tighter security measures at the 2018 https t co m1oeJ5DKK6 The Kentucky Derby the Most Exciting Two Minutes in Sports gets underway at 6 34 p m ET Here s what you n https t co RkyMBiFy7M In <LOCATION>Cleveland</LOCATION> President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> touted the <ORGANIZATION>GOP</ORGANIZATION> tax law ahead of the 2018 midterm elections https t co YVb3HFeZQo https t co 38MjF76ebm <PERSON>Rudy Giuliani</PERSON> speaks his mind on <LOCATION>Iran</LOCATION> deal and hostages in <LOCATION>North Korea</LOCATION> at <LOCATION>Iran</LOCATION> freedom conference https t co gRZ6AQAvQQ WATCH <PERSON>Rudy Giuliani</PERSON> is giving remarks at the <ORGANIZATION>Iran Freedom Convention</ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION>Washington</LOCATION> D C https t co 0cyq0e7Msa https t co Ojx14KWgGq Battling brain cancer at his family ranch <PERSON>Sen John McCain</PERSON> urges former Vice President <PERSON>Joe Biden</PERSON> not to walk away https t co BxcW0VSvIq A 14 foot statue of Communist philosopher <PERSON>Karl Marx</PERSON> was unveiled on the 200th anniversary of his birth in the Germ https t co v7YrbR28rK A <LOCATION>Kansas</LOCATION> man who opened fire last year in a suburban <LOCATION>Kansas City</LOCATION> bar killing an immigrant from <LOCATION>India</LOCATION> was sentence https t co NtZOPWydMW Could <LOCATION>Lagos Nigeria</LOCATION> be the next <LOCATION>Silicon Valley</LOCATION> One tech firm is creating another kind of opportunity for young https t co Lq0J1Uxhr0 The estate of <PERSON>David</PERSON> and <PERSON>Peggy Rockefeller</PERSON> goes up for auction next week and some are calling it the sale of the https t co nLeLuDBgip We are fixing and building walls but we need much more money and we are doing the job President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> says We https t co iklwdAWYL6 We are doing very well on as you know <LOCATION>North Korea</LOCATION> We will see what happens but we have a meeting set up We ha https t co Jx4OCJ6dEm WATCH LIVE President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> is pushing the benefits of the <ORGANIZATION>GOP</ORGANIZATION> tax overhaul at a roundtable with business leaders i https t co PbCmu8KRQD There were 30 active shooter situations in 2017 which is more than any year previously recorded according to a ne https t co FEMyfVnwfY Indian police arrest 14 people suspected of kidnapping raping and burning to death a teenage girl https t co 1XEeFGFVMI <PERSON>Albert Pujols</PERSON> becomes 32nd member of 3 000 hit club with hit against the <ORGANIZATION>Seattle Mariners</ORGANIZATION> https t co Q3W9icHGAE https t co TVC0cgu1mB In <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> nationwide protests have erupted as <PERSON>Vladimir Putin</PERSON> prepares to begin his sixth presidential term Hundre https t co uhuukVMbIG In the last year <PERSON>Mitch Landrieu</PERSON> has built a national profile that many political observers think could lead to a pr https t co vobjGc8IV5 President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> is in <LOCATION>Cleveland</LOCATION> today After a closed meeting with supporters there he s expected to participate i https t co 9REGtoZTcZ The <ORGANIZATION>Kentucky Derby</ORGANIZATION> gets underway Saturday at historic <LOCATION>Churchill Downs</LOCATION> in <LOCATION>Louisville Kentucky</LOCATION> Here s how you can w https t co 7J3b8rX7WU Amid rising tensions with <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> the <ORGANIZATION>Pentagon</ORGANIZATION> announces official launch of a new naval command that will bolster t https t co XvxsSKiffq Two key <ORGANIZATION>FBI</ORGANIZATION> aides who worked closely with fired former <ORGANIZATION>FBI</ORGANIZATION> Director <PERSON>James Comey</PERSON> have left the <ORGANIZATION>FBI</ORGANIZATION> according to The https t co lnXdfTrIyT WATCH Lava could be seen reaching houses on Friday after <LOCATION>Kilauea</LOCATION> volcano erupted on <LOCATION>Hawaii</LOCATION> s <LOCATION>Big Island</LOCATION> sending m https t co lsVFmOVI74 <LOCATION>Cambridge Analytica</LOCATION> has been ordered to release all the personal information and data it has on an American voter https t co 6c1V3s0tWC At least three people are dead after severe weather swept across the upper <LOCATION>Midwest</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Canada</LOCATION> on Friday https t co yej60xyVOD The southern part of <LOCATION>Hawaii</LOCATION> s <LOCATION>Big Island</LOCATION> has been jolted by strong earthquakes sputtering lava and toxic gas as ma https t co 0Ob9xrhT0D An Atlas 5 rocket boosted a robotic <LOCATION>Mars</LOCATION> lander into space Saturday the first step in a 171 day voyage to the red https t co mkSD8KpQYH Russian police detain opposition leader <PERSON>Alexei Navalny</PERSON> at a demonstration against President <PERSON>Vladimir Putin</PERSON> in centr https t co akbWCKvNGv <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> wants <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> to cut trade deficit by 200 billion by 2020 https t co U2vrhwf0TA https t co 2sQP96BKBb <PERSON>Rudy Giuliani</PERSON> releases statement to clarify his remarks on <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> https t co G0Tpv3voKM https t co f4iQ7wneC5 <LOCATION>Hawaii</LOCATION> rattled by quakes as <LOCATION>Kilauea</LOCATION> volcano spews lava and toxic gas https t co 57hwGnqQJW https t co 8848q7QThM Mom found dead with 3 kids in N D home may have struggled with finances https t co hu3FV6Junx https t co WxjGDWF6cg A year after failed Obamacare repeal vote Democrats see election cudgel https t co RMdhJHBn18 https t co KEyXwaoZMX <ORGANIZATION>NASA</ORGANIZATION> s InSight lander readies for launch to <LOCATION>Mars</LOCATION> https t co Q4rWprBZc6 https t co 6dbUS19QNm How to watch the 2018 <ORGANIZATION>Kentucky Derby Start</ORGANIZATION> time live stream and odds https t co jw0LS25Jex https t co 0TsOxaf08l <ORGANIZATION>NASA</ORGANIZATION> launches InSight lander toward <LOCATION>Mars</LOCATION> https t co 0t3omAuge0 https t co gXW7jVRPWl <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> says U S has a date location for <LOCATION>North Korea</LOCATION> meeting https t co bIuIdE8TQU https t co caYFjqNPfE <PERSON>Albert Pujols</PERSON> becomes 32nd member of 3 000 hit club with hit against <ORGANIZATION>Mariners</ORGANIZATION> https t co Zjyw4Kat7k https t co jC17Liq6tU Police called on two Native American students taking college tour https t co SHE3HsQDjZ https t co tfZglnh7pO Top Democrat calls for investigation into <PERSON>Stormy Daniels</PERSON> payment https t co 3w0tiyWWdx https t co jLy0X1xKYh <ORGANIZATION>Vogue Italia</ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON>Gigi Hadid</PERSON> apologize for darkened skin tone on cover https t co cwBWrU8l7Y https t co GyxP1qUVzz <LOCATION>Iowa</LOCATION> abortion bill signed into law by Gov <PERSON>Kim Reynolds</PERSON> https t co jU8poSvxUf https t co WZNZRgKGZr Elon Musk isn t backing down despite weird remarks in <LOCATION>Tesla</LOCATION> call https t co Ox0nSG7Z1d https t co Ocl3QMVU9O Waymo self driving SUV involved in crash in <LOCATION>Chandler Arizona</LOCATION> https t co twVau57LpL https t co 4F8N7rSjLh Nurse charged after allegedly exposing patients to Hep C with needles she used for drugs https t co TCGzCjt4LH https t co oECoeyRde2 <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> booked himself for his first TV interview in months https t co Ce2b0M0QNT https t co 3ZDsJZR2V5 Vice president <PERSON>Mike Pence</PERSON> s doctor resigning https t co j0DXunnMjs https t co 359zbEyG8x Palace reportedly worried about sex scene in Lifetime movie <PERSON>Harry</PERSON> amp amp <PERSON>Meghan</PERSON> https t co FUUAx7xO2a https t co mAQrxyF0Ox Sex offender in custody days after leading police on RV chase https t co qHhbANGerG https t co vYsEtIRTda <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> denies pointing powerful lasers at U S aircraft https t co rwi6Dh0ApV https t co UMEF9CxzFb <LOCATION>Georgia</LOCATION> inmate scheduled for execution in 1996 slaying of off duty prison guard https t co bRMNA0aPGt https t co RO1rppV9dD <ORGANIZATION>New York Mets</ORGANIZATION> cutting ties with pitcher <PERSON>Matt Harvey</PERSON> after he refuses demotion to minors https t co V2ivdO7gJT https t co e2RLrEemq1 More charges filed against dad accused of shackling some of his 13 children https t co ZfrolfTFOe https t co vkp5bHbPt7 <ORGANIZATION>Amazon</ORGANIZATION> plays hardball with <LOCATION>Seattle</LOCATION> over eat the rich tax https t co Sb7EDma4o9 https t co DfUgUfuJWp <PERSON>Diana Alvarez</PERSON> case Missing girl s mother sobs as suspect is charged with murder https t co gBFm6Recy5 https t co BV16PSJMX3 Sex scandal scuttles 2018 Nobel Prize in literature https t co VYSVtgDqfX https t co nPZZ8BqCnY <ORGANIZATION>White House Pentagon</ORGANIZATION> deny report that <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> ordered options for pulling troops from <LOCATION>South Korea</LOCATION> https t co wyYxP5aQGl 132 pound tumor removed from woman s abdomen https t co BKIY4Y58zR https t co UVsOeYhx6G 3 black D C students face racist backlash in <ORGANIZATION>NASA</ORGANIZATION> competition get grant https t co AbRM2Hxs8D https t co X49PzveESu Royal wedding <PERSON>Meghan Markle</PERSON> s parents and <PERSON>Diana</PERSON> s sisters to have roles https t co Y5bCYmZyot https t co W6SjQXCA6y <PERSON>James Comey</PERSON> weighs in on dangerous <PERSON>Giuliani</PERSON> comments <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> probe https t co NAL2acYXRA https t co nN0OcohIYo Nurse charged after allegedly exposing patients to Hep C with needles she used for drugs https t co AEpxaAthGH https t co tIvlvltdRv Earthquakes rock <LOCATION>Hawaii</LOCATION> s <LOCATION>Big Island</LOCATION> as <LOCATION>Kilauea</LOCATION> volcano erupts https t co I5H1Qa5LRe https t co 1KzoGHjul8 Mom found dead with 3 kids in N D home may have struggled with finances https t co Sp6ryGsltg https t co JhwPeit9tX Police called on two Native American students taking college tour https t co NOrcXwPFLg https t co i60PhN2JZH Video captures man jumping on school bus in middle of <LOCATION>Massachusetts Turnpike</LOCATION> https t co HSoP5jiMbk https t co <ORGANIZATION>RiSah6SykI Southwest</ORGANIZATION> captain initially wanted to land crippled plane at different airport https t co jlAswF61Pp https t co wTtatnYSbH My neck s bleeding Young mom s gruesome injury confounds first responders https t co A9HKzpALwn https t co nTMiI17D1c <LOCATION>Florida</LOCATION> woman wakes up with flying cockroach in her ear https t co NrsNZDeRP4 https t co rL8bnGvPAl Woman who kidnapped newborn and raised child as her own apologizes https t co MxvdK5H6SY https t co rwkCafxSxT It burns man <LOCATION>Georgia</LOCATION> man says during execution for killing prison guard https t co r64ZwTxhsv https t co OSx9oAUrsu Rodan Fields hit with suit over eyelash enhancer https t co E2Kb06whKw https t co ppGHg6Yygz More Americans are going without health insurance https t co fo9aBM7JMd https t co TrrdMWLqKG <PERSON>Biden Graham</PERSON> visit <PERSON>John McCain</PERSON> while he recovers from surgery https t co xvWoO29XLA https t co 9A3rpmy1sv Tourist found dead in <LOCATION>India</LOCATION> over a month after she went missing https t co wq3fCwhPkl https t co jK3oJW2E8z Man who opened fire on <LOCATION>Sutherland Springs</LOCATION> shooter honored at <ORGANIZATION>NRA</ORGANIZATION> convention https t co 7dPxBfCG9f https t co <ORGANIZATION>EEChQcZJEM In Young Storytellers</ORGANIZATION> mentorship organization imaginations come to life with the help of <LOCATION>Hollywood</LOCATION> professionals https t co U8fAR3WDED We are hopeful the son of one of the Americans detained in <LOCATION>North Korea</LOCATION> says as President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> touts his admini https t co FXvddjz6MR What one city did to fight high drug prices reveals a drug supply chain in which just about every link can benefit https t co LIbcMbKRJq Self driving SUV operated by <PERSON>Waymo</PERSON> involved in a collision in <LOCATION>Chandler Arizona</LOCATION> authorities say https t co uQrM7TRiqY Four year old <PERSON>Austin Perine</PERSON> is <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> s latest superhero and the only superhero with the power to feed the home https t co LyLro20yZ8 On CBSSunday <PERSON>Kesha</PERSON> says she has always felt like an outcast but feels she s gotten her life back through her new https t co opATUlMVxV <LOCATION>California</LOCATION> s economy has surpassed that of the <LOCATION>United Kingdom</LOCATION> to become the world s fifth largest https t co 99ANrrXNvH <LOCATION>Hawaii</LOCATION> s most active volcano <LOCATION>Kilauea</LOCATION> is erupting with a fury and residents on the <LOCATION>Big Island</LOCATION> are now being war https t co kUO6VWT8IW <ORGANIZATION>ATF</ORGANIZATION> agent shot in the face on <LOCATION>Chicago</LOCATION> s <LOCATION>South Side</LOCATION> is part of special force combating illegal guns https t co MLH5J7aYMk President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> who currently has no <ORGANIZATION>White House</ORGANIZATION> communications director booked himself for his first television https t co ZCgJiJFmAh MORE Two earthquakes rock <LOCATION>Hawaii</LOCATION> s <LOCATION>Big Island</LOCATION> on Friday as eruptions at the <LOCATION>Kilauea</LOCATION> volcano continue https t co A9iidxcDYA As other cities lobby to bring <LOCATION>Amazon</LOCATION> to town the retailer is finding less love these days in <LOCATION>Seattle</LOCATION> https t co b8v4KXTkWS <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> administration to end special immigration protections for about 57 000 Hondurans after a devastating hurrican https t co pEbrYikzdd RT CBSEveningNews There s a tiny superhero with a special gift for capturing the hearts of the homeless in <LOCATION>Alabama</LOCATION> <PERSON>Steve Hartman</PERSON> caught RT CBSEveningNews It s one thing to walk into your kitchen feeling hungry as a bear but quite another to find an actual bear on your coun RT CBSEveningNews Nearly 3 months after the Parkland shooting students who support gun rights are raising their voices There were walko Authorities in <LOCATION>Chicago</LOCATION> in midst of conducting raid as adrianasdiaz reported on manhunt underway just after 3 a m https t co H8qpFPHnDv Another reason the rate dropped was more than 200 000 people left the labor force meaning they retired or went ba https t co 6w8DlDMmBO <PERSON>Rudy Giuliani</PERSON> had to walk back most of the news he made on a recent media blitz as President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> s newest persona https t co TeEsXR7DNr As the <LOCATION>Kilauea</LOCATION> volcano erupted on <LOCATION>Hawaii</LOCATION> s <LOCATION>Big Island</LOCATION> molten lava and ash spewed hundreds of feet into the air and https t co EaN4EiESUB RT CBSEveningNews We re on the air in the East JeffGlor is live from Studio 57 in <LOCATION>NYC Thanks</LOCATION> for being with us <ORGANIZATION>OriginalReporting CBSE New York Mets</ORGANIZATION> are cutting ties with struggling pitcher <PERSON>Matt Harvey</PERSON> designating him for assignment after he refused https t co VuLK9e0HUe <PERSON>James Comey</PERSON> on if the <ORGANIZATION>FBI</ORGANIZATION> sees climate change as a national security threat There s a counter intelligence threa https t co lDcx7GXaGL DEVELOPING 5 6 magnitude earthquake rocks <LOCATION>Hawaii</LOCATION> s <LOCATION>Big Island</LOCATION> as eruptions at the <LOCATION>Kilauea</LOCATION> volcano continue https t co TzWzna9F0A After being dropped from <ORGANIZATION>Amazon</ORGANIZATION> s Transparent <PERSON>Jeffrey Tambor</PERSON> will appear on season five of Arrested Development https t co ZcFs0XjfPK <PERSON>Kennedy</PERSON> cousin <PERSON>Michael Skakel</PERSON> s murder conviction vacated by <ORGANIZATION>Connecticut Supreme Court</ORGANIZATION> new trial ordered in connec https t co IzPGN3jycq <PERSON>Comey</PERSON> on how <ORGANIZATION>FBI</ORGANIZATION> protects communities People of different faiths of different genders of different orientatio https t co 5xtdRRwpFN The foods women eat could be tied to their risk of infertility a new study finds https t co ltrpA61Go6 https t co cLEH3eHZBv <PERSON>Comey</PERSON> on the teachings of Reinhold Nieburhr You ll never achieve pure love in this world the closest you can g https t co Io6oSHf3gB New eruptions from <LOCATION>Hawaii</LOCATION> s <LOCATION>Kilauea Volcano</LOCATION> have damaged at least two homes local authorities say 1 500 people ha https t co LbIaUFHvD2 Close your eyes Republicans and imagine <PERSON>Barack Obama</PERSON> doing that And so we can t become numb to it I can t beco https t co WNLeC8nc9A Six week abortion ban to be signed into law in <LOCATION>Iowa</LOCATION> governor says it would mark the strictest abortion restrictio https t co AMPt5Ivcfb After whirlwind press tour <PERSON>Rudy Giuliani</PERSON> releases statement to clarify the views he s expressed about Pres Trum https t co NawtNZb7IV <PERSON>Pres Trump</PERSON> at <ORGANIZATION>NRA</ORGANIZATION> convention Our entire nation was filled with shock and grief by the monstrous attack on a high https t co ZRNb1wAfYy <PERSON>Pres Trump</PERSON> at <ORGANIZATION>NRA</ORGANIZATION> convention <PERSON>John Kerry</PERSON> was not the best negotiator we ve ever seen He never walked away from https t co CeisRDO8yP WATCH LIVE Pres Trump addresses annual <ORGANIZATION>NRA</ORGANIZATION> convention in <LOCATION>Dallas Texas</LOCATION> https t co RXuv2RT3sl https t co ZYxMq6e02l <PERSON>Gigi Hadid</PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION>Vogue Italia</ORGANIZATION> apologize after the magazine s cover featured the supermodel with a darkened skin tone https t co FgUsYy9FXQ Federal judge asks skeptical questions about special counsel <PERSON>Robert Mueller</PERSON> s authority to bring charges against Pa https t co YzHlZ3l3SD <LOCATION>Georgia</LOCATION> is preparing to execute a man Friday evening who was convicted of robbing and killing an off duty prison gu https t co T7O9ceLcdp Mom found dead with 3 kids in <LOCATION>North Dakota</LOCATION> home may have struggled with finances court records show https t co 91KihpfW9v A year after a failed Obamacare repeal vote Democrats see an election cudgel https t co b5OqrskaVi https t co pHPcUhRWL0 Two Native American students were taking an admissions tour at <ORGANIZATION>Colorado State University</ORGANIZATION> when a parent on the tour https t co tdRSKkhCvI An Atlas 5 rocket is poised for launch from <LOCATION>California</LOCATION> on Saturday to send a robotic lander to <LOCATION>Mars</LOCATION> the centerpiec https t co OIP7Ooz2qg Federal judge asks skeptical questions about special counsel <PERSON>Robert Mueller</PERSON> s authority to bring charges against <ORGANIZATION>Pa</ORGANIZATION> https t co 5aQ1APBijb If <PERSON>Elon Musk</PERSON> has any regrets about dissing some pesky stock analysts in a call this week to discuss <PERSON>Tesla</PERSON> s latest https t co etoTHsMbwa President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> says U S has a date location for <LOCATION>North Korea</LOCATION> meeting https t co alrMEaNGEk https t co HAJYdb3Ome President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> on <PERSON>Rudy Giuliani</PERSON> He started yesterday He ll get his facts straight He s a great guy https t co WdUqWvi2fX <ORGANIZATION>Southwest</ORGANIZATION> captain <PERSON>Tammie Jo Shults</PERSON> initially wanted to land crippled plane at a different airport https t co sNwUv0rq0k A paroled sex offender has been captured two days after he led police on an hours long chase through <LOCATION>Southern Calif</LOCATION> https t co ikKDAr7Ghq <PERSON>James Comey</PERSON> on if <PERSON>Hillary Clinton</PERSON> was fit to be president I ve never met the woman Agents of the <ORGANIZATION>FBI</ORGANIZATION> and ana https t co RqcLRyQYyo I honestly don t the real reason that I was fired I originally took the president at his word when I saw him on T https t co NvjDzQKEmi A spectacular sinkhole the length of two football fields and the depth of a six story building has opened up on a N https t co BYbrFw3AQe <PERSON>Rudy Giuliani</PERSON> we love <PERSON>Rudy</PERSON> he s a special guy what he really understands is that this is a witch hunt Pres https t co fA0vPF1QZf President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> on meeting with <LOCATION>North Korea</LOCATION> We now have a date and we have a location we ll be announcing it soon https t co zB0HPRCciV I would love to speak Nobody wants to speak more than me President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> says on meeting with special counsel R https t co 1Vf6UMp5T3 MOMENTS AGO President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> addresses reporters on his way to <ORGANIZATION>NRA</ORGANIZATION> speech in <LOCATION>Dallas</LOCATION> https t co JseDI9SPqQ https t co 3wYlaPGyrR Singer songwriter kesharose always felt like an outcast but she feels she s gotten her life back through her new https t co JTf5veYwfv RT vladduthiersCBS Coming up on CBSNews CBSN my one on one interview with former <ORGANIZATION>FBI</ORGANIZATION> Director <PERSON>James Comey</PERSON> Watch it here https t c Two days of high winds and heavy rainfall have left more than 120 people dead in northern <LOCATION>India</LOCATION> and officials warn https t co x4433pHzg6 <PERSON>Blake Anderson</PERSON> does not care what the critics think especially not when he s having fun with his former Workaholi https t co iG6XzjSuGi Hard numbers 15 of Tunisians say their local economy is improving while 50 say it s getting worse https t co oE4iRmX5CV <LOCATION>India</LOCATION> s prime minister says all of the country s villages now have access to power When he took office in 2014 30 https t co vQGgOJLdgs <PERSON>Meghan Markle</PERSON> s parents will come to <LOCATION>London</LOCATION> before her May 19 wedding to Prince <PERSON>Harry</PERSON> and will meet with <PERSON>Queen Eliz</PERSON> https t co YCqn3QTA0m Skincare product company <ORGANIZATION>Rodan Fields</ORGANIZATION> faces a federal class action lawsuit over its eyelash enhancing serum https t co 5akTrmb5gg <PERSON>James Comey</PERSON> says he s proud of the work the <ORGANIZATION>FBI</ORGANIZATION> has done since and hopes people will speak out when the nation https t co 9R1zlGyEzy Founded in 1998 Priceline is one of the original online travel agencies More than a million people visit the site https t co GSgagxUTzr RT CBSThisMorning If I was <PERSON>Bob Mueller</PERSON> I would ask him President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> a whole lot of questions and I would want as much time as I ne The unemployment rate dropped to a 17 year low in April to 3 9 as businesses continued to hire modestly https t co UnYGzOQWnK Video captures man jumping on school bus in middle of <LOCATION>Massachusetts Turnpike</LOCATION> https t co 0cRoa1OzUu https t co kcsIJZEs0n A young wife calls 911 to report she attempted suicide in front of her ex husband and child While clinging to life https t co tfLrctMAYa RT CBSThisMorning What I hope people will do is not get caught down in the back and forth of Twitter personnel and personal conflicts bu RT CBSThisMorning The notion that the <ORGANIZATION>FBI</ORGANIZATION> is made up of <ORGANIZATION>Nazi</ORGANIZATION> storm troopers is just wrong and dangerous I think all of us have to say <PERSON>James Comey</PERSON> on what he d ask President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> We want to understand what his state of mind was I have one vie https t co UCLXHTreU5 What I ve learned is that sometimes the way I see myself is not the way reasonable thoughtful people see me Jam https t co G219Yp4aHu Whatever our vigorous policy disagreements our values are all we have and if our leaders and the people they lead https t co XXOlIlo3SI When our nation s leaders the president or his representatives attack the institutions of justice the rest https t co 1mMoup41ad We re lucky to live in a country where facts matter and that people aren t prosecuted by people tweeting about the https t co WJPFDJmqJl Former <ORGANIZATION>FBI</ORGANIZATION> Director <PERSON>James Comey</PERSON> s new book A Higher Loyalty Truth Lies and Leadership is now a <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> Tim https t co Yqtf13yYFo A <LOCATION>Wisconsin</LOCATION> high schooler is fighting to wear shirts with images of guns to school https t co tqeeyrRGZ9 https t co SjKz9ArkDY RT CBSThisMorning Former <ORGANIZATION>FBI</ORGANIZATION> Director <PERSON>James Comey</PERSON> is in Studio 57 he ll just next on CBSThisMorning <ORGANIZATION>CBS</ORGANIZATION> 8 a m https t co PWYTa A <LOCATION>Wisconsin</LOCATION> high schooler is fighting to wear shirts with images of guns to school The student says his T shirts r https t co YnvVuUN59R RT CBSThisMorning <LOCATION>Arizona</LOCATION> students are heading back to class this morning after a 6 day walkout by thousands of teachers Twitter A federal <ORGANIZATION>ATF</ORGANIZATION> agent was shot in the head and critically wounded during an operation in <LOCATION>Chicago</LOCATION> https t co 2zIgLMBfEt Sen <PERSON>John McCain</PERSON> says he doesn t know how much longer he has to live but is prepared for what s ahead The 81 year https t co e7RmpeRF5j A new DNA technology used to track down the alleged Golden State Killer could help identify another infamous serial https t co yhBAqUUVTT The <ORGANIZATION>Washington Post</ORGANIZATION> is signaling there may be more revelations about what <ORGANIZATION>CBS News</ORGANIZATION> knew about claims of inappropria https t co II9aRodyrU 3 black D C students who faced racist comments when they used social media to encourage voting for them in a <ORGANIZATION>NASA</ORGANIZATION> https t co VipN6aKWU1 The <ORGANIZATION>White House</ORGANIZATION> says it would be a goodwill gesture if <LOCATION>North Korea</LOCATION> releases the three Americans it s holding prison https t co pa03KFlYo9 RT CBSThisMorning <PERSON>Rudy Giuliani</PERSON> criticized former <ORGANIZATION>FBI</ORGANIZATION> Director <PERSON>James Comey</PERSON> yesterday Ahead at 8am <PERSON>Comey</PERSON> will be in Studio 57 respondin Military investigators are trying to learn why a C 130 cargo plane being flown to retirement suddenly plunged to https t co hJOHUn3YF5 Father <PERSON>Patrick Conroy</PERSON> the <ORGANIZATION>House</ORGANIZATION> chaplain who had been forced out by Speaker <PERSON>Paul Ryan</PERSON> will now stay on the job I https t co 0z2KxIA2Zl The <ORGANIZATION>White House</ORGANIZATION> is in damage control over news that <PERSON>Pres Trump</PERSON> reimbursed <PERSON>Michael Cohen</PERSON> for the 130K he paid Stor https t co IZbgV5UeuI Lava is pouring from one of <LOCATION>Hawaii</LOCATION> s largest volcanoes forcing around 1 700 people to evacuate the area The massi https t co MRrsn9qHJd In this week s <ORGANIZATION>TakeoutPodcast White House</ORGANIZATION> legislative affairs director <PERSON>Marc Short</PERSON> tells MajorCBS he thinks there https t co 6WhEtpYORU RT CBSThisMorning WATCH A quick preview of what s next on CBSThisMorning See you at 7 https t co yADRGs4TKY AHEAD CBSThisMorning is tracking the volcanic eruption that is forcing nearly 2 000 people from their homes on th https t co EIdpQFQVMl The Nobel Prize in literature will be not awarded this year following sex abuse allegations and other issues that h https t co ZIdOSzmpCP Former <ORGANIZATION>FBI</ORGANIZATION> Director <PERSON>James Comey</PERSON> will be in CBSThisMorning s Studio 57 this morning He ll respond to criticism fr https t co n24tgp0mJ7 Nearly 1 500 residents were ordered to evacuate after <LOCATION>Hawaii</LOCATION> s <LOCATION>Kilauea Volcano</LOCATION> erupted sending molten lava to chew https t co 7iziBnUZMb <PERSON>Tesla</PERSON> slammed after <PERSON>Elon Musk</PERSON> spurns not cool questions https t co oQJbPY3pmU https t co ugo93fGuty <LOCATION>Hawaii</LOCATION> volcano erupts spews lava high in air into subdivision https t co dVl1VwhBnZ https t co MxklNIN7qg <PERSON>Kevin Hart</PERSON> says he s in disbelief about extortion charges against friend <PERSON>Jonathan Todd Jackson</PERSON> https t co 8853IuWRT4 Prosecutors Driver who had seizure killed 2 kids was warned by doctor not to drive https t co UXt4w1Br41 https t co <ORGANIZATION>qZHBHwUOLe Malaysia Airlines</ORGANIZATION> Flight 370 search fails but sonar hunt may solve shipwreck mysteries https t co T3EVnqoxNb https t co AXDgUzaHkZ Golden State Killer case Judge allows more of DeAngelo s DNA to be collected https t co uJEQDW0ii7 https t co 5oejJZMH8F Plane crash video shows <ORGANIZATION>National Guard</ORGANIZATION> C 130 aircraft plunging to ground https t co XzD0vRyOfw https t co T0m74QB5au <PERSON>Rudy Giuliani</PERSON> s whirlwind 24 hours The unusual comments he s made to the press https t co LqsNfM3ZwN https t co 8mu0hOUzYc Sex scandal scuttles 2018 Nobel Prize in literature https t co bH3zUxU2qT https t co pQSBu9mUeX Parent 3 children found dead in <LOCATION>Grand Forks North Dakota</LOCATION> home school officials say https t co 8vI8wRDmCO https t co FvGUlTpSh1 Pill expiration dates can have wiggle room if stored right https t co d1aldmtJSj https t co 3jOD1mqXUo Human feces found on high school track on a daily basis suspect is a school superintendent https t co 6aydDTuTP2 Tinder Fire in <LOCATION>Arizona</LOCATION> destroys dozens of homes and buildings https t co PDTmFdn4oV https t co 2U3ra8s9me Officials Co worker fatally stabs contractor at airport in dispute over light https t co qDeD0F5S2O https t co DbSsEpukt7 <PERSON>Paulina Porizkova Ric Ocasek</PERSON> announce split https t co ZjWTYcDLIC https t co uN09YUD4X7 U S freezes funding for <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> s White Helmets https t co Omc6tccpB5 https t co OMrdAxnOnE <PERSON>Sandra Bullock</PERSON> s stalker found dead after standoff with SWAT team https t co ACafL5SKhl https t co DxK8fcvOqx President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> signs order to protect religious freedom establishes new <LOCATION>White House</LOCATION> faith initiative https t co GUmZhScqhd Will Kelly <PERSON>Slater</PERSON> s artificial wave machine change surfing as we know it https t co 03TF0KlJkY https t co cD37z5nMvv 2 ex <ORGANIZATION>Temple University</ORGANIZATION> cops guilty of beating woman to death in diabolical torture chamber https t co Bu4PIStEkQ https t co uEqvf4jrie Rescuers to submit bill for hiker reported missing then found at luxury hotel https t co 9vcHo4JnTB https t co 4D1lZvqbnr A movie scene Brinks truck drops hundreds of thousands of dollars on <LOCATION>Indiana</LOCATION> highway https t co sILglXaHaH https t co lVRX3rr1eB Frat chapter suspended in wake of student s deadly fall from party bus https t co SYLZeZCtPU https t co l7wNKEDKWu Denim brand debuts extreme cut out jeans for 168 and the internet can t believe it https t co qUM8GFS8Qv https t co yMHaZQZghM Is there a legal strategy behind <PERSON>Rudy Giuliani</PERSON> s comments about the Stormy Daniels payment https t co wZzObYE519 https t co tdJ8jTdtjE <ORGANIZATION>Malaysia Airlines</ORGANIZATION> Flight 370 search fails but sonar hunt may solve shipwreck mysteries https t co xKK3xNlFbj https t co 2BVrtOsi1P <LOCATION>Hawaii</LOCATION> s <LOCATION>Kilauea</LOCATION> volcano Fountains of lava reported evacuations ordered https t co AXCu8gXKCE https t co rOciRTVKea <PERSON>Kevin Hart</PERSON> says he s in disbelief about extortion charges against friend <PERSON>Jonathan Todd Jackson</PERSON> https t co K42XisoCLh Plane crash video shows <ORGANIZATION>National Guard</ORGANIZATION> C 130 aircraft plunging to ground https t co QlmV3ROEMB https t co vD6DPwAKdH Parent 3 children found dead in <LOCATION>Grand Forks North Dakota</LOCATION> home school officials say https t co FBVEr6BSV9 https t co yfgEadyDWy <ORGANIZATION>ACLU</ORGANIZATION> national director calls <ORGANIZATION>NRA</ORGANIZATION> tactics model worthy of emulation https t co bgOLntrthR https t co ELG4Je2wif Human feces found on high school track on a daily basis suspect is a school superintendent https t co crpQgU2Aqo Greitens impeachment to be considered by lawmakers in special session https t co aeKk0JBR5C https t co oaF0uoi0jZ Officials Co worker fatally stabs contractor at airport in dispute over light https t co jjetsJ7Uea https t co CCnKaskLtJ Fire breaks out at chemical plant in <LOCATION>Louisiana</LOCATION> prompting evacuations live updates https t co AtwXN1OH4t https t co wxOn7bP20i Driver who had a seizure and crashed her car into a <LOCATION>Brooklyn</LOCATION> sidewalk killing two children was arrested on mansla https t co VMCL3OHjjH Investors continue to hammer <PERSON>Tesla</PERSON> a day after founder Elon Musk dumbfounded some on Wall Street by cutting off wh https t co uGGY6oxv5d Millions still under severe weather threat as storm winds down in central U S https t co 4j1uiHw5Gh https t co 6bvLD4puWq At least two people have been wounded in a shooting at an apartment complex in <LOCATION>Mill Valley California</LOCATION> police say https t co HCzSArD5Nq Actress <PERSON>Rose McGowan</PERSON> will face indictment in <LOCATION>Virginia</LOCATION> on a felony drug possession charge after a judge found probab https t co O3Y3fvwdUD Many Americans are lonely and younger adults appear to be the hardest hit new report finds https t co HsteIHyXfI Students across the country staged another walkout over guns but this time it was in support of the Second Amen https t co IUJ92w76eC Golden State Killer case opens possibility of using DNA in other notorious cold cases https t co VnpxAOaqbb https t co YEAavo4cc8 Sen <PERSON>John McCain</PERSON> has harsh words for President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> in emotional new memoir https t co GKTeTXTKhi https t co 6RF4LVXqwE President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> no longer denies knowing about payment to adult film star Stormy Daniels https t co 9gQqulIis9 https t co d6UGuRcaHL RT CBSEveningNews This is an anniversary day for the CBSEveningNews 70 years ago this evening May 3 1948 the <ORGANIZATION>CBS</ORGANIZATION> TV news debuted a An analysis of accident data obtained by the <ORGANIZATION>Military Times</ORGANIZATION> found a nearly 40 percent increase in accidents between https t co W0e8LFKmfu Engineers are taking the most detailed look at the <LOCATION>Golden Gate Bridge</LOCATION> since it opened https t co l4NOE6zwi8 https t co 1UO8pjtRDu A DNA match on a genealogy website led to the arrest of the suspected <ORGANIZATION>Golden State Killer</ORGANIZATION> which now has investigat https t co hmChQcUHfy New allegations of sexual harassment against former <ORGANIZATION>CBS</ORGANIZATION> news correspondent <PERSON>Charlie Rose</PERSON> have surfaced The Washingt https t co Bme4mSURtK The military cargo plane that crashed and killed nine in <LOCATION>Georgia</LOCATION> had just completed routine maintenance The cause https t co LmFwmVAk7H Shoppers and workers ran for their lives in <LOCATION>Nashville</LOCATION> when shots were fired inside a mall That led to a large poli https t co o6eqvi9M9P Two federal officials tell <ORGANIZATION>CBS News</ORGANIZATION> there are no wiretaps there are no transcripts there are no phone recordings https t co lBlR4e3y4i POTUS denies the affair with adult film star <PERSON>Stormy Daniels</PERSON> but no longer denies knowledge of the 130K payment https t co 8UzRjn15FQ RT CBSEveningNews WATCH We re on the air in the East JeffGlor is live from Studio 57 in <LOCATION>NYC Thanks</LOCATION> for being with us <ORGANIZATION>OriginalReportin Arizona</ORGANIZATION> governor signs plan Thursday to give striking teachers a 20 percent pay raise ending their five day walkou https t co 99djo3QbJh I want the <ORGANIZATION>Justice Department</ORGANIZATION> to close this thing down <PERSON>Pres Trump</PERSON> s newest lawyer former <LOCATION>New York City</LOCATION> Mayor R https t co N4fJtcpoTP Glitch at Twitter has prompted the social media company to urge its more than 330 million users to consider changin https t co abU7EL5DBh NEW Father <PERSON>Patrick Conroy</PERSON> the <ORGANIZATION>House</ORGANIZATION> chaplain who was controversially ousted from his position rescinds his resig https t co Hui8vnbEbr <LOCATION>Hawaii</LOCATION> will the be the first state to ban sunscreens Here s why they re doing it https t co rCPGbWS5jG https t co eAypVxVeis Jay Z faces subpoena after failing to testify as part of an <ORGANIZATION>SEC</ORGANIZATION> investigation into accounting practices of branding https t co dIt6OKyCrq MNPDNashville says one person shot at mall in <LOCATION>Nashville</LOCATION> suspected gunman is in custody No additional imminent https t co fITmudFvo9 Film Academy votes to expel <PERSON>Bill Cosby</PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION>Roman Polanski</ORGANIZATION> from its membership https t co pnxZITQBrE https t co cdv6aTO7yP DEVELOPING Active shooter reported at mall in <LOCATION>Nashville</LOCATION> https t co 3OdStnxcHG https t co XbJj6UBgKz 40 percent of older Americans still have sex while 54 percent of older couples still do it according to a new pol https t co k9FAGrteHj Today is National Prayer Day a time when Americans are encouraged to turn to God in prayer and meditation https t co RtaRb31T5m The pace of passing new climate change legislation has slowed significantly a new study says https t co fcgLOoVPHV RT CBSThisMorning TOMORROW Former <ORGANIZATION>FBI</ORGANIZATION> Director <PERSON>James Comey</PERSON> will be in Studio 57 He ll react to the latest news on President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> and A teenage boy was brought to tears when a classmate surprised him at his desk with a random act of kindness https t co DeVscROfKH MajorCBS What you have is a scattershot legal strategy that is not coordinated with or in any way sympathetic t https t co ZPL43IRAFh Q How many payments did <PERSON>Pres Trump</PERSON> make to <PERSON>Michael Cohen</PERSON> PressSec You would have to ask the president s o https t co iVIAzDjB2O When you say you gave the best information at the time amp amp it turns out not to be correct or accurate are you then https t co Ln3q0FpHYK Q When did you specifically know that the president repaid Mr <PERSON>Cohen</PERSON> for the 130 000 you personally https t co 2O46ILe0xg Q You said on March 7 there was no knowledge of any payment from the president and that he has denied all of thes https t co SHefqysuSy Q to PressSec When the president or the <ORGANIZATION>White House</ORGANIZATION> shows what appears to be a blatant disregard for the truth https t co ECh0y7QZln ZekeJMiller on Stormy Daniels payment Why the president was not truthful with the American people and with the https t co BpYQpQuXeO WATCH LIVE PressSec <PERSON>Sarah Huckabee Sanders</PERSON> holds briefing after <PERSON>Pres Trump</PERSON> confirms he reimbursed <PERSON>Michael Cohen</PERSON> https t co QtAZRwrplG WATCH A group of smash and grab burglars known across the <LOCATION>Gulf Coast</LOCATION> used a stolen U Haul truck to smash through a https t co aCkLGkYxXk Get the tissues ready After spending 10 months unable to walk a teenage girl surprises her prom date by taking he https t co EBb9ImwQqD <ORGANIZATION>Kroger</ORGANIZATION> supplier recalls 35 000 pounds of ground beef that may contain plastic https t co vGsAlN2Wkz https t co dTrHaFT0Ua A movie scene Brinks truck drops hundreds of thousands of dollars on <LOCATION>Indiana</LOCATION> highway https t co oX4ye6rFyg https t co Bly0KewdGg A four year search of the depths of the <LOCATION>Indian Ocean</LOCATION> fails to find <ORGANIZATION>Malaysia Airlines</ORGANIZATION> Flight 370 but may solve thes https t co UMipQ17yA0 A teenage boy was brought to tears when a classmate surprised him at his desk with a random act of kindness https t co I6qHwSmnGJ Surveillance video captures <ORGANIZATION>National Guard</ORGANIZATION> C 130 aircraft a 1950s era military cargo plane plunging to the ground https t co hqAhtGMSJS More than 35 000 pounds of raw ground beef recalled by <ORGANIZATION>Kroger</ORGANIZATION> supplier after consumer reported hard plastic contami https t co NHoYHDAmRI <PERSON>Michael Avenatti Stormy Daniels</PERSON> lawyer tells CBSThisMorning he is stunned by <PERSON>Giuliani</PERSON> statement on President https t co JzfcV1iBMG A former <ORGANIZATION>White House</ORGANIZATION> staffer was confronted by authorities while lugging boxes into a new apartment The offense h https t co W97NIZe3Pu DEVELOPING Employee stabbed inside <LOCATION>Philadelphia International Airport</LOCATION> terminal on Thursday morning officials say https t co QIqGpSMSZY Denim brand debuts extreme cut out jeans for 168 and the internet can t believe it https t co Viyoq8YLu6 https t co U7xsOPAShh WATCH A fiery explosion rocked a <LOCATION>Connecticut</LOCATION> town while police were negotiating with a man barricaded inside Up t https t co 1xUBr4qMhg It s kind of like when a child tells a lie If they had they just been honest about the data they shared about not https t co iR9xlcvZYf <ORGANIZATION>Cambridge Analytica</ORGANIZATION> is shutting down after the scandal involving 87 million <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> users <ORGANIZATION>Cambridge Analytica</ORGANIZATION> sai https t co <ORGANIZATION>HtwnPtCagh Stormy Daniels</ORGANIZATION> lawyer stunned by <PERSON>Giuliani</PERSON> statement on <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> s hush money reimbursement https t co pSNwMfEsq2 https t co CFfP52NWAe Former <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> campaign adviser <PERSON>Michael Caputo</PERSON> met with special counsel s team https t co pSq99Zb48h https t co rbIrHwKiHl <ORGANIZATION>Washington Redskins</ORGANIZATION> cheerleaders say they were told to pose topless in front of sponsors and felt pimped out as pe https t co cE79lFeWG2 <PERSON>Giuliani Comey</PERSON> was fired because he wouldn t say <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> wasn t a target of <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> probe https t co h8q5kYDvXf https t co o2RsQZiyhu Newly released body cam footage from the night of the <LOCATION>Las Vegas</LOCATION> shooting shows police officers breaching gunman <PERSON>Ste</PERSON> https t co n8qvWNCyuq <PERSON>Bill Cosby</PERSON> s wife breaks her silence after husband s sex assault conviction calls for criminal investigation of pr https t co j099D2K7iQ <ORGANIZATION>Pres Trump</ORGANIZATION> denies paying <PERSON>Stormy Daniels</PERSON> with campaign funds to keep quiet about alleged affair https t co 35LZQQl3x1 <LOCATION>Pennsylvania</LOCATION> governor sets special election to fill the empty seat of resigned U S Rep <PERSON>Patrick Meehan</PERSON> for day of https t co 9eQPRQhLhj 9 tornadoes hit <LOCATION>Midwest</LOCATION> severe weather threatens 40 million across U S https t co KiLtjQznaI https t co BfNuVxUnHN <PERSON>Samira Wiley</PERSON> plays <PERSON>Moira</PERSON> in the hit series the The Handmaid s Tale which was just renewed for a third season The https t co VFrQYeGVGn RT CBSThisMorning In a statement <ORGANIZATION>CBS News</ORGANIZATION> said Since we terminated <PERSON>Charlie Rose</PERSON> we ve worked to strengthen existing systems to ensure RT CBSThisMorning MORE The <ORGANIZATION>Washington Post</ORGANIZATION> reports 27 women include 14 <ORGANIZATION>CBS News</ORGANIZATION> employees said <PERSON>Rose</PERSON> sexually harassed them over a more RT CBSThisMorning This morning the <ORGANIZATION>Washington Post</ORGANIZATION> reports new allegations of sexual misconduct by former CBSThisMorning anchor <PERSON>Charlie</PERSON> Ex Apprentice contestant wants tapes for defamation suit against <ORGANIZATION>Trump</ORGANIZATION> https t co pEoPJtACdu https t co mO23TP3fTr 25 of the world s best professional surfers are converging on an unusual surf spot this weekend of a competition ca https t co dQnM8NLaCA Here are some of this morning s headlines on CBSThisMorning https t co NEh47N3lcU <ORGANIZATION>NIH</ORGANIZATION> wants 1 million people to donate DNA and share their health habits in the name of science The goal is to disco https t co KK0OHKaEVd Lobbyist whose wife rented condo to <PERSON>Scott Pruitt</PERSON> sought <ORGANIZATION>EPA</ORGANIZATION> appointment for client https t co qrsCHI3rIF https t co 1BSaAakfIv <PERSON>Michael Avenatti Stormy Daniels</PERSON> attorney joins CBSThisMorning to discuss I was equally stunned and I was speec https t co heWkrHNDOP President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> s lawyer <PERSON>Rudy Giuliani</PERSON> says the president reimbursed attorney <PERSON>Michel Cohen</PERSON> for a non disclosure a https t co QjI27MASkQ After <ORGANIZATION>CBS News</ORGANIZATION> report on rare eye cancer mystery hundreds share similar stories https t co 0gynphimFl https t co lXSAJvPqPD Doctors are intensifying efforts to find out what caused groups of people in two different cities to mysteriously d https t co O440GJK6wO There is troubling new information about an attack in <LOCATION>Niger</LOCATION> that killed four American soldiers when Islamic militan https t co <ORGANIZATION>GEOPZ3gNGy Southwest Airlines</ORGANIZATION> faces a new federal investigation after the company s second mid air scare in about two weeks A https t co q8dtfKfgn6 Here are three things you should know this morning 1 <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> trade talks 2 <LOCATION>Hawaii</LOCATION> volcano threat 3 Six Flags Autism https t co y3IfiMiArD RT CBSThisMorning AHEAD at <ORGANIZATION>8am Stormy Daniels</ORGANIZATION> lawyer <PERSON>MichaelAvenatti</PERSON> will join us live in Studio 57 to discuss the disclosure and wh <LOCATION>Spain</LOCATION> s <ORGANIZATION>Basque ETA</ORGANIZATION> separatist group has disband after 6 decade fight https t co 3tUneHMfcj https t co VwLYuCbqgo The first death in the nation s growing e coli outbreak is raising new concerns about the source of the contaminate https t co jGdAEXxjH9 A <LOCATION>Texas</LOCATION> teen accused of planning an <ORGANIZATION>ISIS</ORGANIZATION> inspired mass shooting is in jail Prosecutors say the plot by 17 year old https t co CAQR1QFU6O The planned final flight of the 1950s era military cargo plane ended in disaster Video shows the C 130 aircraft ba https t co C2992Sx1jx At least 40 million Americans are under threat of severe weather Nine tornadoes were reported in <LOCATION>Kansas Missouri</LOCATION> https t co 81L1kB0IAO <ORGANIZATION>CBS News</ORGANIZATION> legal analyst rikkijklieman joins CBSThisMorning to discuss <PERSON>Rudy Giuliani</PERSON> s statement that President Tru https t co A1biHlNrAv A startling admission by <PERSON>Rudy Giuliani</PERSON> leaves President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> facing new legal questions about whether he knew abou https t co <ORGANIZATION>cltODbgm8t Redskins</ORGANIZATION> cheerleaders told to pose topless on trip to <LOCATION>Costa Rica</LOCATION> report says https t co Eqp1tblN1J https t co X30Bs3MsBo AHEAD on CBSThisMorning World champion surfer <PERSON>KellySlater</PERSON> shows us how to catch the perfect wave miles from the https t co 5Kp56YQ9vw Person of interest in killing of <LOCATION>Pennsylvania</LOCATION> couple found dead authorities say https t co G2VrtKR2mG https t co u569xKF92G President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> s lawyer <PERSON>Rudy Giuliani</PERSON> contradicts the president s past statement about the payment to <PERSON>Stormy Danie</PERSON> https t co Gkp3yK8RqR President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> reimbursed <PERSON>Michael Cohen</PERSON> 130K for payment to adult film star Stormy Daniels <PERSON>Giuliani</PERSON> says https t co eBgs1wSurX Illegal campfire sparked Tinder Fire in <LOCATION>Arizona</LOCATION> officials say https t co o63tB3qMMG https t co noVdnP4hXC <LOCATION>Spain</LOCATION> s <ORGANIZATION>Basque ETA</ORGANIZATION> separatists disband after 6 decade fight https t co i8PkyOgVze https t co oKAGn1VRyV I want him to burn in hell Man sentenced to death in rape murder of <LOCATION>Fla</LOCATION> girl 8 https t co B6GsNpaNfb https t co 5kOJdc8uQi Will Ferrell and <PERSON>Molly Shannon</PERSON> to cover royal wedding as Cord and <PERSON>Tish</PERSON> for <ORGANIZATION>HBO</ORGANIZATION> https t co Pe8LBiPAdg https t co NwJKYu1Uk8 Hobby Lobby returns thousands of artifacts to <LOCATION>Iraq</LOCATION> https t co iR4zCUamZ4 https t co wBIGAH1PQ5 Conservatives Kanye West follows Who s on the list https t co auRvsqbO6b https t co JRG5G8Drb9 <PERSON>David Goodall</PERSON> 104 year old Australian scientist heads to <LOCATION>Switzerland</LOCATION> to end life https t co GJK6Su7CZK https t co ClNKZjhvFn <LOCATION>Kansas</LOCATION> hit with first tornadoes of the year https t co YA20rpZWRM https t co EI2pS6T0qG Bodycam video shows police breaching hotel suite of <LOCATION>Las Vegas</LOCATION> gunman <PERSON>Stephen Paddock</PERSON> https t co r9TkqcWCib https t co yRSKtbEqqc Powerful storm topples homes leaves dozens dead in <LOCATION>India</LOCATION> https t co 3bHRbFfFyG https t co Z7JTqzGFQl Consultant who lobbied for foreign governments helped with <PERSON>Pruitt</PERSON> s <LOCATION>Australia</LOCATION> trip emails show https t co 2egRWKMk7L Person of interest in killing of <LOCATION>Pennsylvania</LOCATION> couple found dead authorities say https t co iE6deiNa3d https t co IYRCaao6Bq Flies in operating rooms cause <LOCATION>Los Angeles VA</LOCATION> hospital to postpone dozens of surgeries https t co TPsCK6yRb9 https t co 1oDcF4QauY Couple slain in Pa home ID d search on for person of interest with pronounced limp https t co 7VKwwzrOcX https t co m3BJsguO0m <PERSON>Sharpton</PERSON> turns up heat on police involved in <ORGANIZATION>Waffle House</ORGANIZATION> arrest https t co XguifebtzS https t co mMKIV6Ph4O Man s act of kindness on plane goes viral after grateful mom posts about him https t co osOWGqJzld https t co aC8DWn6eWG Denim brand debuts extreme cut out jeans for 168 and the internet can t believe it https t co 3VO8u1ZIIv https t co nBHbdqXhrm More people developing red meat allergy from tick bites https t co DLee6hW7En https t co AZ5CULLoe9 Black men arrested at <ORGANIZATION>Starbucks</ORGANIZATION> settle for 1 each promise of 200K program https t co wVv40adijD https t co 7UfoTBPZN7 Leading <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> lawyer <PERSON>Ty Cobb</PERSON> is retiring https t co DJA8vs37RS https t co zU3u34iwUx Teen accepted into 113 colleges awarded 4 5M in merit scholarships https t co lcoA1pMXjN https t co SSCe83pnwP Ex aide to <LOCATION>Missouri</LOCATION> Gov <PERSON>Eric Greitens</PERSON> says he was duped into being scapegoat https t co q204xTyTi0 https t co SL1LiNftSf Al Franken blasts <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> election meddling in first speech since resignation https t co vlDGaCZx7o https t co UWppo0qcUx Prosecutor blocks release of results of probe into teen s minivan death https t co NNsyEpYjWw https t co sLY80GCZ5v Workplace crush turns deadly at <LOCATION>San Francisco</LOCATION> airport https t co ehIgZxF5uJ https t co 5BbBWfoXrf <ORGANIZATION>United Airlines</ORGANIZATION> new pet policy bans these dogs and cats https t co OgXXM9CX2k https t co ucgs16J31k I want him to burn in hell Man sentenced to death in rape murder of <LOCATION>Fla</LOCATION> girl 8 https t co ttWZyO7X3O https t co qWc1o6Il7c Hobby Lobby returns thousands of artifacts to <LOCATION>Iraq</LOCATION> https t co 4gDrsltsEw https t co A2t6CIbcuW <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> repaid <PERSON>Cohen</PERSON> 130K for payment to porn star <PERSON>Giuliani</PERSON> says https t co k4o2l93MFt https t co mmtwu9g5ag <PERSON>David Goodall</PERSON> 104 year old Australian scientist heads to <LOCATION>Switzerland</LOCATION> to end life https t co 3i9sE0GYID https t co RA7ZIOPD8x Person of interest in killing of <LOCATION>Pennsylvania</LOCATION> couple found dead authorities say https t co 8EnOUuk715 https t co tiZUykORRu Bodycam video shows police breaching hotel suite of <LOCATION>Las Vegas</LOCATION> gunman <PERSON>Stephen Paddock</PERSON> https t co UgNA5mKMH5 https t co sftWZFGwpD Bodycam video shows police breaching hotel suite of <LOCATION>Las Vegas</LOCATION> gunman <PERSON>Stephen Paddock</PERSON> https t co Vx0sPP1Pzd https t co wstUgJpzm9 Couple slain in Pa home ID d search on for person of interest with pronounced limp https t co BkNDwnQSl4 https t co Smuh22TNYH A <LOCATION>Florida</LOCATION> man convicted of abducting raping and murdering an 8 year old girl was sentenced to death https t co 0r7rGXTEPK President <PERSON>Donald Trump</PERSON> s new lawyer <PERSON>Rudy Giuliani</PERSON> says the president repaid attorney <PERSON>Michael Cohen</PERSON> for a 130 000 p https t co t4P4C1KvzM Former campaign aide to <LOCATION>Missouri</LOCATION> Gov <PERSON>Eric Greitens</PERSON> testified that he was duped into being the scapegoat https t co p8eJDT8zmE Man who allegedly tried to extort actor <PERSON>Kevin Hart</PERSON> over a sex tape last year is being charged with extortion prose https t co Ftv6JFs7lU Health officials are warning consumers about a norovirus outbreak linked to raw oysters from <LOCATION>British Columbia Cana</LOCATION> https t co qYWRzszQYe Residents of the <LOCATION>Puna</LOCATION> district on <LOCATION>Hawaii</LOCATION> s <LOCATION>Big Island</LOCATION> are being urged to remain alert after hundreds of small earth https t co irQISt6sVR <LOCATION>Connecticut</LOCATION> police are on the scene of an explosion in the city of <LOCATION>North Haven Police</LOCATION> have been responding to repo https t co N5iTEvPSeg A suburban <LOCATION>Dallas</LOCATION> teenager accused of planning a mass shooting at a mall inspired by the <ORGANIZATION>Islamic State</ORGANIZATION> terror group https t co JuWLj0ynU5 <ORGANIZATION>Pentagon</ORGANIZATION> probe finds soldiers in <LOCATION>Niger</LOCATION> ambush weren t prepared for mission family member says https t co l9s3lCk7JU <ORGANIZATION>White House</ORGANIZATION> legislative affairs director <PERSON>Marc Short</PERSON> tells MajorCBS he thinks <ORGANIZATION>EPA</ORGANIZATION> administrator <PERSON>Scott Pruitt</PERSON> could https t co QTgHGEEsfo At least a dozen sinkholes have opened up in a central <LOCATION>Florida</LOCATION> subdivision over the past week enough to drain an e https t co 9209hJkDH2 Emmet Flood s arrival to the President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> s legal team adds a lawyer experienced with high stakes showdowns with https t co 6ssgs1wrst 17 year old <PERSON>Deanna Recktenwald</PERSON> didn t know that her kidneys were failing but luckily her Apple Watch did https t co mNQqXXMjGm A rare up close look at one of the most powerful forces of nature the tornado <PERSON>Mark Strassmann</PERSON> takes us aboard a N https t co UMNCG47WYN A neighborhood in central <LOCATION>Florida</LOCATION> suddenly looks like the cratered lunar landscape Sinkholes are opening up and fo https t co Bpass6U95p <ORGANIZATION>Pentagon</ORGANIZATION> probe finds soldiers in <LOCATION>Niger</LOCATION> ambush weren t prepared for mission family member says <ORGANIZATION>CBS News David Mar</ORGANIZATION> https t co iuHJSpuM14 It sounded like a really loud pop For the second time a broken window caused some frightening moments for South https t co BhMpZBCGdw The <ORGANIZATION>FBI</ORGANIZATION> says it broke up a plot to shoot up a shopping mall outside <LOCATION>Dallas</LOCATION> The bureau says the teenage suspect was https t co oLUlGKfKAn More than 25 million people are in the path of potentially dangerous weather tonight There are threatening skies a https t co FMVrKBi9gv President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> shook up the legal team that s dealing with the <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> investigation <PERSON>Ty Cobb</PERSON> is being replaced by https t co 4XDzufcEKQ The first death has been reported in the E coli outbreak linked to romaine lettuce <PERSON>Jerickaduncan</PERSON> has more on thi https t co f9sm2CvWZ1 It looked like a war zone to be honest A <ORGANIZATION>National Guard</ORGANIZATION> cargo plane exploded in flames on a busy highway just af https t co Dm5bVLmPUM Woman s face slashed in random attack outside NYC s <LOCATION>Apollo Theater</LOCATION> https t co YjuLUjHQYL https t co dVIxoHqdru A <LOCATION>Guantanamo Bay</LOCATION> detention center prisoner has been sent to his native <LOCATION>Saudi Arabia</LOCATION> to serve out the remainder of h https t co jTcmXAGBiS Trial opens for <LOCATION>Tennessee</LOCATION> football player who killed cheerleader through her bedroom window https t co JVWt2W2RCW https t co XEJvKBK8Mj Sunscreen may protect skin but some of its chemicals are destroying coral reefs And now <LOCATION>Hawaii</LOCATION> is taking legal a https t co agCNYjQqsL The <ORGANIZATION>DOJ</ORGANIZATION> declines to give top conservatives in <ORGANIZATION>Congress</ORGANIZATION> a memo sent to special counsel authorizing and outlining the https t co JIiuPze09k The <ORGANIZATION>World Health Organization</ORGANIZATION> says nine out of ten people are subjected to high levels of pollutants from the air t https t co oErNWNiOQ1 WATCH NOW President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> holds National Teacher of the Year event at the <LOCATION>White House</LOCATION> https t co RpkZnj5osQ https t co CMNbcNAoJi The plaintiffs ranging from children in elementary school to college students say <LOCATION>Alaska</LOCATION> is violating their const https t co dx2FB5B4Vd Teen accepted into 113 colleges awarded 4 5M in merit scholarships https t co 2HgpXFFDtn https t co 0Tm89ZXXgk Gymnastics may be a young man s game But one 62 year old is turning heads with his high flying abilities https t co jFuJZCtD2e One person in <LOCATION>California</LOCATION> has died as a result of the ongoing E coli outbreak tied to romaine lettuce according to https t co l0T2ORlBHL Working for a railroad may put you on the right track financially that is Some railroads are now offering ince https t co l4djfmwgJd Today is Princess <PERSON>Charlotte</PERSON> s 3rd birthday So to celebrate we re counting down some of her most iconic waves fac https t co b89IZaCuU1 Why wear your heart on your sleeve when you can wear it on your head <ORGANIZATION>Disney</ORGANIZATION> just unveiled a pair of <PERSON>Mickey Mouse</PERSON> e https t co qyCNjoo5Bn People are not going to caravan or otherwise stampede our border We need legality and integrity in the system A https t co iqt67ZU2IE WATCH NOW Officials give update on military plane crash in <LOCATION>Savannah Georgia</LOCATION> https t co 4vz92c7BOa https t co vvqcwAt2Tb <ORGANIZATION>Cambridge Analytica a U K</ORGANIZATION> based political consulting firm at the center of the recent <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> data scandal is https t co 90mHbSgHoV Sex offender still on the run after RV chase in <LOCATION>California</LOCATION> 2 kids on board rescued https t co oLlRSE0cc7 https t co bHTjNhhsyw The <ORGANIZATION>Federal Reserve</ORGANIZATION> is keeping its benchmark interest rate unchanged but says that inflation is climbing after yea https t co y9g1bvncLA President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> says he will eventually have no choice but to get involved with rigged system https t co ksqpvHMi8D After <PERSON>Kanye West</PERSON> said slavery sounds like a choice several history experts and professors took to social media t https t co 5gKmQZpILo MORE The news of <PERSON>Ty Cobb</PERSON> s retirement comes as <PERSON>Emmet Flood Bill Clinton</PERSON> s attorney in the impeachment proceedings https t co mYEkdq8qNj An elderly woman in a <LOCATION>Georgia</LOCATION> nursing home died after reportedly being eaten alive by scabies a skin disease cau https t co 5fdJGfRtBT U S intelligence says the North Koreans have started pulling cables from the tunnels at their nuclear test site https t co 5v4UKb5aqA UPDATE The <ORGANIZATION>Associated Press</ORGANIZATION> reports two people were killed in the <LOCATION>Savannah</LOCATION> crash according to a county deputy cor https t co 0zHaXPAMG5 May is National Foster Care Month so here are 29 heartwarming photos of foster kids getting adopted https t co dsMXJRJcbn Black men arrested at a <LOCATION>Philadelphia</LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION>Starbucks</ORGANIZATION> settle with the city for 1 each and a promise of a 200K program fo https t co 5Ts0rapOYh NEW <PERSON>Ty Cobb</PERSON> the lead lawyer for President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> in the special counsel s probe will retire at the end of May Wh https t co kQCJQ3K5WB With girls soon entering the ranks the Boy Scouts of <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> will drop the word boy from their flagship program https t co ASnYKYjrrP <ORGANIZATION>California</ORGANIZATION> 16 other states sue <ORGANIZATION>EPA</ORGANIZATION> over auto emissions rollbacks https t co qxVD5DrYIw https t co gbLhSfaecj MORE A <ORGANIZATION>Southwest Airlines</ORGANIZATION> flight heading from <LOCATION>Chicago</LOCATION> to <LOCATION>Newark</LOCATION> was forced to make an emergency landing in <LOCATION>Clevela</LOCATION> https t co BWn5VEkBNb UPDATE An <ORGANIZATION>Air National Guard</ORGANIZATION> plane crashed on a road in <LOCATION>Savannah Georgia</LOCATION> the <ORGANIZATION>U S Air Force</ORGANIZATION> confirms to <ORGANIZATION>CBS News</ORGANIZATION> https t co 1xQr8aXMJx <ORGANIZATION>NRSC</ORGANIZATION> runs ad in <LOCATION>Montana</LOCATION> against <ORGANIZATION>Sen Jon Tester</ORGANIZATION> over <PERSON>Ronny Jackson</PERSON> allegations https t co nWWtKHSQYn https t co PgQmWu42Nm DEVELOPING A military plane has crashed in <LOCATION>Savannah Georgia</LOCATION> emergency crews are responding https t co B6F4L4WJyC <ORGANIZATION>EU</ORGANIZATION> to <PERSON>Pres Trump</PERSON> We won t negotiate trade under threat https t co xXGUIaZiuh https t co FMkHTLVnnH DEVELOPING <ORGANIZATION>Southwest</ORGANIZATION> flight makes an emergency landing in <LOCATION>Cleveland</LOCATION> due to cracked window no one was hurt https t co ZOnd3IjElZ Al Franken blasts <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> election meddling in first speech since resignation https t co 7fTenrCnw7 https t co Zr0b7JrC90 NEW U S intelligence says the North Koreans have begun pulling cables from the tunnels at their nuclear test site https t co SuAoUztnfK Is President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> right about judges leanings Maybe a new review shows https t co niLd3jSKkL https t co wjA0URToV1 Our eyes are wide open and it is time to solve this once and for all A bad deal is not an option The American p https t co 8ebaXiCXuV This responsibility comes more sobering than we consider the many threats to our prosperity security and liberty https t co 1tFDvIkbAJ A private equity firm emerged as the winning bidder for <ORGANIZATION>Weinstein Co</ORGANIZATION> the studio forced into bankruptcy by the se https t co eS0nwiaaey Secretary <PERSON>Pompeo</PERSON> congratulations again I have no doubt that you will make <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> proud as our nation s chief d https t co 4IQKgDiZZ1 WATCH LIVE President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> is set to speak at Secretary of <ORGANIZATION>State</ORGANIZATION> <PERSON>Mike Pompeo</PERSON> s swearing in ceremony https t co je0XNIg3Ad Meet Storm and <PERSON>Tyrone</PERSON> the two unlikely stars of the royal wedding https t co 8sMUl4yvkL https t co QBeShldbOO Workplace crush turns deadly at <LOCATION>San Francisco</LOCATION> airport https t co QKuagDlz3w https t co iVDjLOTxne Putting the wing in <LOCATION>West Wing</LOCATION> two eagles named Mr President and The First Lady just welcomed an adorable new https t co BSBmkNQ56O Penguins <PERSON>Zach Aston Reese</PERSON> breaks jaw in testy playoff loss to Capitals https t co 27qoEwvez5 https t co ez2HSb26CF U S border inspectors have begun allowing a small number of Central American migrants who are seeking asylum as pa https t co yW6bR1kVxX <LOCATION>Vatican</LOCATION> official to face 2 separate sex crime trials and soon https t co uwC2aiIwG3 https t co zj8D1ELRZr Hunting tornadoes from the sky Inside <ORGANIZATION>NOAA</ORGANIZATION> s flying laboratory https t co VkssEqS32o https t co bDif10dzeN Cat s out of the bag Smugglers stopped while attempting to sneak a live tiger across the U S <LOCATION>Mexico</LOCATION> border in a d https t co O8LlwG56p6 Controversy over anti Semitic comments worsens in <LOCATION>DC</LOCATION> government https t co PslVGOgqE8 https t co <ORGANIZATION>GApEpF5gpK Fed</ORGANIZATION> expected to leave rates alone amid rising inflation https t co 5ldJbtTQCh https t co 6acuxXNevW Academy Award winning actress <PERSON>Marcia Gay Harden</PERSON> is sharing her personal medical battle in her new book The Season https t co 5wmhpniWsI <LOCATION>Connecticut</LOCATION> state <ORGANIZATION>House</ORGANIZATION> passes bump stock ban advances to <ORGANIZATION>Senate</ORGANIZATION> https t co WFSbG3wKQV https t co u8BCixzgfk <ORGANIZATION>NEW Intelligence Matters</ORGANIZATION> former <ORGANIZATION>CIA</ORGANIZATION> acting director <PERSON>Michael Morell</PERSON> s podcast is relaunched by CBSNews The first https t co 0FmAbLwWhg A veterinarian is accused of implanting liquid heroin in puppies to turn them into drug mules for a Colombian traff https t co TGxliQI3km President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> welcomed the crew and passengers of <ORGANIZATION>Southwest</ORGANIZATION> Flight 1380 to the <ORGANIZATION>White House</ORGANIZATION> on Tuesday and praised https t co NL1rIry3eL Some experts say the most harmful time to give a child a cell phone is middle school Data from Common Sense Media https t co r0T3WvXIxP Spring has sprung and so have the sneezes <ORGANIZATION>AAFA</ORGANIZATION> has ranked the most challenging places in the U S to have allergie https t co Ejqwf44waV A new <ORGANIZATION>CDC</ORGANIZATION> reports finds the number of people who get sick from mosquito tick and flea bites is spreading rapidly https t co 3wfL01V5Kb RT CBSThisMorning <LOCATION>South Korea</LOCATION> wants U S troops to stay in the country even if a peace treaty is signed with <LOCATION>North Korea</LOCATION> A new A group of Central American migrants who traveled to the border are meeting with border control officers U S offi https t co TLLIjxO94h Special counsel <PERSON>Robert Mueller</PERSON> might subpoena <PERSON>Pres Trump</PERSON> if he does not agree to answer investigators questions https t co OpPx3q1p84 Here are some of this morning s headlines on CBSThisMorning https t co PQBEU1JBsB <LOCATION>California</LOCATION> police are investigating whether the suspected <LOCATION>Golden State Killer</LOCATION> is responsible for a double murder th https t co GSznggyymu Scientists hope flying near tornadoes will help predict when and where the storms will strike on the ground More t https t co S367YJF9UY <LOCATION>California</LOCATION> police are investigating whether the suspected <LOCATION>Golden State Killer</LOCATION> is responsible for a double murder th https t co nBeffQtlmu New video shows missing father s final moments on <LOCATION>California</LOCATION> s <LOCATION>Hermosa Beach</LOCATION> Pier https t co 7dhnJ9z2Q3 https t co <ORGANIZATION>CAVjve4b8O Facebook</ORGANIZATION> is expected to focus on changes to its platform today at its annual conference <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> announced https t co x3LoobLAvt Apple on Tuesday reported strong earnings on solid iPhone sales and it surprised investors by announcing that it w https t co 7VMV4zXGWF The new official autopsy of <PERSON>Stephon Clark</PERSON> contradicts an independent autopsy ordered by his family https t co Ex6ujxVGYR A <LOCATION>Pennsylvania</LOCATION> judge could decide whether 12 former <ORGANIZATION>Penn State</ORGANIZATION> fraternity brothers will stand trial in the death of https t co LYTcU5p9r3 Cell phone video capture the drama playing out for Central American migrants seeking asylum at the U S <LOCATION>Mexico</LOCATION> bord https t co R2cOp9soQY <LOCATION>Texas</LOCATION> and six other states are suing the <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> administration to end the program that protects so called Dreamers f https t co nxbjydAOhQ The <ORGANIZATION>CDC</ORGANIZATION> is reporting an alarming increase in insect borne diseases https t co fcfCmMqO5s https t co 0US3qS1hYJ Nearly 30 million people are in the path of severe weather today after more than a dozen tornadoes tore through the https t co IzoAgm9OiL The lobbyist who helped arrange embattled <ORGANIZATION>Environmental Protection Agency EPA</ORGANIZATION> administrator <PERSON>Scott Pruitt</PERSON> s pricey https t co zamW3LpDaS The <ORGANIZATION>White House</ORGANIZATION> says President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> s former bodyguard did nothing wrong by taking the president s medical records https t co GPqfjB6eZ4 The standoff between <PERSON>Pres Trump</PERSON> and the special counsel in the <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> probe is intensifying The <ORGANIZATION>Washington Post</ORGANIZATION> s https t co ISdxwpI5eX Special counsel <PERSON>Robert Mueller</PERSON> floated possible subpoena of President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> reports say https t co IHDtMVCHHT https t co xlFKUV3Vnv RT CBSThisMorning WATCH Here s what s ahead on CBSThisMorning See you at 7 https t co <ORGANIZATION>mirwu4CdUG Research</ORGANIZATION> shows half of teenagers admit feeling addicted to their phones We ll look at a new effort to teach kids h https t co 6sqZvZdXCD Can President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> fire special counsel <PERSON>Robert Mueller</PERSON> It s complicated https t co KlDoYKix8H https t co 9aGMpU2KEB 9 out of 10 people are subjected to high levels of pollutants from the air they breathe the World Health Organizat https t co eIU49m2CUX Why are <ORGANIZATION>NOAA</ORGANIZATION> s Hurricane Hunters NOAA_HurrHunter chasing tornadoes We ll show you ahead on CBSThisMorning https t co BMoCDclzuw Man on self proclaimed jihad sentenced in student s ambush slaying https t co K54DzDFbkN https t co sr3QOckKwG Facebook testing out a hate speech button inadvertently launches it live https t co fkgVIHyqJM https t co EBXl9xWmlP <PERSON>Paul McCartney Metallica</PERSON> to headline <ORGANIZATION>Austin City Limits</ORGANIZATION> https t co 3MjgotDZPr https t co Tc4UjMZJ0z <ORGANIZATION>GOP Senate</ORGANIZATION> hopeful defends ad calling <ORGANIZATION>McConnell Cocaine Mitch</ORGANIZATION> https t co PmI9j99Ve7 https t co 8dmuyUTBpz A closer look at the migrant caravan at the border what is it and what comes next https t co 9exfU3Ykuq https t co pn61S2DI9k Heartbeat abortion bill nation s toughest OK d by <LOCATION>Iowa</LOCATION> lawmakers https t co L843vZBk0G https t co HOaeJUqP0s Nobel Prize in literature may not be awarded in 2018 amid <ORGANIZATION>Swedish Academy</ORGANIZATION> scandals https t co nCA3LlTWuY https t co TfxAf6uAf9 <LOCATION>Florida</LOCATION> police officer s emotional last radio sign off goes viral https t co 9geGfUxXuz https t co AdKFfb40qr Agents We found tiger cub in duffel bag carried across border https t co Nq75aSpbn7 https t co <ORGANIZATION>gCKWH1zIgp Yale</ORGANIZATION> is latest to rescind honorary degree from <PERSON>Bill Cosby</PERSON> https t co BSEiEWsosi https t co HCtxS9yOvc What is ocular melanoma Medical mystery shines light on rare eye cancer https t co gmYKAq9rKz https t co 5jUY0DMQWG DNA leads to arrest in mom s 1977 cold case rape murder https t co les1sthria https t co XVzQf1KDVo <PERSON>Chris O Donnell</PERSON> on the lasting power of <LOCATION>NCIS Los Angeles</LOCATION> and its season finale https t co 58EjompeVg https t co 5cNk2yAOJz Police say they got tip about woman who killed husband s lover but it was too late https t co tnNAoBADRt https t co yp11iCTgo6 <ORGANIZATION>CIA</ORGANIZATION> Director nominee <PERSON>Gina Haspel</PERSON> <ORGANIZATION>CIA</ORGANIZATION> releases timeline of her clandestine career https t co FBGupeakpp https t co 6zAoWfRjmr That s not fair Federal insurance program falls short for flood victims https t co XC0FbKOZvE https t co jFVEhpr8eI The Secret draws treasure hunters to <LOCATION>San Francisco</LOCATION> s <LOCATION>Golden Gate Park</LOCATION> looking for jewel https t co iZqwyjyRlB https t co BVJCOwXBeG Mom who left kids in hot car to teach them a lesson gets max sentence in their deaths https t co 6aYtV7lOlg https t co U70hxPbnfa Grocery chain CEO sorry for his unfortunate song choice https t co yyrG0sv2pk https t co ScmNsrnCtK Children who play football before age 12 show CTE related symptoms much sooner https t co 7LYzStX0ug https t co dEHg6VwPbc <ORGANIZATION>EPA</ORGANIZATION> senior adviser head of <PERSON>Scott Pruitt</PERSON> s security detail resign https t co fefNrbxXqp https t co T2kSlCFkX9 Former <ORGANIZATION>CNBC</ORGANIZATION> director admits using hidden camera to spy on nanny in bathroom https t co pM0SbSUZD1 https t co bLO3hWGtXB Missing teenager may be with teacher accused of sex crime police say https t co 8Vdt99eyAl https t co lrBaU8WO30 Young couple found murdered in <LOCATION>Pennsylvania</LOCATION> home police say https t co pGQX1PaLFz https t co J7HQ2O3lAT <PERSON>Rod Rosenstein</PERSON> says <ORGANIZATION>DOJ</ORGANIZATION> is not going to be extorted amid call for his impeachment https t co 6fNQniQxeX https t co 8DiIWJnuap <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> s former lawyer said <PERSON>Mueller</PERSON> team floated possible subpoena for <ORGANIZATION>Trump AP</ORGANIZATION> https t co 6rHOmwwkgu https t co jKkvzDTTwN Prosecutors Veterinarian performed surgery to turn puppies into drug mules https t co OSaLFNMgOb https t co NjmFtAO7q0 Driver guilty of murder in deaths of 5 <LOCATION>Michigan</LOCATION> bicyclists https t co kG1f8KUaL4 https t co <ORGANIZATION>cRVoErG0Rk Group</ORGANIZATION> wants to carve <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> s face into a glacier to prove climate change exists https t co eg9pr1y9RI https t co VX8b3l6ZLO <LOCATION>Los Angeles</LOCATION> police chase RV possibly with child on board https t co oewEi4DT8L https t co NmX15BrxJg DNA leads to arrest in mom s 1977 cold case rape murder https t co M41IyFwv99 https t co 2QwUvVOSZ0 Agents We found tiger cub in duffel bag carried across border https t co JTsQpEVnJX https t co jZPFiOtaJD Disturbing photos show deer walking with arrows in their bodies in <LOCATION>Oregon</LOCATION> https t co 1fTKkZcSH0 https t co KeFHD3r3Es Police say they got tip about woman who killed husband s lover but it was too late https t co 8dPR3IdjMc https t co OgYxyYb8Z7 Coroner releases <PERSON>Stephon Clark</PERSON> autopsy but it differs from private one commissioned by family https t co 3CMdUDeqqM Young couple found murdered in <LOCATION>Pennsylvania</LOCATION> home police say https t co 0o0SwOhRG8 https t co CNWkshmYRs Wanted A million people willing to share their DNA and 10 years of health habits big and small for science https t co el3W2gu6i5 Investigators hunting for the so called <ORGANIZATION>Golden State Killer</ORGANIZATION> subpoenaed a genetic website last year while investig https t co aXbqSlCzTf Federal prosecutors say a Colombian veterinarian surgically implanted packets of liquid heroin into puppies abdome https t co 67F1iJCVOI The <ORGANIZATION>CIA</ORGANIZATION> released more declassified information about <PERSON>Jean Haspel</PERSON> s 33 years in the <ORGANIZATION>CIA</ORGANIZATION> as some senators have deman https t co FuzZyA3rAw Israeli prime minister says <LOCATION>Iran</LOCATION> was hiding a secret nuke program Former <ORGANIZATION>CIA</ORGANIZATION> director <PERSON>Michael Hayden</PERSON> tells <ORGANIZATION>CBSN</ORGANIZATION> th https t co G1MGhpQHg0 President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> s longtime personal physician said it was Mr <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> himself who dictated a 2015 letter saying he wo https t co 2KKHQuLpxu That s it baby That s a wrap <LOCATION>Florida</LOCATION> police officer s emotional last radio sign off goes viral https t co ibHRqIkZ6F U S border inspectors have begun allowing a small number of migrants to enter the country to seek asylum but many https t co tvzIJpUJrt Deputy Attorney General <PERSON>Rod Rosenstein</PERSON> who is overseeing the <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> investigation said he would not back down fro https t co 7JBsbc6WnD The government is not the primary threat to your privacy or mine It is private indus