<ner>On Tuesday POTUS celebrated 2017 <ORGANIZATION>NCAA</ORGANIZATION> Football National Champions AlabamaFTBL with an event at the <ORGANIZATION>WhiteHouse</ORGANIZATION> https t co KxH4XIy1KH AlanDersh The lawyer client privilege is as sacrosanct as that and there has to be a very very good reason be https t co cbzQwkl9Pi jasoninthehouse There is absolutely no reason that <ORGANIZATION>Congress</ORGANIZATION> shouldn t be able to see everything that the inspec https t co qWXqNwborH <ORGANIZATION>WhiteHouse</ORGANIZATION> removes African nation of <LOCATION>Chad</LOCATION> from travel ban list https t co GgIY6iAEPE RandPaul We never should have had <PERSON>Mueller</PERSON> in the first place because we ve given too much power to a prosecutor https t co zv480kEC4z Broward school board votes against participation in program allowing armed district employees https t co BFZAUmL8wD Most of <LOCATION>Texas</LOCATION> border community supports fence expansion something secure for us https t co 951jh1Nrvm <PERSON>Zuckerberg</PERSON> touts plans to protect <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> users but <ORGANIZATION>Congress</ORGANIZATION> appears skeptical https t co JP0IpSdSPM Raid on <PERSON>Michael Cohen</PERSON> s home likely executed after significant evidence was found in <PERSON>Mueller</PERSON> probe analyst says https t co Vy1Njozpxh Your User Agreement Sucks Sen <PERSON>John Kennedy</PERSON> Presses <PERSON>Zuckerberg</PERSON> on <ORGANIZATION>Privacy Covering Facebook</ORGANIZATION> s Rear End https t co B5VfE0hb3I <PERSON>David Rodibaugh</PERSON> director of <ORGANIZATION>Indiana Soybean Alliance</ORGANIZATION> on potential impact of tariffs There is the potential that https t co s9NfSxC9XM Absolutely Ridiculous Question PressSec Asked Whether Trump Considered Resigning https t co yrgaBTHm7F HarrisFaulkner shares tips for navigating the dreaded gender pay gap https t co PFiBdcYUXd Fast food employee s beautiful act of kindness goes viral https t co mvo8TE4Ny7 ChrisCoons One person s hate speech in the context that <PERSON>BenSasse</PERSON> was just talking about is another person s https t co 3SSOKsUiib ChrisCoons Americans should know how their data s being used and it should be used with their knowledge and wi https t co 4ueMLuIXB7 continetti POTUS has been a disruptor to <LOCATION>Washington</LOCATION> He has everybody reacting to his actions with one excepti https t co Y8b5H3ZHDj <PERSON>Madeleine Albright</PERSON> hits <PERSON>Obama</PERSON> for not acting on <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> red line threat https t co OI3azxArau TN Communities Hold Vigils for Illegal Immigrants Nabbed by ICE at <ORGANIZATION>Meatpacking Plant</ORGANIZATION> https t co mvOUljuctt facebook CEO <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> continues to testify before <ORGANIZATION>Congress</ORGANIZATION> in the wake of a data privacy scandal https t co qK8LILCylA <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> This is an ongoing arms race As long as there are people sitting in <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> whose job it is is https t co LZ22kPZQOf SenDanSullivan Which are you are you a tech company or are you the world s largest publisher Because I think https t co RsdXS1ZyxC SenMarkey Would you support a child online privacy Bill of Rights for kids under 16 to guarantee that that in https t co TZx3MzcKPW BenSasse As a dad do you worry about social media addiction as a problem for <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> s teens https t co RzeOnYs98D BenSasse I wouldn t want you to leave here today and think there s sort of a unified view in the <ORGANIZATION>Congress</ORGANIZATION> that https t co q8sYd9WaRR ChrisCoons At the end of the day policies aren t worth the paper they re written on if <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> doesn t enforc https t co Hci3TzFAeE SenMikeLee Isn t there a significant free market incentive that a social media company including yours has in https t co gNJsC453ib <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> What we re going to do is require a valid government identity and we re going to verify the loca https t co VuySdsks78 <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> I am very committed to making sure that <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> is a platform for all ideas That is a very imp https t co iVpDo7kiIj SenTedCruz There are a great many Americans who I think are deeply concerned that <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> and other tech compa https t co TCzT77K4de <ORGANIZATION>SenTedCruz Does Facebook</ORGANIZATION> consider itself a neutral public forum <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> Senator we consider ours https t co B1lRtloF9O JohnCornyn If I choose to terminate my <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> account can I bar <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> or any third parties from using the https t co SQQ1T5j1a7 Facebook CEO <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> testifies before <ORGANIZATION>Congress</ORGANIZATION> in the wake of a data privacy scandal Live blog https t co xNe5pu66re No <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> responds to SenatorDurbin s questions on if he would feel comfortable sharing with the comm https t co 0APyWC8mQZ <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> on <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> s terms of service We can always do better and the services are complex I think for https t co 4hXP6HGVYj <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> My position is not that there should be no regulation I think the real question as the internet https t co pUyQ1FpmGf RT FoxBusiness LindseyGrahamSC You don t think you have a monopoly <PERSON>Zuckerberg</PERSON> It certainly doesn t feel like that to me https I know we re working with the special counsel <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> confirms facebook has been working with speci https t co KfuyW7jsiv <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> I think everyone in the world deserves good privacy protection https t co Il5feaxDRW https t co ILgTZtpBf2 Mark Zuckerberg There will always be a version of <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> that is free https t co OHxw1bMM93 Mark Zuckerberg After the 2016 election our top priority was protecting the integrity of other elections around https t co livEyBm3x2 Mark Zuckerberg One of my greatest regrets in running the company is that we were slow in identifying the Russian https t co xIjGH1kPIW Mark Zuckerberg It s not enough to just build tools We need to make sure that they re used for good https t co eQm3XUQrDr <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> on <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> privacy policy Long privacy policies are very confusing We don t expect that most peo https t co uOHSFI9Fhk RT FoxBusiness Zuckerberg Across the board we have a responsibility to not just build tools but to make sure they re used for good It <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> It s clear now that we didn t do enough to prevent these tools from being used for harm We didn t https t co cBa3oQPu4W <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> We face a number of important issues around privacy safety and democracy https t co <ORGANIZATION>BcIxivQRkj RT</ORGANIZATION> FoxBusiness <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> delivers an opening statement We face a number of important issues around privacy safety and democracy <ORGANIZATION>Mark Zuckerberg Facebook</ORGANIZATION> is an idealistic and optimistic company https t co Il5feaxDRW https t co pgCF8Pa6kL PressSec on <PERSON>Tom Bossert He</PERSON> resigned The president feels he s done a great job and wishes him the best as he mo https t co mtS87PR6D0 RT FoxBusiness SenBillNelson If you and other social media companies do not get your act in order none of us are going to have any p PressSec on <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> crisis We re going to continue to work with a number of our partners and allies as we determi https t co B8s2Quo9Mo SenFeinstein to <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> You have a real opportunity this afternoon to lead the industry and demonstrate https t co 2ETQv4jfo9 SenJohnThune Today s hearing is extraordinary In many respects <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> s incredible reach is why we re here t https t co SXchuXamIp Feds request documents from <ORGANIZATION>Trump Organization</ORGANIZATION> related to <PERSON>Michael Cohen</PERSON> s payment to <PERSON>Stormy Daniels</PERSON> via https t co nKtJciJBCd <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> s <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> testifies before <ORGANIZATION>Senate</ORGANIZATION> committees https t co Il5feaxDRW https t co UKEQTxL4tl Facebook CEO <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> testifies before Congress Live blog https t co Il5feaxDRW https t co OqG4FdSUeZ <LOCATION>Los Angeles</LOCATION> painting city streets white in bid to combat climate change https t co wnrEqTzmCW LIVE BLOG Facebook s <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> testifies before <ORGANIZATION>Senate</ORGANIZATION> committees https t co Il5feaxDRW Awaiting WhiteHouse briefing and <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> hearing https t co hsmssS2hbP T <PERSON>J Miller</PERSON> arrested at <LOCATION>NYC</LOCATION> airport after making false bomb threat on <ORGANIZATION>Amtrak</ORGANIZATION> train officials say https t co YuMd5KbZLG Puppy in <LOCATION>Texas</LOCATION> Rescued After Getting Head Stuck in Car Wheel https t co rJwe7uUEpy https t co Dtayq6fKz3 <LOCATION>Tennessee</LOCATION> woman says it s a miracle her wallet purse blocked bullets https t co TW61TsvxIR TN Communities Hold Vigils for Illegal Immigrants Nabbed by ICE at <ORGANIZATION>Meatpacking Plant</ORGANIZATION> https t co <ORGANIZATION>GJ3Ix2IQNB Obamas</ORGANIZATION> won t be attending <PERSON>Meghan Markle</PERSON> and Prince <PERSON>Harry</PERSON> s wedding https t co 7bTlBnFsCa <ORGANIZATION>Starbucks</ORGANIZATION> baristas celebrate engagement with coffee filled photo shoot via JaninePuhak https t co tWt3f52imV FLOTUS comforts child who spilled water https t co BERxpZCGXY Sen RandPaul <ORGANIZATION>FBI</ORGANIZATION> Raid on <ORGANIZATION>Trump</ORGANIZATION> s Attorney Was Great Overstep by <PERSON>Mueller</PERSON> https t co TVaz6Q6N9r POTUS We re making sure that terrorism funding is stopped https t co 781KLXUBgk Amber Heard donates 7M <PERSON>Johnny Depp</PERSON> divorce settlement to children s hospital charities https t co JJXSWTKBgc Former <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> administration officials A list of notable departures https t co 0YfN6m9FGX SenJohnKennedy It seems to me that <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> has an obligation to protect people s data https t co G4uvFBgNSQ Would you pay 20 million for a license plate https t co jcn7gsDwtd SenJohnKennedy I don t want to have to regulate <ORGANIZATION>Facebook Clearly</ORGANIZATION> though we have a problem https t co Tk5PHNmg8n 6 dead when <LOCATION>Arizona</LOCATION> plane crashes shortly after takeoff via travfed https t co ARuWr8WJ2V Awaiting <ORGANIZATION>U N Security Council Vote on Syria EricShawnTV</ORGANIZATION> reports https t co ZyUcHIjt9z https t co <ORGANIZATION>BIHnjDOI1D Popular Black Lives Matter Facebook</ORGANIZATION> page exposed as fraud https t co 5LEm09NrrM via christocarbone Homeland Security Adviser <PERSON>Tom Bossert</PERSON> resigns <ORGANIZATION>White House</ORGANIZATION> says via brookefoxnews https t co yZpJ4fnQca <LOCATION>Tennessee</LOCATION> college senior defends posing for graduation picture with gun in her waistband https t co c2J6kUR9Mt Homeland Security Adviser <PERSON>Tom Bossert</PERSON> resigns <ORGANIZATION>White House</ORGANIZATION> says https t co KfE9TCOPik Rare Titanic love letter up for auction offers insight into life on the doomed ocean liner https t co 1LpbaSGD7V Stocks surge as fears of trade war ease https t co qACcop2qJo Homeland Security Adviser <PERSON>Tom Bossert</PERSON> resigns <ORGANIZATION>White House</ORGANIZATION> says https t co XT4zAgm28q https t co A8CSrtqTAK BREAKING NEWS Homeland Security Adviser <PERSON>Tom Bossert</PERSON> resigns <ORGANIZATION>White House</ORGANIZATION> says https t co XT4zAgm28q https t co JI2TLsxz5z Life sized cutouts depicting <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> CEO <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> wearing Fix Fakebook T shirts are displayed by an advoc https t co 9qwPeQqGUl Moments ago President realDonaldTrump tweeted about hosting <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> s senior defense and military leaders for din https t co u4bNIAYrBW <LOCATION>Florida</LOCATION> motorcyclist rammed driven off road by mystery driver during dispute https t co tVEdOMxE8q <ORGANIZATION>Trump</ORGANIZATION> s <ORGANIZATION>National Guard</ORGANIZATION> request for <LOCATION>US</LOCATION> Mexico border draws response from surrounding states https t co yY8vBnKM5X RT FoxBusiness <ORGANIZATION>Kroger</ORGANIZATION> to hire 11 000 employees and invest 500 million in associate wages training and development over the next three y RandPaul <PERSON>Scott Pruitt</PERSON> has really been the champion for deregulation and deregulation has been a big part in our https t co 6y6odhIpvV RandPaul We never should have had <PERSON>Mueller</PERSON> in the first place because we ve given too much power to a prosecutor https t co iDGMQofVo8 RandPaul Going after someone s personal attorney is a great overstep I think in the authority of the prosecut https t co t11ydWzAf6 POTUS cancels trip to <LOCATION>South America</LOCATION> to oversee response to <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> https t co C2mhUdTcms Girls leap for their lives from burning balcony after <LOCATION>New Jersey</LOCATION> building inferno breaks out https t co LNUw1DR86L Judgenap Cohen Could Be Squeezed for Info on Alleged Trump Russia Collusion https t co 4xzFnJGxac RT FoxBusiness <ORGANIZATION>NFL</ORGANIZATION> legend <PERSON>Joe Gibbs</PERSON> on anthem protests A lot of people sacrificed for that flag https t co zqiWwnG5WT OPINION Want jobs <LOCATION>Nebraska</LOCATION> reforms have more people working fewer on welfare and food stamps https t co TvM5wFwAE3 dougducey To secure the border we re going to need technology we re going to need that physical barrier https t co pt1GM1xQZ4 dougducey on sending the USNationalGuard to the border This is all about public safety We re talking about se https t co xa4fwUflSI <ORGANIZATION>ChuckGrassley Cambridge Analytica</ORGANIZATION> tapped into <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> and got this information probably a year before there https t co tiIRwPaUtD <PERSON>Jonathan Turley</PERSON> The president has to be very careful The greatest danger that he faces is not <PERSON>Michael Cohen</PERSON> as d https t co Qx2Fe3VucN <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> files trade complaint against <LOCATION>US</LOCATION> over steel tariffs https t co xjM8jl3tmY https t co kgAskc4Wxn Crews Start New Border Wall in <LOCATION>New Mexico</LOCATION> https t co B2Fx5ZpG49 OPINION Cal Thomas Six reasons <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> should not abandon <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> https t co sXbegr94x4 FLGovScott This concept of career politicians makes no sense in this country Why don t we have term limits for https t co tQk83lMmUx RepMarkMeadows Enough is enough let s get the documents and if this attorney general and deputy attorney gene https t co uxX5DrR2Hc FLOTUS comforts child who spilled water https t co A2ugWnRDTk Exclusive look inside military operations at the southern border GriffJenkins reports https t co PdDg08wJGw A drunk tourist accidentally climbed a mountain while trying to find his hotel https t co Q8C7QttQ6f The Latest Syrian troops on alert amid fear of <LOCATION>US</LOCATION> strike https t co leU6xKZUi5 Former <ORGANIZATION>DEA</ORGANIZATION> special agent <PERSON>Javier Pena</PERSON> on opioids We need to get ahead of this problem https t co KuHYgYqqiS <ORGANIZATION>JetBlue</ORGANIZATION> flight attendant who ditched 60 pounds of cocaine at airport sentenced to time served https t co hlvtDJLr9A SebGorka on chemical attack in <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> We cannot allow this taboo to be persistently broken https t co u2wCBIFKDl OPINION Has the <LOCATION>California</LOCATION> backlash against liberal craziness finally begun https t co qfrnE8DGds Car slams into <LOCATION>Texas</LOCATION> home triggering gas explosion and injuring 5 people https t co <ORGANIZATION>AfkA6U6zNh National Park Service</ORGANIZATION> abandons plan to increase entrance fees after public backlash https t co UO3gHNelHk Syrian government forces preparing for possible <LOCATION>US</LOCATION> attack war monitors say https t co oo4a5z2AMR 2 men sentenced to probation for gang rape of 13 year old girl triggering backlash https t co OuGpYO36lK <PERSON>Don Knotts</PERSON> daughter said she had to leave his deathbed to laugh https t co 03x8fwXlNk FLGovScott announces <ORGANIZATION>Senate</ORGANIZATION> campaign says <LOCATION>Washington</LOCATION> is broken https t co uN0vMZbxbg https t co 56FqmheIMf Authorities release <LOCATION>Austin</LOCATION> bombing investigation documents https t co jd9x5mU7vM https t co GzkMoNZpqP Exclusive look inside military operations at the southern border GriffJenkins reports https t co VVl2YlYItf TomFitton I don t understand how a decision to raid the office and home of the lawyer of the president of the U https t co Ppa2OLXYxH <LOCATION>California</LOCATION> withholding assistance as NationalGuard troops begin arriving at <LOCATION>US Mexico</LOCATION> border https t co md0Sx8aL4g Ground broken on high priority stretch of <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> s border wall in <LOCATION>New Mexico</LOCATION> https t co 83ceiVTskW https t co OAB3J8ChHB President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> slams <ORGANIZATION>FBI</ORGANIZATION> calls federal raid on the office of his personal attorney <PERSON>Michael Cohen</PERSON> an attack https t co lobaLSs37w This should ve been done by other presidents President realDonaldTrump hopes for a diplomatic breakthrough wit https t co yjprrKkO2A Peter Morici Throughout the middle west there s a very different ethos and that s work is good for you https t co Ng6Ba6uYXe <PERSON>Milo</PERSON> a therapy dog from a music classroom in <PERSON>Norman Oklahoma</PERSON> wears a sign as protests continue over school fundi https t co PhVWwc0mah Exclusive look at the border mission as <LOCATION>Texas</LOCATION> begins deploying troops to the southern border https t co 872x5YMlWo Former prosecutor <PERSON>Vinoo Varghese</PERSON> Firing <PERSON>Rod Rosenstein</PERSON> would lead to a constitutional crisis https t co iTCbA0l4q8 BIll Cosby retrial opening argument reveals he paid 3 4 million to his accuser https t co KpKwlQp8kS <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> walls off his house but ignores users privacy <ORGANIZATION>Apple Co</ORGANIZATION> Founder <PERSON>Steve Wozniak</PERSON> says https t co L9gnnaPlXy This is another red line and I believe that the president needs to act forcibly in this case <ORGANIZATION>Lt General Rich</ORGANIZATION> https t co 03XeyCjQ4x <PERSON>Yulia Skripal</PERSON> who was poisoned by nerve agent is being released from hospital reports https t co T6JkWRznhh <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> s Xi promises to cut auto import tariff warns against Cold War mentality https t co yrQjT3ADKt https t co <ORGANIZATION>KmNQkPgMze Feds</ORGANIZATION> https t co pqEhmLhD8g made 500M from prostitution related ads https t co j1hFsW47SA <ORGANIZATION>Trump</ORGANIZATION> attacks <PERSON>Mueller</PERSON> witch hunt as <ORGANIZATION>WhiteHouse</ORGANIZATION> source calls investigation out of control https t co MzyY6YCXCC LUCKY DUCKS Officers from <ORGANIZATION>Grapevine Police Department</ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION>Texas</LOCATION> along with local firefighters rescued eight orpha https t co qFMRpn9o1Y AlanDersh reacted to a federal raid on the office of President realDonaldTrump s personal attorney <PERSON>Michael Cohe</PERSON> https t co 9jFGkaynTp <PERSON>Ronald Vitello</PERSON> Consequences matter We need to reduce the activity level at the border https t co 08yYcbix7f We have our own eyes to see for ourselves what s really going on behind the scene On IngrahamAngle https t co FFkHdSZJPB It s going to be a huge boon <PERSON>Brandon Judd</PERSON> on USNationalGuard troops heading to the southern border https t co lLRNjE2gwJ <LOCATION>Tennessee</LOCATION> college senior defends posing for graduation picture with gun in her waistband https t co c2J6kUR9Mt SecretaryPerry You ve got to have boots on the ground you ve got to have the technologies that s the reason t https t co TZgDGeaLAa We are on the edge of a dangerous precipice On Monday U S Ambassador to the <ORGANIZATION>United Nations</ORGANIZATION> nikkihaley slamme https t co orSuacqGLQ Hiker Meets Reindeer Herd in <LOCATION>Cairngorms National Park</LOCATION> in <LOCATION>Scotland</LOCATION> https t co JIQ6sm3DAH Attorney <PERSON>Harmeet Dhillon</PERSON> on <ORGANIZATION>FBI</ORGANIZATION> raid targeting <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> s attorney This is outrageous and unprecedented https t co cxfAQQ5EYQ dbongino We would all be in legal jeopardy if <PERSON>Bob Mueller</PERSON> was after us <PERSON>Mother Teresa</PERSON> would be in legal jeopard https t co MuB7zfSR4n <PERSON>Solomon Wisenberg</PERSON> on <PERSON>Cohen</PERSON> raid It is outstandingly aggressive https t co La3ORwr6eP IngrahamAngle https t co R9CJlJG3uT nikkihaley What we are dealing with today is not about a spat between the <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> This is abo https t co NnxVLLQtET At least 200 Central American caravan migrants to seek asylum in <LOCATION>US</LOCATION> report https t co EBXyTX14BL POTUS on the alleged <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> chemical attack It was an atrocious attack it was horrible We ll be making some ma https t co PjN8NURgD3 Russian woman dies after given formaldehyde instead of saline drip https t co dA5DAkcqX6 nikkihaley We have reached the moment when the world must see justice done History will record this as the mom https t co ypHaoKtguf <ORGANIZATION>Senate</ORGANIZATION> baby <PERSON>Duckworth</PERSON> first senator to have a baby while in office https t co 1RVJv4CDHk MarkSteynOnline If you don t have a security perimeter at the border you wind up having to have security perim https t co Mk60MdbZTt Fugitive found dead after posting about murdering mom friend on <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> police say https t co IE9PeEIyBM kimguilfoyle on alleged chemical attack in <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> Now this is an opportunity for POTUS to show his resolve and https t co 136aFanBkX <ORGANIZATION>OPINION House Homeland Security</ORGANIZATION> Chairman In <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> We Must Punish Assad <LOCATION>Iran Russia</LOCATION> and Destroy <ORGANIZATION>ISIS</ORGANIZATION> https t co LQg6X3YTLG POTUS orders <ORGANIZATION>National Guard</ORGANIZATION> to the southern border https t co SheF76PMez <ORGANIZATION>Border Patrol</ORGANIZATION> agents in <LOCATION>Santa Teresa New Mexico</LOCATION> were on horseback during the first day of construction for the new https t co jw0dEBOwxI Democratic strategist <PERSON>Chuck Rocha</PERSON> Nobody in <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> wants anybody coming here who wants to do harm to <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> https t co yEzV3XxEvv <LOCATION>Australia</LOCATION> vows investigation after 2 400 sheep die aboard death ship https t co IogneN6qpn PressSec The president and his national security team are consulting closely with allies and partners to determ https t co uVnLZd22jJ Man on Wheel of Fortune misses out on 7G after pronouncing Flamenco as Flamingo https t co BlbAO2P4YZ DiamondandSilk to facebook It s got to be fair on each side https t co mF6iYyhwTv https t co HzzelDrCW0 We would all be in legal jeopardy if <PERSON>Bob Mueller</PERSON> was after us <PERSON>Mother Teresa</PERSON> would be in legal jeopardy if <PERSON>Bob Mue</PERSON> https t co 4wBcAghT9X POTUS We are here to discuss <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> tonight We re making a decision as to what we do with respect to the horribl https t co liAnb3yexV Solar storm could strike <LOCATION>Earth</LOCATION> this week What you need to know https t co ji311frJMA dbongino They are not targeting a crime here They are targeting <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> https t co La3ORwr6eP https t co dURDdukQSY Man who ate world s hottest chili is hospitalized with excruciating headaches https t co 0nyUwMkjHM DiamondandSilk We see the corruption that s going on in <LOCATION>Washington</LOCATION> and we didn t like it That s why we voted https t co w3Hm1Z0d8j <LOCATION>Texas</LOCATION> begins deploying troops to southern border https t co Qh31DkytRf POTUS We need a wall It ll stop a lot of people that we don t want in this country from coming into our countr https t co 22bzujH04K <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> says <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> chemical attack will be met forcefully but won t say when https t co DZF3wuA3y1 JesseBWatters on <LOCATION>London</LOCATION> mayor enacting new knife restrictions It s turned into a joke What if you re just car https t co GAwCZgxssu DiamondandSilk to facebook What about our freedom of speech This is censorship You are censoring our voices https t co QXrrWc5F37 It s an attack on our country in a true sense It s an attack on what we all stand for President https t co ZSjKVQKLtC POTUS Why don t I just fire Mueller Well I think it s a disgrace what s going on We ll see what happens A https t co hhiMyy5Xng nikkihaley shames <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> after suspected chemical attack We are on the edge of a dangerous precipice https t co bzu9etHyLX <PERSON>Douglas MacGregor</PERSON> retired <ORGANIZATION>Army</ORGANIZATION> colonel <PERSON>Donald Trump</PERSON> said he would control the border It s time to put the mil https t co 0cR4LLRtNh <LOCATION>Texas Arizona New Mexico</LOCATION> pledge hundreds of USNationalGuard troops for <LOCATION>US</LOCATION> Mexico border https t co hvSeiOvini AlanDersh <PERSON>Michael Cohen</PERSON> cooperated completely and what did they get for it A raid on the office with everyt https t co aBe3hG8iBI <ORGANIZATION>Trump</ORGANIZATION> attacks <PERSON>Mueller</PERSON> witch hunt as WH source calls investigation out of control https t co gRjnV2OAbV POTUS It s a disgraceful situation It s a total witch hunt I ve been saying it for a long time https t co aKfUFqHfhI On Monday FLOTUS joined by <PERSON>BetsyDeVos</PERSON> held a discussion at the <ORGANIZATION>WhiteHouse</ORGANIZATION> with students regarding issues they https t co HJTaXRpcE9 Woman s armless legless body found in NYC park https t co 2GrvB11vDS <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> s Xi promises to cut auto import tariff warns against Cold War mentality https t co 1iRoyLUyrk LindseyGrahamSC If President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> didn t work with the Russians the American people will see through all t https t co 8IRYPe6c2y FrankLuntz on midterm elections Democrats are more activated than they ve been for no reason other than to send https t co 2MMm9K3Kdw dbongino They are not targeting a crime here They are targeting <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> https t co La3ORwr6eP https t co csDsR3c4CE Attorney <PERSON>Harmeet Dhillon</PERSON> on <ORGANIZATION>FBI</ORGANIZATION> raid targeting <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> s attorney This is outrageous and unprecedented https t co U3yLMQA3FO dbongino We would all be in legal jeopardy if <PERSON>Bob Mueller</PERSON> was after us <PERSON>Mother Teresa</PERSON> would be in legal jeopard https t co YjrMQqRdBi <PERSON>Solomon Wisenberg</PERSON> on <PERSON>Cohen</PERSON> raid It is outstandingly aggressive https t co La3ORwr6eP IngrahamAngle https t co TNdZ6eFDv3 DiamondandSilk to facebook It s got to be fair on each side https t co mF6iYxZW1X https t co 5VsUTw06pT DiamondandSilk We see the corruption that s going on in <LOCATION>Washington</LOCATION> and we didn t like it That s why we voted https t co 6PRcVPQU8h DiamondandSilk to facebook What about our freedom of speech This is censorship You are censoring our voices https t co aVrnB39nil <LOCATION>Virginia</LOCATION> woman accused of beheading boyfriend shouting let me get my heads https t co 92toeaO3j3 Ex AG <PERSON>Lynch Clinton</PERSON> tarmac talk was about innocuous things https t co AVx76nxcfU AlanDersh Deafening Silence of <ORGANIZATION>ACLU</ORGANIZATION> After Raid on <ORGANIZATION>Trump</ORGANIZATION> Lawyer Really Appalling https t co SDmG6MxnTT <PERSON>Mark McGwire</PERSON> says he definitely could have hit 70 home runs without PEDs report https t co VQ6zGwCkHt AlanDersh <PERSON>Michael Cohen</PERSON> cooperated completely and what did they get for it A raid on the office with everyth https t co CXMzGCJsUf <ORGANIZATION>Trump</ORGANIZATION> attacks <PERSON>Mueller</PERSON> witch hunt as WH source calls investigation out of control https t co gRjnV36bAv <LOCATION>Texas Arizona New Mexico</LOCATION> pledge hundreds of National Guard troops for <LOCATION>US</LOCATION> Mexico border https t co ylUPsovYST MarkSteynOnline If you don t have a security perimeter at the border you wind up having to have security perim https t co zLNBPAOBKi POTUS We need a wall It ll stop a lot of people that we don t want in this country from coming into our countr https t co CtH15DOzA9 We are on the edge of a dangerous precipice On Monday U S Ambassador to the <ORGANIZATION>United Nations</ORGANIZATION> nikkihaley slamme https t co qtmd6jnNAD <PERSON>Douglas MacGregor</PERSON> retired <ORGANIZATION>Army</ORGANIZATION> colonel <PERSON>Donald Trump</PERSON> said he would control the border It s time to put the mil https t co Hk2ohLdUzw seanspicer on Cohen Raid Trump Should Let Mueller Probe Play Out It s Not About Him https t co n5UBSHDwek SenJohnThune on <ORGANIZATION>Facebook Mark Zuckerberg Congress</ORGANIZATION> testimony Clearly there were lines that were crossed I thin https t co 8CrpPW7cVR <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> says <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> chemical attack will be met forcefully but won t say when https t co IM8pb2L4xS <LOCATION>California</LOCATION> appeals <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> victory on border wall https t co VnEZUeYPVn seanspicer My hope is that this investigation continues to be focused very broadly on Russian interference We c https t co PeWQLXF0dk POTUS Why don t I just fire Mueller Well I think it s a disgrace what s going on We ll see what happens A https t co LyIjKDcnYB POTUS We are here to discuss <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> tonight We re making a decision as to what we do with respect to the horribl https t co pxYcDD7EMX <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> slams <ORGANIZATION>FBI</ORGANIZATION> raid targeting attorney <PERSON>Michael Cohen</PERSON> calls <PERSON>Mueller</PERSON> investigation an attack on our country in https t co o0W5lnhK40 POTUS It s a disgraceful situation It s a total witch hunt I ve been saying it for a long time https t co uxt1kvovlo Sperm whale swallows 64 pounds of trash dies of gastric shock https t co rnR2s86dmo nikkihaley shames <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> after suspected chemical attack We are on the edge of a dangerous precipice https t co 7VGjt8AECI https t co pqEhmLhD8g founders accused of promoting prostitution money laundering https t co bsmKbYq41U JesseBWatters on <LOCATION>London</LOCATION> mayor enacting new knife restrictions It s turned into a joke What if you re just car https t co 3GI5SHfDR7 TheJuanWilliams on Parkland survivor blasting sheriff amp amp school From his perspective even if we never settle th https t co UoSkfYKtb4 FLGovScott s press secretary 33 dies in <LOCATION>Florida Keys</LOCATION> boat crash https t co u1Noj8mg4R <ORGANIZATION>FBI</ORGANIZATION> raids home office of <ORGANIZATION>Trump</ORGANIZATION> attorney <PERSON>Michael Cohen</PERSON> under scrutiny over <ORGANIZATION>Stormy Daniels</ORGANIZATION> payments via https t co iEZix1mxgI kimguilfoyle on alleged chemical attack in <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> Now this is an opportunity for POTUS to show his resolve and https t co 6JikwJNlU3 UPDATE <ORGANIZATION>FBI</ORGANIZATION> raids home office of <ORGANIZATION>Trump</ORGANIZATION> attorney <PERSON>Michael Cohen</PERSON> under scrutiny over <ORGANIZATION>Stormy Daniels</ORGANIZATION> payments https t co <ORGANIZATION>CJbWkVS79j Fleetwood Mac</ORGANIZATION> replacing <PERSON>Lindsey Buckingham</PERSON> before upcoming tour https t co fVF9Mp9opJ Opioid crisis worse than <PERSON>Pablo Escobar</PERSON> era ex <ORGANIZATION>DEA</ORGANIZATION> agents https t co c3DMnxYixV BREAKING Feds seize documents from <LOCATION>Trump</LOCATION> attorney <PERSON>Michael Cohen</PERSON> AP reports https t co AlkKHP0WVT nikkihaley We have reached the moment when the world must see justice done History will record this as the mom https t co PKo1hhqM84 nikkihaley What we are dealing with today is not about a spat between the <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> This is abo https t co UtEWInHzYg nikkihaley We must not overlook <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Iran</LOCATION> s roles in enabling the <PERSON>Assad</PERSON> regime s murderous destruction https t co wcfeCswMbG <ORGANIZATION>Teachers Union Threatens Wells Fargo Ditch NRA</ORGANIZATION> or Lose Our Business https t co RVPCKD9VBg JUST IN <LOCATION>Israel</LOCATION> gave heads up to <LOCATION>US</LOCATION> before launching airstrike on <LOCATION>Syria US</LOCATION> official says https t co 1nO6QysDyf <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> CEO <PERSON>Zuckerberg</PERSON> testimony too slow in <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> interference response via FoxBusiness https t co bsQw2mfxqL <PERSON>Brandon Judd</PERSON> When We Have the <ORGANIZATION>National Guard</ORGANIZATION> on the Border the Cartels Take Notice https t co WiInGzgyO0 Right to carry guns in schools case headed to <ORGANIZATION>Michigan Supreme Court</ORGANIZATION> https t co qFnfZPQdAO Gov Walker Democrats Rhetoric Ahead of Midterms Filled With Hatred and Anger https t co 3hO7y7q4ir New foam armor for tanks can pulverize enemies https t co LZQv9MQFJy PressSec The president wants to bring our troops home after we complete the mission to eradicate <ORGANIZATION>ISIS</ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> https t co vkJPE2gzaU PressSec The president and his national security team are consulting closely with allies and partners to determ https t co gtCxEaN9nc PressSec <PERSON>Sarah Sanders</PERSON> holds a briefing https t co YxMR6d0PDd SenBillNelson on <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> s upcoming testimony If we don t do something about this we re not going to ha https t co 90Dgie3h0M <LOCATION>Georgia</LOCATION> reignites longstanding feud over border with northern neighbors https t co HNQBOEfStS FLGovScott on dailybriefing We have to make sure we defend our own borders and defend the freedom of this coun https t co jB9CN4Uoqs FLGovScott on dailybriefing I believe that we can change <LOCATION>Washington</LOCATION> https t co etdgQ3PUtP https t co M5vF2Fem6G Ex AG <PERSON>Lynch Clinton</PERSON> tarmac talk was about innocuous things via brookefoxnews https t co Dv1DOgEbXi POTUS calls <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> chemical attack atrocious says U S to make major decisions in coming hours https t co TihuiGkTVR Hiker Meets Reindeer Herd in <LOCATION>Cairngorms National Park</LOCATION> in <LOCATION>Scotland</LOCATION> https t co hOowjIx64X <PERSON>Brandon Judd</PERSON> When We Have the <ORGANIZATION>National Guard</ORGANIZATION> on the Border the Cartels Take Notice https t co ekjweddTYh Gov ScottWalker Democrats Rhetoric Ahead of Midterms Filled With Hatred and Anger https t co wf9kbtInq6 Puppy in <LOCATION>Texas</LOCATION> Rescued After Getting Head Stuck in Car Wheel https t co rJwe7uUEpy POTUS orders <ORGANIZATION>National Guard</ORGANIZATION> to the southern border https t co 0RXkQA4C3x <LOCATION>US</LOCATION> Attorney <PERSON>John Lausch</PERSON> to oversee <ORGANIZATION>FISA</ORGANIZATION> warrant document release via brookefoxnews JakeBGibson https t co U6X5kS5ZCD Solar storm could strike <LOCATION>Earth</LOCATION> this week What you need to know https t co ji311frJMA <LOCATION>US</LOCATION> Attorney <PERSON>John Lausch</PERSON> to oversee <ORGANIZATION>FISA</ORGANIZATION> warrant document release https t co 9WPO96H5iu Secretary <PERSON>Mattis</PERSON> on <ORGANIZATION>Possible US Military Action Against Assad</ORGANIZATION> I Don t Rule Out Anything https t co <PERSON>RiGBLS5PQn Mattis</PERSON> faults <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> on <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> won t rule out <LOCATION>US</LOCATION> strike https t co wOB9EKByH9 POTUS We need a wall It ll stop a lot of people that we don t want in this country from coming into our countr https t co 55wEoECcWe POTUS We re putting the <ORGANIZATION>National Guard</ORGANIZATION> and military at the border We re beefing up the border patrol https t co JGa4JiYLZE POTUS on trade <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> has been taking advantage of the <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> for many years They have really done a num https t co XbqM27U4AX POTUS on the alleged <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> chemical attack It was an atrocious attack it was horrible We ll be making some ma https t co NLaDnkB6fs Richardafowler on escalating trade tension between <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> and the U S https t co cEPZmWKl72 Alex Conant Everyone loses in a trade war https t co pPKIsqKU3f RT FoxBusiness Dow at session highs https t co I7RKNQgnlb https t co 6GPmRL0K23 Shirtless daredevil draped in American flag climbs 200 foot crane in <LOCATION>Hollywood</LOCATION> https t co LObFSY5JsF Breaking News Body of <LOCATION>Tennessee</LOCATION> double murder suspect believed to be found sheriff says https t co lEbAZCvlrf Toddler on <ORGANIZATION>American Airlines</ORGANIZATION> flight hit in head with oxygen canister that fell from ceiling during landing https t co BO5ZoXFtDO <PERSON>Brandon Judd</PERSON> When we have the National Guard on the border the cartels take notice https t co zQ5dC38M6D It s going to be a huge boon <PERSON>Brandon Judd</PERSON> on USNationalGuard troops heading to the southern border https t co HpdVpSk2WD <LOCATION>Texas</LOCATION> Gov on Sending Nat l Guard to Border There s a Mathematical Need For This https t co zaGRhlMHdb Horse trailer carrying at least 18 illegal immigrants crashes in <LOCATION>Southern California</LOCATION> https t co vDBNYCcCfP Mac Thornberry We ve got to do whatever it takes to have planes that fly and have training that is appropriate fo https t co PxyBSYRb7e Mac Thornberry What we do speaks much more clearly than what we say and to show <PERSON>Putin</PERSON> and <PERSON>Assad</PERSON> and everybody el https t co pXOMQvtSfZ Mac Thornberry We cannot fix <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> We have to work with our allies to try to keep a lid on things https t co VaXqZgzSTW <PERSON>Tony Robbins</PERSON> apologizes for MeToo comments https t co <ORGANIZATION>NDTXRdhvmr Mac Thornberry Syria</ORGANIZATION> is a cauldron of security concerns for all sorts of countries https t co UjnLduMUV4 https t co b3lTjMkMql RT FoxBusiness SecretaryPerry Now because of American innovation American technology we are now in the driver s seat when it comes RT FoxBusiness SecretaryPerry Fracking horizontal drilling completely changed the dynamic out there in the world from the standpoint <PERSON>Meghan Markle</PERSON> Prince <PERSON>Harry</PERSON> ask for donations to charities as wedding gifts https t co UPI4eSKubw Homeless residents brag about makeshift mansion near <LOCATION>Seattle</LOCATION> s famed Space Needle https t co O3WadCSrqE <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> must shape up or it will be broken up senator warns https t co Q8Rozj7Hrr fntech via christocarbone Topless woman charges at <PERSON>Bill Cosby</PERSON> as he arrives for sex assault retrial https t co 7ekE4V4H7F SecretaryPerry You ve got to have boots on the ground you ve got to have the technologies that s the reason t https t co nGnZTfWihb 73 year old survives crash through brick wall and down 10 foot drop https t co JH9HTBtN4u ScottWalker We protect our shores and our borders and I applaud the president for stepping up to take on illega https t co p97zi26qGq Hackers hit <LOCATION>Iran</LOCATION> with <LOCATION>US</LOCATION> flag and <PERSON>Don</PERSON> t mess with our elections warning https t co Wp8Qc5G4Si GovAbbott on foxandfriends <LOCATION>Texas</LOCATION> wants to ensure that we secure the border https t co fwGehxeoqM GovAbbott The people of <LOCATION>Texas</LOCATION> are very appreciative that the president of the <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> has recognized this https t co kMRze2Y37o <PERSON>Ronald Vitello</PERSON> Consequences matter We need to reduce the activity level at the border foxandfriends https t co IfOPglGQfx Cooler than average temperatures continue for the <LOCATION>Midwest</LOCATION> and Northeast via JaniceDean https t co ci8Hm7Q6Of JUST IN <LOCATION>Florida</LOCATION> GOP Gov <PERSON>Rick Scott</PERSON> running for <ORGANIZATION>Senate</ORGANIZATION> report says https t co hQgoeiQpsb <PERSON>Ronald Vitello</PERSON> on USNationalGuard at the southern border They re going to help us by adding capacity https t co oiOA1sIqWU RalphNorman I believe that the only thing that stops a bad guy with a gun is a good guy with a gun https t co eboQAn54i6 OPINION Want jobs <LOCATION>Nebraska</LOCATION> reforms have more people working fewer on welfare and food stamps via https t co t9QPR8HRKx LindseyGrahamSC on the suspected <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> chemical attack I think now <PERSON>Assad</PERSON> is a legitimate war criminal in the https t co nunsCfmgbG LindseyGrahamSC on the suspected <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> chemical attack We should make <PERSON>Assad</PERSON> pay a heavy price by destroying h https t co e9yFdSIgWJ <ORGANIZATION>Army</ORGANIZATION> identifies 2 killed in helicopter crash in <LOCATION>Kentucky</LOCATION> https t co O2k3izcQvA https t co wWVEuIaCpL <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> blames <LOCATION>Israel</LOCATION> for deadly airstrike on <PERSON>Assad</PERSON> base after alleged chemical attack https t co ttl3yWlLZf RLHeinrichs on the <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> chemical attack You can t allow chemical weapons to continue being used https t co CnW8ZaedJP Sen <PERSON>Jeff Flake</PERSON> s son seeks new civil trial against <PERSON>Joe Arpaio</PERSON> https t co rqc9nLB9Tm https t co RhieDXVfYz <LOCATION>Texas</LOCATION> Begins Deploying Troops to the Border https t co 9gYLu12hvH https t co VsUSbZhUtE <LOCATION>South Carolina</LOCATION> reps introduce bill to allow debate on secession over gun laws https t co xa9m1r0ptu Democratic strategist <PERSON>Chuck Rocha</PERSON> Nobody in <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> wants anybody coming here who wants to do harm to <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> https t co MYBFQmnRBu larry_kudlow tries to calm trade war fears but says <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> not bluffing about <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> tariffs https t co dUUt2Xc9G6 New high speed <LOCATION>Florida</LOCATION> train kills 4th person since launching service https t co bQAcrPIa3x <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> blames <LOCATION>Israel</LOCATION> for deadly airstrike on <PERSON>Assad</PERSON> base after alleged chemical attack https t co ttl3yWDmQN RepMcCaul I remember JohnKerry saying We took all their chemical weapons away Obviously not https t co x7G1yQlN19 NanHayworth Extreme vetting which has been applied to targeted nations that we know are the sources of terror https t co OV0e9TAMSN Child advocates ask <ORGANIZATION>FTC</ORGANIZATION> to investigate YouTube https t co vZEB4ezBGD <LOCATION>Texas</LOCATION> begins deploying troops to southern border https t co iKj4LWihu4 On foxandfriends cvpayne praised President realDonaldTrump s economic policies and their positive results for A https t co Cos9MFoHLP <ORGANIZATION>Delta</ORGANIZATION> passenger suffered painful cartilage damage after child on flight repeatedly kicked her she claims https t co bcvwOCIhxd National security analyst <PERSON>Ryan Mauro</PERSON> on Syrian chemical attack I see no other option besides military action https t co mbBmTmeoQH States sending troops to <LOCATION>Mexico</LOCATION> border https t co Zep3xNOoPF TheRealJohnHCox This criminal idea of the sanctuary state movement the people are upset about this because it https t co EGULsWk376 Hackers hit <LOCATION>Iran</LOCATION> with <LOCATION>US</LOCATION> flag and <PERSON>Don</PERSON> t mess with our elections warning https t co <ORGANIZATION>Wp8Qc5XGgS Army</ORGANIZATION> identifies 2 killed in helicopter crash in <LOCATION>Kentucky</LOCATION> https t co O2k3izcQvA https t co Zy0NMuT2el The lava lake at the summit of <LOCATION>Hawaii</LOCATION> s <LOCATION>Kilauea Volcano</LOCATION> bubbled and spat on the morning of April 4 The <ORGANIZATION>USGS Hawaii</ORGANIZATION> https t co edPWaWO7Fp SarahPalinUSA This is unprecedented all those elements of a perfect storm against the will of the people havin https t co 50FsSD8zBl <LOCATION>Arizona</LOCATION> mom arrested after toddler ate THC laced mac and cheese cops say https t co jQii3c6P4C https t co K5C9IRUSRU DOG OF ALL TRADES Besides being a detection dog <ORGANIZATION>Belle</ORGANIZATION> doubles as a fetch expert showcasing advanced skill by sna https t co WEJxOK3WHA larry_kudlow Look POTUS is great negotiator He has a whole history of that But in this process tariffs h https t co ddr3vFEmn4 <PERSON>Kyle Busch</PERSON> gets first win at <ORGANIZATION>Texas NASCAR</ORGANIZATION> race https t co PKCjX7kuUT TomFitton TheJusticeDept was a mess under <PERSON>Loretta Lynch</PERSON> This meeting was an indication or an example of the w https t co sM0FKs7CP4 Syrian media report missile attack <LOCATION>US</LOCATION> says it didn t fire https t co kYjEZvRJjl SarahPalinUSA on ObamaCare It s an atrocity https t co gb39DWQdUU elonmusk posts picture of BFR s main body tool to be used for interplanetary missions https t co prcYknD0jT cvpayne This last month we saw the second lowest unemployment rate for black Americans in history https t co MAmmH6WoBb POTUS and the economy https t co 844HTnymWT SarahPalinUSA on running for governor We had a lot of corruption going on in our state and people wanted it cl https t co xmE8GHaXmL DevinNunes on the chemical attack in <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> I haven t been briefed on this yet but obviously it s very troublin https t co s2M4bT3z2Z The Latest Syrian monitors say 14 killed in air base strike https t co VwGz1EbzDx U S demanding <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> end Syrian support after poison gas attack kills dozens activists and medics say https t co cNAcRL4uo4 SarahPalinUSA on her vice presidential run I would do it again in a heartbeat https t co 9dhXbbodpd We re not used to leaders that stand up and be tough On foxandfriends Nigel_Farage compared President https t co 7Ayny95bHm larry_kudlow on tariffs <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> s response was highly unsatisfactory and I think that s unfortunate We do have c https t co HqPG4Hb77g Earlier <PERSON>MayorofLondon Sadiq Khan</PERSON> vowed to get tough on knife violence as the number of stabbing murders rapidly r https t co 3SizlzosOO AlanDersh President realDonaldTrump Won t Repeat Fmr President <PERSON>BarackObama</PERSON> s Tragic Mistake With <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> Red https t co UH37YfRTZ8 Former South Korean President <PERSON>Lee Myung</PERSON> bak charged with corruption https t co JEX6EjfgbQ SarahPalinUSA We have every God given right that s codified in our Bill of Rights to protect ourselves https t co XQEbG1H3CZ FrankLuntz I think the Republicans are in deep trouble in the <ORGANIZATION>House</ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION>Senate</ORGANIZATION> as well If the election wer https t co tcTnklGZyO <PERSON>Brandon Judd</PERSON> We want to once and for all secure the border so that we don t have to continue to sit here and say https t co UfHLYLSNsE A large Canadian flag at half mast is seen from a cemetery in <LOCATION>Humboldt Saskatchewan</LOCATION> 15 people traveling with the https t co rb1xNjbhWN SarahPalinUSA It s obvious why TheDemocrats don t believe in securing the border I think that they just fear https t co 9sILJ2d0xx The <ORGANIZATION>Rio Grande Valley Sector</ORGANIZATION> graduated eight new horse agents for its Horse Patrol Unit The Horse Patrol Unit uses https t co 84w17Cw6Vy JudgeJeanine It s Time for Republicans to <ORGANIZATION>Start Wielding Power</ORGANIZATION> https t co IpEU7L5UtG https t co Vpsm4EBCUN On <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> s <ORGANIZATION>News HQ</ORGANIZATION> former <LOCATION>Arizona</LOCATION> GovBrewer slammed <LOCATION>California</LOCATION> JerryBrownGov s illegal immigration policies https t co VdEqR4TDFT DiamondandSilk If a privately owned bakery has to go against their Christian values to bake a cake then Mark Z https t co eo8EPKc7rP Lt Gen H <PERSON>Steven Blum</PERSON> Ret The only people that view this as a threat are the coyotes and the cartels and j https t co GATvZWMqtj <LOCATION>Canada</LOCATION> town grieves after road crash decimates youth team https t co ClouPDtjVH GovBrewer It s absolutely unfortunate not only for <LOCATION>California</LOCATION> but for our country that we have people in elec https t co LpZl4gLzHJ RT FoxBusiness JUST IN Novartis to buy AveXis for 8 7 billion https t co HsAVhwuRHL If we have thousands and thousands of people trying to come into our country we have to protect our border On https t co 6Qkroyg7wZ Former ICE official <PERSON>Tommy Kilbride</PERSON> These landing mat fences don t work So anybody that says the wall won t work https t co AH30Qwl6kr Man hailed as a real life <ORGANIZATION>Disney</ORGANIZATION> prince after 70 pound weight loss goes viral on <LOCATION>Reddit</LOCATION> https t co IZ9Ml5Z4pE TomiLahren on the state of the GOP Why is it always the Right that has to become more moderate No I don t thi https t co XMdKVqScNw <ORGANIZATION>Hero Humbolt Broncos</ORGANIZATION> player taken off life support to donate organs https t co iGIwTPexpu AntonioSabatoJr on immigration debate The <ORGANIZATION>Democratic Party</ORGANIZATION> is always saying Well if you want a border if you https t co onmo4XdKBy Survivors of <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> chemical attack forced to leave or die https t co J1nyGPjS40 hogangidley45 The number one function of the federal government is to protect the American people President Do https t co xU8fl4vvdd Senator <PERSON>Jeff Flake</PERSON> s son seeks new civil trial against <PERSON>Joe Arpaio</PERSON> https t co rqc9nLSKKU RepDeSantis on FISA warrants Both TheJusticeDept and the <ORGANIZATION>FBI</ORGANIZATION> have tried for months and months to deemphasize https t co htKCBY7mHu robertjeffress The reason Evangelicals overwhelmingly support POTUS is not because he has a perfect past None https t co pKgPICqx8m Illegal immigration is not a race it s an activity And it s an activity that Americans should not believe in sh https t co eVyulmpRMM Sheriff <PERSON>Mike Jolley</PERSON> I can t see what the problem is with saying Merry Christmas or In God we trust or We s https t co sY1piIqIab Volcanic lightning is seen above <LOCATION>Shinmoedake</LOCATION> peak as the peak erupts between <PERSON>Miyazaki</PERSON> and <LOCATION>Kagoshima</LOCATION> prefectures so https t co hCV8YbRowU TomiLahren on immigration debate Americans are going to be safe in the <LOCATION>United States of America</LOCATION> https t co 4VbPiAHhJg DiamondandSilk to facebook Why are you censoring two women of color two black women https t co MXXB32gl5C <LOCATION>North Korea</LOCATION> has told the realDonaldTrump administration that <PERSON>Kim Jong Un</PERSON> is ready to discuss denuclearization of t https t co bCB1FuEnHE Rain or shine soldiers keep watch over the <LOCATION>Tomb of the Unknown Soldier</LOCATION> to honor the service members who made the u https t co YCGkAOVmC2 FrankLuntz It s POTUS s own tweets that are causing so much of the trouble He should be focused on the ec https t co 57MKdp2BRb kdeleon This President realDonaldTrump and this Attorney General <PERSON>Jeff Sessions</PERSON> their policies are driven https t co 11Iqe6IHtC RepMcCaul When the drug cartel sees our military down there it s going to stop them before they can get in https t co 0c4FEiQiJn SarahPalinUSA This is unprecedented all those elements of a perfect storm against the will of the people havin https t co nar1gngbbn <PERSON>Moose</PERSON> kicks man in <LOCATION>Alaska</LOCATION> after he kicked first https t co Gxun8jLsu5 A Quiet Place surprises with second biggest opening of 2018 behind Black Panther https t co TzesDpbKlU TGowdySC I think we could see a second special counsel https t co ZmoH6aaa3i On foxandfriends TheRealJohnHCox the leading Republican candidate for governor of <LOCATION>California</LOCATION> talked about the https t co pXELTL5glS On foxandfriends JudicialWatch President <PERSON>TomFitton</PERSON> said that AGLynch needs to be candid about the infamous tar https t co ECWHE4oBWx Injuries in human smuggling crash on <LOCATION>California</LOCATION> highway https t co fEmixKpCEP kdeleon Sending military men and women who are highly trained to protect Americans not just on American soil b https t co am4bF8veuM JudgeJeanine Who do we blame for the repeated trashing of FLOTUS Why is it open season on the First Family W https t co SMfg3TK3rr SarahPalinUSA We have every God given right that s codified in our Bill of Rights to protect ourselves https t co Zh2NvfKeZ5 SarahPalinUSA I see that war does to an individual to a family War is hell and I don t want <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> to go to https t co yyYxr9skZ7 On foxandfriends cvpayne praised President realDonaldTrump s economic policies and their positive results for A https t co L2kfZR7PAJ SarahPalinUSA It was past agendas that were based on special interests that have gotten us into the pickle that https t co cTWs6zqZN6 SarahPalinUSA President realDonaldTrump was adamant about doing things different in the campaign and that s https t co EK2RMKIQX5 SarahPalinUSA It s obvious why TheDemocrats don t believe in securing the border I think that they just fear https t co 7XdAYQqXxe Citizens Have a Right to Protect Themselves GA Sheriff Explains Viral Concealed Carry Sign https t co e5UpJWvP0D SarahPalinUSA on ObamaCare It s an atrocity https t co 3mo7MCnCsy SarahPalinUSA on omnibus bill That s why people are so up in arms when it comes to the direction of our governm https t co C7ieLuxAyD TheRealJohnHCox This criminal idea of the sanctuary state movement the people are upset about this because it https t co b2c2Qbe23k SarahPalinUSA I m privileged to have come into my own politically speaking during the <PERSON>Reagan</PERSON> years so I kne https t co 3bmCf7J2WI SarahPalinUSA on vice presidential run I would do it again in a heartbeat https t co mAlKDniX8a BREAKING Airstrikes hit <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> after deadly chemical attack state TV reports https t co YPf4Xv727K SarahPalinUSA on running for governor We had a lot of corruption going on in our state and people wanted it cl https t co WjKJ2iQjO6 TomiLahren on <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> trade war fears When the <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> leads from the front others come to the table We r https t co H8sT9qtstp RIGHT NOW on Life Liberty amp amp Levin SarahPalinUSA sits down with marklevinshow to discuss the border Tune in https t co H6cgmHCDGp OPINION Divorce is an epidemic that causes as much pain as any disease so why don t we treat it that way https t co 4hpTBLlxJ6 TomiLahren on the state of the GOP Why is it always the Right that has to become more moderate No I don t thi https t co pDaOwjuF8d Schwarzenegger <LOCATION>California</LOCATION> is coming back economically right now and hopefully we get to this four percent tha https t co CZ8rWrluqT TomiLahren on immigration debate Americans are going to be safe in the <LOCATION>United States of America</LOCATION> https t co z8AwlkO3ch AntonioSabatoJr on immigration debate The <ORGANIZATION>Democratic Party</ORGANIZATION> is always saying well if you want a border if you https t co eErO7mcoM7 Earlier <PERSON>MayorofLondon Sadiq Khan</PERSON> decried the uptick in stabbings that have raised <LOCATION>London</LOCATION> s homicide rate higher t https t co mySxOGNLk8 RepDeSantis on suspected <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> chemical attack There s not an appetite to have a ground war in that region https t co exylvH2vBE <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> warns Assad Big price to pay for fatal <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> attack https t co 89YDwXM5Cv <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> national security spokesman <PERSON>Michael Anton</PERSON> to leave the <ORGANIZATION>WhiteHouse</ORGANIZATION> https t co <PERSON>QcwMRiCZho Anheuser Busch</PERSON> debuts summery new Bud Light Orange https t co OdJArWGqI9 Sketch released in severed head case in <LOCATION>Texas</LOCATION> man sought https t co zrgu5aWc0O Gas prices jump to 2 74 per gallon https t co tjCwMlwaDI Manhunt for <LOCATION>Tennessee</LOCATION> man 23 who admits he killed his mother and his friend https t co wsxEPP5w36 Lyft driver abandons pilot in parking lot after learning he would only make 6 on ride https t co lKigZYnIia OPINION Has the <LOCATION>California</LOCATION> backlash against liberal craziness finally begun https t co qfrnE8DGds <LOCATION>London</LOCATION> Mayor <PERSON>Sadiq Khan</PERSON> targets knives as murder rate spikes There is never a reason to carry a knife https t co NY8C3D3NPy <LOCATION>Florida</LOCATION> woman caught with cocaine in purse blames it on windy day police say https t co DwvnksWJ5V <LOCATION>Hungary</LOCATION> leader <PERSON>Viktor Orban</PERSON> sweeps to re election win with super majority https t co oKTpx7ZBgy TONIGHT on Life Liberty amp amp Levin SarahPalinUSA sits down with marklevinshow to discuss the border Tune in at https t co zYDzhZ2KsP <PERSON>Sergei Yulia Skripal</PERSON> to get new identities to live in the <LOCATION>US</LOCATION> report says https t co <PERSON>K5t4Bs5OEB Crowley</PERSON> says <ORGANIZATION>GOP</ORGANIZATION> attacking NancyPelosi because bankrupt on ideas mum on plan to lead <ORGANIZATION>House</ORGANIZATION> caucus https t co 5I5bLbnlWH <ORGANIZATION>Delta</ORGANIZATION> passenger suffered painful cartilage damage after child on flight repeatedly kicked her she claims https t co NFM6j0lNxM TheRock to give away largest HQ Trivia prize ever https t co lNkkTtva2V <PERSON>Pruitt</PERSON> slammed as unfit to lead <ORGANIZATION>EPA</ORGANIZATION> by 2 <ORGANIZATION>GOP</ORGANIZATION> senators one calls him chucklehead https t co rePg4vRBpb <LOCATION>Florida</LOCATION> woman 23 killed by lightning at mud bog site https t co 75NAzcd7RD On Friday the CBPRGV welcomed eight new horses to the Horse Patrol Unit The wild Mustangs will be part of the te https t co iPHdqBqaSG larry_kudlow on tariffs <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> s response was highly unsatisfactory and I think that s unfortunate We do have c https t co w99MtLhcIX OPINION <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> attack shows we now live in a world where using chemical weapons is considered OK and that should https t co <ORGANIZATION>xV7d1u7kC3 Cambridge Analytica</ORGANIZATION> whistleblower thinks <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> data breach affected more users than reported https t co HAAbSOQ5oZ BREAKING <PERSON>Patrick Reed</PERSON> wins Masters to claim first major title https t co v1Y6lRcSga New high speed train in <LOCATION>Florida</LOCATION> kills 4th person since launching service https t co qDOkQjSDaS OPINION Do convicted criminals deserve a second chance One man s incredible story offers a clue https t co 25M6oOhxaQ <PERSON>Conor McGregor</PERSON> was causing trouble in hotel room after release on bail report says https t co LNaRCOOHIa Parkland massacre survivor says she hid under dead classmate s body https t co 0aIJndwxS6 On <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> s <ORGANIZATION>News HQ</ORGANIZATION> former <LOCATION>Arizona</LOCATION> GovBrewer slammed JerryBrownGov s illegal immigration policies and praised https t co jMZqqsJP1V cvpayne This last month we saw the second lowest unemployment rate for black Americans in history https t co <ORGANIZATION>6Ls7sqgZkL RT FoxBusiness Facebook</ORGANIZATION> to send <ORGANIZATION>Cambridge Analytica</ORGANIZATION> data use notices on Monday https t co EJLtiXUt2G <PERSON>Brandon Judd</PERSON> I have to applaud President realDonaldTrump for putting the USNationalGuard on the border because https t co 4uRviSLXh5 DEVELOPING <LOCATION>North Korea</LOCATION> has told the realDonaldTrump administration that <PERSON>Kim Jong Un</PERSON> is ready to discuss denuclear https t co mMmIqNvaud Blooming red tulips are seen in the gardens of the <LOCATION>South Lawn</LOCATION> of the <ORGANIZATION>WhiteHouse</ORGANIZATION> https t co 5tbQb72pjG RT EricShawnTV Chemical weapons were banned by the 1925 Geneva Protocol after their horrific use in World War One It is an attack on wor Rain or shine soldiers keep watch over the <LOCATION>Tomb of the Unknown Soldier</LOCATION> to honor the service members who made the u https t co rB1qmAgE4X <PERSON>Kim Jong</PERSON> Un willing to discuss getting rid of <LOCATION>North Korea</LOCATION> s nukes <LOCATION>US</LOCATION> says https t co Gh5W2f8Ea7 RT foxnewspolitics <PERSON>Kennedy</PERSON> dynasty faces a reckoning as controversial film hits theaters via brookefoxnews https t co IRLIK1G7f2 Lt <ORGANIZATION>Col Travis Walters TexasGuard</ORGANIZATION> is able to deploy immediately to meet the call of our governor and the call o https t co pXZnKP88Fw DiamondandSilk If a privately owned bakery has to go against their Christian values to bake a cake then Mark Z https t co NUgKC7p4FJ BREAKING NEWS <LOCATION>North Korea</LOCATION> has told the realDonaldTrump administration that <PERSON>Kim Jong Un</PERSON> is ready to discuss denucl https t co rt9bQNZIBv NY Times Op Ed slamming Chappaquiddick film as character assassination spurs online outrage https t co 51am3hJGgV Tommy Kilbride These landing mat fences don t work So anyone that says the wall won t work has never been on the https t co trVC5RNsK3 TomFitton TheJusticeDept was a mess under <PERSON>Loretta Lynch</PERSON> This meeting was an indication or an example of the w https t co xl47PvFyaN On foxandfriends former political science Professor carolmswain sounded off on a <LOCATION>North Carolina</LOCATION> elementary schoo https t co B8BZ0amlzn BREAKING <LOCATION>North Korea</LOCATION> tells the <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> administration that it is ready to discuss denuclearization https t co gR9KrFO9gw States sending troops to <LOCATION>Mexico</LOCATION> border https t co lROHVeMd6u Amb <PERSON>Dan Gillerman</PERSON> on <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> suspected chemical attack I m disappointed at the reaction so far of the internationa https t co ASRalWh3Hq <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> slams <PERSON>Obama</PERSON> over not crossing red line in <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> with Animal Assad https t co FZVYN2pmON TONIGHT on Life Liberty amp amp Levin SarahPalinUSA sits down with marklevinshow to discuss the border Tune in at https t co 6q5mzImK8S Outrage at <PERSON>Kimmel</PERSON> comments on <PERSON>Melania</PERSON> surges as protest petition exceeds 50K signatures https t co riRjV4TDX4 <PERSON>Wallace</PERSON> Presses Dem Rep Is <PERSON>Nancy Pelosi</PERSON> a Liability for Democrats https t co RnQDsoSwKQ A large Canadian flag at half mast is seen from a cemetery in <LOCATION>Humboldt Saskatchewan</LOCATION> on Sunday April 8 2018 15 https t co Wo12db9hiQ A firefighter looks out from the window of a damaged apartment in <LOCATION>Trump Tower</LOCATION> in <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> on Saturday April 7 201 https t co GbVHvxh0hi The <ORGANIZATION>USArmy</ORGANIZATION> has identified the two pilots killed in an Apache helicopter crash night at <ORGANIZATION>Ft Campbell Ky</ORGANIZATION> as Chief https t co IX3m9sRudo Sen <PERSON>Jeff Flake</PERSON> s son seeks new civil trial against <PERSON>Joe Arpaio</PERSON> https t co rqc9nLB9Tm RT EricShawnTV I anchor at 4 pm EDT FoxNews with ArthelNeville Amb <PERSON>Dan GIllerman</PERSON> joins me on how POTUS realDonaldTrump should respo <PERSON>Jimmy Kimmel</PERSON> defends mean spirited dig at <PERSON>Melania Trump</PERSON> apologizes for lewd <PERSON>Hannity</PERSON> joke https t co nDUlZflGz1 Alleged potted plant serial killer may be linked to grisly unsolved 1970s murders https t co PyoBhghZfX <LOCATION>Trump Tower</LOCATION> fire victim was prominent art dealer friends with <PERSON>Andy Warhol</PERSON> https t co ENvsX7P2Po On foxandfriends TheRealJohnHCox the leading Republican candidate for governor of <LOCATION>California</LOCATION> talked about the https t co w5RvPGupsg <PERSON>Kudlow</PERSON> tries to calm trade war fears but says <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> not bluffing about <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> tariffs https t co dUUt2XtL4G KatrinaPierson Rips MichelleObama For Comparing President realDonaldTrump to Bad Parent https t co i5YUgeOqGX Victims slowly identified in Canadian hockey team bus crash disaster death toll rises to 15 https t co XO2PX5Hdt5 AlanDersh President realDonaldTrump Won t Repeat Fmr President <PERSON>BarackObama</PERSON> s Tragic Mistake With <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> Red https t co 3hF4HUBKMJ KarlRove on border security There are things along the border that the <ORGANIZATION>National Guard</ORGANIZATION> can do in a moment like t https t co KBWLTbuIiS Ala teen turns down 25 year plea deal gets sentenced to 65 years instead and laughs https t co pueYqOQ9tk <PERSON>Michael Needham</PERSON> For 20 years liberal elites have promised us that if we just integrate <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> into the global trad https t co uDqskeLdQN <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> must shape up or it will be broken up senator warns https t co Q8RozjpiiZ via christocarbone <PERSON>Joe Crowley</PERSON> on 2018 midterms Voters have an opportunity here to change course and correction that s the beauty https t co tBkOZzpk7x Joe Crowley The notion of the tax cut is going to lead to somehow help the American people along I think is a sca https t co iV1n2roaQN GovBrewer It s absolutely unfortunate not only for <LOCATION>California</LOCATION> but for our country that we have people in elec https t co va4Sgwq03r JudgeJeanine It s Time for Republicans to <ORGANIZATION>Start Wielding Power</ORGANIZATION> https t co IpEU7L5UtG https t co BDl4Ch10a8 POTUS and the economy FoxNewsSunday https t co iu4Jtpp8X4 RT EricShawnTV I anchor FoxNews with ArthelNeville at 4 pm EDT The brazen vote hacking by <LOCATION>Moscow</LOCATION> It was the Russians it may not be larry_kudlow on cutting spending I think the <ORGANIZATION>Republican Party</ORGANIZATION> on the <LOCATION>Hill</LOCATION> has finally figured out It s really n https t co viEFlwOJXk <LOCATION>Berlin</LOCATION> half marathon attack plot foiled 6 detained officials say https t co Ta03VbuEyf larry_kudlow Look POTUS is great negotiator He has a whole history of that But in this process tariffs h https t co og6BFQu8W4 larry_kudlow on tariffs <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> s response was highly unsatisfactory and I think that s unfortunate We do have c https t co SjGUp9gESa On foxandfriends cvpayne praised President realDonaldTrump s economic policies and their positive results for A https t co ngeFIXxfu0 Car slams into <LOCATION>Texas</LOCATION> home triggering gas explosion and injuring 5 people via travfed https t co AfkA6UoaEP JudgeJeanine Who do we blame for the repeated trashing of FLOTUS Why is it open season on the First Family W https t co ejSgX4XtmX AlanDersh President realDonaldTrump Won t Repeat Fmr President <PERSON>BarackObama</PERSON> s Tragic Mistake With <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> Red https t co DBmOx7EvPj On <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> s <ORGANIZATION>News HQ</ORGANIZATION> former <LOCATION>Arizona</LOCATION> GovBrewer slammed <LOCATION>California</LOCATION> JerryBrownGov s illegal immigration policies https t co fD7dapFV6R On foxandfriends <LOCATION>Harris County</LOCATION> Sheriff <PERSON>Mike Jolley</PERSON> who recently posted a sign outside the sheriff s office that https t co Nj36krRPcr robertjeffress The reason Evangelicals overwhelmingly support POTUS is not because he has a perfect past None https t co BIF5gnrDIA Disgusted mom discovers used needles on <ORGANIZATION>McDonald</ORGANIZATION> s baby changing table https t co b6pJ9t29Ve Citizens Have a Right to Protect Themselves GA Sheriff Explains Viral Concealed Carry Sign https t co AInt7rwbx3 <LOCATION>Berlin</LOCATION> half marathon attack plot foiled 6 detained officials say https t co 7tLI5e7v5u https t co hp1EOvXFJ6 <PERSON>Elizabeth Hurley</PERSON> slammed for wearing cleavage baring dress with her 16 year old son https t co hG2osQzsf5 TheRealJohnHCox This criminal idea of the sanctuary state movement the people are upset about this because it https t co snCudXuYsI Fire at <ORGANIZATION>Trump Tower</ORGANIZATION> leaves one man dead several firefighters injured BryanLlenas reports https t co nNnUbhorwR On foxandfriends JudicialWatch President <PERSON>TomFitton</PERSON> said that AGLynch needs to be candid about the infamous tar https t co j7ZGExKRTb cvpayne This last month we saw the second lowest unemployment rate for black Americans in history https t co pcyPRMezaX Pro gun rights activists rally against new measures on firearm sales in <LOCATION>Vermont</LOCATION> https t co d90JsaUjGS President realDonaldTrump slams former Preisdent <PERSON>BarackObama</PERSON> over not crossing red line in <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> with Animal A https t co 9xcIMbqpLi <LOCATION>Trump Tower</LOCATION> fire victim was prominent art dealer friends with <PERSON>Andy Warhol</PERSON> https t co ENvsX7P2Po RepMcCaul <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Iran Complicit</LOCATION> in <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> Chemical Attack https t co qMDZp854AC https t co wSAICfMoSh President realDonaldTrump attacks garbage washingtonpost calls <PERSON>Kelly</PERSON> story hit job https t co 3E6edclo30 TONIGHT on Life Liberty amp amp Levin SarahPalinUSA sits down with marklevinshow to discuss the border Tune in at https t co sc5DQqk7Sv On <ORGANIZATION>Twitter VP</ORGANIZATION> <PERSON>Mike Pence</PERSON> backed up President realDonaldTrump s condemnation of a suspected chemical attack in Sy https t co sUYgvqdvxo Lt Gen H <PERSON>Steven Blum</PERSON> Ret The only people that view this as a threat are the coyotes and the cartels and j https t co oXLG7iabFY Body recovered near <LOCATION>California</LOCATION> cliff crash site may be one of the missing <PERSON>Hart</PERSON> children https t co doPkiMcdex TomFitton TheJusticeDept was a mess under <PERSON>Loretta Lynch</PERSON> This meeting was an indication or an example of the w https t co <ORGANIZATION>JgHWUcCTil RT</ORGANIZATION> EricShawnTV I anchor FoxNews with ArthelNeville at 12 Noon EDT POTUS realDonaldTrump calls out <PERSON>Vladimir Putin</PERSON> for the suspected S FrankLuntz It s POTUS s own tweets that are causing so much of the trouble He should be focused on the ec https t co XGIbrWFzaT FrankLuntz I think the Republicans are in deep trouble in the <ORGANIZATION>House</ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION>Senate</ORGANIZATION> as well If the election wer https t co xyCpb4Sl9k <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> slams <PERSON>Obama</PERSON> over not crossing red line in <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> with Animal Assad https t co FZVYN2pmON MZHemingway We have a media that is obsessed with palace intrigue MediaBuzz https t co OaK9EhfEfE Citizens Have a Right to Protect Themselves GA Sheriff Explains Viral Concealed Carry Sign https t co W4d4UYyRPC Russian hack of 2016 voter rolls leaves <LOCATION>Galesburg Illinois</LOCATION> reeling https t co 1D8e8Ab9uU Outrage at <PERSON>Kimmel</PERSON> comments on <PERSON>Melania</PERSON> surges as protest petition nears 50K signatures https t co riRjV4TDX4 RepMcCaul I remember JohnKerry saying We took all their chemical weapons away Obviously not https t co QFnt9kVPTY RepMcCaul When the drug cartel sees our military down there it s going to stop them before they can get in https t co tLRD5XlhTb RepMcCaul This cannot stand in the civilized world SundayFutures MariaBartiromo https t co 5Ckpt8UPBw RepMcCaul I also blame <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Iran</LOCATION> I think they re complicit with this SundayFutures MariaBartiromo https t co UdSpv3WNye RepMcCaul I remember JohnKerry saying We took all their chemical weapons away Obviously not https t co 9H0185LjnO RepMcCaul It s a humanitarian crisis it s barbaric There has to be a consequence to this SundayFutures https t co IQ7QFeCjQf TGowdySC I think we could see a second special counsel SundayFutures MariaBartiromo https t co YyDV8NRL2v RepMcCaul Since last year crossings have gone up 200 last month up nearly 40 I think this bold action by https t co xEfjpi5Fac RepMcCaul When the drug cartel sees our military down there it s going to stop them before they can get in https t co vQFv6AFTtL President realDonaldTrump responds to <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> poison gas attack which has killed at least 40 according to activists https t co KxoZ7c6Ls9 RT FoxNewsSunday On the possibility of running for Speaker if Democrats take the <ORGANIZATION>House</ORGANIZATION> after 2018 Midterms repjoecrowley tells <PERSON>Chris DiamondandSilk</PERSON> If a privately owned bakery has to go against their Christian values to bake a cake then Mark Z https t co E7173gL0d8 DiamondandSilk on facebook Who makes a determination on what s unsafe https t co tWnR1jZS58 DiamondandSilk to facebook Why are you censoring two women of color two black women https t co I2gSsAicX0 RT FoxNewsSunday <ORGANIZATION>White House</ORGANIZATION> Chief Economic Adviser <PERSON>Larry Kudlow</PERSON> tells <PERSON>Chris We</PERSON> re not going to end up in a trade war https t co 3m kdeleon This President realDonaldTrump and this Attorney General <PERSON>Jeff Sessions</PERSON> their policies are driven https t co MErBUiocJk kdeleon Border crossings are in fact at a 50 year low https t co 6Yk7GVvjle kdeleon Sending military men and women who are highly trained to protect Americans not just on American soil b https t co 4sC6NRk9tK kdeleon We have a dysfunctional and we have a broken immigration system No question about it https t co smXIK4816p kdeleon What we want to do in <LOCATION>California</LOCATION> is make sure that those who enforce federal immigration laws will do t https t co I1LgPIMOP5 RT FoxNewsSunday On the possibility of running for Speaker of the <ORGANIZATION>House</ORGANIZATION> if Democrats take the <ORGANIZATION>House</ORGANIZATION> after 2018 Midterms repjoecrowley t COMING UP on <PERSON>SundayFutures MariaBartiromo</PERSON> speaks to TGowdySC Tune in at 10a ET on <ORGANIZATION>Fox News Channel</ORGANIZATION> https t co NhtqpPYoQl RT FoxNewsSunday On the 2018 Midterms repjoecrowley tells <PERSON>Chris</PERSON> I m confident that the American people want to bring balance back to t RT FoxNewsSunday On the Economy repjoecrowley tells <PERSON>Chris</PERSON> The notion that this tax cut bill is going to help the American people in th RT FoxNewsSunday On possible tariffs repjoecrowley tells <PERSON>Chris</PERSON> I do recognize that there is a role for tariffs in our economy but ther AlanDersh on the <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> gas attack We have an obligation in the name of humanity to prevent these killing from https t co Q28PCzEfXA RT FoxNewsSunday On proposed tariffs <ORGANIZATION>WH Economic Adviser</ORGANIZATION> larry_kudlow tells <PERSON>Chris</PERSON> The path to free trade has to include <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> acting i RT FoxNewsSunday On proposed tariffs <ORGANIZATION>WH Economic Adviser</ORGANIZATION> larry_kudlow tells <PERSON>Chris</PERSON> President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> has told me he likes and respects Pr RT FoxNewsSunday On proposed tariffs <ORGANIZATION>WH Economic Adviser</ORGANIZATION> larry_kudlow tells <PERSON>Chris</PERSON> President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> is not bluffing RT FoxNewsSunday On possibility of trade war <ORGANIZATION>WH Economic Adviser</ORGANIZATION> larry_kudlow tells <PERSON>Chris</PERSON> I know there s some jitters out there ther <LOCATION>Kentucky</LOCATION> pizza driver rescues two people from burning house https t co RGhYnS9Ahe <PERSON>John Cox</PERSON> <LOCATION>California</LOCATION> gubernatorial candidate I m a business leader We get things done we solve problems You https t co bPMwUqsYRT U S demanding <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> end Syrian support after poison gas attack kills dozens activists and medics say https t co gIPY4kD6sP Seven year old girl hikes <LOCATION>Mount Kilimanjaro</LOCATION> in honor of late dad breaks record https t co yk87LhyTKR <LOCATION>Galesburg Ill</LOCATION> reels from 2016 Russian hack of voter rolls https t co 1D8e8Ab9uU DevinNunes on the chemical attack in <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> I haven t been briefed on this yet but obviously it s very troublin https t co Dfi2tmrOMQ Country music star <PERSON>Jason Aldean</PERSON> makes special visit to <LOCATION>Las Vegas</LOCATION> shooting victim https t co g24pbX4Ryu <PERSON>Russell Crowe</PERSON> s divorce auction sells Gladiator armor other valuable movie gear https t co nCoE81lgJC <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> poison gas attack kills at least 40 activists and medics say https t co d924aMZguZ Sheriff <PERSON>Mike Jolley</PERSON> I can t see what the problem is with saying merry Christmas or in God we trust or we s https t co whfGpabP7L <LOCATION>Georgia</LOCATION> sheriff s concealed carry sign goes viral https t co QOKFWyqWef cvpayne There s no such thing as <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> starting a trade war We re in one we ve been losing one https t co <ORGANIZATION>LR3SlREaJj Lt Gen</ORGANIZATION> H <PERSON>Steven Blum Ret</PERSON> on USNationalGuard going to the southern border The only people who view this as https t co <ORGANIZATION>PXXfjcKUXT Lt Gen</ORGANIZATION> H <PERSON>Steven Blum Ret</PERSON> on <ORGANIZATION>National Guard</ORGANIZATION> going to the southern border This is a brilliant idea to use the https t co Q1ATxNJeof <ORGANIZATION>NHL</ORGANIZATION> players fans pay tribute to <ORGANIZATION>Humboldt</ORGANIZATION> bus crash victims https t co NSp0UihPJ7 <PERSON>Jill Colvin</PERSON> on impact of <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> trade war This isn t just the farmers the people producing these goods that are s https t co Q8OWBptKUc LindseyGrahamSC If you leave <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> now <ORGANIZATION>ISIS</ORGANIZATION> will come back like they did when we left <LOCATION>Iraq</LOCATION> It s gonna cost https t co rVY8BNmBLX <PERSON>Mary Anastasia O Grady</PERSON> We have a trade deficit amp amp we will have a trade deficit as long as we are richer than <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> https t co Sc3b01DBXN hogangidley45 The number one function of the federal government is to protect the American people President Do https t co R1i5K0DrCq <PERSON>Jill Colvin</PERSON> on trade tensions with <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> Most experts would agree that <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> is clearly not being a fair player o https t co 6lLIryhJGH On foxandfriends former political science Professor carolmswain sounded off on a <LOCATION>North Carolina</LOCATION> elementary schoo https t co YUt1gEH1ti On Cavuto Live former <LOCATION>Arizona</LOCATION> GovBrewer praised President realDonaldTrump for delivering on his promise to pro https t co vqej02cSso <PERSON>Tim Pawlenty</PERSON> announces he s running for his old job as <LOCATION>Minnesota</LOCATION> governor https t co 7JcJl7mLqv LindseyGrahamSC You gotta hit <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> in the wallet https t co RGjytEkhhY https t co tOdbyqI0lq <ORGANIZATION>Trump GOP</ORGANIZATION> plan to rescind budget spending has precedent but rocky path in <ORGANIZATION>Congress</ORGANIZATION> https t co V2h9NW4unv DarrellIssa Republicans want to make sure the border patrol has the tools it needs to be both safe and effect https t co A068IEw0Qz <LOCATION>Oklahoma</LOCATION> mom embarrassed her daughter s textbook was used by blakeshelton nearly 4 decades ago https t co DaoZYr4zqJ <PERSON>Jonathan Schanzer</PERSON> We need to take a look at the fact that we have an <ORGANIZATION>ISIS</ORGANIZATION> threat that is not waning and that we h https t co SIxPQTTOqo Shooting on adult themed party bus in <LOCATION>Illinois</LOCATION> kills 3 suspect sought https t co W82g9X9vku DOG OF ALL TRADES Besides being a detection dog <ORGANIZATION>Belle</ORGANIZATION> doubles as a fetch expert showcasing advanced skill by sna https t co 2mX3H7mOPh OPINION <LOCATION>San Diego</LOCATION> lawmaker says <LOCATION>California</LOCATION> has become rogue state https t co OXV6XG6CQD Lanhee Chen There should be no dispute that enforcing the laws we have on the books particularly those that pert https t co G5BIzvmaKy <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> poison gas attack kills at least 40 activists and medics say https t co d924aNgRmx <ORGANIZATION>Justice Department</ORGANIZATION> announces zero tolerance policy on illegal border crossings <PERSON>Anita Vogel</PERSON> has the story https t co eZFTg7Yjdm GovMikeHuckabee is in favor President realDonaldTrump s desire to send between 2 000 and 4 000 USNationalGuard https t co n3k5eiWg0p neelkashkari I m sympathetic with the need to push <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> to really engage in fair trade not just one sided tra https t co DzfMoxloXq Volcanic lightning is seen above <LOCATION>Shinmoedake</LOCATION> peak as the peak erupts between <PERSON>Miyazaki</PERSON> and <LOCATION>Kagoshima</LOCATION> prefectures so https t co <ORGANIZATION>Nz7s2pQutU Lt Col Travis Walters TexasGuard</ORGANIZATION> is able to deploy immediately to meet the call of our governor and the call o https t co mni03tKR7d Blooming red tulips are seen in the gardens of the <LOCATION>South Lawn</LOCATION> of the <ORGANIZATION>WhiteHouse</ORGANIZATION> https t co xPemSxX96d Reince I think <PERSON>Scott Pruitt</PERSON> is doing a great job https t co 7HfX14EJcg <LOCATION>Kansas</LOCATION> lawmakers boost school funding despite <ORGANIZATION>GOP</ORGANIZATION> s battles https t co CqbOJjc0SD MayorSamAbed <LOCATION>California</LOCATION> now is sanctuary for poverty for illegal immigration for illegal criminals We have 1 https t co mEgmVisIXy dbongino Dems Obstruct Border Security Because It Sells Well Amongst Radical Liberal Base https t co Ugwyc3n7W3 Man falsely accused of murder is awarded 10M https t co 1qkIgblp3n <PERSON>Brandon Judd</PERSON> on border security I have to applaud President realDonaldTrump for putting the USNationalGuard on https t co kWjmnVL3xa The <ORGANIZATION>Latest Kansas</ORGANIZATION> lawmakers pass 534M school funding plan https t co EzciVJfymb <PERSON>Ali Noorani</PERSON> on border security If you want to secure the border outside the ports of entry that s where you put https t co Tj6DVbTait Country music star <PERSON>Jason Aldean</PERSON> makes special visit to <LOCATION>Las Vegas</LOCATION> shooting victim https t co g24pbXmsq2 On foxandfriends Trump 2020 campaign senior adviser <PERSON>KatrinaPierson</PERSON> slammed former first lady MichelleObama afte https t co Th4DF0ByN1 Jim_Jordan We do need a second special counsel to get to the bottom of this entire FISA abuse that took place a https t co rnA7PYq57d hogangidley45 on border security We re working with <LOCATION>Mexico</LOCATION> and I think this is beginning to break up But wha https t co NnhXt0neVF Illegal border crossings up https t co 1OcoWYsMzS <PERSON>Brandon Judd</PERSON> We want to once and for all secure the border so that we don t have to continue to sit here and say https t co 8MIheeo3WF RepMarkMeadows calls on <ORGANIZATION>DOJ</ORGANIZATION> to hand over documents https t co nsjHOjV7kL JudgeJeanine RepDeSantis on FISA warrants Both TheJusticeDept and the <ORGANIZATION>FBI</ORGANIZATION> have tried for months and months to deemphasize https t co GoMXEg7YIs TrumpTower well built but lacks sprinklers on upper floors FDNY commissioner says https t co 428STwJzdo hogangidley45 on border security If <ORGANIZATION>Congress</ORGANIZATION> doesn t act POTUS will JudgeJeanine https t co 299ilorDKQ We re not used to leaders that stand up and be tough On foxandfriends Nigel_Farage compared President https t co Ci0w9WyLlp <PERSON>Brandon Judd</PERSON> on border security Most drugs are coming across the border between the ports of entry not through t https t co 6Aac7PQXqc Liberal Elitism KatrinaPierson Rips <PERSON>Michelle Obama</PERSON> For Comparing <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> to Bad Parent https t co 36FKWlzCHC PaulBabeuAZ If you re gonna send <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> s military to the southern border that s hard force <PERSON>Don</PERSON> t send a t https t co 7HtYXp71P9 Once wildly popular <LOCATION>Brazil</LOCATION> s <PERSON>da Silva</PERSON> is jailed for graft https t co 8eift8HfcV The <ORGANIZATION>Texas National Guard</ORGANIZATION> said on April 6 that they were mobilizing toward the <LOCATION>US</LOCATION> Mexico border after an announcemen https t co fv2bYhMvMZ Man crashes into <LOCATION>Miami</LOCATION> Police station https t co lYoCejjWHp At least one person died and four others were injured after a fire broke out in <LOCATION>TrumpTower</LOCATION> in <LOCATION>New York City</LOCATION> on Sat https t co aIhtxlRAay Yesterday President realDonaldTrump tweeted about bolstering security at our southern border https t co ZWDrxsAaCG Pressure tempers up in push for <LOCATION>Kansas</LOCATION> school aid increase https t co CqbOJjc0SD USNationalGuard sends troops to U S <LOCATION>Mexico</LOCATION> border https t co iGLLtNr3Wt https t co 3Z0nlFuWbU TrumpTower fire victim ID d as <PERSON>Todd Brassner</PERSON> art dealer who sold <PERSON>Warhol</PERSON> prints reports https t co CJPse0jmeY DiamondandSilk I think what s sexist is the fact that MichelleObama is trying to make women feel guilty for no https t co jOko3fCBZ6 We have to secure the border On WattersWorld <PERSON>Brandon Judd</PERSON> President of the <ORGANIZATION>National Border Patrol Council</ORGANIZATION> https t co WeWEJcSDk0 I really feel that God opened the door for our family to have that opportunity amp amp I just really wanted to express https t co 1A9hB5cZJu On <PERSON>Cavuto Live Escondido MayorSamAbed</PERSON> told <PERSON>TeamCavuto</PERSON> that he was fighting for our sovereignty against the https t co AKe1LsmNMX Nigel_Farage I think with <PERSON>Barack Obama America</PERSON> virtually disappeared off the world stage No one took <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> https t co pIryiIPkHo Fire erupts at <ORGANIZATION>TrumpTower</ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION>New York City</LOCATION> 1 fatality ID d at least 4 hurt https t co gUrouFtixK <PERSON>KatrinaPierson Has MichelleObama</PERSON> ever asked herself the simple question of Maybe middle class voters believe https t co QdeftbN9f1 JudgeJeanine It s time for Republicans to stop fighting with each other and start supporting the president https t co N8x5WcwSnZ USDOL U S economy added 103 000 jobs in March https t co pZcD6ADdgi https t co FXwqdkFyqg DiamondandSilk on <PERSON>Obama</PERSON> being the good parent BarackObama wanted to feed us some ObamaCare we got the <PERSON>Oba</PERSON> https t co anMOsRwRvq Nigel_Farage The liberal media they re so full of their own prejudice against <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> that even when he gets thi https t co ae7aoEMXvF YODELING KID Watch this young boy stun <ORGANIZATION>Walmart</ORGANIZATION> shoppers with his ear catching voice in a now viral video https t co nxx0ENTIL2 Why is it open season on the first family On Justice JudgeJeanine slammed Republicans stating they were to https t co yyml3TEwG7 West Virginian mom <PERSON>Jessica Hodge</PERSON> thanked POTUS for tax cuts I just really wanted to express to the president ho https t co 3wiHibShab At least 2 killed 20 injured after van plows through crowd in <LOCATION>Muenster Germany</LOCATION> https t co l5qZpHn2so Surgeon_General POTUS has made clear that one of his three priorities in regards to the opioid epidemic is sav https t co 2nLWq7QtJi MayorSamAbed If <LOCATION>California</LOCATION> is the only sanctuary state here we re going to be a magnet for criminals for pove https t co FYKaYz7L0Q <PERSON>Meghan Markle</PERSON> once starred in a Tostitos commerical https t co rgLwwqNfSv Rep <PERSON>Kevin Cramer</PERSON> expected to win <ORGANIZATION>GOP</ORGANIZATION> endorsement to seek <ORGANIZATION>North Dakota Senate</ORGANIZATION> seat https t co IspPexKKbF carolmswain I don t believe that causing one race to feel guilty about things that happened generations ago is https t co f09zfzxmmE TOMORROW on Life Liberty amp amp Levin SarahPalinUSA sits down with marklevinshow to discuss the Second Amendment https t co WxwVHqeXRy <ORGANIZATION>EPA</ORGANIZATION> says unprecedented number of death threats against <PERSON>Pruitt</PERSON> https t co R12Wx8pBOy The <ORGANIZATION>Vatican Museums</ORGANIZATION> offer early bird special to see its art https t co SJGU41Cbs7 Victims slowly identified in Canadian hockey team bus crash disaster death toll rises to 15 https t co XO2PX5Hdt5 <LOCATION>California</LOCATION> highway crash injures more than a dozen possible illegal immigrants reports say https t co MUJULws4e5 GovBrewer The first and foremost thing that government is responsible for is to keep our country sovereign and https t co g1q7M9u8XK Body suspected to be from <LOCATION>California</LOCATION> cliff crash found https t co m7EbD8AO4S Holocaust victim s heirs awarded Nazi looted paintings in landmark case https t co LQt88eLx1F Alleged potted plant serial killer may be linked to grisly unsolved 1970s murders https t co PyoBhghZfX <ORGANIZATION>Emily Blunt</ORGANIZATION> asked husband <PERSON>John Krasinski</PERSON> to fire another actress so she could appear in Quiet Place film https t co 6lb3vgWVSy The Latest <LOCATION>Kansas</LOCATION> lawmakers work on schools plan stalls https t co EzciVJx9KL <LOCATION>Georgia</LOCATION> sheriff s concealed carry sign goes viral https t co QOKFWyqWef <PERSON>MollyRingwald</PERSON> says her hit film The Breakfast Club is troubling in MeToo era https t co niLHZecUfy Man hailed as a real life <ORGANIZATION>Disney</ORGANIZATION> prince after 70 pound weight loss goes viral on reddit https t co IZ9Ml5Z4pE <PERSON>Russell Crowe</PERSON> s divorce auction sells Gladiator armor other valuable movie gear https t co nCoE81lgJC Shooting on adult themed party bus in <LOCATION>Illinois</LOCATION> kills 3 https t co zqLlRDwpjP Ala teen turns down 25 year plea deal gets sentenced to 65 years instead and laughs https t co Falh89eTHs OPINION <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> sanctions on <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> This is as far from collusion as you can get https t co S445JXvtT5 DarrellIssa Republicans want to make sure the border patrol has the tools it needs to be both safe and effect https t co 1rTmv1chYh newtgingrich <LOCATION>California</LOCATION> may elect a Republican governor Incredible as that sounds https t co DtIRNIh486 PaulBabeuAZ If you re gonna send <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> s military to the southern border that s hard force <PERSON>Don</PERSON> t send a t https t co hwP16JzXBA hogangidley45 on border security If <ORGANIZATION>Congress</ORGANIZATION> doesn t act POTUS will JudgeJeanine https t co de59FdFvqh JudgeJeanine It s time for Republicans to stop fighting with each other and start supporting the president https t co AljIXI8Yd5 hogangidley45 on border security We re working with <LOCATION>Mexico</LOCATION> and I think this is beginning to break up But wha https t co mVY3dL1dFZ At least one person died and four others were injured after a fire broke out in <LOCATION>TrumpTower</LOCATION> in <LOCATION>New York City</LOCATION> on Sat https t co Apx1KMnwOi <ORGANIZATION>Kroger</ORGANIZATION> is expanding restaurant chain https t co vDMh3OGoMX DiamondandSilk I think what s sexist is the fact that MichelleObama is trying to make women feel guilty for no https t co OOjtS0Agsa DiamondandSilk on <PERSON>Obama</PERSON> being the good parent BarackObama wanted to feed us some ObamaCare we got the <PERSON>Oba</PERSON> https t co 4sI9kWqmlO RepDeSantis on FISA warrants Both TheJusticeDept and the <ORGANIZATION>FBI</ORGANIZATION> have tried for months and months to deemphasize https t co Hy6caSttmo <LOCATION>Tennessee</LOCATION> prison brawl injures 11 two critically https t co CKHPrJ5rcB BREAKING 1 person killed in fire at <LOCATION>Trump Tower</LOCATION> in <LOCATION>NYC</LOCATION> officials say fire now under control https t co wdVIFDc6Gf RT FoxNewsResearch The U S economy added 103 000 jobs in March 2018 its 90th consecutive month of net growth Man hailed as a real life <ORGANIZATION>Disney</ORGANIZATION> prince after 70 pound weight loss goes viral on <LOCATION>Reddit</LOCATION> https t co sINHfCYg7Y <PERSON>Brandon Judd</PERSON> We want to once and for all secure the border so that we don t have to continue to sit here and say https t co KN7JOkp9kr <PERSON>Brandon Judd</PERSON> on border security I have to applaud President realDonaldTrump for putting the USNationalGuard on https t co zqRy8sgRY1 <PERSON>Brandon Judd</PERSON> on border security Most drugs are coming across the border between the ports of entry not through t https t co r4O51zdBCk <PERSON>Ali Noorani</PERSON> on border security If you want to secure the border outside the ports of entry that s where you put https t co LfjSMbkXVi TOMORROW on Life Liberty amp amp Levin SarahPalinUSA sits down with marklevinshow to discuss the Second Amendment https t co yHhB4u70zI Viral singing grocery store worker accepted to elite music school https t co i88hnfLfMo toddstarnes <LOCATION>San Diego</LOCATION> lawmaker says <LOCATION>California</LOCATION> has become rogue state https t co YDQdDeyhvn marcthiessen <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> is threatening to repeat <PERSON>Obama</PERSON> s mistakes https t co mhaI2Jdf81 <PERSON>Russell Crowe</PERSON> s divorce auction sells Gladiator armor other valuable movie gear https t co pcCxEeCgam JUST IN 3 firefighters 1 other person hurt in fire at <LOCATION>Trump Tower</LOCATION> in NYC https t co V0SMyno1bu FDNY on <LOCATION>Trump Tower</LOCATION> fire It s still not considered under control because of the smoke conditions on all the flo https t co 7xle5FFGeF FDNY There are no members of the first family in residence today https t co RcQVLe7Zu1 Moments ago <PERSON>EricTrump</PERSON> thanked the <ORGANIZATION>FDNY</ORGANIZATION> and NYPD for quickly extinguishing a fire in <LOCATION>Trump Tower</LOCATION> https t co sb6MiXNQh4 Parkland shooting hero blames sheriff and superintendent for failing to prevent massacre https t co 23jjJimAk6 <ORGANIZATION>Fmr Vanderbilt Prof Elementary School</ORGANIZATION> s White Privilege Flyer Meant to Instill Shame Guilt Among White Youth https t co N8wPrP0RPR TOMORROW on Life Liberty amp amp Levin SarahPalinUSA sits down with marklevinshow to discuss the border Tune in a https t co ejifTTNnB1 Pilots warned of safety concerns before helicopter crashed in NYC s <LOCATION>East River</LOCATION> and killed 5 report says https t co Vpu1u7ioD6 Seven year old girl hikes <LOCATION>Mount Kilimanjaro</LOCATION> in honor of late dad breaks record https t co 7UuoLVbWcQ Moments ago President realDonaldTrump thanked the FDNY for their swift action after a fire broke out in <LOCATION>Trump</LOCATION> To https t co BWI8quXPuN The NYPDnews and <ORGANIZATION>FDNY</ORGANIZATION> are on the scene of a fire on the 50th floor of <LOCATION>Trump Tower</LOCATION> https t co Hz3zrjSrGA https t co kyhXaaZMGu BREAKING The FDNY is battling a multi alarm fire on the 50th floor of <LOCATION>Trump Tower</LOCATION> in <LOCATION>New York City</LOCATION> https t co uh2R7NoSRK Victims slowly identified in Canadian hockey team bus crash disaster death toll rises to 15 https t co dDnMLSCjDD Fire erupts at <LOCATION>Trump Tower</LOCATION> in <LOCATION>New York City</LOCATION> https t co V0SMyno1bu susanferrechio If <PERSON>Pruitt</PERSON> goes whoever comes in is not going to be as aggressive rolling back the <ORGANIZATION>EPA</ORGANIZATION> regulatio https t co 8MQlf1ZLAz realDonaldTrump slams <ORGANIZATION>DOJ FBI</ORGANIZATION> over missed document deadline What is going on https t co iAvfAkQhNc RepKevinCramer expected to win <ORGANIZATION>GOP</ORGANIZATION> endorsement to seek <ORGANIZATION>North Dakota Senate</ORGANIZATION> seat https t co N8AQVi5cU2 POTUS zeroes in on tackling illegal immigration after spending bill criticism https t co XutrkLzr0N Volcanic lightning is seen above <LOCATION>Shinmoedake</LOCATION> peak as the peak erupts between <PERSON>Miyazaki</PERSON> and <LOCATION>Kagoshima</LOCATION> prefectures so https t co Qx6IAKOyap Earlier PressSec reiterated the <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> administration s dedication to keeping the U S <LOCATION>Mexico</LOCATION> border safe https t co herlbVAHIr Nigel_Farage In terms of foreign policy this president has been a huge success so far https t co 15VgjtLPNV Nigel_Farage I think with <PERSON>Barack Obama America</PERSON> virtually disappeared off the world stage No one took <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> https t co ykNWEuZdQT Reince I think <PERSON>Scott Pruitt</PERSON> is doing a great job https t co VL2nrFaAvv GovMikeHuckabee is in favor President realDonaldTrump s desire to send between 2 000 and 4 000 USNationalGuard https t co OjfpxX3rQp DiamondandSilk Long gone are the days that people can cross our borders and think they can rip away at the fabr https t co t99G0Q6EYR BREAKING Death toll in Canadian hockey team bus crash rises to 15 police say coach team captain reportedly amon https t co 7vMihjphnz Madness Family outraged that 4 teens sentenced to youth treatment after sandbag hits car kills man https t co WLOh2s4qQ0 Pilots warned of safety concerns before helicopter crashed in NYC s <LOCATION>East River</LOCATION> and killed 5 report says https t co PBqmLZmXtK I really feel that God opened the door for our family to have that opportunity amp amp I just really wanted to express https t co x498qR3eKL Nigel_Farage The liberal media they re so full of their own prejudice against <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> that even when he gets thi https t co KgMArH6HjT On <PERSON>Cavuto Live Escondido MayorSamAbed</PERSON> told <PERSON>TeamCavuto</PERSON> that he was fighting for our sovereignty against the https t co 0brGGMy65Y <LOCATION>California</LOCATION> deputy arrested for alleged unlawful sex acts with 2 inmates he committed https t co JkuV2JBMDG Crash of hockey team s bus leaves at least 14 dead town devastated https t co kpbosHhWTW https t co jwi5LMHdA1 <ORGANIZATION>Qantas</ORGANIZATION> former poster girl flight attendant reveals she was sexually harassed says issue is rampant across ind https t co jrbiy8TGjw RT FoxBusiness <ORGANIZATION>CBS</ORGANIZATION> said to plan all stock bid for <ORGANIZATION>Viacom</ORGANIZATION> below valuation https t co lW4rF8rsVI RT FoxBusiness LouDobbs <LOCATION>California</LOCATION> state government depending on your perspective are either making fools of themselves or their ci RT FoxBusiness High tax states are already taking a hit from next tax law <PERSON>Varney</PERSON> https t co Kb2XbLzSfT <PERSON>Jonathan Schanzer</PERSON> We need to take a look at the fact that we have an <ORGANIZATION>ISIS</ORGANIZATION> threat that is not waning and that we h https t co m3jf0XW7Ir <PERSON>Conor McGregor</PERSON> seen in new video shattering window amid bloody bus fight https t co RyMwYWpW0i USDOL U S economy added 103 000 jobs in March https t co pZcD6ADdgi https t co 4ZQadqDsYR RT EricShawnTV Can MarkZuckerberg fix <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> s troubles when he testifies before <ORGANIZATION>Congress</ORGANIZATION> next week At 6pm EDT FoxNews what steps More jobs than workers in <LOCATION>Elkhart</LOCATION> IN there are 9 000 job openings https t co FRfXHeZ3lL <ORGANIZATION>Texas Lt Gov Keep National Guard</ORGANIZATION> at the Border Until Hell Freezes Over https t co IDN4EVd7DM <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> zeroes in on tackling illegal immigration after spending bill criticism https t co xgukf5IXvH On foxandfriends former political science Professor carolmswain sounded off on 