<ner>OPINION <PERSON>Michael Goodwin Trump</PERSON> is putting the <LOCATION>US</LOCATION> back on top https t co i05vQsOwqu Moments ago President realDonaldTrump tweeted about <PERSON>Gina Haspel</PERSON> https t co 9vAKzemyzD https t co hkyMhoqJTg RichardGrenell The <LOCATION>Iran</LOCATION> deal needs to be fixed https t co BXI3ZGrff2 RichardGrenell The president won if you don t give someone a vote you re really undermining democracy He won https t co tAxjldYYtc RichardGrenell I wish every American can see the way <PERSON>Donald Trump</PERSON> negotiates He is a great negotiator https t co VBdXpBpr4U JUST IN <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> comes out against <PERSON>Blankenship</PERSON> in <ORGANIZATION>West Virginia Senate</ORGANIZATION> race says he can t win https t co <ORGANIZATION>bN6H1QD2cL Top Republican</ORGANIZATION> tells <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> to remain in nuclear deal with <LOCATION>Iran</LOCATION> https t co HdlvIjGIiS DineshDSouza <PERSON>Rosie</PERSON> broke the law and she broke the law five times https t co DbpYWI7pWT https t co Jf9JAMmae5 Grandma 70 shoots alleged home intruder Kill him before he kills me https t co Q2RMeLF2D1 https t co YWI1vR1g6c Game of Thrones star named 2018 World s Strongest Man https t co 8JWp08ycX4 dbongino The far left is in this never ending battle against religion and God https t co sKFmkI9I39 https t co kVT7glwx6N In God We Trust Motto Sparks Debate In <LOCATION>Minnesota</LOCATION> How About Bringing Respect Back In Schools https t co sKFmkI9I39 jasoninthehouse The improbable election of <PERSON>Donald Trump</PERSON> is not probable cause to pursue him https t co Di2LoGcOri Boy 13 regains consciousness after parents sign papers to donate his organs https t co xWjitNeRIR Lady Antebellum botches part of national anthem at <ORGANIZATION>NHL</ORGANIZATION> playoff game https t co DFXzeHnzh1 Federal judge accuses <PERSON>Mueller</PERSON> s team of lying trying to target <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> C mon man https t co fyVt88HWyo 50 live crocodiles seized at <LOCATION>Heathrow Airport</LOCATION> https t co GutFrZ0s5F <PERSON>Ken Jeong</PERSON> stopped a live show to provide medical attention to an audience member https t co 4Rz8AFBVLc <LOCATION>Dallas</LOCATION> restaurant s gun regulation message sparks controversy with <ORGANIZATION>NRA</ORGANIZATION> https t co <LOCATION>VNemsX1oWw Illinois</LOCATION> counties form sanctuaries for gun owners to thwart state s push for gun control https t co y4MUKFYydN <LOCATION>Florida</LOCATION> deputy responding to reported dispute shot critically wounded https t co V77ZTRXszI https t co E4mjnyA1Eq <PERSON>Christian Whiton</PERSON> I think <PERSON>John Kerry</PERSON> should be prosecuted under the Logan Act https t co pl7Z2L9dT9 https t co uvNnXG8ZLo FLOTUS to lay out initiatives supporting children today https t co vjL2MI9cix Emergency alert issued for residents near <LOCATION>Hawaii</LOCATION> volcano Go Now https t co z02jtRm7MV https t co ewQNYlwci5 <PERSON>Patrice Lee Onwuka</PERSON> Parents were overwhelmingly supportive of ensuring young people understand what our nation sta https t co Pp6HbkuPAt This is <ORGANIZATION>Unsustainable Group</ORGANIZATION> Pushes for <LOCATION>California</LOCATION> to Secede from <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> https t co CSKm3ADOVD https t co R47bWV3fU8 On foxandfriends DiamondandSilk called out what they called the very fake news the left wing media https t co cYvYa9Se46 Former AG <PERSON>Michael Mukasey</PERSON> We should see the memo https t co <ORGANIZATION>HVcePnt0oS British Airways</ORGANIZATION> passengers greeted at airport with live music whiskey after inaugural flight to <LOCATION>Nashville</LOCATION> https t co hSh3KU7lWj Attorney General <PERSON>Jeff Session</PERSON> and Ice Director head to southern border today https t co bCqafvEqmc GOPLeader NancyPelosi will not be Speaker Republicans will keep the majority https t co 5ifSehJW7R <PERSON>Rosie O Donnell</PERSON> s donations to Dems exceeded limit report https t co 5UkN5g7tgW <PERSON>John Cena</PERSON> and <PERSON>Nikki Bella</PERSON> share inspirational posts with fans on what would have been their wedding day https t co 2kp26xzVfC <PERSON>Mike Baker</PERSON> If it was any other administration that had chosen <PERSON>Gina Haspel</PERSON> I think they would be praised for a ro https t co gn1zHvQXXL Dennis_Kucinich Both party establishments are locked into yesterday https t co XKfO2RSbpN On foxandfriends realCandaceO made clear she has no time to be PC https t co 5vdRMF49NM https t co 0Bzx8TVErq VP <PERSON>Mike Pence</PERSON> to discuss <LOCATION>Iran</LOCATION> nuclear deal with U K https t co 0vmPuLIcvd <LOCATION>Hawaii</LOCATION> s volcanic eruption has destroyed at least 26 homes forced thousands to evacuate https t co PY9KqEdcwi https t co dciNemGuGN <LOCATION>Florida</LOCATION> deputy in critical condition after being shot responding to reported dispute https t co V77ZTRXszI https t co Crgm8xm4MD World War II veteran graduates college https t co HPfKUUpUOU DiamondandSilk People are tired of the very fake news the left wing media spreading lies I mean deliberatel https t co IgebpmClD7 RealCandaceO I blame <PERSON>Obama</PERSON> his 8 years in office did a lot of damage in terms of race relations in this countr https t co ChBVWoppcM <PERSON>Rudy Giuliani</PERSON> on <PERSON>Mueller</PERSON> probe The only crimes committed here have been committed by the government https t co <ORGANIZATION>MDBkoKOH6v Former AG Michael Mukasey</ORGANIZATION> This investigation was launched initially in a flawed way https t co jOOxDmPWKc Deployed military unit surprises soldier s daughter with cheer routine https t co P0DCw9MCJc dbongino I would never want a Republican to do to a Democrat what they re doing to realDonaldTrump now https t co pQMFO65Ohp <LOCATION>Dallas</LOCATION> restaurant s gun regulation message sparks controversy with <ORGANIZATION>NRA</ORGANIZATION> https t co VNemsX1oWw After a young giraffe was rejected by her mother she has learned how to stand on her own feet <LOCATION>South Australia</LOCATION> s M https t co R7aLpdWhD5 On foxandfriends Congressman <PERSON>SteveScalise</PERSON> discussed the midterm elections stating that Republicans have the ec https t co L23mceoSJC <PERSON>Rudy Giuliani</PERSON> Attorney General Sessions should step up and dismiss this entire investigation https t co JRPHb4xPiL An adventurer in <LOCATION>Canada</LOCATION> set sail down a driveway as high winds and severe thunderstorms swept across <LOCATION>Ontario Canad</LOCATION> https t co ugakOIY4xW <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> doctor pleads guilty in fatal abortion https t co gt25hGx4Mn dbongino <PERSON>Bob Mueller</PERSON> is effectively the most powerful person in the world right now because the Constitution is https t co d0t0MgPYri Lady Antebellum botches part of national anthem at <ORGANIZATION>NHL</ORGANIZATION> playoff game https t co DFXzeHnzh1 https t co uLMmkA9xLU michaeljknowles Illegal immigration is illegal We know that 60 80 of women and girls who cross the border https t co TOiK1Xgn2d SebGorka on HillaryClinton She s a disaster that s why she lost GregGutfeldShow https t co YgDyttc3Wb Comedian sorry for edgy joke hoping Warriors star gets shot in the face https t co pwY0HQmtxn <PERSON>Joe diGenova Mueller</PERSON> is investigating to impeach That is an unconstitutional position for him to be in https t co AD0Hiwo5oP Woman s 18 bet on <ORGANIZATION>Kentucky Derby</ORGANIZATION> day wins 1 2 million https t co uI0UwQ4AKH Dramatic video shows inside the evacuated <ORGANIZATION>Leilani Estates</ORGANIZATION> where lava erupting from <LOCATION>Hawaii</LOCATION> s powerful <LOCATION>Kilauea</LOCATION> volca https t co <LOCATION>OjmRTQaJgQ Illinois</LOCATION> counties form sanctuaries for gun owners to thwart state s push for gun control https t co y4MUKGg95l DevinNunes We have to move quickly to hold the Attorney General of the <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> in contempt and that s wha https t co 6l3snqqH9L <PERSON>Ken Jeong</PERSON> stopped a live show to provide medical attention to an audience member https t co 4Rz8AFTwCK dbongino on special counsel investigation This has been a witch hunt from the start https t co TZ4QJu27tG People react to <ORGANIZATION>MeghanMarkle</ORGANIZATION> and Prince <PERSON>Harry</PERSON> postponing their royal honeymoon https t co 0DjJ2FzbSX Joe diGenova on <PERSON>Mueller</PERSON> investigation They re investigating a person not a crime and in so doing it is the most https t co sMLYBa9ijW On Life Liberty amp amp <PERSON>Levin</PERSON> dbongino claimed Democrats are not only setting up a path for impeachment they re al https t co htIXVASv1X JudgeJeanine It s time to end the <PERSON>Mueller Comey Rosenstein</PERSON> cabal for once and for all https t co Abe8pCpJcE RealCandaceO For so long black conservatives have not been able to have a voice https t co voMeZnbpcf 50 live crocodiles seized at <LOCATION>Heathrow Airport</LOCATION> https t co GutFrZ0s5F KatrinaPierson I do think a lot of people are shocked to see just how in your face that a lot of these agenci https t co hzZGyNSq3x <ORGANIZATION>NHL</ORGANIZATION> warns <PERSON>Bruins Brad Marchand</PERSON> to stop licking opponents https t co jrgwoeWDCR https t co YdXyRQ3cSt GOPLeader There was no collusion SundayFutures MariaBartiromo https t co <ORGANIZATION>RyjSAYLU8k College</ORGANIZATION> football player who died in <LOCATION>Mexico</LOCATION> was murdered family says https t co S6jJAmt7sG dbongino I think the entire <PERSON>Mueller</PERSON> operation is a smoke screen to keep the attention on realDonaldTrump and https t co 2mHsK2pTND Reince I was the Chief of Stuff POTUS is the Chief of Staff https t co k1Tv8pLYBb SteveScalise We worked very hard with President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> to get this economy moving again after 8 years of <PERSON>Barack</PERSON> https t co OWQqT1ssRx Poll average POTUS approval rating now vs December https t co KeqVbq5q6A Dems Remove In God We Trust from schools https t co sKFmkIriUH https t co gt7snBtOan <PERSON>WhiteHouse</PERSON> says <PERSON>Gina Haspel</PERSON> <ORGANIZATION>CIA</ORGANIZATION> nomination won t be derailed by partisan critics after reports she offered to w https t co Z4B4FuAjEe On Twitter DineshDSouza weighed in on a report that liberal comedian and inveterate realDonaldTrump adversary https t co gmy5soKc3m Joe diGenova on <PERSON>Manafort</PERSON> raid <PERSON>Bob Mueller</PERSON> should be ashamed of himself to allow that to happen on his watch https t co zsg2wqF0F7 SebGorka on the <LOCATION>Iran</LOCATION> deal As far as I m concerned the deal is dead https t co CqD5AHWL7I <LOCATION>Hawaii</LOCATION> s volcanic eruption has destroyed at least 26 homes officials say https t co PY9KqEuNnQ RLHeinrichs This is about for <PERSON>John Kerry</PERSON> preserving a legacy It is not about pursuing U S national interest https t co 8DEAzaHZWt More than 60 years after last attending class <PERSON>Bob Barger</PERSON> a 96 year old World War II veteran received his college https t co zVDzJBqD4q RepGallagher Term limits are a way of getting us back to that model of the citizen legislator that the framers https t co Uq2yoPOl1g A nine year old passes the American flag while carrying an airsoft gun in a holster at an open carry firearm rally https t co Ts3p5Ny4VE POTUS If you don t have borders you don t have a country https t co aiUOyRGXkV On foxandfriends RealCandaceO blamed former President <PERSON>BarackObama</PERSON> and others in the <ORGANIZATION>Democratic Party</ORGANIZATION> for racial https t co Q1qhKzfJE5 SebGorka I just want to know now after this report came out about <PERSON>Kerry</PERSON> colluding this is collusion this is https t co Z6mHR453fV This is <ORGANIZATION>Unsustainable Group</ORGANIZATION> Pushes for <LOCATION>California</LOCATION> to Secede from <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> https t co CSKm3ADOVD https t co O5DfLLZ4ck Earlier today FLOTUS <PERSON>Melania Trump</PERSON> revealed that tomorrow she ll make a major announcement at The WhiteHouse https t co W4C4eAJPbm GOPLeader Not only did <LOCATION>Iran</LOCATION> get billions of dollars they spent that money fostering terrorism around the wor https t co VHdJ15uABj Joe diGenova The president will not sit down for an interview because this investigation has now reached the leve https t co uMIFjaR2Vz World War II veteran graduates college https t co Zwejahyct0 JoeLieberman on JohnKerry What he s doing is inappropriate https t co R6emtwrlow On foxandfriends DiamondandSilk called out what they called the very fake news the left wing media https t co krvUShHEJU MariaBaritiromo <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> has been stealing from <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> for years on years We have not pushed back on it https t co EGf81fT5CD dbongino <PERSON>Mueller</PERSON> s sole purpose right now is to run a smoke screen while investigating <PERSON>Donald Trump</PERSON> to protect https t co F1AjiDo32g <PERSON>Don Gorske</PERSON> the Big Mac Man When I bit into that first Big Mac it was just so good and I just knew I was going https t co 2qMnInraUP Joe diGenova The only thing that President realDonaldTrump did wrong in firing <PERSON>Comey</PERSON> was that he didn t do it I https t co y7leAIKu3m dbongino I would never want a Republican to do to a Democrat what they re doing to realDonaldTrump now https t co 0c9zShuWTj <PERSON>Joe diGenova</PERSON> on <PERSON>Mueller</PERSON> investigation They re investigating a person not a crime and in so doing it is the most https t co sKWtIhGQyZ On foxandfriends SebGorka praised President realDonaldTrump for getting tough on <LOCATION>Iran</LOCATION> https t co Cl32Iacq9H https t co t9WDHoO5N0 <PERSON>Joe diGenova Mueller</PERSON> is a tool of that vast group of people who cannot stand <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> who want to destroy him https t co HTx1kV0HSG dbongino <PERSON>Bob Mueller</PERSON> is effectively the most powerful person in the world right now because the Constitution is https t co vQcbG7ElPM dbongino on <PERSON>Mueller</PERSON> investigation This is an ongoing negative advertising campaign against the president https t co eSRtMGfb9V dbongino Not only are the Democrats setting up one path for impeachment they re also setting up a path to https t co BqTJSabrpK <LOCATION>Florida</LOCATION> deputy responding to reported dispute shot critically wounded https t co 7sLex7glzh DiamondandSilk People are tired of the very fake news the left wing media spreading lies I mean deliberatel https t co dBd9RnRxgk <PERSON>Joe diGenova Mueller</PERSON> is investigating to impeach That is an unconstitutional position for him to be in https t co NyNHHhjn8m charliekirk11 Republican victories in 2018 midterms are a sure bet if they play to win like realDonaldTrump https t co P1YISrB5C5 dbongino I think the entire <PERSON>Mueller</PERSON> operation is a smoke screen to keep the attention on realDonaldTrump and https t co X6tNaRxl7O dbongino on special counsel investigation This has been a witch hunt from the start https t co Uex9UN9tJ0 Grandma 70 shoots alleged home intruder Kill him before he kills me https t co hP4MrNpDMH <PERSON>Joe diGenova</PERSON> I don t think there s any question that the <PERSON>Mueller</PERSON> investigation as it sits now is illegitimate https t co YLbxWNvrqN MichelleObama still questioning why women voted for <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> in 2016 https t co oohoGwNXPO <LOCATION>Hawaii</LOCATION> s volcanic eruption has destroyed at least 26 homes officials say https t co SEcEkLri0d KatrinaPierson We have career politicians because our electorate isn t very informed on what they re doing https t co c8BeFFVHI6 reihan If 2016 taught us anything it is that there is a deep well of discontent and unless we start thinking https t co wmwIVNbvaj <ORGANIZATION>OPINION Supreme Court</ORGANIZATION> case could give public employees more freedom https t co PDQgI6OPpR <ORGANIZATION>GOP</ORGANIZATION> outsider <PERSON>Blankenship</PERSON> emerges as factor in <ORGANIZATION>West Virginia Senate</ORGANIZATION> race ahead of 4 state primaries Tuesday https t co owk2EvOzuh reihan on POTUS critics What they try to do is become best selling authors they try to become celebrities t https t co H35NRGNFu4 KatrinaPierson I do think a lot of people are shocked to see just how in your face that a lot of these agenci https t co 1NTYdANmGR netanyahu to visit <PERSON>Putin</PERSON> for talks on <LOCATION>Mideast</LOCATION> developments https t co sGdZShWzzf Van Hipp For the first time we have a president who has actually dealt with the North Korean threat https t co KwZSEaGtoe TUNE IN KatrinaPierson joins SteveHiltonx on NextRevFNC on <ORGANIZATION>Fox News Channel</ORGANIZATION> https t co qZYAOHdUNI <PERSON>SteveHiltonx Mueller</PERSON> probe is a political counter revolution to overthrow <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> It must be defeated https t co mn1Nu0R6fb How <PERSON>Robin Williams</PERSON> was being torn apart and couldn t fight back https t co rJq9hWnTra taylorswift13 surprised a young fan at the <LOCATION>Arizona Burn Center</LOCATION> after learning the 8 year old girl wouldn t be abl https t co x4mTvfVhr6 <LOCATION>Hawaii</LOCATION> volcanic eruption destroys home of single mother of 2 https t co hm3284AvAn RT FoxNewsResearch Longest streaks of months with positive job growth 1 91 and counting Oct 2010 Apr 2018 2 48 July 1986 SebGorka I just want to know now after this report came out about <PERSON>Kerry</PERSON> colluding this is collusion this is https t co E8nRRtvYcC <PERSON>Bill Murray</PERSON> reveals gender of <LOCATION>Florida</LOCATION> couple s baby on the golf course https t co VHRBs8ETCZ BREAKING At least 21 homes destroyed as powerful Hawaiian volcano continues to spew lava officials say https t co PoD2KPb8Ei TUNE IN Legends amp amp Lies The Civil War Ulysses S Grant Intoxicated By War hosted by <PERSON>Brian Kilmeade</PERSON> on <PERSON>Fox</PERSON> https t co p5OR6UXTcd guypbenson My suspicion is realDonaldTrump is happy to have someone in his corner who s a fighter and who s https t co E9cjj7GRLs GOPLeader NancyPelosi will not be Speaker Republicans will keep the majority SundayFutures MariaBartiromo https t co FPK7eC5DGY TONIGHT KatrinaPierson joins SteveHiltonx on NextRevFNC at 9p ET on <ORGANIZATION>Fox News Channel</ORGANIZATION> https t co oDoT0YNsvg Exploding vape pen may have caused deadly <LOCATION>Florida</LOCATION> house fire investigators say https t co esbsplXf6V On foxandfriends SenatorDanHall denounced the Democrats who challenged his bill to allow the national motto In https t co UiiwoA7SwM <PERSON>Lanny Davis</PERSON> on <PERSON>Rudy Giuliani</PERSON> Number one is don t make matters worse for a client and I think by what he said on t https t co 5OFBv2VnR5 On FoxNewsSunday President realDonaldTrump s former attorney <PERSON>Joseph diGenova</PERSON> said the president will not meet wi https t co tJ4LJF35hR Game of Thrones star ThorBjornsson_ named 2018 WorldsStrongestMan https t co O1MzdMDmLo <PERSON>Joseph diGenova</PERSON> on Stormy Daniels payment What matters here is that the payment was legal It was for personal re https t co <ORGANIZATION>aAZZ476m9z College</ORGANIZATION> football player who died in <LOCATION>Mexico</LOCATION> was murdered family says https t co 5D0lxYvDNu In God We Trust Motto Sparks Debate In <LOCATION>Minnesota</LOCATION> How About Bringing Respect Back In Schools https t co Fpn2y4qHfQ People react to <PERSON>Meghan Markle</PERSON> and Prince <PERSON>Harry</PERSON> postponing their royal honeymoon https t co Qwrszs64YF <PERSON>Rudy Giuliani</PERSON> There is a good chance that three long time hostages in <LOCATION>North Korea</LOCATION> will be released over the next https t co M4RSQ5PMrs WH says <PERSON>Gina Haspel</PERSON> <ORGANIZATION>CIA</ORGANIZATION> nomination won t be derailed by partisan critics after reports she offered to withdraw https t co E35jNDgq6h <PERSON>Eliza Collins</PERSON> We do know that <PERSON>Mueller</PERSON> wants to interview POTUS I imagine that <PERSON>Giuliani</PERSON> s comments this week jus https t co <ORGANIZATION>K4I0ZZsHRx West Virginia Senate</ORGANIZATION> candidate <PERSON>Morrisey</PERSON> says <PERSON>Blankenship</PERSON> should be disqualified for failing to submit financial dis https t co Z2tbeGK23k Rule requiring new vehicles to have rearview technology goes into effect https t co q7ylngERxD OPINION Military training and energy security are not a zero sum decision https t co NFAq8PRym7 PlanetTyrus on why <PERSON>HillaryClinton</PERSON> lost the presidential election It s very simple more people voted for him t https t co xwnKaYieuJ RealCandaceO I blame <PERSON>Obama</PERSON> his 8 years in office did a lot of damage in terms of race relations in this countr https t co U0wG3MrcWx Earlier today FLOTUS <PERSON>Melania Trump</PERSON> revealed that tomorrow she ll make a major announcement at The WhiteHouse https t co n0T4flTG1n SecretaryAcosta The <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> economy has created since his election 3 2 million new jobs https t co Q8R3zAgUiH On Twitter DineshDSouza weighed in on a report that liberal comedian and inveterate realDonaldTrump adversary https t co x7CUNxH1t1 Joe diGenova The president will not sit down for an interview because this investigation has now reached the leve https t co xD2crWN6YG Business Owner <PERSON>Sherry Sheely</PERSON> to President realDonaldTrump We felt with your strong leadership that now was the https t co xi8ORM9q9N cvpayne on unemployment numbers These numbers are absolutely remarkable https t co nVFiJTn2SW <PERSON>Giuliani</PERSON> says <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> doesn t need to comply with <PERSON>Mueller</PERSON> subpoena <PERSON>Cohen</PERSON> may have paid off other women https t co aIBCTwNBK9 Newborn suffers skull fractures after getting hit with softball at ballfield https t co KHcsQJoF4a <LOCATION>Dallas</LOCATION> restaurant s gun regulation message sparks controversy with <ORGANIZATION>NRA</ORGANIZATION> https t co rGRzmaqsbK RepGallagher Term limits are a way of getting us back to that model of the citizen legislator that the framers https t co lrqWq2TQRt mzhemingway <ORGANIZATION>CNN</ORGANIZATION> has had a series of problematic stories on the overall story of <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> collusion and investiga https t co kbinXoKtMo Avengers Infinity War scores second highest week 2 ever becomes fastest film to break 1 billion https t co hDNOKvKMzp PastorDScott The African American community is not against the president https t co tbVXGlmxBT DevinNunes We have to move quickly to hold the Attorney General of the <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> in contempt and that s wha https t co YcfsQBvVGk Van Hipp For the first time we have a president who has actually dealt with the North Korean threat https t co qnjSYHZsBi <PERSON>Sharlene Thornton</PERSON> to President realDonaldTrump I do want to thank you Mr President https t co 50Tdyt0W3R This Is Real Collusion <PERSON>Gorka Blasts Kerry</PERSON> for Reported Shadow Diplomacy to <ORGANIZATION>Save Iran Deal</ORGANIZATION> https t co 05r95qnm4t Do What the President Would Do GregGutfeldShow on Teen s Racist Prom Dress https t co YWT0QOgGmD shanvav on Tuesday s primaries If all these candidates are linking themselves to POTUS and <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> s approval ra https t co jCnBfOOI8g Poll average POTUS approval rating now vs December https t co MTwpeMGbZO <PERSON>Caroline Pelosi</PERSON> on T S <PERSON>Ellis</PERSON> This is the first time really in open court we ve ever seen in a court of law a que https t co lUKQrgZIW4 JudgeJeanine It s time to end the <PERSON>Mueller Comey Rosenstein</PERSON> cabal for once and for all https t co YgybCcxp6a <PERSON>Rudy Giuliani</PERSON> says POTUS doesn t need to comply with a possible special counsel subpoena Garrett_FoxNews has the https t co HGz30yLPrX <PERSON>Rudy Giuliani</PERSON> Attorney General Sessions should step up and dismiss this entire investigation https t co Meaa8FxnXg On foxandfriends AlanDersh called out the <ORGANIZATION>ACLU</ORGANIZATION> for being fair weather civil libertarians https t co FNReWFANrL During the <LOCATION>United State of Women Summit</LOCATION> former First Lady <PERSON>MichelleObama</PERSON> wondered what is going on in women s h https t co ZiSLQ8XUGV wjmcgurn I think it s incredible that a high ranking justice official would talk about a legitimate Congression https t co CtISV5i8dc SteveScalise We worked very hard with President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> to get this economy moving again after 8 years of <PERSON>Barack</PERSON> https t co LFzDuACuuG At his round table on tax reform in <LOCATION>Ohio</LOCATION> President realDonaldTrump touted the two slogans that encapsulate his ap https t co zN5ywFZEZE 50 live crocodiles seized at <LOCATION>Heathrow Airport</LOCATION> https t co fm7vmxH18y <PERSON>Netanyahu</PERSON> to visit <PERSON>Putin</PERSON> for talks on <LOCATION>Mideast</LOCATION> developments https t co <ORGANIZATION>B8XN9Npr7L Temple University</ORGANIZATION> student 21 shot and killed near campus https t co FJfnLhkyaX This is <ORGANIZATION>Unsustainable Group</ORGANIZATION> Pushes for <LOCATION>California</LOCATION> to Secede from <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> https t co CSKm3ADOVD https t co 2ggYoxWTTI KimStrassel Mr Flood s job is going to be to try to circumscribe what realDonaldTrump is going to even answer https t co nTRpfMEweE TONIGHT Legends amp amp Lies The Civil War Ulysses S Grant Intoxicated By War hosted by <PERSON>Brian Kilmeade</PERSON> Tune https t co 4Wl7ts7B1N President realDonaldTrump We have Make America Great Again We have America First You can choose whichever https t co cXGlblIKpB How <PERSON>Robin Williams</PERSON> was being torn apart and couldn t fight back https t co NfWgckvbAr Suspect in brutal sex assault is ID d 40 cops tapped in manhunt https t co BIRdLkQ4my Rep Mac Thornberry So I m not necessarily opposed to sticking with this deal forever but you need to have a cle https t co EzVzUZVZOT Rep <PERSON>Mac Thornberry</PERSON> on <LOCATION>North Korea</LOCATION> I think the history of these negotiations through several administrations show https t co JhB1fGU7my Rep <PERSON>Mac Thornberry</PERSON> on <LOCATION>North Korea</LOCATION> I have no doubt their hope is to divide us from our allies in <LOCATION>South Korea</LOCATION> to https t co I14a84r1je michaeljknowles Illegal immigration is illegal We know that 60 80 of women and girls who cross the border https t co 3RGXgCMKJM GillianHTurner I think the president genuinely does want to sit down with <PERSON>Mueller</PERSON> I think he believes so ferve https t co WffWUv7wee POTUS We re doing very well on as you know <LOCATION>North Korea</LOCATION> We have a meeting set up we have the location all https t co 2NvwI0x6b7 guypbenson My suspicion is realDonaldTrump is happy to have someone in his corner who s a fighter and who s https t co BRuXHUH27p SteveScalise I strongly support the work that Chairman <PERSON>Nunes</PERSON> and his entire committee have been doing to uncove https t co MTOOvxZTCM guypbenson When your job is to come in and get your arms around a problem and put out a new story with new info https t co hlLWqFxtTa Joe diGenova The president will not sit down for an interview because this investigation has now reached the leve https t co 2JpRgb5TmR Joe diGenova on <PERSON>Manafort</PERSON> raid <PERSON>Bob Mueller</PERSON> should be ashamed of himself to allow that to happen on his watch https t co hce85At463 On foxandfriends DiamondandSilk called out what they called the very fake news the left wing media https t co 16cKAy4xet Joe diGenova Judge <PERSON>Ellis</PERSON> did something very important on Friday He started a national civics lesson about what t https t co VCrHe5t2Cz <PERSON>Joe diGenova</PERSON> I do not believe that Mr <PERSON>Giuliani</PERSON> is going to get a subpoena from anybody and if they do it s an https t co UDZAeaB0tv <PERSON>Lanny Davis</PERSON> on <PERSON>Rudy Giuliani</PERSON> Number one is don t make matters worse for a client and I think by what he said on t https t co oFow2nX97U DanielRitchie I was born with no arms and thought I was a hopeless mistake and then this happened https t co s6BYffx813 Joe diGenova on Stormy Daniels payment What matters here is that the payment was legal It was for personal reaso https t co zxnsuR7bk0 NYC Mayor Plans to <ORGANIZATION>Open Safe Drug Injection Centers</ORGANIZATION> to Combat Opioid Crisis https t co JdDHuP2t40 Prince <PERSON>William</PERSON> and his wife <PERSON>Kate Middleton</PERSON> shared a photo that captured a sweet moment between the newborn <PERSON>Prince</PERSON> https t co b7suPQMzWp On foxandfriends realCandaceO made clear she has no time to be PC https t co 5vdRMEMypc https t co ryC71oQwpa <PERSON>Uma Thurman</PERSON> says she would work with <PERSON>Quentin Tarantino</PERSON> again despite <PERSON>Kill Bill</PERSON> controversy https t co <ORGANIZATION>kRSibCNBgT George Washington U Students Petition</ORGANIZATION> to Get Rid of Offensive Colonials Mascot https t co UtaR9RDTNR <PERSON>Nancy Pelosi</PERSON> won t be <ORGANIZATION>House</ORGANIZATION> speaker <ORGANIZATION>GOP</ORGANIZATION> will keep majority Rep <PERSON>Kevin McCarthy</PERSON> https t co cnPgahyW6i On foxandfriends SebGorka praised President realDonaldTrump for getting tough on <LOCATION>Iran</LOCATION> https t co Cl32Iacq9H https t co Q2txcBmUZx DevinNunes We have to move quickly to hold the Attorney General of the <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> in contempt and that s wha https t co 7ITj5AAypo <LOCATION>Hawaii</LOCATION> s volcanic eruption has destroyed at least 5 homes officials say https t co 1FqP9QDyUC SebGorka I just want to know now after this report came out about <PERSON>Kerry</PERSON> colluding this is collusion this is https t co GhMi8UsJ16 Dems Remove In God We Trust from schools https t co sKFmkIriUH https t co dusWnRbnqs TODAY <PERSON>Joseph diGenova</PERSON> and <PERSON>Lanny Davis</PERSON> join <PERSON>Chris Wallace</PERSON> for exclusive interviews on FoxNewsSunday at 2p ET on Fo https t co 2vyqZaUb3a Boy 13 regains consciousness after parents sign papers to donate his organs https t co xWjitNeRIR On Twitter DineshDSouza weighed in on a report that liberal comedian and inveterate realDonaldTrump adversary https t co VbXWT9SE21 DiamondandSilk People are tired of the very fake news the left wing media spreading lies I mean deliberatel https t co WnqHD86XRy <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> won t testify in bad faith Mueller probe <PERSON>DiGenova</PERSON> https t co dbMvJV3bip Dennis_Kucinich Both party establishments are locked into yesterday https t co JaQXaur0Fh RealCandaceO For so long black conservatives have not been able to have a voice https t co bGPThfpoFw RLHeinrichs This is about for <PERSON>John Kerry</PERSON> preserving a legacy It is not about pursuing U S national interest https t co qCJadDIkdw <PERSON>Don Gorske</PERSON> the Big Mac Man When I bit into that first Big Mac it was just so good and I just knew I was going https t co oiF2Zaoozv <LOCATION>Iran</LOCATION> warns U S of historic regret ahead of May 12th deadline on nuke deal https t co wdAuNxElAc TONIGHT <PERSON>Don</PERSON> t miss Life Liberty amp amp <PERSON>Levin</PERSON> with marklevinshow Tune in at 10p ET on <ORGANIZATION>Fox News Channel</ORGANIZATION> https t co xj5qf76rZy How <PERSON>Robin Williams</PERSON> was being torn apart and couldn t fight back https t co NfWgckvbAr On <PERSON>SundayFutures JoeLieberman</PERSON> talked about JohnKerry and the <LOCATION>Iran</LOCATION> Deal with MariaBartiromo https t co iqOxhzaY2O <PERSON>Rudy Giuliani</PERSON> Attorney General Sessions should step up and dismiss this entire investigation https t co J9j25tM6Ly <ORGANIZATION>Pirro Blasts Russia Probe Expansion End the Mueller Comey Rosenstein Cabal</ORGANIZATION> For Good https t co PSU1g462wg KatTimpf Because this was a woman on the right they were able to get away with a lot more MediaBuzz https t co oFudS2OMD0 Reince I was the Chief of Stuff POTUS is the Chief of Staff MediaBuzz https t co 5a0BAjvVnJ NYC muggers jump teen for 2G Air Jordans which turn out to be fake https t co AmzOhqv4d3 TODAY <LOCATION>Texas</LOCATION> Rep <PERSON>Mac Thornberry</PERSON> joins <PERSON>Chris Wallace</PERSON> for an exclusive interview on FoxNewsSunday at 2p ET on Fox N https t co kCrsHm1exD RT EricShawnTV At 12 Noon EDT FoxNews I anchor with lauraingle Should JohnKerry be lobbying for the IranDeal And remember MittRom On foxandfriends RealCandaceO blamed former President <PERSON>BarackObama</PERSON> and others in the <ORGANIZATION>Democratic Party</ORGANIZATION> for racial https t co b0BtjmyujF An adventurer in <LOCATION>Canada</LOCATION> set sail down a driveway as high winds and severe thunderstorms swept across <LOCATION>Ontario Canad</LOCATION> https t co EZtgCD4ZhL In God We Trust Motto Sparks Debate In <LOCATION>Minnesota</LOCATION> https t co Fpn2y4qHfQ JoeLieberman on JohnKerry What he s doing is inappropriate SundayFutures MariaBartiromo https t co lzQGFzMT8M TONIGHT KatrinaPierson joins SteveHiltonx on NextRevFNC at 9p ET on <ORGANIZATION>Fox News Channel</ORGANIZATION> https t co txQaRcJmwY GOPLeader There was no collusion SundayFutures MariaBartiromo https t co c0U16ITXe3 JoeLieberman I hope <PERSON>John Kerry</PERSON> stops SundayFutures MariaBartiromo https t co 5ivuCuRw4A JoeLieberman JohnKerry is not negotiating on behalf of the U S government I hope everybody he s talking to k https t co CEoZ7dJhhM Former AG <PERSON>Michael Mukasey</PERSON> We should see the memo SundayFutures MariaBartiromo https t co diVWfZz7EO JoeLieberman <LOCATION>Iran</LOCATION> deal gave them a hundred billion dollars which they ve used to support terrorists and to sp https t co WEtbFClz4y JoeLieberman What the <ORGANIZATION>Obama Administration</ORGANIZATION> and our allies in <LOCATION>Europe</LOCATION> did was basically gave away all of our l https t co zLPFKiAKcl GOPLeader NancyPelosi will not be Speaker Republicans will keep the majority SundayFutures MariaBartiromo https t co OP2qGVw1PU BREAKING NEWS TheJusticeDept responds to DevinNunes https t co rfrCP4BdN8 BREAKING NEWS <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> won t testify in bad faith <PERSON>Mueller</PERSON> probe <PERSON>DiGenova</PERSON> https t co IK4dzHRr0s <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> won t testify in bad faith <PERSON>Mueller</PERSON> probe <PERSON>DiGenova</PERSON> https t co dbMvJV3bip <ORGANIZATION>Former AG Michael Mukasey</ORGANIZATION> This investigation was launched initially in a flawed way SundayFutures https t co woeV5sYRPE NEW RADIO SHOW Guy <PERSON>Benson</PERSON> and <PERSON>Marie Harf</PERSON> give a fresh take on all the day s issues BensonAndHarf premieres <PERSON>Monda</PERSON> https t co uWJIdLfy6K GOPLeader Not only did <LOCATION>Iran</LOCATION> get billions of dollars they spent that money fostering terrorism around the wor https t co gVq4uMm2Bf <PERSON>McCain</PERSON> says <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> should skip his funeral wants Pence to attend via christocarbone https t co YaT1DFkAl4 GOPLeader There was no collusion SundayFutures MariaBartiromo https t co bfnx9RXnwe GOPLeader NancyPelosi will not be Speaker Republicans will keep the majority SundayFutures MariaBartiromo https t co s9gP4xflZ6 GOPLeader 48 out of 50 states their electrical bills are lower because of that tax cut SundayFutures https t co HVpahDDd6d GOPLeader Unemployment below 4 we have not seen that in more than 18 years If you have a child going after https t co <ORGANIZATION>VPLCoGoRxu RT</ORGANIZATION> FoxNewsSunday <PERSON>Lanny Davis</PERSON> tells <PERSON>Chris</PERSON> he believes <PERSON>Rudy Giuliani</PERSON> has to be replaced https t co p1kjw5BOij RT FoxNewsSunday <PERSON>Joseph diGenova</PERSON> on the possibility of President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> sitting down for an interview with <PERSON>Robert Mueller</PERSON> The President w <LOCATION>MariaBaritiromo China</LOCATION> has been stealing from <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> for years on years We have not pushed back on it https t co p9BfZBqciv MariaBartiromo <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> understands that they cannot do business the way they have in the past STAY TUNED for https t co 40pO42SwUX <PERSON>Sarah Sanders</PERSON> touts <ORGANIZATION>Trump CIA</ORGANIZATION> pick Haspel blasts hypocrite Dems who oppose nominee https t co PafzGHerVS World War II veteran graduates college https t co 7CqX5RS1tL RT <ORGANIZATION>FoxNewsSunday House Armed Services Cmte</ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON>MacTXPress</PERSON> on possible tariffs I believe we re better off with free and fair trade POTUS If you don t have borders you don t have a country https t co <ORGANIZATION>XcjOmFbiXn RT FoxNewsSunday House Armed Services Cmte</ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON>MacTXPress</PERSON> on <LOCATION>Iran</LOCATION> Nuclear Deal You need to have a clear idea of next steps if we r <PERSON>Rosie O Donnell</PERSON> s donations to Dems exceeded limit report https t co <ORGANIZATION>5UkN5gp4Fw RT FoxNewsSunday House Armed Services</ORGANIZATION> Chairman <PERSON>Mac Thornberry</PERSON> on possible summit with <PERSON>NoKo</PERSON> I think you can hope for the best but we have michaeljknowles Illegal immigration is illegal We know that 60 80 of women and girls who cross the border https t co MpwIq8LoEo SteveScalise We worked very hard with President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> to get this economy moving again after 8 years of <PERSON>Barack</PERSON> https t co ZtqPjs0uXs SteveScalise I strongly support the work that Chairman <PERSON>Nunes</PERSON> and his entire committee have been doing to uncove https t co caJaVtjJjc RT FoxNewsSunday <PERSON>Lanny Davis</PERSON> on <PERSON>Rudy Giuliani</PERSON> s statements I think by what he has said on television he s exposed President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> to pos RT FoxNewsSunday <PERSON>Lanny Davis</PERSON> on <PERSON>Rudy Giuliani</PERSON> s statements By his words on television I think he has to be replaced RT FoxNewsSunday <PERSON>Joseph diGenova</PERSON> on <PERSON>Rudy Giuliani</PERSON> s statements I think they re irrelevant what matters here is that the payment was leg <PERSON>Sarah Sanders</PERSON> touts <ORGANIZATION>Trump CIA</ORGANIZATION> pick Haspel blasts hypocrite Dems who oppose nominee https t co PafzGHerVS Losing <PERSON>Streak Lois</PERSON> son says his mom snapped before alleged murders https t co HwP19vjMWA DevinNunes We have to move quickly to hold the Attorney General of the <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> in contempt and that s wha https t co BYB30khSuX RealCandaceO At the end of the day it s not about left or right Republican or Democrat it s that we re all h https t co pTWBdovtFL RealCandaceO I blame <PERSON>Obama</PERSON> his 8 years in office did a lot of damage in terms of race relations in this countr https t co JOBSTuqQ4X <PERSON>Anthony Triscari</PERSON> on meeting President realDonaldTrump It was quite an experience for me and something I ll never https t co OzSBvuApm9 <ORGANIZATION>White House</ORGANIZATION> slams <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> s demands to <LOCATION>US</LOCATION> airlines as Orwellian nonsense https t co lxom4INHlE <ORGANIZATION>George Washington U Students Petition</ORGANIZATION> to Get Rid of Offensive Colonials Mascot https t co Yn2DMW3H7U ManUtd s <PERSON>Alex Ferguson</PERSON> in intensive care after brain surgery https t co j7JiuGKWrD <LOCATION>Iowa</LOCATION> governor signs fetal heartbeat bill into law https t co E9t1EgW5qs SebGorka on the <LOCATION>Iran</LOCATION> deal As far as I m concerned the deal is dead https t co auFplv7wLg SebGorka When are <ORGANIZATION>FBI</ORGANIZATION> agents with guns drawn going to raid <PERSON>John Kerry</PERSON> s house https t co OVi5PZclr9 https t co QeOeUdu2RN Prince <PERSON>William</PERSON> and his wife <PERSON>Kate Middleton</PERSON> shared a photo that captured a sweet moment between the newborn <PERSON>Prince</PERSON> https t co <ORGANIZATION>VR02GXDFw1 Spurs</ORGANIZATION> assistant coach <PERSON>Becky Hammon</PERSON> plans to interview for Bucks head coaching job https t co 9hCPcIZDiR Dennis_Kucinich The Democratic party lost touch with the people years ago https t co up2s4RZMKf DiamondandSilk I think people are tired of the very fake news the left wing media spreading lies https t co 1ocyyD4d4f RLHeinrichs <PERSON>John Kerry</PERSON> is using his former position as U S Secretary of <ORGANIZATION>State</ORGANIZATION> not to help the <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> https t co T6rumuJlaO <PERSON>Robert Charles</PERSON> It looks an awful lot like <PERSON>Rod Rosenstein</PERSON> is conflicted https t co hIYWLo7QJR <PERSON>John Kerry</PERSON> under fire for reported shadow diplomacy to save <LOCATION>Iran</LOCATION> deal https t co 8Qm6nV6Sew <PERSON>McCain</PERSON> tells former VP and old colleague <PERSON>Biden</PERSON> to not walk away from politics https t co cELK0fDxXd TONIGHT on Legends amp amp Lies The Civil War Ulysses S Grant Intoxicated By War hosted by <PERSON>Brian Kilmeade</PERSON> Tune https t co XoPv4MRpx3 WWII Marines bodies ID d returned home thanks to tech advances https t co tLG5mo40a6 Mueller team questions <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> friend <PERSON>Tom Barrack</PERSON> https t co bK5oVVGvNL <ORGANIZATION>McDonald s Big Mac</ORGANIZATION> lover now at 30 000 consumed and counting https t co tdVpQbCd6C World War II veteran 96 receives college degree more than 60 years after his last class report says https t co r2lbzBnAqd Award winning filmmaker <PERSON>Carlos Carvalho</PERSON> dies after giraffe head butts him https t co 3EOfPrOLPx How <PERSON>Robin Williams</PERSON> was being torn apart and couldn t fight back https t co NfWgckvbAr JCLayfield The unemployment rate s probably going down to 3 8 which would be the lowest it s been in 50 years https t co wu5F0Ijq3M Dr <PERSON>James Mitchell</PERSON> on <PERSON>Gina Haspel</PERSON> She adheres very strictly to the rule of law and she is in no way likely to bec https t co x8UfurmYVu cvpayne No niche of this economy is more excited about what s happening than small businesses https t co Xx638eCHcO Highway sniper wounds 3 kills self likely inspired by Parkland suspect sheriff says https t co ArufzJKyjq OPINION Military training and energy security are not a zero sum decision https t co TeKaybvpN7 <PERSON>Victoria Toensing</PERSON> All this angst about whether attorney client privilege was waived What do they think Muelle https t co vbzmlT5KLV After a young giraffe was rejected by her mother she has learned how to stand on her own feet <LOCATION>South Australia</LOCATION> s M https t co PqsjDbQhLD <PERSON>Sharlene Thornton</PERSON> to President realDonaldTrump I do want to thank you Mr President https t co zdfEABgLKR POTUS should adopt first lady <PERSON>Nancy Reagan</PERSON> s famous anti drug slogan in his current fight with Special Counsel Ro https t co Pq7J7FjwmR Woman facing life in prison for 1 2M embezzlement kills herself in front of <ORGANIZATION>Walmart</ORGANIZATION> https t co 3phG9ECMGe On foxandfriends AlanDersh gave his unvarnished take on the <PERSON>Mueller</PERSON> investigation of President realDonaldTrump https t co 7ANDmTnTXW SecretaryAcosta The <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> economy has created since his election 3 2 million new jobs https t co Zkm46ByH2h seanspicer The men and women of the <ORGANIZATION>FBI</ORGANIZATION> work throughout this country to uphold the law https t co 4COqCM0JN1 POTUS Look at our economy Today we broke 4 https t co WJxMjCBJNB https t co RH9jkl6VQd <LOCATION>Hawaii</LOCATION> s volcanic eruption has destroyed at least 5 homes officials say https t co 1FqP9QV9Ma POTUS TheDemocrats want open borders We have to have borders If you don t have borders then you don t hav https t co pwsjpKMWv8 MaryTaylorOH We in <LOCATION>Ohio</LOCATION> we support and I support POTUS Build the wall Secure our borders Shut down sanc https t co AaeEY8pY5M During the <LOCATION>United State of Women Summit</LOCATION> former First Lady <PERSON>MichelleObama</PERSON> wondered what is going on in women s h https t co aghvgXu3br POTUS It s going much better than people really understand https t co fPv3pP9mah BillRichardson Watch out <PERSON>Kim Jong</PERSON> Un s probably got something up his sleeve https t co yp4EJIZuOR Customer buying Mentos is confronted by off duty cop report https t co YAyYqUfm9r There is no evidence of collusion with the Russians gone WATCH Full interview with President realDonaldTrump https t co vEWGeqLR5W <LOCATION>California</LOCATION> s <LOCATION>Orange County</LOCATION> may play key midterm election role https t co GBvmk4bC5Z RepDeSantis <PERSON>Rosenstein</PERSON> has bungled this from the start He s let <PERSON>Mueller</PERSON> basically run wild He s not imposed https t co Wmv50fm9rr POTUS s <ORGANIZATION>Council on Sport Fitness and Nutrition</ORGANIZATION> https t co PBpAqv9J8P On SNL Stormy <PERSON>Daniels</PERSON> warns <PERSON>Alec Baldwin</PERSON> s fake <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> that a storm s a comin https t co VIqd05LDwY Business Owner <PERSON>Sherry Sheely</PERSON> to President realDonaldTrump We felt with your strong leadership that now was the https t co rU8n1Sbpcn TeamCavuto I think both BarackObama amp amp realDonaldTrump deserve credit https t co fWtmUncLCe POTUS Since the election the stock market is up almost 35 https t co hTucdBGPYO POTUS Other countries they put themselves first We want to be first We re going to make OUR country great https t co rXASnU2Rs1 April unemployment rate https t co lbvzTPVPOe https t co hFCnqJLcqx KatrinaPierson <PERSON>Paul Manafort</PERSON> was raided back in July 2017 and <PERSON>Rosenstein</PERSON> didn t expand the scope until a month https t co rhDFpFUBVi <PERSON>Rosie O Donnell</PERSON> s donations to Dems exceeded limit report https t co 5UkN5g7tgW SebGorka on HillaryClinton She s a disaster that s why she lost GregGutfeldShow https t co TgmZVokdbb On Justice with JudgeJeanine President realDonaldTrump s attorney <PERSON>Rudy Giuliani</PERSON> slammed the special counsel in https t co wEsCPF6If0 GiannoCaldwell People are quick to blame history as to why they re not succeeding We do live in a country whe https t co LubJ0N4cMR <ORGANIZATION>NHL</ORGANIZATION> warns <PERSON>Bruins Brad Marchand</PERSON> to stop licking opponents https t co jrgwoeF2Lj https t co DmgLuVlS8W <PERSON>Rudy Giuliani</PERSON> There is no evidence of collusion with the Russians gone There s no evidence of obstruction of ju https t co OHe8DazaZT Lava flows along a street near a fissure in <LOCATION>Leilani Estates</LOCATION> on the <LOCATION>Kilauea</LOCATION> volcano s lower East Rift Zone The volc https t co ZGNy8qNjDQ RealCandaceO on radio station banning kanyewest It s saddening and it s disheartening to me that this is the r https t co 50WtJx5drS On foxandfriends AlanDersh called out the <ORGANIZATION>ACLU</ORGANIZATION> for being fair weather civil libertarians https t co XvgsZHMXjC POTUS Our borders are and our laws are a mess Our immigration laws are a disgrace And <LOCATION>Mexico</LOCATION> has very some of https t co h3IDvIXCa4 RepSwalwell The investigation is very much under control https t co 1uEHRttDhN ADORABLE Watch three year old <PERSON>Callum</PERSON> s dream come true as he marched and played the bagpipes with the Ce l N amh p https t co BVe0lEsKVN WhiteHouse slams <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> s demands to <LOCATION>US</LOCATION> airlines as Orwellian nonsense https t co lxom4J5idc JudgeJeanine It s time to end the <PERSON>Mueller Comey Rosenstein</PERSON> cabal for once and for all https t co sDrbsfDmL0 <PERSON>Giuliani</PERSON> talks Stormy payment <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> probe with <ORGANIZATION>Justice</ORGANIZATION> host JudgeJeanine https t co nufmwNluaX https t co MyWaKujEUw <PERSON>Rudy Giuliani</PERSON> on <PERSON>Mueller</PERSON> probe The only crimes committed here have been committed by the government https t co S6srId46A1 POTUS s <ORGANIZATION>Council on Sport Fitness and Nutrition</ORGANIZATION> https t co cdwIDby8kb dbongino <PERSON>Adam Schiff</PERSON> s a fraud I m sorry He s a fraud and I say that and I mean it https t co 5CiJg5OKhd https t co ps7TrXPrYY Woman fined after urine sample damages 7eleven microwave police say https t co L26Wh1Gehf https t co Ncg1jBEAIN GiannoCaldwell People are quick to blame history as to why they re not succeeding We do live in a country whe https t co RaFXY0Q5xk At his round table on Saturday in <LOCATION>Ohio</LOCATION> President realDonaldTrump discussed border security <LOCATION>Mexico</LOCATION> and the carav https t co 0zk8ev1W5e Citizen to President realDonaldTrump With the bonus that you made possible we were able to pay down some of our https t co o94CIKkRyE More than 60 years after last attending class <PERSON>Bob Barger</PERSON> a 96 year old World War II veteran received his college https t co P3zEfpRXlO mzhemingway <ORGANIZATION>CNN</ORGANIZATION> has had a series of problematic stories on the overall story of <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> collusion and investiga https t co 6ixCqfL8aE <ORGANIZATION>Capitol Hill</ORGANIZATION> s Tae Kwon Do master <PERSON>Jhoon Rhee</PERSON> has died leaving scores of disciples behind https t co mml2eg4PI1 PlanetTyrus on why <PERSON>HillaryClinton</PERSON> lost the presidential election It s very simple more people voted for him t https t co FBlZ3Bse2g realDonaldTrump thanks kanyewest in <ORGANIZATION>NRA</ORGANIZATION> speech claims rise in poll numbers among African Americans https t co c5kV1KM6HY AlanDersh You don t go after a distinguished man like <PERSON>Flynn</PERSON> I ve said right from the beginning I don t see https t co L3VABKKtsL On foxandfriends dbongino labeled the allegations of collusion between the 2016 <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> campaign and the Russians https t co vhcPJ5hWYD <PERSON>Rudy Giuliani</PERSON> Judge <PERSON>Ellis</PERSON> has the right to determine that by government misconduct <PERSON>Mueller</PERSON> s team has fatall https t co BUnqTdgnwu <PERSON>John Kerry</PERSON> under fire for reported shadow diplomacy to save <LOCATION>Iran</LOCATION> deal https t co 8Qm6nVot64 <LOCATION>Wisconsin</LOCATION> man has eaten 30 000 Big Macs since 1972 He s been eating 2 of the sandwiches every day https t co cQJLS36Npc A sly move by a quick thinking grandfather tripped up an armed suspect who was trying to run from police https t co VobQaiazwE At yesterday s round table discussion on tax reform in <LOCATION>Cleveland Ohio</LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION>USDOL</ORGANIZATION> SecretaryAcosta praised President https t co DqmKDTGGty Will Riley It s not about me getting to keep my guns I don t have any It s about people s rights https t co tv9TKjQYxH Man who drowned in a <LOCATION>Virginia</LOCATION> creek identified as <ORGANIZATION>US Navy</ORGANIZATION> sailor https t co gY8Hp5ZsoL POTUS We have Make America Great Again We have America First You can choose whichever one you want or you https t co s9lLo4TVhx JCLayfield The unemployment rate s probably going down to 3 8 which would be the lowest it s been in 50 years https t co KXEhkZ9WNu michellemalkin There s a word for this It s called treachery And I believe <PERSON>John Kerry</PERSON> should be prosecuted as https t co PEniAu07Nh PastorDScott The African American community is not against the president https t co vIVQQMvIlk <ORGANIZATION>McDonald s Big Mac</ORGANIZATION> lover now at 30 000 consumed and counting https t co tdVpQbkBI2 At his round table today in <LOCATION>Ohio</LOCATION> President realDonaldTrump discussed immigration <LOCATION>Mexico</LOCATION> and the caravan https t co NwFA0WHUjL POTUS I get nothing but bad publicity https t co lkeHVPc0dQ In his speech to the <ORGANIZATION>NRA</ORGANIZATION> yesterday President realDonaldTrump assured law abiding gun owners across <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> that https t co xdoORIKjGj Judge T S <PERSON>Ellis</PERSON> accuses <PERSON>Mueller</PERSON> s team of lying trying to target <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> C mon man https t co coJxIXTbVX https t co WEBGYmNURP <PERSON>Michael Caputo</PERSON> The truth of the matter is and the truth I gave them along the way there is no Russian collusion https t co 1nbSm64Svo Student Organizes Pro Gun Walkout StandfortheSecond https t co pomalsYQ91 https t co gb86x0mjRb PlanetTyrus on why <PERSON>HillaryClinton</PERSON> lost the presidential election It s very simple more people voted for him t https t co NzcQpqYcRQ TOMORROW KatrinaPierson joins SteveHiltonx on NextRevFNC at 9p ET on <ORGANIZATION>Fox News Channel</ORGANIZATION> https t co cQGiYZpOx1 SebGorka on HillaryClinton She s a disaster that s why she lost GregGutfeldShow https t co 7m1a4xNqHu <PERSON>Michael Caputo</PERSON> The truth of the matter is and the truth I gave them along the way there is no Russian collusion https t co ouJI7Vu776 World War II veteran 96 receives college degree more than 60 years after his last class report says https t co r2lbzBnAqd <ORGANIZATION>Kensington Palace</ORGANIZATION> shares new baby photos of <LOCATION>Prince Louis</LOCATION> https t co xoU6YmXtXJ https t co ZbzcEKMzzM There is no evidence of collusion with the Russians gone WATCH Full interview with President realDonaldTrump https t co x1XvhyqWOM RT FoxNewsResearch KentuckyDerby 144th Run for the Roses 1 1 4 miles Fastest Secretariat 1973 at 1 59 40 <ORGANIZATION>Purse</ORGANIZATION> 2 million <ORGANIZATION>Kensington Palace</ORGANIZATION> shares new baby photos of <LOCATION>Prince Louis</LOCATION> https t co oO64wacnM4 Moments after defying the odds at the KentuckyDerby2018 jockey <PERSON>Mike Smith</PERSON> thanked <PERSON>Jesus Christ</PERSON> https t co PGXF7jmQ8q RealCandaceO on radio station banning kanyewest It s saddening and it s disheartening to me that this is the r https t co 5MrdcXxOX6 RepDeSantis <PERSON>Rosenstein</PERSON> has bungled this from the start He s let <PERSON>Mueller</PERSON> basically run wild He s not imposed https t co QGsjAp1cHG <PERSON>David Tafuri</PERSON> on <PERSON>Manafort</PERSON> investigation I think the evidence if you read the indictment is overwhelming There https t co jdkhbdovur KatrinaPierson <PERSON>Paul Manafort</PERSON> was raided back in July 2017 and <PERSON>Rosenstein</PERSON> didn t expand the scope until a month https t co vOB1EEkhmE Victoria Toensing All this angst about whether attorney client privilege was waived What do they think Muelle https t co 8SEhDx2Owu TOMORROW <LOCATION>Texas</LOCATION> Rep <PERSON>Mac Thornberry</PERSON> joins <PERSON>Chris Wallace</PERSON> for an exclusive interview on FoxNewsSunday at 2p ET on Fo https t co Awycc7n8Lo <PERSON>Rudy Giuliani</PERSON> Judge <PERSON>Ellis</PERSON> has the right to determine that by government misconduct <PERSON>Mueller</PERSON> s team has fatall https t co UeHHrKqx73 <PERSON>Rudy Giuliani</PERSON> on <PERSON>Mueller</PERSON> probe The only crimes committed here have been committed by the government https t co 1dqnJd8crs <PERSON>Rudy Giuliani</PERSON> There is no evidence of collusion with the Russians gone There s no evidence of obstruction of ju https t co 2zdycBPHnx <PERSON>Rudy Giuliani</PERSON> on <PERSON>Mueller</PERSON> probe It kind of gives the American people a glimpse of what we have to deal with day in https t co twiJeD90Ji <PERSON>Rudy Giuliani</PERSON> on <PERSON>Mueller</PERSON> probe Maybe they think <PERSON>Manafort</PERSON> s somebody they can flip faster JudgeJeanine https t co DZV3Fw1wZb JudgeJeanine It s time to end the <PERSON>Mueller Comey Rosenstein</PERSON> cabal for once and for all https t co 7hX3C9tBdt <PERSON>Rudy Giuliani</PERSON> This all plays into what my client realDonaldTrump has been saying for quite some time The jud https t co XGVOSCiMER SenJohnMcCain tells former VP and old colleague <PERSON>JoeBiden</PERSON> to not walk away from politics https t co XBluaIpUXr TUNE IN <PERSON>Rudy Giuliani</PERSON> joins JudgeJeanine on <ORGANIZATION>Fox News Channel</ORGANIZATION> https t co nHwm5ir2Gd <LOCATION>Hawaii</LOCATION> s <LOCATION>Kilauea</LOCATION> volcano erupts mandatory evacuations ordered for more than 1 000 people https t co ChAcKYR4rM Bigfoot spotted in <LOCATION>New Jersey</LOCATION> https t co ZJn2rmwVpm YesCalifornia President <PERSON>Marcus Ruiz Evans America</PERSON> s had 30 years to deal with immigration policy and it never d https t co 0luxdCEGQC GiannoCaldwell People are quick to blame history as to why they re not succeeding We do live in a country whe https t co vIqapj8jRO TONIGHT <PERSON>Rudy Giuliani</PERSON> joins JudgeJeanine at 9p ET on <ORGANIZATION>Fox News Channel</ORGANIZATION> https t co bqWMIvdrRO <PERSON>Wendy Osefo</PERSON> The dialogue that kanyewest is perpetuating is very very dangerous https t co 7DaUjKe58t https t co fYT5ish5Vp Dr <PERSON>James Mitchell</PERSON> on <PERSON>Gina Haspel</PERSON> She adheres very strictly to the rule of law and she is in no way likely to bec https t co CwOJ8VnLt2 AndrewCMcCarthy on special counsel investigation It s an unguided missile https t co fyVt88HWyo https t co x8oA7O27sg A giant of <ORGANIZATION>Congress</ORGANIZATION> has passed leaving scores of martial arts disciplines behind https t co mml2egmr6B TOMORROW on Legends amp amp Lies The Civil War Ulysses S Grant Intoxicated By War hosted by <PERSON>Brian Kilmeade</PERSON> Tune https t co IVmF6YlJak POTUS TheDemocrats want open borders We have to have borders If you don t have borders then you don t hav https t co tiA7FfSteX TONIGHT <PERSON>Rudy Giuliani</PERSON> joins JudgeJeanine at 9p ET on <ORGANIZATION>Fox News Channel</ORGANIZATION> https t co ZxeGwyTY8S <ORGANIZATION>White House</ORGANIZATION> slams <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> s demands to <LOCATION>US</LOCATION> airlines as Orwellian nonsense https t co NU6suGur1q More than 1 600 arrested in <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> amid anti <PERSON>Putin</PERSON> protests https t co R9DvcdTaDs OPINION <PERSON>Mueller</PERSON> s <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> probe should wrap up and <PERSON>Rosenstein</PERSON> should accept congressional oversight https t co c2aRsHuUeK 8 vents open following <LOCATION>Hawaii</LOCATION> volcano eruption <ORGANIZATION>USGS</ORGANIZATION> says https t co PZ8J6Ub67A <PERSON>Steven Nelson</PERSON> I think POTUS knows the political storm that would be created by firing <PERSON>Mueller</PERSON> FoxReport https t co 8oenScA8NI ICE arrests man in <LOCATION>Maryland</LOCATION> crash that killed <ORGANIZATION>FBI</ORGANIZATION> agent fire marshal https t co bAc6FLbBj1 BREAKING Justify wins KentuckyDerby2018 https t co DqPxCa3N27 https t co CwbxuVtAjt LarrySabato on <LOCATION>Ohio</LOCATION> primaries The Democratic vote virtually collapsed in eastern <LOCATION>Ohio</LOCATION> You can see that when yo https t co LgQyTh1HRP In <LOCATION>Ohio</LOCATION> POTUS touts <ORGANIZATION>GOP</ORGANIZATION> tax cuts ahead of key primaries next week https t co 83A5SDVbHh <PERSON>Daniel Hoffman</PERSON> on the <LOCATION>Iran</LOCATION> nuclear deal There are major issues with the deal and POTUS I think is frustrated by https t co BahQbb3KBy <PERSON>Giuliani</PERSON> sticks to foreign policy script steering clear of Stormy Daniels dustup https t co Maw0GeQCiA <PERSON>Mueller</PERSON> team questions <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> friend <PERSON>Tom Barrack</PERSON> https t co 3VggZyLpXg seanhannity Don t be fooled by the tactics of the left their <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> collusion obsession their blatant hatred https t co Zvuue03U0J Exotic fish native to <LOCATION>China Russia</LOCATION> found in <LOCATION>Virginia</LOCATION> reservoir https t co 3aIS3TaHDK TOMORROW <PERSON>Joseph diGenova</PERSON> and <PERSON>Lanny Davis</PERSON> join <PERSON>Chris Wallace</PERSON> for exclusive interviews on FoxNewsSunday at 2p ET on https t co KuDVpejpY0 Will Riley It s not about me getting to keep my guns I don t have any It s about people s rights <PERSON>Cavuto</PERSON> https t co vgu5BAzu6E Man who drowned in a <LOCATION>Virginia</LOCATION> creek identified as <ORGANIZATION>US Navy</ORGANIZATION> sailor https t co Wkcj08RWfX TONIGHT <PERSON>Rudy Giuliani</PERSON> joins JudgeJeanine at 9p ET on <ORGANIZATION>Fox News Channel</ORGANIZATION> https t co l8PseuTLkt POTUS We re doing very well on as you know <LOCATION>North Korea</LOCATION> We have a meeting set up we have the location all https t co JxIcrIBonR Moviemaker <PERSON>Michael Moore</PERSON> wishes <PERSON>Karl Marx</PERSON> a happy 200th birthday https t co 6574Lsh6FW POTUS s <ORGANIZATION>Council on Sport Fitness and Nutrition</ORGANIZATION> https t co SW8oDC9ntP OPINION The <LOCATION>Iran</LOCATION> deal is dead <LOCATION>Iran</LOCATION> killed it https t co O8NCgdkoXl <LOCATION>Tennessee</LOCATION> teen stabs male student with scissors after he pulls up her dress police say https t co 5RgkFwt5Ky POTUS should adopt first lady <PERSON>Nancy Reagan</PERSON> s famous anti drug slogan in his current fight with Special Counsel Ro https t co IGeIODDj9F <PERSON>SteveHiltonx Mueller</PERSON> probe is a political counter revolution to overthrow <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> It must be defeated https t co mn1Nu0R6fb <ORGANIZATION>White House</ORGANIZATION> slams <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> s demands to <LOCATION>US</LOCATION> airlines as Orwellian nonsense https t co lxom4INHlE <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> could address <LOCATION>UK</LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION>Parliament</ORGANIZATION> as members look to nix anti <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> speaker s ban https t co YNHupdE3Tn newtgingrich realDonaldTrump should just say no to <PERSON>Mueller</PERSON> s absurd questions https t co csirBCc9z2 At today s round table discussion on tax reform in <LOCATION>Cleveland Ohio</LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION>USDOL</ORGANIZATION> SecretaryAcosta praised President https t co S9aP0Pwiv7 RT FoxNewsResearch <LOCATION>US</LOCATION> Trade Deficit in Goods with <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> Jan Mar 2018 Jan 35 9B Feb 29 2B Mar 25 8B 3 month deficit 90 9 bil April unemployment rate https t co lbvzTPVPOe https t co P2Ys9lCK5B <PERSON>Behnam Ben Taleblu</PERSON> A fair amount of POTUS leverage comes from sanctions and right now the U S is in a position https t co GsyA26Es7Z A Circus at the Border michellemalkin Rips Questionable Asylum Claims From Migrant Caravan https t co g1r7hUbztx Teen girl 16 burnt alive after rape in <LOCATION>India</LOCATION> 14 people arrested https t co WKa8y3gztW AlanDersh You don t go after a distinguished man like <PERSON>Flynn</PERSON> I ve said right from the beginning I don t see https t co gn1D1cUHpG <PERSON>Rudy Giuliani</PERSON> POTUS is surrounded by really terrific foreign policy advisers and I would think AmbJohnBolton https t co o9MEwwhQrC TOMORROW <LOCATION>Texas</LOCATION> Rep <PERSON>Mac Thornberry</PERSON> joins <PERSON>Chris Wallace</PERSON> for an exclusive interview on FoxNewsSunday at 2p ET on Fo https t co 4mAVLWCs1w In his speech to the <ORGANIZATION>NRA</ORGANIZATION> yesterday President realDonaldTrump assured law abiding gun owners across <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> that https t co nKcW1IgeiQ DevinNunes on the <ORGANIZATION>FBI</ORGANIZATION> We don t see a systemic problem out in the field with field agents or with people oversea https t co 0p7WlsmZ2z TONIGHT <PERSON>Rudy Giuliani</PERSON> joins JudgeJeanine at 9p ET on <ORGANIZATION>Fox News Channel</ORGANIZATION> https t co Q7G1SZxtH3 <PERSON>Rudy Giuliani</PERSON> There is a good chance that three long time hostages in <LOCATION>North Korea</LOCATION> will be released over the next https t co Uu3n8HzAZt At his round table today in <LOCATION>Ohio</LOCATION> President realDonaldTrump discussed immigration <LOCATION>Mexico</LOCATION> and the caravan https t co waZr3LNu6Q <LOCATION>Wisconsin</LOCATION> man has eaten 30 000 Big Macs since 1972 He s been eating 2 of the sandwiches every day https t co 6ccfrJeTqE TOMORROW on Legends amp amp Lies The Civil War Ulysses S Grant Intoxicated By War hosted by <PERSON>Brian Kilmeade</PERSON> Tune https t co o2ZJ3TaYm4 Cliff May This agreement never stopped <LOCATION>Iran</LOCATION> from developing nuclear weapons https t co pl7Z2L9dT9 https t co iJxaLfi3zh On foxandfriends AlanDersh called out the <ORGANIZATION>ACLU</ORGANIZATION> for being fair weather civil libertarians https t co AnlpYubdEg Award winning filmmaker <PERSON>Carlos Carvalho</PERSON> dies after giraffe head butts him https t co 3EOfPrOLPx <LOCATION>Tennessee</LOCATION> woman 70 mugged after leaving Bible study surveillance video shows https t co CbW5lrnM6y wjmcgurn I think it s incredible that a high ranking justice official would talk about a legitimate Congression https t co OFzpzThQ8r <PERSON>Rudy Giuliani</PERSON> delivers the keynote speech at the annual <LOCATION>Iran</LOCATION> Freedom Convention https t co BWljs3Ld88 Do you agree with Sen KamalaHarris https t co B7ZscGCe9A KimStrassel Mr Flood s job is going to be to try to circumscribe what realDonaldTrump is going to even answer https t co bX7nQAVaHh mzhemingway <ORGANIZATION>CNN</ORGANIZATION> has had a series of problematic stories on the overall story of <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> collusion and investiga https t co aXw8sj4WiM Shunned by corporations U S gun entrepreneurs launch start ups via FoxBusiness https t co 08wGGhdUwr ICE arrests man for <LOCATION>Maryland</LOCATION> crash that killed <ORGANIZATION>FBI</ORGANIZATION> agent fire marshal https t co b13dg2rI04 Ex Trump Campaign Adviser My Family Receives Death Threats Over Mueller Probe https t co QNS6NQyh40 <PERSON>John Kerry</PERSON> under fire for reported shadow diplomacy to save <LOCATION>Iran</LOCATION> deal https t co 8Qm6nV6Sew TOMORROW KatrinaPierson joins SteveHiltonx on NextRevFNC at 9p ET on <ORGANIZATION>Fox News Channel</ORGANIZATION> https t co yFSpUdlPTI On foxandfriends michellemalkin said that former Secretary of <ORGANIZATION>State</ORGANIZATION> JohnKerry should be prosecuted for failing https t co WWfoVXeZFs <LOCATION>Texas</LOCATION> teen killed in crash after unbuckling seat belt to take selfie https t co pTEQvdJoCw Business Owner I know there ve been many people in the media and some of your opposition who ve claimed that your https t co 7pm067n1g7 Citizen to President realDonaldTrump With the bonus that you made possible we were able to pay down some of our https t co 9UjkEPPDCW RepJimRenacci I was so happy when <PERSON>POTUS</PERSON> said that we re going to cut taxes for Americans https t co BS0mtYwSpJ POTUS I get nothing but bad publicity https t co tw6UnmGPEp POTUS It s going much better than people really understand https t co KYpUrzjUwi SecretaryAcosta The <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> economy has created since his election 3 2 million new jobs https t co 8Jwj4Y15FI Business Owner <PERSON>Sherry Sheely</PERSON> to President realDonaldTrump We felt with your strong leadership that now was the https t co PeI7Wy1ltZ <PERSON>Sharlene Thornton</PERSON> to President realDonaldTrump I do want to thank you Mr President https t co Z8C0LMV4cN POTUS Our borders are and our laws are a mess Our immigration laws are a disgrace And <LOCATION>Mexico</LOCATION> has very some of https t co ys6jC4G90M POTUS We re going to keep a lot of friends but they re going to respect us again https t co MQturELjlY POTUS We re doing very well on as you know <LOCATION>North Korea</LOCATION> We have a meeting set up we have the location all https t co bMQds7K8DZ POTUS Other countries they put themselves first We want to be first We re going to make OUR country great https t co lTMytKp3UD POTUS TheDemocrats want open borders We have to have borders If you don t have borders then you don t hav https t co tGL2gSqCIx On foxandfriends dbongino labeled the allegations of collusion between the 2016 <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> campaign and the Russians https t co aFEHd3uKMG POTUS Since the election the stock market is up almost 35 https t co c6O0NAeKPF POTUS The poll came out that I m above <PERSON>Obama Above Obama</PERSON> https t co Es7Dw1AmFu POTUS We have Make America Great Again We have America First You can choose whichever one you want or you https t co TAlhdxrVAk POTUS They want open borders We have to have borders If you don t have borders then you don t have a country https t co R3xwIDMMEA POTUS Our borders are and our laws are a mess Our immigration laws are a disgrace And <LOCATION>Mexico</LOCATION> has very some of https t co USKBN3ln0d POTUS We want to get our workers back We want to make our product here This is <ORGANIZATION>America First</ORGANIZATION> now folks This https t co XxMyQkB9b2 POTUS We broke 4 yesterday https t co 1PU23lMfcW POTUS We re doing very well on as you know <LOCATION>North Korea</LOCATION> We have a meeting set up we have the location all https t co 67nEzMV6lg POTUS We re going to have to rework trade with <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> https t co Xjs1is4n3X POTUS RepJimRenacci will be fantastic in the <ORGANIZATION>Senate</ORGANIZATION> I ve known him for a long time https t co F4JlZPeFm4 POTUS We just had a couple of meetings We have great great people in this state This is a very very speci https t co r71bf0DnJY POTUS You have to win the great state of <LOCATION>Ohio</LOCATION> and did we win the great state of <LOCATION>Ohio</LOCATION> https t co z3VI4mljPm President realDonaldTrump attends a roundtable discussion on tax reform https t co UKsdnZnZSK RIGHT NOW Awaiting POTUS tax roundtable in <LOCATION>Cleveland</LOCATION> for full live coverage tune in to <ORGANIZATION>Fox News Channel</ORGANIZATION> https t co 03Pv8Uw64p Russians angered by the impending inauguration of <PERSON>Vladimir Putin</PERSON> to a new term as president demonstrate in the stre https t co dAqakTCXZD Student Organizes Pro Gun Walkout StandfortheSecond https t co pomalsHfht https t co ZPBieDVEB4 NancyPelosi Statement on RepCardenas https t co sREJeB2yP1 Russians angered by the impending inauguration of <PERSON>Vladimir Putin</PERSON> to a new term as president demonstrate in the stre https t co NW9DMjWuyY <PERSON>Michael Caputo</PERSON> The truth of the matter is and the truth I gave them along the way there is no Russian collusion https t co 7X0wmbpQV4 MaryTaylorOH We in <LOCATION>Ohio</LOCATION> we support and I support POTUS Build the wall Secure our borders Shut down sanc https t co Yh6SH6W9mL Brutal confirmation process threatens to turn off would be <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> picks https t co bgseEBFjyQ In his speech to the <ORGANIZATION>NRA</ORGANIZATION> yesterday President realDonaldTrump assured law abiding gun owners across <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> that https t co WkjjA1ULgs RIGHT NOW Awaiting POTUS tax roundtable in <LOCATION>Cleveland</LOCATION> for full live coverage tune in to <ORGANIZATION>Fox News Channel</ORGANIZATION> https t co iVDCaV1bvz On <ORGANIZATION>Fox amp amp Friends Alan</ORGANIZATION> M <PERSON>Dershowitz</PERSON> gave his unvarnished take on the <PERSON>Mueller</PERSON> investigation of President <PERSON>Donald</PERSON> https t co zsearcIIaf NYC Mayor Plans to <ORGANIZATION>Open Safe Drug Injection Centers</ORGANIZATION> to Combat Opioid Crisis https t co JdDHuP2t40 Prince <PERSON>Harry</PERSON> and <PERSON>Meghan Markle</PERSON> are reportedly postponing their royal honeymoon https t co 6iIgzVbt5g Latvian woman s decomposed body detached head found a month after going missing from yoga retreat https t co PheGEwH0jf Will Riley It s not about me getting to keep my guns I don t have any It s about people s rights <PERSON>Cavuto</PERSON> https t co m5pwYmqARE SecPriceMD Repealing the individual mandate is important because the individual mandate forces people to buy wh https t co 9JWQ4zIDKj POTUS should adopt first lady <PERSON>Nancy Reagan</PERSON> s famous anti drug slogan in his current fight with Special Counsel Ro https t co v9eXxOXDNC RepSwalwell The investigation is very much under control <PERSON>Cavuto</PERSON> https t co P2t4JfmtFk Will Riley We have had viewpoint discrimination in schools across the country <PERSON>Cavuto</PERSON> https t co JgtKPq3mxr Will <PERSON>Riley</PERSON> If you re someone who is allowed to vote you re allowed to serve in the military I think that you al https t co NiT0ubTsYS Will Riley It s a very dangerous precedent to set that you may not be able to exercise your natural right until y https t co iTLuTKroGe Will Riley People forget that the right to bear arms is just that It s a right It can t be taken away by repeal https t co emNrf9ooEn Will Riley It s not about me getting to keep my guns I don t have any It s about people s rights <PERSON>Cavuto</PERSON> https t co kpHCzlzRez JCLayfield The unemployment rate s probably going down to 3 8 which would be the lowest it s been in 50 years https t co 0SWbBg95ld TONIGHT <PERSON>Don</PERSON> t miss an all new GregGutfeldShow Tune in at 10p ET on <ORGANIZATION>Fox News Channel</ORGANIZATION> https t co QhyUoRhQLI RIGHT NOW POTUS arrives in <LOCATION>Cleveland</LOCATION> for tax reform roundtable for full live coverage tune in to <ORGANIZATION>Fox News Chan</ORGANIZATION> https t co 7ZTPriFw0O Air Force One arrives at <LOCATION>Burke Lakefront Airport Cleveland</LOCATION> OH Courtesy WJW https t co CHVBSpjP48 dbongino <PERSON>Adam Schiff</PERSON> s a fraud I m sorry He s a fraud and I say that and I mean it https t co 5CiJg5OKhd https t co hlk6F2uPWq cvpayne No niche of this economy is more excited about what s happening than small businesses https t co S5U6jScsuN DEVELOPING Reports More than 1 000 anti <PERSON>Putin</PERSON> protesters detained across <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> https t co hPlv5jYlRn <PERSON>Warren Buffett</PERSON> holding yearly shareholder meeting today in <LOCATION>Omaha</LOCATION> LizClaman reports <PERSON>Cavuto</PERSON> https t co hiFdznpQSX Teen accused of slut shaming his girlfriend over her prom dress says it wasn t him https t co WOZJBnv7lI Do you agree with Sen KamalaHarris https t co TX6n8nukC8 BillRichardson Watch out <PERSON>Kim Jong</PERSON> Un s probably got something up his sleeve <PERSON>Cavuto</PERSON> https t co riXOycL9Rz NEW RADIO SHOW Guy <PERSON>Benson</PERSON> and <PERSON>Marie Harf</PERSON> give a fresh take on all the day s issues BensonAndHarf premieres <PERSON>Monda</PERSON> https t co YEKyyZMnCm PastorDScott The African American community is not against the president https t co 7w7KihC0g1 <LOCATION>Wisconsin</LOCATION> man has eaten 30 000 Big Macs since 1972 He s been eating 2 of the sandwiches every day https t co K11OpHxPZW HAPPENING NOW <PERSON>Anti Putin</PERSON> protests break out in <LOCATION>Moscow</LOCATION> https t co FxzoE1T53U News Alert POTUS heads to <LOCATION>Ohio</LOCATION> to highlight tax reform https t co d8zsnfasvC Judge T S <PERSON>Ellis</PERSON> accuses <PERSON>Mueller</PERSON> s team of lying trying to target <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> C mon man https t co coJxIXTbVX https t co 1D9XvgFf7f HAPPENING NOW <PERSON>Anti Putin</PERSON> protests break out in <LOCATION>Moscow</LOCATION> https t co zCGODGC9Ui Air Force One departs JBA en route to <LOCATION>Cleveland</LOCATION> OH https t co MXne1ma6mq TeamCavuto I think both BarackObama amp amp realDonaldTrump deserve credit https t co TfnLf4LfXI POTUS Look at our economy Today we broke 4 https t co WJxMjCk8p1 https t co kFIJHLweBC edhenry JohnKerry the former Secretary of <ORGANIZATION>State</ORGANIZATION> he could be in violation of the Logan Act https t co 0l15lEJAzE April unemployment rate https t co lbvzTPVPOe https t co RMzaSmmmDm <LOCATION>Hawaii</LOCATION> volcano quake evacuees share stories of shock fear frustration https t co gWL7LvBRx1 OPINION <PERSON>Newt Gingrich Trump</PERSON> should just say no to <PERSON>Mueller</PERSON> s absurd questions https t co 1UZo9XhlJe AlanDersh I would like to see the <LOCATION>Iran</LOCATION> deal changed We can do much better https t co 1sy0nzCHPm AlanDersh You know <PERSON>Flynn</PERSON> I ve said right from the beginning I don t see the crime there https t co U1GoFzFX94 cvpayne Small business optimism surged after the election and has remained high and it s translating into jobs https t co xawCPraDqj cvpayne on unemployment numbers These numbers are absolutely remarkable https t co u73i8nGITy April Unemployment Rate https t co ixUHO4rpEu JaniceDean Gets a Lesson from a <LOCATION>Derby Jockey</LOCATION> https t co f39975zJGm House of Horrors dad gets 8 perjury charges added https t co G2D9nW4lo0 realDonaldTrump thanks kanyewest in <ORGANIZATION>NRA</ORGANIZATION> speech claims rise in poll numbers among African Americans https t co c5kV1L3I6y <ORGANIZATION>NASA</ORGANIZATION> launches historic InSight spacecraft with mission to <LOCATION>Mars</LOCATION> https t co jPBETbjYTA https t co OJ7rwVQfoO seanspicer There is definitely people with a personal agenda against this president and against conservatives https t co rCp0YcvrW6 seanspicer The men and women of the <ORGANIZATION>FBI</ORGANIZATION> work throughout this country to uphold the law https t co 9BCsmX28Xd Deployed military unit surprises soldier s daughter with cheer routine https t co P0DCwa4e7M antjuansea This president has failed the American people https t co eHdppquvO3 <PERSON>McCain</PERSON> welcomes visitors as he recovers from cancer treatment surgery https t co kaHHMq1zCD JUST IN <ORGANIZATION>NASA</ORGANIZATION> launches historic InSight spacecraft with mission to <LOCATION>Mars</LOCATION> https t co jPBETbjYTA <ORGANIZATION>Fresno State</ORGANIZATION> hears from students public about <PERSON>Bush</PERSON> bashing professor https t co 1GZAIVEjzA IA Governor Signs Nation s Strictest Abortion <PERSON>Bill</PERSON> into Law https t co E9t1EgW5qs https t co BOqRz5c80B AMAZING VIDEO Man trips suspect running from police https t co sUJYtj0zoF TOMORROW <PERSON>Joseph diGenova</PERSON> and <PERSON>Lanny Davis</PERSON> join <PERSON>Chris Wallace</PERSON> for exclusive interviews on FoxNewsSunday at 2p ET o https t co PHG29HoT8o OPINION The Kentucky Derby and the power of horses to heal https t co Bok4C97opt <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> asks <PERSON>Bill Belichick Mariano Rivera Herschel Walker Misty May Treanor</PERSON> to join sports council https t co fXOliiIKGT dbongino <PERSON>Adam Schiff</PERSON> s a fraud https t co bsUfqC2rVN <ORGANIZATION>FBI</ORGANIZATION> officials <PERSON>Jim Baker Lisa Page</PERSON> resign from bureau https t co 3m4ZiH6oXI Former President <PERSON>GeorgeHWBush</PERSON> released from hospital spokesman says https t co 9AjGz1eWHI https t co 3R0sMmMnK7 <LOCATION>Indiana</LOCATION> police officer fatally shot suspect confirmed dead after shootout https t co vDk5n0LkPD https t co F8rQveMwGR Federal judge accuses <PERSON>Mueller</PERSON> s team of lying trying to target <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> C mon man https t co fyVt88HWyo OPINION The cure for obesity heart disease and anxiety Puppies https t co Cx3YycSja7 Woman lived with cockroach in her ear for 9 days after it crawled in while she was sleeping https t co 991LSmI3bj Deployed military unit surprises soldier s daughter with cheer routine https t co P0DCwa4e7M <ORGANIZATION>DOJ</ORGANIZATION> inspector general s testimony postponed amid new leads in <PERSON>Clinton</PERSON> case review https t co Nbun0DhcQv There were shocking moments in a <LOCATION>Utah</LOCATION> courthouse when a defendant sprinted from the courtroom and catapulted over https t co SYbSlXpA28 LisaMarieBoothe Democrats run a risk in trying to embrace gun control efforts too much https t co yCIU5XBhhM SteveHiltonx Good news for <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> is bad news for POTUS critics in the media in the political establishment https t co VqIeemiUQz GovMikeHuckabee POTUS is constantly under this intense pressure to answer all these questions about somethin https t co HxzgHYpZQM RepDeSantis shared his gut feeling about the <PERSON>Mueller</PERSON> investigation with TeamCavuto Friday saying This thing https t co 7m6zd2Y2lh POTUS In my administration we have a simple policy We will protect those who protect us https t co UC9CYo9W4r GovMikeHuckabee POTUS is constantly under this intense pressure to answer all these questions about somethin https t co G2HF7DsWG9 marklevinshow This is not a campaign contribution It s not an in kind campaign contribution There s no ille https t co thCjDsXGNT TuckerCarlson Mueller Probe Shows Political Campaigns Now Waged With Guns and Subpoenas https t co wD7zN5jehI President realDonaldTrump Like those early Texans Americans will never surrender Ever ever ever We will neve https t co VpEv8rtVK6 AMAZING VIDEO Man trips suspect running from police https t co japVRVAhc9 President realDonaldTrump Like those early Texans Americans will never surrender Ever ever ever We will neve https t co AKm1lLJXB5 guypbenson Our border is not secure https t co TzDJDAgRTt A sly move by a quick thinking grandfather tripped up an armed suspect who was trying to run from police https t co tcJosXsVBG Yesterday IvankaTrump celebrated the Jobs Report https t co lbvzTQdqFM https t co WtYpW3J4wn OPINION Hey liberals owning a gun IS the responsible thing to do https t co SNiSscYFN0 <ORGANIZATION>FBI</ORGANIZATION> officials <PERSON>Jim Baker Lisa Page</PERSON> resign from bureau https t co PLga9ZEOWA <PERSON>Bill Paxton</PERSON> s surgeon hospital deny responsibility for his death https t co psoROa5rSA RepJimRenacci sherrodbrown is one of the 3 most liberal senators in the country He votes with SenWarren https t co mSsl7UGk8w Trial set for Smallville actress <PERSON>Allison Mack</PERSON> alleged sex cult leader <PERSON>Keith Raniere</PERSON> https t co xOmIb606as replouiegohmert <PERSON>Mueller</PERSON> has a history of not being a man of integrity but of using and abusing the law to go a https t co QVwOcEwF8B <LOCATION>Iowa</LOCATION> governor signs fetal heartbeat bill into law https t co w6vZjIR05p realDonaldTrump at <ORGANIZATION>NRA</ORGANIZATION> Convention 2nd Amendment Will Never Be Under Siege While I m President https t co UcPrx0KoPa GovMikeHuckabee POTUS is constantly under this intense pressure to answer all these questions about somethin https t co y8vBjiNrYT <ORGANIZATION>Caldwell Politics</ORGANIZATION> in the Pulpit May Have Prompted <PERSON>Ryan</PERSON> to Dismiss House Chaplain https t co ogGS6oB6Dm marcthiessen On <LOCATION>North Korea Trump</LOCATION> should refuse to take the bait https t co uIyTpXNu0B Women security think LaGuardia s surveillance robot is ogling them report says https t co BOcZBrBITg TuckerCarlson Mueller Probe Shows Political Campaigns Now Waged With Guns and Subpoenas https t co mMwRTJCMOJ Former President <PERSON>George H W Bush</PERSON> released from hospital spokesman says https t co n7z82balQr https t co hrWttKqU17 POTUS to host South Korean president amid planning for U S <LOCATION>North Korea</LOCATION> summit <ORGANIZATION>White House</ORGANIZATION> says https t co 5jqhb8hpyU AlanDersh on judge questioning <PERSON>Mueller</PERSON> s team It s about time a judge honestly looked at the situation and asse https t co <PERSON>YhFKfbslpn DevinNunes</PERSON> on the <ORGANIZATION>FBI</ORGANIZATION> We don t see a systemic problem out in the field with field agents or with people oversea https t co MzjRgCEBJt There were shocking moments in a <LOCATION>Utah</LOCATION> courthouse when a defendant sprinted from the courtroom and catapulted over https t co KVMnULGNfD DevinNunes on <PERSON>Mueller</PERSON> investigation Everything in this case has just gone off the rails There s not a day that https t co 5wiSkAdSCx Former President <PERSON>GeorgeHWBush</PERSON> released from hospital spokesman says https t co IXG74erSPq SebGorka <PERSON>Robert Mueller</PERSON> is trying to pin a crime on the president and it cannot be allowed This is <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> https t co ccuQJ0HSDh <PERSON>David Limbaugh</PERSON> Here s what s ironic This <PERSON>Mueller</PERSON> investigation is set up on the pretense of protecting democra https t co EJgVUVda7Z seanhannity Federal Judge s Excoriation of <PERSON>Mueller</PERSON> Team Biggest Beatdown I Have Ever Seen Hannity https t co ojFdQ4EB2b Fmr <ORGANIZATION>FBI</ORGANIZATION> Director <PERSON>Comey</PERSON> testified to the <ORGANIZATION>House Intel Committee</ORGANIZATION> that <ORGANIZATION>FBI</ORGANIZATION> agents did not believe <PERSON>Michael Flynn</PERSON> inten https t co aPQNJmFbiA seanhannity Don t be fooled by the tactics of the left their <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> collusion obsession their blatant hatred https t co pCJA7MBgFI <PERSON>Bailey Davis</PERSON> on <ORGANIZATION>NFL</ORGANIZATION> treatment of cheerleaders I want equal and fair rules that are free of discrimination and I t https t co y0tOXB0nbV Russian Collusion Delusion Roger Stone Blasts <PERSON>Mueller</PERSON> s Fairy Tale Probe as Attempt to Hurt <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> https t co se9mvlBQIx dbongino on <PERSON>Mueller</PERSON> investigation You do not investigate people you investigate crimes and you find people https t co z061qPSgqQ Trying to Go Viral Conway Says April Ryan Sought Confrontation With <PERSON>Sanders</PERSON> https t co HXiVNT4fpX realDonaldTrump Friday tweeted about attending the <ORGANIZATION>NRA</ORGANIZATION> s annual meeting earlier in the day where he made wide r https t co j6hzBi21Gp newtgingrich <PERSON>Mary Mayhew Hope</PERSON> for those trapped in welfare dependency Thanks to realDonaldTrump https t co NnS2DYsKhh TulsiPress Whatever people feel about realDonaldTrump this is the time for people to rise above the partisan https t co <ORGANIZATION>KK2tBzW5Zp House Intel</ORGANIZATION> report <PERSON>Comey</PERSON> testified <ORGANIZATION>FBI</ORGANIZATION> agents saw no physical indications of deception by <PERSON>Flynn</PERSON> https t co View3Zo49v <PERSON>Tom Dupree</PERSON> on federal judge rebuking <PERSON>Mueller</PERSON> s team The <PERSON>Mueller</PERSON> camp has to be very surprised and disturbed by wh https t co Z1EXWJUlYD <PERSON>Tina Fey</PERSON> says she s relieved she s not at SNL admits screwing up <LOCATION>Charlottesville</LOCATION> sketch https t co SO4acUetDX BREAKING Former President <PERSON>GeorgeHWBush</PERSON> has been discharged from the hospital and his doctors say he is doing wel https t co FlRUekpSen Earlier VP <PERSON>Mike Pence</PERSON> met with law enforcement officers in <LOCATION>Texas</LOCATION> and praised them for their work https t co cNfOUZZtFD JUST IN 6 9 magnitude earthquake hits <LOCATION>Hawaii</LOCATION> s <ORGANIZATION>Big Island USGS</ORGANIZATION> says following a recent volcanic eruption https t co gykHLF4ldY <ORGANIZATION>FBI</ORGANIZATION> will not collect Page Strzok messages on personal accounts despite top <ORGANIZATION>GOP</ORGANIZATION> lawmaker s request https t co Nmo04MPpmp <LOCATION>Texas</LOCATION> cop former KState football star tackles thief first day on the job https t co yaaIL6R3bs kanyewest banned from radio station over recent comments https t co CPOZ1d1JNH Footage shows CarnivalCruise flooding with water due to issue with fire system https t co BSu9w3JGka RepDeSantis Says <PERSON>Rosenstein</PERSON> Botched the Mueller Probe It s Gone Far Beyond the Original Mandate https t co 21xkF3ave3 SusanPage on <PERSON>Giuliani</PERSON> joining POTUS legal team I think they are laying the groundwork for if there is a very https t co xcKZe6cSZC <PERSON>Jason Riley</PERSON> on <PERSON>Giuliani</PERSON> s Stormy Daniels comments Ironically <PERSON>Giuliani</PERSON> was brought in to help speed along the Mue https t co 5kIa8so8wr johnrobertsFox What is the U S doing to ensure that this isn t just another ploy by <LOCATION>North Korea</LOCATION> to play the https t co 20UCn52S4l <LOCATION>Iowa</LOCATION> governor signs fetal heartbeat bill into law https t co domVJYOjzE President realDonaldTrump arrives at Joint Base Andrews following his trip to <LOCATION>Dallas Texas</LOCATION> https t co kC8xQGIRBL President realdonaldtrump delivered a campaign style speech at the annual <ORGANIZATION>NRA</ORGANIZATION> convention kevincorke has the stor https t co UxVGhJxadU <LOCATION>Iran</LOCATION> aims to be king of the hill on key strategic mountain in <LOCATION>Iraq</LOCATION> https t co LPVWJU43Sx I think what are universities teaching today but oppression of free speech conformity and groupthink https t co Fv5H8i5d1n Waymo autonomous vehicle involved in crash in <LOCATION>Arizona</LOCATION> https t co niJ6WV51p3 TheJuanWilliams on POTUS <ORGANIZATION>NRA</ORGANIZATION> speech He is trying to make the case that he is the man who the <ORGANIZATION>NRA</ORGANIZATION> poured 30 https t co 8rqpibSYhr jasoninthehouse on POTUS NRA speech Let s remember going into 2018 midterms it s about getting the base https t co S2z0c21aAN RepDeSantis Says <PERSON>Rosenstein</PERSON> Botched the Mueller Probe It s Gone Far Beyond the Original Mandate TeamCavuto https t co 21xkF2SUmv <ORGANIZATION>Eta Aquarid</ORGANIZATION> meteor shower peaks this weekend What you need to know https t co FRRCqdzTLp <PERSON>Ben Carson</PERSON> hits back at hysterical critics says rent reform gives poor people a way out of poverty https t co qE0Gd331l9 GiannoCaldwell Politics in the Pulpit May Have Prompted <PERSON>Ryan</PERSON> to Dismiss House Chaplain https t co ogGS6ojvLO While speaking at the <ORGANIZATION>NRA</ORGANIZATION> s annual convention President realDonaldTrump vowed to protect the Second Amendment whi https t co XfTa1vVi6L <PERSON>Mike Baker</PERSON> on <LOCATION>North Korea</LOCATION> negotiations All sides Democrats Republicans should be standing hoping that this https t co 2lsumckD7i RepDeSantis I think <PERSON>Mueller</PERSON> should put up or shut up If he doesn t have collusion evidence then let s move on https t co kkLUkkm5ZB RT FoxBusiness AT THE CLOSE All three major indices finished the day in positive territory as technology shares rallied led by <ORGANIZATION>Apple</ORGANIZATION> ht BREAKING <LOCATION>Connecticut</LOCATION> court orders new trial for <PERSON>Kennedy</PERSON> cousin <PERSON>Michael Skakel</PERSON> convicted in 1975 murder AP reports https t co kMmn1E4jiV J <PERSON>Christian Adams</PERSON> on <PERSON>Mueller</PERSON> probe TheJusticeDept lawyers will do everything they can to keep this witch hunt https t co 0eiMKZmamX OPINION The <LOCATION>Iran</LOCATION> nuclear deal is dead and the mullahs who rule the <LOCATION>Islamic Republic</LOCATION> have only themselves to bla https t co 1X9u02ZxlK AMAZING VIDEO Man trips suspect running from police https t co F2sFx7TU8K POTUS We will never give up our freedom Americans are born free we will live free and we will die free https t co WVpXvqVXhj POTUS Nothing is more important than protecting innocent lives My administration has pursued an aggressive stra https t co 9VRTOOdQKb POTUS In my administration we have a simple policy We will protect those who protect us https t co UdggK9VwCF POTUS My administration believes our cities should be safe havens for Americans not sanctuaries for criminals https t co AKstbG2iTz President realDonaldTrump Like those early Texans Americans will never surrender Ever ever ever We will neve https t co rxWA1n9di4 POTUS We re going to start defending our country We re going to start defending our borders https t co v3s5dGs3HD This morning President realDonaldTrump tweeted about the Jobs Report https t co lbvzTQdqFM https t co BAm6AqSrjP POTUS We re here today because we recognize a simple fact The one thing that has always stood between the Amer https t co 6QUPHarBgJ POTUS We all know what s going on in <LOCATION>Chicago</LOCATION> but <LOCATION>Chicago</LOCATION> has the toughest gun laws in our country https t co jY0F4WhUXz RT FoxBusiness POTUS on gun control We re going to have to outlaw immediately all vans and all trucks which are now the new form of RT FoxBusiness POTUS The unemployment rate you saw that just today just fell beneath 4 for the first time since the beginning of t RT FoxBusiness POTUS We re really doing well with <LOCATION>North Korea</LOCATION> https t co KCCITqfg14 President realDonaldTrump JohnKerry not the best negotiator we ve ever seen He never walked away from the ta https t co Ll7zrefAwR What great people POTUS responds to <LOCATION>USA</LOCATION> chant https t co ZtA5n3lUNM POTUS We are all finally putting <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> first https t co U1vM3t8078 POTUS We put our hands on our hearts for the Pledge of Allegiance and we all proudly stand for the National Ant https t co 1TVibhpD5d President realDonaldTrump kanyewest must have some power because you probably saw I doubled my African American https t co TOPwb7m9ya POTUS We support the men and women of law enforcement https t co MqqhvQgnzW POTUS to <ORGANIZATION>NRA</ORGANIZATION> The people in this hall have never taken our freedom for granted and you have never stopped fight https t co 2GePYrl0cL POTUS We will protect your Second Amendment https t co mrsxZWsyC7 POTUS I want to thank all of you the true American patriots of the <ORGANIZATION>NRA</ORGANIZATION> who defend our rights our liberty and https t co D3OrSAM4kG President realDonaldTrump Full endorsement for this man tedcruz https t co BNYt54eGAt President realDonaldTrump to GregAbbott_TX <PERSON>Greg</PERSON> I fully endorse you You are endorsed He has done a great job https t co Hvwt0LEhSw <PERSON>Giuliani</PERSON> clarifies statements on Stormy payment <PERSON>Comey</PERSON> firing via brookefoxnews johnrobertsFox https t co c164qzIeeO President realDonaldTrump speaks at the <ORGANIZATION>NRA</ORGANIZATION> s annual convention in <LOCATION>Dallas Texas</LOCATION> https t co AiUIQYJw0a Physician for VP Pence resigns amid <PERSON>Ronny Jackson</PERSON> fallout via brookefoxnews https t co O2WhkgplO5 News Alert Awaiting POTUS s speech to the <ORGANIZATION>NRA</ORGANIZATION> For full live coverage tune in to <ORGANIZATION>Fox News Channel</ORGANIZATION> https t co 1AeT5i3bel Woman claims drunk or stoned flight attendant endangered everybody s lives https t co M65kCTCymC Last night on IngrahamAngle benshapiro gave his take on the left s response to kanyewest s declaration of admir https t co FS7hOooiVy Trying to Go Viral Conway Says April Ryan Sought Confrontation With <PERSON>Sanders</PERSON> https t co HXiVNT4fpX Lt <PERSON>Cmdr Jose Garcia</PERSON> renders a salute while being honored with a water salute during his retirement ceremony at Nav https t co SbT8RYaKw4 BREAKING NEWS <PERSON>Rudy Giuliani</PERSON> issues statement clarifying recent comments https t co jJIKzJy3e6 VP <PERSON>Mike Pence</PERSON> speaks at the <ORGANIZATION>NRA</ORGANIZATION> s annual convention in <LOCATION>Dallas Texas</LOCATION> https t co 54v2p4fSei <PERSON>Snoop Dogg</PERSON> lightens <PERSON>Kanye West</PERSON> s skin calls him all white now in Photoshopped Instagram post https t co hBQaXokHID POTUS arrives in <LOCATION>Texas</LOCATION> ahead of his speech at the <ORGANIZATION>NRA</ORGANIZATION> convention https t co SLT64Tr3YT Aerial drone footage shows a line of lava snaking its way through forest land and bubbling up on paved streets afte https t co J7POxoEW3b BREAKING NEWS VP <PERSON>Mike Pence</PERSON> s doctor who complained about <PERSON>Ronny Jackson</PERSON> s behavior has resigned https t co khTnoFsw2T Poll SenWarren leads Democrats including JoeBiden and BernieSanders in 2020 <LOCATION>New Hampshire</LOCATION> primary https t co JGFgl9CchX PROGRAMMING ALERT Awaiting President realDonaldTrump s speech to the <ORGANIZATION>NRA</ORGANIZATION> convention for full live coverage tu https t co mB9ly8hhm7 TimUSCCA Hey liberals owning a gun IS the responsible thing to do https t co PWeXgURXgi guypbenson Our border is not secure Outnumbered https t co aLjhiiSaBX LisaMarieBoothe Democrats run a risk in trying to embrace gun control efforts too much Outnumbered https t co EmV0ixWXec Deputy Attorney General <PERSON>Rod Rosenstein</PERSON> addresses the <ORGANIZATION>Montgomery County MD Bar Association</ORGANIZATION> 2018 Annual Meeting amp amp L https t co 0i32MNavsm BREAKING NEWS Federal judge harshly rebukes <PERSON>Mueller</PERSON> team during a hearing for <PERSON>Manafort</PERSON> suggests they lied about s https t co NYs07tRk7g BREAKING NEWS Federal judge in Manafort hearing accuses Special Counsel <PERSON>Mueller</PERSON> s team of lying about scope of inv https t co G52hsbtKOC KennedyNation The egregious part isn t that <ORGANIZATION>NBC</ORGANIZATION> might have misreported something The egregious part is that t https t co 43vIGGtM8h <ORGANIZATION>George Washington U Students Petition</ORGANIZATION> to Get Rid of Offensive Colonials Mascot https t co UtaR9RDTNR Trial set for Smallville actress <PERSON>Allison Mack</PERSON> alleged sex cult leader <PERSON>Keith Raniere</PERSON> https t co kO5pjquqtI POTUS <PERSON>Rudy</PERSON> is a great guy but he just started a day ago But he really has his heart into it He s working hard https t co kEl2mVmRK0 bevhallberg NBCNews is making the whole claim by President realDonaldTrump that fake news exists they re h https t co rtCig5u6bd 33 000 emails requested by <ORGANIZATION>Congress</ORGANIZATION> with a subpoena and they get burned they get deleted and nobody says anythin https t co TPENLhhqQ1 <PERSON>Kim Jong</PERSON> Un ordered North Korean hit squad to hunt high ranking defector with nuke secrets reports say https t co AjQ7hn0ANz replouiegohmert <PERSON>Mueller</PERSON> has a history of not being a man of integrity but of using and abusing the law to go a https t co Bq4XIpfkud NEW RADIO SHOW Guy <PERSON>Benson</PERSON> and <PERSON>Marie Harf</PERSON> give a fresh take on all the day s issues BensonAndHarf premieres <PERSON>Monda</PERSON> https t co fdn7KAE3Iw Report <LOCATION>North Korea</LOCATION> moves 3 detained Americans to hotel ahead of planned President realDonaldTrump <PERSON>Kim</PERSON> summit https t co PMcWu7r76P R <PERSON>Kelly</PERSON> accused of sexually abusing minor brainwashing another woman in his cult https t co DyLwVtvTJJ IvankaTrump is celebrating the Jobs Report this morning https t co lbvzTPVPOe https t co 2MAhCKhAKe Americans detained in <LOCATION>NorthKorea</LOCATION> https t co rqSBx2Z43h https t co 8T57tERbB9 This morning President realDonaldTrump tweeted about the Jobs Report https t co lbvzTPVPOe https t co P5CMHKBkau <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> says <PERSON>Giuliani</PERSON> will get his facts straight knows <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> probe is witch hunt via brookefoxnews https t co M9krIrzR2W Convoy of new pickups stolen from Ram assembly plant https t co GuzmGxBb1R <LOCATION>Hawaii</LOCATION> s <LOCATION>Kilauea</LOCATION> volcano erupts mandatory evacuations ordered for more than 1 000 people https t co ChAcKYzt3c RepJimRenacci sherrodbrown is one of the 3 most liberal senators in the country He votes with SenWarren https t co IYLJazyHE7 POTUS We re doing very well with the hostages We re in constant contact with the leadership We re in constant https t co QoeizGDV9b <PERSON>John Kelly</PERSON> Everything is going phenomenally well https t co cyyLpYFzgq 33 000 emails requested by <ORGANIZATION>Congress</ORGANIZATION> with a subpoena and they get burned they get deleted and nobody says anythin https t co CoDzqdpTFD GovMikeHuckabee POTUS is constantly under this intense pressure to answer all these questions about somethin https t co QAAc0MvVRH POTUS departs Joint Base Andrews en route to <LOCATION>Dallas Texas</LOCATION> where he will speak at the <ORGANIZATION>NRA</ORGANIZATION> convention this after https t co 7i9yD4YijI <ORGANIZATION>CNN</ORGANIZATION> s April <PERSON>Ryan</PERSON> misquotes <PERSON>Sarah Sanders</PERSON> to imply she wanted physical fight It was street https t co akaRFD4GDm Happening Now POTUS speaking to reporters ahead of departure for <ORGANIZATION>NRA</ORGANIZATION> convention https t co DZA2IKXOtq <PERSON>Bill Paxton</PERSON> s surgeon hospital deny responsibility for his death https t co K2xfnQmxUe AMAZING VIDEO Man trips suspect running from police https t co iAZkREoDiE Ex Dem IT aide <PERSON>Imran Awan</PERSO