<ner>Two <ORGANIZATION>Senate</ORGANIZATION> Democrats say they have documents that show there have been no security threats against <ORGANIZATION>EPA</ORGANIZATION> head <PERSON>Scott</PERSON> P https t co BvolhApT5U RT MSNBC EXCLUSIVE maddow obtains what appear to be handwritten notes from <ORGANIZATION>Fmr Deputy AG</ORGANIZATION> <PERSON>Dana Boente</PERSON> about President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> and <PERSON>James</PERSON> C The Russian military has been jamming some U S military drones operating in the skies over <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> seriously affect https t co LQM9ye1Vwi History will record that on this day <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> chose protecting a monster over the lives of the Syrian people <ORGANIZATION>Amb</ORGANIZATION> https t co f5Wf5Wrjx6 Legal analysis Any move to fire special counsel <PERSON>Robert Mueller</PERSON> either directly or indirectly would have serious https t co 6AtmLt0OGg RT MaddowBlog Exclusive <PERSON>Dana Boente</PERSON> letter that he has been asked for an interview by <PERSON>Robert Mueller</PERSON> https t co <ORGANIZATION>DLGXHVuBna Cambridge Analytica</ORGANIZATION> used powerful algorithms to trawl through <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> user data here s how they worked via https t co wJ5El9IIMe 21 Savage best known for his single Bank Account tells NBCNewsTHINK why he s teaching cash strapped kids how t https t co iLFci0ajkq <PERSON>Bossert</PERSON> was the face of the <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> administration s response to the crisis in <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> as recently as Sunday https t co zUZOF6dIjO With due respect President <LOCATION>Trump America</LOCATION> has been around for over two and a half centuries An investigation of https t co yJgd1dbRNB Opinion <PERSON>Ashley Pratte Trump</PERSON> is making the <ORGANIZATION>GOP</ORGANIZATION> even more male dominated to its detriment https t co 5rL0CYw6TL via NBCNewsTHINK Reporter Does the president believe he has the power to fire Special Counsel <PERSON>Mueller</PERSON> Press Sec Sanders He ce https t co o3paHWsocL Today is <ORGANIZATION>EqualPayDay</ORGANIZATION> and advocates for workplace gender parity say women still have a long way before catching u https t co tiOQHehODl NBCNewsBETTER Which is healthier a hot dog or a hamburger https t co Q76TypruSc Russian troll farm s most popular account on <LOCATION>Reddit</LOCATION> which received almost 100 000 upvotes pushed fake <PERSON>Clinton</PERSON> por https t co pNTG2LmwQh A recent <ORGANIZATION>Arizona Supreme Court</ORGANIZATION> ruling means that tuition could cost double even triple for more than 2 000 <ORGANIZATION>DACA</ORGANIZATION> r https t co cxE2RgoymT The <ORGANIZATION>European Commission</ORGANIZATION> seized records from the <LOCATION>London</LOCATION> offices of the <ORGANIZATION>Fox Networks Group</ORGANIZATION> which houses 21st Century https t co zcCtAtijkN <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> sat in the hot seat as senators fired off questions about how he plans to address <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> s growin https t co 1QXAtiOUQw NBCNewsBETTER How you can close your own personal wage gap https t co b0DHWOBsX5 EqualPayDay Senator <PERSON>Kennedy</PERSON> to <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> CEO <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> Your user agreement sucks the purpose of that user agreement is https t co 2sWZD0HNXU Sen Harris There was a decision made not to inform the users Zuckerberg That s my understanding yes kn https t co rkuybywWXC <PERSON>Harvey Milk</PERSON> picture book teaches children about LGBTQ history https t co O0CXkmBthb via NBCOUT NBCNewsBETTER Strengthen abs and banish back pain with this one move https t co n5ZdbSDpG1 The next visitors to <LOCATION>Mars</LOCATION> may be swarms of robotic bees https t co 2st39HpQmH via NBCNewsMACH S_Fitzpatrick Tom_Winter <PERSON>Stormy Daniels</PERSON> is cooperating with federal investigators probing 2016 non disclosure agr https t co bVXtJAebHS This couple had always dreamed of running the <LOCATION>Boston Marathon</LOCATION> together but when an accident left him paralyzed th https t co <ORGANIZATION>CNJeCtQHvx Sen Heller If a Facebook</ORGANIZATION> user deletes their account do you delete their data <PERSON>Zuckerberg</PERSON> Yes Heller How https t co fGBu1Vq9T3 It s clear now that we didn t do enough Watch <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> s full opening statement at his <ORGANIZATION>Senate</ORGANIZATION> testimony https t co cPJh4N7kyI WATCH <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> says <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> is working with Special Counsel <PERSON>Mueller</PERSON> https t co mek68l4pBn JUST IN <LOCATION>White House</LOCATION> President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION>DHS</ORGANIZATION> declare that <LOCATION>Chad</LOCATION> has raised its travel security standards Chadian n https t co yq8EtoeGsT During questioning from <ORGANIZATION>Sen Cruz Facebook</ORGANIZATION> CEO <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> avoids labeling his company a neutral public forum https t co wgw7MlAqDe Legal analysis Can <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> fire Mueller Maybe https t co ThCFTc4cOh RT NBCNewsTHINK Rapper 21savage is best known for his single Bank Account and now he s sharing tips on how to improve your own http Some Republicans warn President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> it would be suicide and a massive mistake to fire Special Counsel <PERSON>Robert</PERSON> https t co VzdlNQHjBT <ORGANIZATION>NEW Stormy Daniels</ORGANIZATION> cooperating with federal investigators probing 2016 non disclosure agreement and 130 000 payme https t co <ORGANIZATION>URnoUi8bWB RT NBCPolitics NEW Stormy Daniels</ORGANIZATION> cooperating with federal investigators probing 2016 non disclosure agreement and 130 000 payment she DOJ regulations could not be more clear the president does not have the authority to remove Special Counsel Muell https t co 7JcZNJb32v <ORGANIZATION>White House</ORGANIZATION> says President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> certainly believes he has the power to fire Special Counsel <PERSON>Mueller</PERSON> https t co PNq5CPQ9zN Abs_NBC History will record that on this day <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> chose protecting a monster over the lives of the Syrian peo https t co ubJ3CSajgZ RT NBCNews Sen Durbin If you ve messaged anybody this week would you share the names of the people you ve messaged <PERSON>Zuckerberg No SavannahGuthrie</PERSON> LIVE <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> congressional hearing continues Live updates https t co q55BstfZ1p https t co ECCE3Z8RUs Sen Durbin If you ve messaged anybody this week would you share the names of the people you ve messaged <PERSON>Zucker</PERSON> https t co IufTckPcvF RT NBCNews Reporter Does the president believe he has the power to fire Special Counsel <PERSON>Mueller</PERSON> Press Sec Sanders He certainly bel <PERSON>Zuckerberg</PERSON> I know we re working with Special Counsel <PERSON>Mueller</PERSON> s office says he has not been interviewed by them https t co 2Rz4N3qGhU Abs_NBC BREAKING <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> has vetoed <LOCATION>US</LOCATION> resolution to create independent mechanism to investigate chemical weapons https t co TK71r7zz9H SavannahGuthrie LIVE <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> testimony continues Live updates https t co q55BstfZ1p https t co ECCE3Z8RUs Sen Thune After more than a decade of promises to do better how is today s apology different Why should we tru https t co vTw0eKnlP1 It was my mistake and I m sorry I started <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> I run it and I am responsible for what happens here Wat https t co II2NWPP9i5 NEW <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> security aide <PERSON>Bossert</PERSON> who the <ORGANIZATION>White House</ORGANIZATION> said has resigned was called in to new National Security Adv https t co aFDJqa51u8 Reporter Does the president believe he has the power to fire Special Counsel <PERSON>Mueller</PERSON> Press Sec Sanders He ce https t co s23YRai4D5 <PERSON>Zuckerberg</PERSON> participated in 4 full practice sessions in preparation for today s testimony before <ORGANIZATION>Congress</ORGANIZATION> source te https t co 136DDbKq3W LIVE <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> makes opening statement before <ORGANIZATION>Congress Live</ORGANIZATION> updates https t co q55BstfZ1p https t co ECCE3Z8RUs ALERT NBCNews Special Report <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> testifies before <ORGANIZATION>Congress Live</ORGANIZATION> updates https t co VWJZjYJJZD RT NBCPolitics <PERSON>Sarah Huckabee Sanders</PERSON> President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> certainly believes he has the power to fire <PERSON>Robert Mueller</PERSON> frankthorp LIVE <PERSON>Zuckerberg</PERSON> congressional hearing opening statements Live updates https t co q55BstfZ1p https t co ECCE3Z8RUs frankthorp <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> arrives for testimony before <ORGANIZATION>Congress</ORGANIZATION> https t co q55BstfZ1p https t co HdoNdKLxXt RT MSNBC TUNE IN to <ORGANIZATION>MSNBC</ORGANIZATION> for live coverage of <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> s testimony before <ORGANIZATION>Congress</ORGANIZATION> https t co qwt34M3lAx frankthorp Demonstrators stand and protest ahead of <PERSON>Zuckerberg</PERSON> congressional hearing https t co q55BstfZ1p https t co ehsfogicE1 Suits cast members to attend upcoming royal wedding according to a person familiar with the guest list but not https t co b1QDpBi2Kq <ORGANIZATION>Senate</ORGANIZATION> Democrats say there s no evidence to justify <PERSON>Pruitt</PERSON> s security spending https t co S5CWVQyhSF frankthorp <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> has arrived at the <LOCATION>US Capitol</LOCATION> ahead of congressional hearing frankthorp https t co q55BstfZ1p A <LOCATION>Tennessee</LOCATION> man accused of harassing two teenage girls wearing hijabs and then swinging a knife and attacking their https t co LnG6koAP82 WATCH This is the line to get into <PERSON>Zuckerberg</PERSON> congressional hearing frankthorp https t co q55BstfZ1p https t co oLDnPrl6VD A <LOCATION>Michigan</LOCATION> State Univ student alleges in a new lawsuit that she was raped by three members of the men s basketball https t co XsiZcN9X3o LIVE <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> CEO <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> to testify before <ORGANIZATION>Congress Live</ORGANIZATION> updates https t co q55BstfZ1p https t co Cw72aNkow8 <PERSON>Joel Winston</PERSON> The <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> data breach is a scandal of our own making Legally there s nothing we can do about it https t co XvEm14SDiz RT NBCNews <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> to face <ORGANIZATION>Congress</ORGANIZATION> this afternoon Watch live on <ORGANIZATION>NBC TV MSNBC</ORGANIZATION> https t co kdrUxk2XiK https t co QMA4TJnu The <LOCATION>White House</LOCATION> s latest measures have sent Russian stocks tumbling and weakened the ruble https t co qxhrHtAZae NBCNewsWorld <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> s testimony alone won t fix <ORGANIZATION>Facebook Here</ORGANIZATION> s what might <PERSON>Dipayan Ghosh</PERSON> and <PERSON>Ben Scott</PERSON> write for https t co FRKXIed2Oi How <ORGANIZATION>Cambridge Analytica</ORGANIZATION> used powerful algorithms to trawl through <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> user data https t co xncBR81oIr via NBCNewsMACH <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> to face <ORGANIZATION>Congress</ORGANIZATION> this afternoon Watch live on <ORGANIZATION>NBC TV MSNBC</ORGANIZATION> https t co kdrUxk2XiK https t co 2FJ6FuLpIo Girls leap from balcony to escape dance studio fire https t co SOWSaANItu JUST IN In call today President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> and British PM May condemned Syrian President <PERSON>Assad</PERSON> s vicious disregard fo https t co i05qirgqG6 <PERSON>Stormy Daniels</PERSON> lawyer says he feels sorry for <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> s personal attorney branding him the president s scapegoat https t co HNleAwUkIb RT <ORGANIZATION>MSNBC</ORGANIZATION> WATCH President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> greets the Emir of <LOCATION>Qatar</LOCATION> as he arrives for a meeting at the <ORGANIZATION>White House</ORGANIZATION> https t co VrCd6TjzhD Deputy <PERSON>AG Rosenstein</PERSON> directly approved application for search warrant on <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> personal attorney <PERSON>Michael Cohen</PERSON> per https t co YeXTA8SISW RT NBCNews With due respect President <LOCATION>Trump America</LOCATION> has been around for over two and a half centuries An investigation of your person New way of defining Alzheimer s aims to find disease sooner https t co n64CLIyg1n NEW <PERSON>Sec Mattis</PERSON> will no longer travel to <LOCATION>Nevada</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>San Francisco</LOCATION> over the weekend <ORGANIZATION>Pentagon</ORGANIZATION> officials say <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> administration s religious liberty guidance a license to discriminate report says https t co 3xrQq7vTrY via <ORGANIZATION>NBCOUT RT</ORGANIZATION> NBCNewsTHINK <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> s testimony today won t magically fix <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> notes ghosd7 and <PERSON>Ben Scott</PERSON> Here s what might https NBCNewsBETTER Use the same behavior that gets you into debt in the first place to grow your savings https t co HE8ZgT7f26 <ORGANIZATION>Trump</ORGANIZATION> s company asked <LOCATION>Panama</LOCATION> president to help with hotel fight https t co fa6wgcajiL via NBCNewsWorld JUST IN Org for the Prohibition of <ORGANIZATION>Chemical Weapons OPCW</ORGANIZATION> says a team is preparing to deploy to <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> to inves https t co gOamHN1aGh NEW US calling for <ORGANIZATION>UN Security Council</ORGANIZATION> meeting at 3 p m ET to vote on <LOCATION>US</LOCATION> proposed resolution that proposes to ins https t co bamlWzSURM Video shows a gay couple brutally attacked after <LOCATION>Miami</LOCATION> Beach Gay Pride event Police are searching for the four men https t co lsUrIi0SQb With due respect President <LOCATION>Trump America</LOCATION> has been around for over two and a half centuries An investigation of https t co GY19IoLdBP <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> is jamming U S military drones in <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> which could lead to crashes four U S officials tell <ORGANIZATION>NBCNews</ORGANIZATION> https t co rxD7wz4Art RT NBCPolitics <PERSON>Schumer</PERSON> If the president is thinking of using this raid to fire Special Counsel <PERSON>Mueller</PERSON> or otherwise interfere with the LATEST <ORGANIZATION>Trump Homeland Security</ORGANIZATION> Adviser <PERSON>Tom Bossert</PERSON> is resigning <ORGANIZATION>White House</ORGANIZATION> says https t co l1cRR2XOUX NBCNewsBETTER I figured out how to get paid what I m worth and you can too https t co XKupmy4JnX EqualPayDay https t co kHNcdma3LP The President is grateful for <PERSON>Tom</PERSON> s commitment to the safety and security of our great country President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> https t co byWE9299pG BREAKING <ORGANIZATION>Trump Homeland Security</ORGANIZATION> Adviser <PERSON>Tom Bossert</PERSON> is resigning <ORGANIZATION>White House</ORGANIZATION> says https t co kdrUxk2XiK The daughter of poisoned ex Russian spy <PERSON>Sergei Skripal</PERSON> has been discharged from a British hospital officials confi https t co uwWMmKlgPn I have confidence in <PERSON>Mueller</PERSON> The president ought to have confidence in <PERSON>Mueller</PERSON> And I think it would be suici https t co SRh9iD6QTT LATEST President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> cancels first foreign trip to <LOCATION>Latin America</LOCATION> to oversee the American response to <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> Wh https t co PHld8mKdep My water stinks It still burns to take a shower There s no way they can say it s safe <LOCATION>Flint</LOCATION> braces as Michiga https t co TzrYxIEt5e NBCNewsBETTER How you can close your own personal wage gap https t co ZL7lCwM2jq EqualPayDay Voters in <LOCATION>Anchorage</LOCATION> blocked a measure that would have forced transgender people to use public facilities that match https t co zRpdFf87nn Legal analysis For the <LOCATION>US</LOCATION> president and his attorney attorney client privilege goes only so far https t co r9MVcbGBYP https t co PGIV1vGIA5 BREAKING <ORGANIZATION>White House</ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> no longer going on upcoming <LOCATION>South America</LOCATION> trip will remain in <LOCATION>US</LOCATION> to overse https t co WwXWlqjZcV In today s NBCFirstRead Do congressional Republicans finally draw a line in the sand when it comes to protecting https t co dbobM0zrXi Relying on a woman s previous salary to determine her pay for a new job is illegal when it results in higher pay fo https t co Pjaff8zuq7 Russian Embassy to the <LOCATION>UK</LOCATION> Secret resettlement of Mr and Ms <PERSON>Skripal</PERSON> barred from any contact with their family wil https t co 3xGyx3RGiD Legal analysis For the <LOCATION>US</LOCATION> president and his attorney attorney client privilege goes only so far https t co QG3wGoNtKf CevallosLaw RT NBCNews Exclusive <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> is jamming U S military drones in <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> which could lead to crashes four U S officials tell <ORGANIZATION>NBCNews</ORGANIZATION> htt Sounds like President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> or President <PERSON>Obama</PERSON> UK s Queen <PERSON>Elizabeth</PERSON> jokes about loud helicopters as she talks w https t co PdHx6Rmg2q <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> CEO <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> will face questions from lawmakers keen to get answers about the company s data privac https t co yPAZoQRiYK NEW <PERSON>Stormy Daniels</PERSON> lawyer says he feels sorry for <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> s personal attorney branding him the president s scap https t co TkKl4AXuXR Attorney client privilege is dead President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> tweets Tuesday morning after court authorized raids on his law https t co tdyVTVJh1Y A <ORGANIZATION>Sinclair Broadcast</ORGANIZATION> talk show was after its host <PERSON>Jamie Allman</PERSON> wrote an explicit tweet about assaulting a survivo https t co eErNwczpVT Exclusive <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> is jamming U S military drones in <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> which could lead to crashes four U S officials tell https t co iC2jgHLbme The daughter of poisoned ex Russian spy <PERSON>Sergei Skripal</PERSON> has been discharged from a British hospital officials confi https t co IPlG94JzfC President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> blasts the <ORGANIZATION>FBI</ORGANIZATION> and special counsel <PERSON>Robert Mueller</PERSON> following news that investigators had raided the https t co zWWX9TaVmF RT TODAYshow Today on TODAY The fallout from the <ORGANIZATION>FBI</ORGANIZATION> raid on the office of President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> s personal attorney and we re live on <PERSON>Capito</PERSON> Opinion <PERSON>John Bolton</PERSON> is scary because much of D C agrees with him https t co 4TpFwtrFFn NBCNewsTHINK Young students leap from a balcony to escape a fire at a dance studio in <LOCATION>Edgewater New Jersey</LOCATION> Despite the feroc https t co TXkglhDFwz The <LOCATION>White House</LOCATION> s latest measures have sent Russian stocks tumbling and weakened the ruble https t co mhldt8d3dW NBCNewsWorld In <LOCATION>Springfield Massachusetts</LOCATION> <PERSON>Kim George</PERSON> and her volunteers help families in need keep their best friends when the https t co ZbthmCet2T <ORGANIZATION>FBI</ORGANIZATION> raids office of <PERSON>Michael Cohen</PERSON> President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> s personal lawyer seeking information about a 130 000 payment https t co NZPHozpqJb Russian military has been jamming some U S military drones operating in the skies over <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> seriously affecting https t co <ORGANIZATION>DlekEoR8tN Russian Embassy</ORGANIZATION> to the <LOCATION>UK</LOCATION> We congratulate <PERSON>Yulia Skripal</PERSON> on her recovery Yet we need urgent proof that what is be https t co gW8Usgc198 <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> CEO <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> will face questions from lawmakers keen to get answers about the company s data privac https t co d9xySPV2EQ <PERSON>Lindsey Buckingham</PERSON> lead guitarist and a key songwriter for <ORGANIZATION>Fleetwood Mac</ORGANIZATION> is again leaving the group the band say https t co EVo6DWYct9 JUST IN <LOCATION>UK</LOCATION> hospital confirms <PERSON>Yulia Skripal</PERSON> the daughter of former Russian spy <PERSON>Sergei Skripal</PERSON> has been discharged https t co LZ4FeebWCw The latest missile strikes targeting a Syrian air base highlight the nightmare scenario <LOCATION>Israel</LOCATION> is facing arch enem https t co vgSxUQZ8hh A <ORGANIZATION>Sinclair Broadcast</ORGANIZATION> talk show has been cancelled after its host <PERSON>Jamie Allman</PERSON> wrote an explicit tweet about assau https t co doRAQ6c1lI President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> We ll be making some major decisions in the next 24 to 48 hours https t co fURmg7hzas NBCNewsWorld The average American consumes almost 20 teaspoons of sugar per day Do you need a sugar detox https t co ad1C2lx3jA NBCNewsBETTER Opinion <PERSON>Ronda Penrice Cardi</PERSON> B s pregnancy announcement sends powerful message about motherhood https t co 2cqVJc9Z1A NBCNewsTHINK If road trips theme parks and beach resorts just don t do it for you how about a stay in a swanky space hotel https t co 9TUgxEfQYB <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> is commissioning an independent study on the effects of social media on elections and democracy CEO and https t co FPUkal6XOB Without her plastic in hand one woman was forced to face the cold hard reality of her spending habits https t co jlx4xwRr7I Against the backdrop of higher mortgage rates new data shows that rental rates continue to climb https t co 0TQMaPYpDZ Raftlike homes and buoyant buildings may be a fix for rising sea levels https t co ayXnf7QCt8 NBCNewsMACH The Carolina Reaper billed as the world s hottest pepper causes thunderclap headaches doctors say https t co 4pX9GGQPF4 WATCH The <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> share a chilly exchange during the <ORGANIZATION>United Nations Security Council</ORGANIZATION> meeting on a https t co ODsDolXrm2 Voters in <LOCATION>Anchorage</LOCATION> blocked a measure that would have forced transgender people to use public facilities that match https t co 1T3WFiJBMI Young immigrants with DACA status who want to attend college in their home state of <LOCATION>Arizona</LOCATION> will have to pay out of https t co aeQVhmel57 <ORGANIZATION>Bayer</ORGANIZATION> has reached a deal with the <ORGANIZATION>U S Justice Department</ORGANIZATION> for antitrust approval for its 62 5 billion bid to acqui https t co gqHrSI8CTn I was raped when I was 8 years old By a grownup that I truly trusted Award winning author <PERSON>Junot</PERSON> D az revealed t https t co OHzvQcqNbO My water stinks It still burns to take a shower There s no way they can say it s safe <LOCATION>Flint</LOCATION> braces as Michiga https t co M0XizBexUz No working smoke detector was found in the 50th floor <LOCATION>Trump Tower</LOCATION> apartment that went up in flames in <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> kil https t co tKOVCtVaBC The <ORGANIZATION>NRA</ORGANIZATION> and supporters have sponsored legislation to stop pediatricians from asking parents about guns in the home https t co T7rqDmm780 Families and friends already stunned by the deaths of 15 players and team personnel for <ORGANIZATION>Humboldt</ORGANIZATION> s youth hockey clu https t co jksGGBV46m A new report by a <LOCATION>Washington</LOCATION> based think tank suggests that <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> s dire warnings about those who seek asylum in th https t co sh3FyoOw37 NBCNewsBETTER Setting options to private is one step in the right direction if we want to deal with Venmo more s https t co W8aUB1lmbF A food processing company in <LOCATION>Iowa</LOCATION> is responsible for the outbreak which appears to be over the <ORGANIZATION>CDC</ORGANIZATION> said https t co 2CiN4ASFXB At least five openly transgender women are signed up to run the storied 26 2 mile race through <LOCATION>Boston</LOCATION> and its subur https t co 89jAwgufPf Jessica Luther The <ORGANIZATION>NFL</ORGANIZATION> s next big scandal is its disgusting treatment of its cheerleaders https t co Jdz9TLqpkk via NBCNewsTHINK As sea levels continue to rise many builders and urban planners are turning to floating architecture https t co EV4XHK7Ff8 Child advocates are asking the <ORGANIZATION>Federal Trade Commission</ORGANIZATION> to investigate <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> for allegedly violating children s on https t co pltk1YFzXA Naked protester shouts Women s lives matter in front of <PERSON>Bill Cosby</PERSON> as he walks into court https t co zAS4CWWwkW https t co afyjqGOqZ4 It was my mistake and I m sorry <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> chief executive <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> released prepared statements for his https t co gedLOZbT3G I don t rule out anything right now <ORGANIZATION>U S Defense</ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON>Mattis</PERSON> says when asked about possibility of the U S https t co cHvA3xIvhk WATCH The Russian regime whose hands are all covered in the blood of Syrian children cannot be ashamed by pictu https t co 9Sci2QTZdZ When you look at the top TV shows among Democrats and Republicans the programs that members of each party say the https t co 5I57GrWj1m Senator <PERSON>Tammy Duckworth</PERSON> gave birth to a daughter becoming the first U S senator to have a baby while in office O https t co 6mvjCl2djx Sunday s episode of The Simpsons took on complaints of stereotyping surrounding the character of <PERSON>Apu Nahasapeemap</PERSON> https t co BYkP6DpLKG <ORGANIZATION>Lucasfilm</ORGANIZATION> dropped a new trailer for Solo A Star Wars Story that reveals a lot of new information about director https t co fhRcyEadIi NBCNewsBETTER The average American consumes almost 20 teaspoons of sugar per day Do you need a sugar detox https t co UAptdKNCWt Why this boat plane hybrid that hovers above the water could revolutionize traveling by sea https t co mypYzgLnDe https t co uJqE8co4R9 <LOCATION>Florida</LOCATION> Governor <PERSON>Rick Scott</PERSON> announces <ORGANIZATION>Senate</ORGANIZATION> run We must change <LOCATION>Washington</LOCATION> https t co vBkbFpWEJ9 <PERSON>Lynch</PERSON> speaking with NBC News <PERSON>Lester Holt</PERSON> defended the tens of thousands of people who work for the Justice Depar https t co LfCShxnoCx For six months NBCNews documented the lives of children in depleted hospitals across <LOCATION>Yemen</LOCATION> finding few doctors https t co s1W71TZ8f8 Chicken salad contaminated with salmonella bacteria made by an <LOCATION>Iowa</LOCATION> food processing company has sickened 265 people https t co nyelwhJza6 350 pediatricians will head to <LOCATION>Capitol Hill</LOCATION> to lobby in favor of gun violence legislation including two <ORGANIZATION>Senate</ORGANIZATION> bil https t co bGgQSggfIS RT NBCLeftField Let s say on Saturday night I would party super hard and Sunday morning I was always in church We spoke with young Data breaches are down almost 25 percent this year but it s no cause for celebration Cyber thieves have simply c https t co i4BEWBRZ91 WATCH President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> says he ll meet with <LOCATION>North Korea</LOCATION> in May or early June https t co NolgnGbyhZ Mexican leftist candidate Andr s <PERSON>Manuel L pez Obrador</PERSON> has a nearly 11 point lead over his closest rival ahead of th https t co 2puMJZw0Nh Prime Minister <PERSON>Viktor Orban</PERSON> won a third straight term in power in the Hungarian elections after his anti immigratio https t co eMNn3Q0WyL RT NBCNightlyNews WATCH In an exclusive interview with LesterHoltNBC <PERSON>Loretta Lynch</PERSON> discusses former <ORGANIZATION>FBI</ORGANIZATION> Director <PERSON>James Comey</PERSON> her airp NBCNewsBETTER How <PERSON>Johnny Weir</PERSON> found and stayed true to his authentic self https t co Tooz6wD7Ay President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> blasted the <ORGANIZATION>FBI</ORGANIZATION> and special counsel <PERSON>Robert Mueller</PERSON> following news that investigators had raided the https t co AJ4ZMBR6OE NBCNewsBETTER Don t get hangry These healthy snacks can help you reach your weight loss goals https t co fjxpVwTekd President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> calls the <ORGANIZATION>FBI</ORGANIZATION> raid of his lawyer <PERSON>Michael Cohen</PERSON> s office and hotel room a disgrace and says Attorn https t co UDfqdiHoiP <PERSON>Ronda Penrice Cardi</PERSON> B s pregnancy announcement sends powerful message about motherhood https t co yALQhmujtc via NBCNewsTHINK President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> says decision to be made following suspected <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> chemical attack near <LOCATION>Damascus</LOCATION> It will be met a https t co R8aP24RiqE President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> responds to question about firing special counsel <PERSON>Robert Mueller</PERSON> Well I think it s a disgrace w https t co gUfNKDnTZD Low crime village bans military style guns citing Parkland and other mass shootings https t co MgEWEwqZMq Motivational speaker and business strategist <PERSON>Tony Robbins</PERSON> publicly apologized after suggesting during a March 15 ev https t co cPFHKwjupM The <ORGANIZATION>CBO</ORGANIZATION> report says that that the twin tax and spending bills will push the budget deficit to 804 billion this yea https t co ydlvEpUURz President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> condemned the suspected chemical attack in <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> calling it a heinous act and saying his adminis https t co 3nRobu1FGy RT TheBeatWithAri Breaking <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> responds to <PERSON>Michael Cohen</PERSON> raid It s a disgrace it s an attack on our country https t co TcuHJ6y8 Dozens of people have died in a suspected chemical weapons attack on the city of <LOCATION>Douma Local</LOCATION> activists tell <ORGANIZATION>NBC N</ORGANIZATION> https t co MVZJSqyNe1 <LOCATION>Israel</LOCATION> carried out air strikes against a Syrian air base and informed the U S in advance two U S officials told https t co YdlBiCc6cG A brief history of chemical weapons from World War I to <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> https t co 0iujo9IjEW via <ORGANIZATION>NBCNewsMACH Arizona Supreme Court</ORGANIZATION> No in state tuition for <ORGANIZATION>DACA</ORGANIZATION> college students https t co zOnJUo72ft via <ORGANIZATION>NBCLatino</ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> calls suspected Syrian chemical attack atrocious and barbaric https t co OPk76Duwms The <ORGANIZATION>NFL</ORGANIZATION> s next big scandal is its disgusting treatment of its cheerleaders <PERSON>Jessica Luther</PERSON> writes for NBCNewsTHINK https t co nIlAdVx93e Pop star <PERSON>Kesha</PERSON> officiated a same sex wedding in a recently unveiled music video for her song I Need a Woman to Lov https t co g7IztzpxwX RT NBCLeftField In <LOCATION>Springfield Massachusetts</LOCATION> <PERSON>Kim George</PERSON> and her volunteers help families in need keep their best friends when they can <ORGANIZATION>RT NBCLatino JUST IN Arizona Supreme Court</ORGANIZATION> rules no in state tuition for <ORGANIZATION>DACA</ORGANIZATION> college students https t co pKDE40yQJN Amphibious houses look like ordinary buildings But their foundations function as a sort of raft when water starts https t co 3SzyAEpxB8 RT NBCNews <ORGANIZATION>MSNBC</ORGANIZATION> LATEST <ORGANIZATION>FBI</ORGANIZATION> raids the office of <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> lawyer <PERSON>Michael Cohen</PERSON> his lawyer says https t co UWoaiimcAo RT LesterHoltNBC Tonight my interview with former Attorney General <PERSON>Loretta Lynch</PERSON> about the <PERSON>Clinton</PERSON> email server investigation <PERSON>James</PERSON> Come We are beyond showing pictures of dead babies History will record this as the moment when the <ORGANIZATION>Security Council</ORGANIZATION> https t co hU27yEYZdM <ORGANIZATION>MSNBC</ORGANIZATION> LATEST <ORGANIZATION>FBI</ORGANIZATION> raids the office of <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> lawyer <PERSON>Michael Cohen</PERSON> his lawyer says https t co UWoaiimcAo <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> s obstructionism will not continue to hold us hostage when we are confronted with an attack like this one https t co MsBzp2EUJc Amb Haley at <ORGANIZATION>UN Security Council</ORGANIZATION> emergency meeting Here we are in a world where chemical weapons use is becomi https t co ZdTxE3kpZy MSNBC <PERSON>Cohen</PERSON> s lawyer The decision by the <ORGANIZATION>U S Attorney s Office</ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> to conduct their investigation using https t co 5B2XBiq32U Live breaking news coverage now on <ORGANIZATION>MSNBC</ORGANIZATION> https t co L92IcvBHXb BREAKING <ORGANIZATION>FBI</ORGANIZATION> raids office of President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> s longtime lawyer <PERSON>Michael Cohen</PERSON> his lawyer says https t co kdrUxk2XiK Amb <PERSON>Haley</PERSON> at <ORGANIZATION>UN Security Council</ORGANIZATION> meeting When the Syrian military pummels civilians they rely on the military https t co kziv4Yr6Jo <ORGANIZATION>Amb Haley</ORGANIZATION> on suspected chemical attack in <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> The monster who was responsible for these attacks has no conscie https t co TuMnSVQKmd LIVE Amb <PERSON>Haley</PERSON> speaks at <ORGANIZATION>UN Security Council</ORGANIZATION> emergency meeting on suspected chemical attack in <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> https t co <ORGANIZATION>OXdVFJIKxd Boston</ORGANIZATION> other marathons say transgender women can compete as women https t co F0Tx80w7d4 via NBCOUT In one on one interview with LesterHoltNBC former <ORGANIZATION>AG Lynch</ORGANIZATION> addresses <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> criticisms and discusses the <LOCATION>Phoenix</LOCATION> https t co x4C9Mjnfb4 RT NBCNewsTHINK Electing to become a mother amidst burgeoning stardom is unconventional But so is most everything about <PERSON>Cardi</PERSON> B s rise <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> CEO <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> releases prepared statements for his upcoming testimony before U S lawmakers https t co 6I5iqw1hgZ RT NBCNews LIVE Russian representative speaks at <ORGANIZATION>UN Security Council</ORGANIZATION> emergency meeting on suspected chemical attack in <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> https t LIVE Russian representative speaks at <ORGANIZATION>UN Security Council</ORGANIZATION> emergency meeting on suspected chemical attack in <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> https t co mbRS7hEbfV LIVE <ORGANIZATION>UN Security Council</ORGANIZATION> holds emergency meeting after suspected chemical attack in <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> https t co tY1q4VWdm1 https t co qFdaXpsNRy RT NBCPolitics <PERSON>Sarah Sanders</PERSON> on criticism from <PERSON>McCain</PERSON> that <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> s rhetoric emboldened suspected chemical attack in <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> I think tha LIVE <ORGANIZATION>White House</ORGANIZATION> press briefing https t co ISFcRz7uXf Sen <PERSON>Tammy Duckworth</PERSON> gave birth to a daughter becoming the first U S senator to give birth while in office https t co 2UP5ayDVTy <LOCATION>Arizona</LOCATION> s governor says he s deploying 225 members of the state <ORGANIZATION>National Guard</ORGANIZATION> to the U S <LOCATION>Mexico</LOCATION> border becoming https t co diMLUPAtAK RT <ORGANIZATION>MSNBC</ORGANIZATION> SenBillNelson reveals details from his meeting with <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> today ahead of his Tuesday testimony on <ORGANIZATION>Capitol Hill</ORGANIZATION> Wat NEW A new budget analysis says the combined effects of President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> s tax cuts and last month s budget busting https t co M16KcfHCHE NBCNewsBETTER A smarter way to use Venmo https t co B2qyW7n3tS NEW Stormy <PERSON>Daniels</PERSON> says she always believed agreement was with <ORGANIZATION>Trump</ORGANIZATION> https t co fn5wXAH5tp Sen <PERSON>Tammy Duckworth</PERSON> gives birth to a baby girl becoming the first U S Senator to give birth while in office <PERSON>Sec Mattis</PERSON> on possible airstrikes against <PERSON>Assad</PERSON> I don t rule out anything right now https t co x5gwGO17uv RT NBCNewsMACH How floating architecture could help save cities from rising seas https t co BPkm7vHuJS https t co MBVmmXY5bY <ORGANIZATION>Trump</ORGANIZATION> officials can t agree whether U S has hit <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> where it hurts https t co rIjHKagGNr Jessica Luther The <ORGANIZATION>NFL</ORGANIZATION> s next big scandal is its disgusting treatment of its cheerleaders https t co XjGB1gGsxE via <LOCATION>NBCNewsTHINK</LOCATION> President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> says major decisions on <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> likely in next 24 to 48 hours https t co y3RvmTwsp3 RT NBCNewsWorld 5 park rangers and their driver killed Monday during an ambush by suspected rebels in <LOCATION>Virunga National Park</LOCATION> home to crit My water stinks It still burns to take a shower There s no way they can say it s safe <LOCATION>Flint</LOCATION> braces as Michiga https t co jnQV38xboR Facebook CEO <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> arrives for <LOCATION>Capitol Hill</LOCATION> meetings ahead of scheduled testimonies in the <ORGANIZATION>Senate</ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON>Hou</PERSON> https t co NWbvQM9Wh0 He may President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> says when asked if Russian President <PERSON>Putin</PERSON> bears responsibility for alleged chemical atta https t co NevvrUI5C2 Opinion <PERSON>Robert Moore John Bolton</PERSON> is scary because much of D C agrees with him https t co h3P4Q1sBtf via <ORGANIZATION>NBCNewsTHINK U S</ORGANIZATION> will meet with <LOCATION>North Korea</LOCATION> sometime in May or early June President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> says in Cabinet meeting https t co 85ZE5yMNCZ If it s <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> if it s <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> if it s <LOCATION>Iran</LOCATION> if it s all of them together we ll figure it out and we ll know t https t co 912ng9qOw4 I d like to begin by condemning the heinous attack on innocent Syrians with banned chemical weapons It was an atr https t co W0q5UOOqXo BREAKING President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> says his admin will be making a decision in 24 to 48 hours on a response to alleged chem https t co tkndOLn1n9 News analysis <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> strikes spotlight <LOCATION>Israel</LOCATION> s nightmare <LOCATION>Iran</LOCATION> on its border https t co rvVg0NyPrY via <ORGANIZATION>NBCNewsWorld RT</ORGANIZATION> NBCNewsBETTER What your venmo feed says about you and your financial data https t co 1rOTnoC8iY RT NBCNewsTHINK The <ORGANIZATION>NFL</ORGANIZATION> needs female fans to survive argues jessicawluther So why does it still treat its female employees like second <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> is commissioning an independent study on the effects of social media on elections and democracy CEO and https t co XlAXKo42WT <PERSON>John Bolton</PERSON> the one time U S ambassador to the <ORGANIZATION>UN</ORGANIZATION> whose unapologetic brand of foreign policy has led him to clash https t co xsHckSvw5c NEW In one on one interview with LesterHoltNBC former <ORGANIZATION>AG Lynch</ORGANIZATION> addresses <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> criticisms and discusses the Pho https t co cazn7HCCsY Canadian authorities identify ten hockey players and five staff of <ORGANIZATION>Humboldt Broncos</ORGANIZATION> hockey team who died in collisi https t co WrbjsHAeP7 I don t rule out anything right now <ORGANIZATION>US Defense Sec Mattis</ORGANIZATION> says when asked about possibility of <LOCATION>US</LOCATION> launching str https t co a7dC7M7eAJ Women s lives matter Protester jumps in front of <PERSON>Bill Cosby</PERSON> as he walks into court https t co m6JBEOHOQE Here s what s left on the pre midterms congressional agenda and how likely lawmakers with an eye on Election Day https t co kTzoX7MYd7 Spanglish is here to stay and it s good exercise for your brain https t co q7kgXXMaLO via NBCLatino Syrian opposition activists and aid groups say dozens of people have died in a suspected chemical weapons attack on https t co 7AJCJSdXmX In today s NBCFirstRead Republican <LOCATION>Florida</LOCATION> Gov <PERSON>Scott</PERSON> will challenge vulnerable Sen <PERSON>Bill Nelson</PERSON> https t co dWk2uj2Z8L Sen <PERSON>Claire McCaskill</PERSON> is locked in what is sure to be one of the nastiest most closely contested and expensive ele https t co RxJa48QXAZ I don t rule out anything right now <ORGANIZATION>US Defense Sec Mattis</ORGANIZATION> says when asked about possibility of <LOCATION>US</LOCATION> launching str https t co 6GC4DhvXtg Child advocates are asking the <ORGANIZATION>Federal Trade Commission</ORGANIZATION> to investigate <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> for allegedly violating children s on https t co Jnt5meXQFW RT NBCPolitics NEW <LOCATION>Florida</LOCATION> Gov <PERSON>Rick Scott</PERSON> to challenge <PERSON>Sen Bill Nelson</PERSON> for <ORGANIZATION>US Senate</ORGANIZATION> seat a <PERSON>Scott</PERSON> political adviser tells NBCPolitic <PERSON>Bill Cosby</PERSON> s sexual assault retrial will be the first big celebrity court case since the MeToo movement saw dozens https t co Cg5eTbbwBE A new report released by a <LOCATION>Washington</LOCATION> based think tank suggests that President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> s dire warnings about those wh https t co qSCh2EyTwh Get ready to find out if your <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> data has been swept up in the <ORGANIZATION>Cambridge Analytica</ORGANIZATION> scandal https t co kENqjCTgyj <LOCATION>Israel</LOCATION> carried out the strikes against Syrian base two U S officials tell <ORGANIZATION>NBCNews</ORGANIZATION> and the <LOCATION>US</LOCATION> was informed of th https t co 3XapQveuEL RT NBCNews Dozens of people have died in a suspected chemical weapons attack on the city of <LOCATION>Douma Local</LOCATION> activists tell <ORGANIZATION>NBC News</ORGANIZATION> that th Opinion <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> s use of the Mexican rapist trope is as old as colonialism https t co oHFkwuf7WE NBCNewsTHINK RT NBCNightlyNews WATCH Did he go to you and question your credibility with regard to the <PERSON>Clinton</PERSON> case <ORGANIZATION>LesterHoltNBC</ORGANIZATION> asks former Att Any company or U S individual can put stakes in the ground and prospect in Bears Ears National Monument all for th https t co xMQHG3Kxc3 Coming in the wake of fake news factories and troll farms experts warn it is the latest way in which public trust https t co h8BkwbCSQX Here s what s left on the pre midterms congressional agenda and how likely lawmakers with an eye on Election Day https t co vOtpgeoPkF Syrian opposition activists and aid groups say dozens of people have died in a suspected chemical weapons attack on https t co Xy5pXuasnZ RT TODAYshow Today on TODAY President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> says there s a big price to pay after a suspected chemical attack in <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> We re live wit <LOCATION>NEW Russia</LOCATION> and the Syrian military blame <LOCATION>Israel</LOCATION> for a pre dawn missile attack on an air base in central <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> https t co tXy94383Bo A new report released by a <LOCATION>Washington</LOCATION> based think tank suggests that President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> s dire warnings about those wh https t co kcPySL9UN1 Sen <PERSON>Claire McCaskill</PERSON> is locked in what is sure to be one of the nastiest most closely contested and expensive ele https t co vI2rwIFrW1 <LOCATION>Hungary</LOCATION> s right wing nationalist Prime Minister <PERSON>Viktor Orban</PERSON> wins a third straight term in power in the country s e https t co 3OClzzYE61 Here s what s left on the pre midterms congressional agenda and how likely lawmakers with an eye on Election Day https t co LSb6ENh4pZ Coming in the wake of fake news factories and troll farms experts warn digital diplomacy is the latest way in whic https t co tgJrkY7Kgy Dozens of people have died in a suspected chemical weapons attack on the city of <LOCATION>Douma Local</LOCATION> activists tell <ORGANIZATION>NBC N</ORGANIZATION> https t co EjLkLeWLFo A Quiet Place opened with the second best week of any movie this year behind only Black Panther https t co mEspuen70W At least six people have been seriously injured after a bus carrying teenagers returning from a spring break trip s https t co iG1WEloRKX President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> s tweets calling <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> s President <PERSON>Bashar al Assad</PERSON> an animal for the suspected use of poison gas https t co Ik7Prz6bzn Canadian authorities have identified the 15 members of a junior league hockey team who died after their bus collide https t co X0id0f9ba3 Syrian opposition activists and aid groups say that dozens of people have died in a suspected chemical weapons atta https t co Zkcr6Rr0zr Springtime allergies aren t curable but these doctor recommended tips will make the season a whole lot more bearab https t co D3lsiXy9T2 Opinion <PERSON>Sinclair</PERSON> s fake news script risked viewers trust in local news https t co IKBKiCAxpN NBCNewsTHINK Chemical layer is seen as a way to protect the Great Barrier Reef from effects of global warming https t co Ftvrb6tD02 NBCNewsMACH Nightmare bacteria are trying to spread in the <ORGANIZATION>U S CDC</ORGANIZATION> says https t co DTJ1O5ie0H What it takes to be a good listener and how you can get better at this crucial skill https t co 82sDBrKCMF NBCNewsBETTER Woman wanted for stealing 17 500 rock from <PERSON>Yoko Ono</PERSON> exhibition https t co Jb630kJCoA <LOCATION>NEW UK</LOCATION> based <ORGANIZATION>Syrian Observatory for Human Rights</ORGANIZATION> 14 people including Iranians killed in missile attack near city of Homs The asteroid threat is unique It s the only natural disaster that can be predicted and averted https t co Zb8PWzj852 NBCNewsMACH NBCNewsBETTER Slack is changing its privacy policy this month Here s how you can check if your boss can read yo https t co syJXJrqZYB <PERSON>Heidi Heitkamp</PERSON> bets big on small state politics to save her seat https t co 4TzkpdDMXR Do marches and protests actually make a difference https t co 8gULUIwfgQ via <ORGANIZATION>NBCLeftField Ani Bundel Killing Eve</ORGANIZATION> is a welcome addition to the boy s club that is British crime dramas https t co CCLzWP8mOm via NBCNewsTHINK Large parts of <LOCATION>Australia</LOCATION> s <LOCATION>Great Barrier Reef</LOCATION> are dying Can this ultra thin sunscreen save it https t co B6uIwv1QxX via NBCNewsMACH Patient advocacy groups take in millions from drugmakers new database reveals Is there a payback https t co tn76zfX4s9 Men in STEM subject areas overestimate their own intelligence and underestimate the abilities of female colleagues https t co PfBjwMLsFP We have to fight I won t go out without a fight High teacher turnover helps fuel educators march on statehou https t co 2w8u6On84I Legal analysis Does President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> s response help or hurt <ORGANIZATION>Stormy Daniels</ORGANIZATION> legal claims https t co m7O9TBGDbV Canadian authorities identify ten hockey players and five staff of <ORGANIZATION>Humboldt Broncos</ORGANIZATION> hockey team who died in collisi https t co ygQs3jyzvh Spanglish is here to stay and it s good exercise for your brain https t co 2ZmOxgeAal via <ORGANIZATION>NBCLatino NBCPolitics</ORGANIZATION> https t co uwGs4LZeSW <ORGANIZATION>NEW White House</ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> and French President <PERSON>Macron</PERSON> spoke via phone today strongly condemned the horrif https t co tIQzjKqqk5 NBCNewsBETTER Do ASMR videos and podcasts really work https t co 9btxvizKAI Renters are squeezed on both ends Sluggish wage growth means paychecks haven t kept up with rent increases and sa https t co HpXIEo20Jj NBCNewsBETTER Here s what depression does to your brain and how you can overcome it https t co Cxd2IHfwPP Health officials are sounding an alarm on the drug gabapentin And it s not even an opioid https t co 5C3ljBFPDM Suzanne Garment What <PERSON>Nixon</PERSON> s Watergate blunders suggest about the trouble <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> is in now https t co P9SEuwV2X8 via NBCNewsTHINK His name has become synonymous with one of the most talked about political investigations of our time But who is https t co vKJV4in3K3 <PERSON>Warren Jeffs</PERSON> polygamous sect in sacred land standoff https t co 1UevZCj988 via <ORGANIZATION>NBCLeftField Patrick Reed</ORGANIZATION> holds off <LOCATION>Jordan Spieth</LOCATION> and <PERSON>Rickie Fowler</PERSON> at Masters for first major victory https t co 39VDSLbGL1 via NBCSports This luxury space hotel could be up and running in four years and a room will cost you 80 000 per night https t co GXmTJduC20 Politicians call for action after suspected <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> chemical attack https t co COiK1Xr4dh RT NBCLeftField Any company or U S individual can put stakes in the ground and prospect in Bears Ears National Monument all for the low <ORGANIZATION>GOP</ORGANIZATION> senator wants President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> to explain endgame on tariffs https t co 3YYycnTga1 RT tvkatesnow Coming up <ORGANIZATION>NBCNightlyNews</ORGANIZATION> reports of a horrific chemical attack in <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> amp amp <LOCATION>US</LOCATION> response on the ground with migrants in <LOCATION>Mex Woman</LOCATION> wanted for stealing 17 500 rock from <PERSON>Yoko Ono</PERSON> exhibition https t co nRCtUtUkr5 President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> uncharacteristically criticizes <PERSON>Putin</PERSON> after reports of chemical attack in <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> https t co hEF8C7ba68 News analysis Did <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> s tweets on the <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> attack lock him into an even bigger military retaliation https t co McTz86wNY2 Legal analysis Does President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> s response help or hurt <ORGANIZATION>Stormy Daniels</ORGANIZATION> legal claims https t co <ORGANIZATION>Ww5pkzqagJ RT NBCPolitics Sen McCain</ORGANIZATION> says Syrian President <PERSON>Assad</PERSON> has been emboldened by American inaction in statement on suspected chemical atta JUST IN The U S has confirmed <PERSON>Kim Jong Un</PERSON> is willing to discuss the denuclearization of the <LOCATION>Korean Peninsula</LOCATION> acc https t co 3gG3gFqSUY NBCNewsBETTER What one woman learned about her spending habits when she quit credit cards cold turkey https t co zTQbXoOa7L RT MeetThePress COMING SOON We re launching The Lid a new daily audio briefing from the <ORGANIZATION>NBC News</ORGANIZATION> political unit that will keep you up t I love teaching and I love the kids but I don t know that I can continue to do it High teacher turnover helps https t co ktt4LEfdvr JUST IN <ORGANIZATION>UN Security Council</ORGANIZATION> confirms it will hold emergency meeting Monday after suspected <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> chemical attack https t co C5TdlkGPtr But while Democrats are more likely to watch certain shows than Republicans and vice versa the most popular entert https t co <ORGANIZATION>B5gBtnBt2i Research</ORGANIZATION> shows that more Democrats favor programs like Empire and Veep while Republicans prefer Last Man <PERSON>Stan</PERSON> https t co TnWt8mneo3 Data Download How deep are the partisan divides in <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> s entertainment TV viewing That depends on how you loo https t co yyZJQXdoYc Black Panther star <PERSON>Chadwick Boseman</PERSON> pokes fun at the film s success on SNL https t co OMduVbsCS0 Dozens reported killed in suspected <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> chemical attack https t co GZeOqujUXM <PERSON>Shohei Ohtani</PERSON> dubbed the Japanese Babe <PERSON>Ruth</PERSON> forges own path while following one paved by past Japanese stars https t co v7vkaCMnqG Opinion <PERSON>Marie Myung Ok Lee</PERSON> We can t blame race for every Asian American rejected by <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> https t co c09g3XXaAE via <ORGANIZATION>NBCNewsTHINK RT</ORGANIZATION> NBCNewsWorld JUST IN Emergency meeting of <ORGANIZATION>United Nations Security Council</ORGANIZATION> expected on Monday in response to reported <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> chemical a Renters are squeezed on both ends Sluggish wage growth means paychecks haven t kept up with rent increases and sa https t co Wr8hxLYcMR Black Panther star <PERSON>Chadwick Boseman</PERSON> pokes fun at the film s success on SNL https t co 005LfxSa1t President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> uncharacteristically criticizes <PERSON>Putin</PERSON> after reports of chemical attack in <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> https t co EKcTcwFUnP NBCNewsBETTER How to bounce back from a hangover https t co kdgNlu9ADa RT NBCNewsTHINK <ORGANIZATION>BBC America</ORGANIZATION> s new KillingEve is a welcome addition to the boy s club that is British crime dramas argues anibundel P President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> defends <PERSON>Pruitt</PERSON> suggests death threats justify spending https t co <ORGANIZATION>YxcHDsJWez RT</ORGANIZATION> NBCLeftField Would you give up your home for your religion Many members of the Fundamentalist Church of <PERSON>Jesus Christ</PERSON> of Latter Day Sa Body found near site of <PERSON>Hart</PERSON> family crash but connection unclear authorities say https t co VaHYB0siNl RT DatelineNBC Tonight on an all new Dateline at 7 6c LesterHoltNBC speaks with a <ORGANIZATION>DEA</ORGANIZATION> agent about his role in the quest to capture the Criticism of <ORGANIZATION>EPA</ORGANIZATION> head <PERSON>Scott Pruitt</PERSON> amounts to nitpicking <ORGANIZATION>GOP</ORGANIZATION> senator says https t co h5FvXYX034 TONIGHT <PERSON>Robert Mueller</PERSON> is a household name But who is the man behind the <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> investigation Find out tonight https t co Pq45FH561O RT NBCNewsTHINK Asian Americans rejected by <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> need to resist the anti affirmative action narrative argues MarieMyungOkLee https RT DatelineNBC Tonight at 7 6c on <ORGANIZATION>NBC LesterHoltNBC</ORGANIZATION> has an all new Dateline report We hope you ll join us for as we go Inside the Hu FULL STORY As dozens reported dead in suspected <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> chemical attack President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> warns of big price to pay https t co xBsIB57fw3 RT MeetThePress FULL INTERVIEW chrisinsilico former <ORGANIZATION>Research Director at Cambridge Analytica</ORGANIZATION> tells <PERSON>Chuck</PERSON> that absolutely more than RT chucktodd chrisinsilico tells me he can t say definitively that the <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> campaign used the harvested <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> data however There RT chucktodd <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> announced this week it was 87 million profiles that were harvested not 50M as originally thought <PERSON>Christopher Wyli</PERSON> RT MeetThePress WATCH Sen Mike Rounds says <PERSON>Scott Pruitt</PERSON> doing a good job at <ORGANIZATION>EPA</ORGANIZATION> criticism is a nitpick https t co xzpF6Tbw61 RT MeetThePress FULL INTERVIEW SenatorRounds joins <ORGANIZATION>MTP</ORGANIZATION> in an exclusive interview to discuss how <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> could respond to <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> tariffs RT chucktodd Does SenatorRounds think <ORGANIZATION>EPA</ORGANIZATION> Admin <PERSON>Scott Pruitt</PERSON> should remain in his job I do because he s following through with the RT MeetThePress Don t get pushed into doing based on <PERSON>Putin</PERSON> s terms but in our terms SenatorRounds says on <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> and the U S respond RT chucktodd Has <PERSON>Navarro</PERSON> heard of <PERSON>John Kelly</PERSON> threatening to resign He serves the president he has the president s ear He runs the <ORGANIZATION>Wes RT</ORGANIZATION> MeetThePress <PERSON>Peter Navarro</PERSON> says tariffs are not a negotiating tactic with the Chinese we re moving forward in a measured way he sa President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> on reports of a possible chemical weapons attack in <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> President <LOCATION>Putin Russia</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Iran</LOCATION> are re https t co vAUdTCmf2g Some experts have warned that trying to squeeze these so called oligarchs will do little to immediately harm <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> https t co pQODil9nsr <ORGANIZATION>Trump</ORGANIZATION> defends <ORGANIZATION>EPA</ORGANIZATION> chief <PERSON>Pruitt</PERSON> suggests death threats justify spending https t co rfKWHZQ9AY <LOCATION>North Dakota</LOCATION> Democrat <PERSON>Heidi Heitkamp</PERSON> is one of the <ORGANIZATION>GOP</ORGANIZATION> s top <ORGANIZATION>Senate</ORGANIZATION> targets in the midterm elections She s betting https t co mUyzutyYMi Teachers in <LOCATION>Kentucky Arizona West Virginia</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Oklahoma</LOCATION> have already taken to the streets and others are beginni https t co tLL98oNfOJ Homebuyers in the grip of a tightening housing market have yet more cause for concern Against the backdrop of high https t co fd2pPmX61Z Black Panther has been in theaters for almost two months so for this week s Saturday Night Live host the fil https t co yYwUv1kLGF A man found critically injured after an apartment fire at <LOCATION>Trump Tower</LOCATION> in <LOCATION>New York City</LOCATION> on Saturday has died police https t co ye5cfpG9lo <LOCATION>California</LOCATION> claims bias after <LOCATION>Florida</LOCATION> s exempted from <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> s offshore drilling plan https t co vMXPUk9dhD The <ORGANIZATION>State Department</ORGANIZATION> says it is monitoring disturbing reports of a possible chemical weapons attack that may have https t co n9YlKOaiHk In a statement to <ORGANIZATION>NBC News the Israeli Defense Force</ORGANIZATION> said that The <ORGANIZATION>IDF</ORGANIZATION> does not intentionally target journalists https t co tiAIWmuu14 A motive remains unclear after a van crashed into a crowd of people in the western German city of <LOCATION>Muenster</LOCATION> killing https t co NCDhwNPutn <LOCATION>Hungary</LOCATION> s <PERSON>Viktor Orban</PERSON> set to extend rule after embracing far right https t co zqxfB5tQIC NBCNewsBETTER The best ways to bounce back from a hangover according to doctors https t co XoUGK4XTEs Why juuling has become a nightmare for school administrators https t co VZKOeMW8D4 Low back pain is the top cause of disability globally yet most people are getting the wrong treatments for it a n https t co ZbVmDo7jxp Health officials are sounding an alarm on the drug gabapentin And it s not an opioid https t co suHPYftWMH NBCNewsBETTER Here s what depression does to your brain and how you can overcome it https t co zwSVx4wDv3 A new study finds that men in STEM subject areas overestimate their own intelligence and credentials underestimate https t co 8Hqz64Oha1 Upset about how much of your data Facebook has Wait until you see what <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> has got on you https t co CANNATEkWZ Low back pain is the top cause of disability globally yet most people are getting the wrong treatments for it a n https t co K34EIBna6n UPDATE Civilian who was injured in <LOCATION>Trump Tower</LOCATION> fire has died <LOCATION>New York City</LOCATION> law enforcement official tells https t co MdgKXxwLmx NBCNewsBETTER Registered dietitians share the top food misconceptions they d prefer you d forget https t co WJrawdjGUv For profit colleges struggle despite assist from <PERSON>Betsy DeVos</PERSON> https t co cpr3BEJ2l4 RT NBCNews JUST IN FDNY 1 person seriously injured in <LOCATION>Trump Tower</LOCATION> fire https t co p3p08jFkhW https t co zIAyxKIu7I JUST IN FDNY 1 person seriously injured in <LOCATION>Trump Tower</LOCATION> fire https t co p3p08jFkhW https t co zIAyxKIu7I 3D printers mean a basic one story home with three rooms can be built for only 4 000 https t co H5LuaHVikl via NBCNewsMACH President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> tweets on <LOCATION>Trump Tower</LOCATION> fire Fire at <LOCATION>Trump Tower</LOCATION> is out Very confined well built building Fire https t co 5QiAgoU0ou President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> the First Lady and <PERSON>Barron Trump</PERSON> are not in <LOCATION>New York City</LOCATION> today officials say https t co WsURdYKhhB FDNY There are currently no injuries reported from fire in <LOCATION>Trump Tower</LOCATION> https t co kdrUxk2XiK https t co MAXrV4zgJq NBCNewsBETTER Here s what depression does to your brain and how you can overcome it https t co VJWSZf8omV FDNY 3 alarm fire burning in <LOCATION>Trump Tower</LOCATION> in <LOCATION>New York City</LOCATION> NYPD Expect traffic and street closures nearby by due to emergency vehicles 15 killed in bus crash involving Canadian junior hockey team police say https t co 8LxDMUw9Jh <LOCATION>California</LOCATION> claims bias after <LOCATION>Florida</LOCATION> s exempted from President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> s offshore drilling plan https t co aQ6jBxsnYk RT NBCNewsPictures Photos <LOCATION>South Africa</LOCATION> mourns anti apartheid hero clashes escalate in <LOCATION>Gaza Villanova</LOCATION> takes <ORGANIZATION>NCAA</ORGANIZATION> crown and more of t NBCNewsBETTER I gave up my credit card for a month and learned a lot about my spending habits https t co JGEzeTj4hJ <PERSON>Robert Mueller</PERSON> could be on a collision course with the president but what drives the man behind the investigation https t co lnk6rMQ5uF Scramble over 2020 presidential election already underway in <LOCATION>New Hampshire</LOCATION> https t co hKb2xCih38 There is no indication that the van crash in M nster is a terror attack motivated by Islam German police tell https t co 83vo0hgUgr LIVE Lawmakers discuss gun control with constituents at <LOCATION>Austin</LOCATION> town hall TownHallForOurLives https t co tt62QRoIMB LIVE Lawmakers participate in <LOCATION>Chicago</LOCATION> town hall TownHallForOurLives https t co sTiC71IDT8 RT NBCNewsBETTER A neuroscientist teaches us how to handle bad customer service without letting it ruin your day https t co xinuYwu RT jacobsoboroff Monday on the TODAYshow we head 750 miles north of the <LOCATION>Arctic Circle</LOCATION> to the top of the on an epic journey <ORGANIZATION>NASA</ORGANIZATION> t LIVE <LOCATION>Texas</LOCATION> lawmakers participate in <LOCATION>Austin</LOCATION> town hall TownHallForOurLives https t co HCYD9lNpOZ <LOCATION>Sacramento</LOCATION> Mayor <PERSON>Darrell Steinberg</PERSON> offers measured response in wake of unrest https t co uRg69MgrEd LIVE Lawmakers participate in town hall in <LOCATION>Kenosha Wisconsin</LOCATION> TownHallForOurLives https t co HCYD9lNpOZ LIVE Father of Parkland school shooting victim speaks at town hall in <LOCATION>Broward County Florida</LOCATION> TownHallForOurLives https t co HCYD9lNpOZ 10 Palestinians killed by Israeli fire in latest <LOCATION>Gaza</LOCATION> protests officials say https t co FCvEp8SmKn RT NBCNewsTHINK The vilification of men of color by the president also serves as an indicator about some white men s own malicious intent Van crashes into crowd in M nster <LOCATION>Germany</LOCATION> leaving at least 3 dead including the driver police say https t co jqmQMmDvWr Virgin Galactic s <ORGANIZATION>VSS Unity</ORGANIZATION> successfully completed its first test flight and <ORGANIZATION>NASA</ORGANIZATION> plans to send robotic bees to Mar https t co G9ZIyzbScg Nearly 53 of Alaskans vote no on anti transgender bathroom bill https t co cqmshk83Bt Van crashes into crowd in M nster <LOCATION>Germany</LOCATION> killing and injuring several people police say https t co jqmQMmDvWr LATEST German police say suspect is dead after vehicle strikes pedestrians in M nster causing deaths and injuries Sanctions for Russian oligarchs unlikely to seriously impact <PERSON>Putin</PERSON> experts say https t co 6TeiUXayeM UPDATE Deaths and injuries reported after vehicle strikes pedestrians in M nster according to German police JUST IN Multiple injuries reported after vehicle strikes crowd in <LOCATION>Muenster Germany</LOCATION> police tell <ORGANIZATION>NBCNews Elon Musk</ORGANIZATION> s plans for colonizing space might have been predicted in a 1940s novel https t co i23FaxKkc1 NBCNewsMACH His name has become synonymous with one of the most talked about political investigations of our time But who is https t co <ORGANIZATION>UfZBM9K95K Defense Sec Mattis</ORGANIZATION> OKs up to 4 000 <ORGANIZATION>National Guard</ORGANIZATION> troops for U S <LOCATION>Mexico</LOCATION> border https t co MnSwZAHsAv Parkland student journalists honor fallen with commemorative newspaper https t co 0I3lmzuwRq Opinion <LOCATION>Jordan Rosenfeld Hot</LOCATION> flashes at 41 What I learned about myself after starting perimenopause https t co leSq26J967 <PERSON>Robert Mueller</PERSON> could be on a collision course with the president but what drives the man behind the investigation https t co PzwrTs2pXT A 15 percent tariff is being added to wines on top of a pre existing tariff and tax pushing the total levies on a https t co 0gcJbqKhhV NBCNewsBETTER If there s only one room you can keep totally allergy proof this time of year make it your bedroo https t co trPPcQCTjR Apple CEO <PERSON>Tim Cook</PERSON> talks about what he s doing to fight for DREAMers right to stay in the U S at the Recode https t co 7IPZC6N7MZ In <LOCATION>New Hampshire</LOCATION> the 2020 presidential race is already well underway https t co 34lhx27h3s If people want to opt out of all of <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> s data driven advertising they would have to pay for it <PERSON>Sheryl Sandb</PERSON> https t co 0ovn0yGhJ3 Forty nine years after the mysterious car crash in <LOCATION>Chappaquiddick Massachusetts</LOCATION> that left a woman drowned in a po https t co iEXkF74h3o For a large fee people will be able to spend 12 days in the first ever luxury space hotel Space technology start https t co IZodxjKK1G 14 killed in bus crash involving Canadian junior hockey team police say https t co eW8j2piwZ5 NBCNewsBETTER When it comes to nutrition the former <ORGANIZATION>White House</ORGANIZATION> chef wants people to eat better not right https t co 5v4miApu7E A <ORGANIZATION>Pentagon</ORGANIZATION> memo about the deployment calls for up to 4 000 troops from border states to be assigned through Sept 3 https t co R3IqJaV0cq Some experts have warned that trying to squeeze these so called oligarchs will do little to immediately harm <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> https t co QinlKt3Z18 As parts of <LOCATION>Hollywood</LOCATION> has dealt with criticism over a lack of diversity including after no actors of color were no https t co UuZnpYWXFN JUST IN Canadian authorities confirm 14 dead 14 injured after bus crash involving <ORGANIZATION>Humboldt Broncos</ORGANIZATION> junior hockey team Opinion <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> s use of the Mexican rapist trope is as old as colonialism https t co arYZb1HZvo The <ORGANIZATION>Environmental Protection Agency</ORGANIZATION> spent millions of dollars for a 20 member full time security detail for <PERSON>Scott</PERSON> P https t co iYZwofVt52 <PERSON>Jordan Peele</PERSON> the Oscar winner behind the horror smash Get Out wants to take a closer look at the crime that sho https t co Zm9ZOy09dd <PERSON>Kurt Bardella</PERSON> Why on earth would members of the free press degrade themselves and undermine their own credibility https t co fwyWAh1iaZ Cherry blossoms in the nation s capital attract thousands to marvel at their short lived beauty See more https t co FlTIOqYp13 Former South Korean President <PERSON>Park Geun hye</PERSON> was sentenced to 24 years in prison a year after she was driven from o https t co Rd5dwxmFNS The <ORGANIZATION>Humboldt Broncos</ORGANIZATION> organization confirms in a statement that its junior hockey team bus was involved in an accide https t co DhgK7Synif Facebook potentially endangered hundreds of thousands of people in conflict ridden <LOCATION>Myanmar</LOCATION> with its inadequate at https t co MySOrnQ2wg <PERSON>Richard Branson</PERSON> s Virgin Galactic venture announces that its passenger spacecraft Virgin Space Ship Unity had suc https t co tJWmigIGjl <LOCATION>Chicago</LOCATION> man who died on March 28 after smoking synthetic pot was found to have in his system traces of the antico https t co Bb4N5LLxcU WATCH Press Secretary <PERSON>Sarah Huckabee Sanders</PERSON> says President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> was possibly referencing an L A <ORGANIZATION>Times</ORGANIZATION> article w https t co E10resaLx3 With a potential trade war brewing between the U S and <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> dozens of industries including wine producers ar https t co 6W6GtcOTI6 <LOCATION>Walden Pond</LOCATION> the once pristine jewel that inspired the American naturalist and philosopher in the mid 1800s has be https t co jQGo1SCYEr A 2 million settlement has been reached in the 2015 fatal police shooting of a <LOCATION>California</LOCATION> man whose family said wa https t co fqt4jgYFMj RT NBCPolitics MORE <PERSON>Manafort</PERSON> s attorneys say their client s Fourth Amendment rights regarding search and seizure were violated They cla <LOCATION>Puerto Rico</LOCATION> s <ORGANIZATION>Department of Education</ORGANIZATION> announced that it will close 283 schools this summer following a sharp drop i https t co guTv8nFDpn RT NBCPolitics NEW <PERSON>Paul Manafort</PERSON> s attorneys are seeking to stop evidence gathered by federal investigators from a search of <PERSON>Manafort</PERSON> s The next step in planetary defense is already underway at <ORGANIZATION>Johns Hopkins University</ORGANIZATION> s Applied Physics Lab There a https t co U34tJtjbZq NBCNewsBETTER Over time added sugars can mess up your metabolism play a role in weight problems raise the ris https t co IXsv7Mj2lY <PERSON>Akaka</PERSON> sponsored legislation to enhance Hawaiian education programs and a resolution acknowledging the U S governme https t co ZXN1tELliL OPINION Primary care doctors now shoulder half of mental health treatment in the U S which wouldn t be a problem https t co W1XDKhd56i Federal agencies including the <ORGANIZATION>FBI</ORGANIZATION> have seized controversial classified advertising website https t co Al2uN6vWIx WATCH <ORGANIZATION>MMA</ORGANIZATION> fighter <PERSON>Conor McGregor</PERSON> exits precinct after arrest following incident in <LOCATION>Brooklyn</LOCATION> He has been charged w https t co 6E1ErqFwza Rep <PERSON>Blake Farenthold</PERSON> announced that he has resigned from <ORGANIZATION>Congress</ORGANIZATION> months after details surfaced about his use of https t co bJD54a5EHi Reporter Does President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> still think that trade wars are easy to win <ORGANIZATION>White House Press</ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON>Sanders</PERSON> https t co NUBJE6udLp Suzanne Garment Some of the troubles that <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> s lawyers have had reflect the general problem of representing a https t co AomcEdXWT1 Elected leaders in <LOCATION>Deerfield Illinois</LOCATION> voted unanimously to ban many types of semiautomatic firearms they labeled https t co 1tLm8AyomA WATCH After massive cuts to education funding and no raises for the last ten years teachers in <LOCATION>Oklahoma</LOCATION> staged a https t co kROocMy1lx <ORGANIZATION>Marjory Stoneman Douglas High School</ORGANIZATION> student journalists published a commemorative edition of its student newspaper https t co o3naSImEV5 NBCNewsBETTER Just having snacks available could be the problem Add in stress multitasking boredom and more https t co 2spBJJZ0MF <ORGANIZATION>Defense</ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON>Mattis</PERSON> OKs 4 000 <ORGANIZATION>National Guard</ORGANIZATION> troops for border starting Friday night https t co dKvurYXUhC https t co VFsCjVQRvd 360 VIDEO Take a rare look around the underground of the <ORGANIZATION>Lincoln Memorial Known</ORGANIZATION> as the undercroft it s home to https t co cbx3ox5R84 Taxes on junk food sodas tobacco and other unhealthy products help cut both disease and the cost to society and a https t co SHcwgJSOdZ The <ORGANIZATION>Environmental Protection Agency</ORGANIZATION> spent millions of dollars for a 20 member full time security detail for <PERSON>Scott</PERSON> P https t co reJnlAUy07 <PERSON>Robert Mueller</PERSON> could be on a collision course with the president but what drives the man behind the investigation https t co ycCpQXwAey UPDATE In a statement the <ORGANIZATION>National Guard</ORGANIZATION> said that it was moving nearly 500 <ORGANIZATION>National Guard</ORGANIZATION> soldiers and airmen to https t co zq7rZGUwT7 <PERSON>Howell Raines</PERSON> To aging Republican environmentalists <PERSON>Pruitt</PERSON> is a disgrace who wants to unravel President <PERSON>Richar</PERSON> https t co 4AsbIePHOm In a TODAYShow exclusive <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> s <PERSON>Sheryl Sandberg</PERSON> says other data breaches in addition to that of <LOCATION>Cambridge Ana</LOCATION> https t co <ORGANIZATION>EOtDeqbWbq Facebook</ORGANIZATION> will require political advertisers to verify their identities and locations before they are approved to bu https t co HHVCKfO2mU The <ORGANIZATION>National Guard</ORGANIZATION> will deploy a handful of troops to the U S <LOCATION>Mexico</LOCATION> border according to three U S officials Th https t co jtxfHEYJ0r WATCH <ORGANIZATION>White House</ORGANIZATION> says sending between 2 000 to 4 000 <ORGANIZATION>National Guard</ORGANIZATION> troops to the border will be a good first st https t co nFoXKm6vQh RT <ORGANIZATION>MSNBC</ORGANIZATION> If you re trading between countries you find a way for both to win If you re working with a partner in business find a way f <PERSON>Lisa Selin Davis</PERSON> Just because gluten free food is a fad and a billion dollar global industry doesn t mean there i https t co L1Lw4JWygN The federal government shut down classifieds site https t co ATm53fU4I2 after searching the home of one of its fo https t co RhToadSEGn <ORGANIZATION>Texas National Guard</ORGANIZATION> is preparing to immediately deploy with supporting aircraft vehicles and equipment to the Te https t co h81RR1MTVT NBCNewsBETTER Today s low interest rates and balance transfer offers have meant that if you do carry a balance o https t co 8xb4togKND RT NBCLeftField Any company or U S individual can put stakes in the ground and prospect in <LOCATION>Utah</LOCATION> s Bears Ears National Monument all for t NEW In memo President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> directs <ORGANIZATION>Sec of Homeland Security Sec</ORGANIZATION> of Defense Attorney General and <ORGANIZATION>Sec of Hea</ORGANIZATION> https t co <ORGANIZATION>I4zmJ7E2cR Press</ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON>Sanders</PERSON> said the president was likely referring to a news report describing conditions that migrant https t co osGEejQS0X TONIGHT <PERSON>Don</PERSON> t miss <PERSON>Chris Hayes</PERSON> amp amp <PERSON>Kara Swisher</PERSON> s revealing town hall with <ORGANIZATION>Apple</ORGANIZATION> CEO <PERSON>Tim Cook</PERSON> as the tech leader so https t co 4B6eaKEMVl Executives at Americans for Prosperity just one part of the ever growing <PERSON>Koch</PERSON> influence empire said that tariffs https t co 4719dQGvKr This luxury space hotel could be up and running in 4 years https t co 8En4O5wr3F via NBCNewsMACH I made more money as a college student than I make as a teacher After massive cuts to education funding and no https t co sxaKW1Ks5d RT NBCNightlyNews EXCLUSIVE LesterHoltNBC interviews former Attorney General <PERSON>Loretta Lynch Lynch</PERSON> will discuss former <ORGANIZATION>FBI Director Jam City of Long Beach</ORGANIZATION> settles lawsuit filed by family of man fatally shot by police https t co Ppmjtisypi via <ORGANIZATION>NBCAsianAmerica An American dad</ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION>Sweden</LOCATION> now has plenty of family time https t co 6QXCmnX8Mv via <ORGANIZATION>NBCNewsWorld Rep Blake Farenthold</ORGANIZATION> who previously announced that he would not seek re election after sexual harassment allegati https t co XXJ0W7BDSe This is a massacre against <LOCATION>Puerto Rico</LOCATION> s education says <ORGANIZATION>Puerto Rico Teachers Association</ORGANIZATION> president Aida D az https t co L3LYYSp0Pf <PERSON>Matt Laslo Sinclair</PERSON> s fake news script put its viewers trust in their local news at risk https t co 3twrI9ojAF via NBCNewsTHINK The drop in enrollment comes as roughly a half million people have fled <LOCATION>Puerto Rico</LOCATION> for the U S mainland in the pa https t co 8pk60CAUVZ Two teens who vanished in December were found dead at the bottom of an abandoned mine shaft in <LOCATION>Utah</LOCATION> GadiNBC has https t co hC16svmqbI Former Democratic Sen <PERSON>Daniel Akaka</PERSON> who represented <LOCATION>Hawaii</LOCATION> in <ORGANIZATION>Congress</ORGANIZATION> for nearly four decades and was regarded as https t co XXz0XNd7C8 While I planned on serving out the remainder of my term in <ORGANIZATION>Congress</ORGANIZATION> I know in my heart it s time for me to move a https t co x5XaonJ7vm RT NBCPolitics BREAKING Rep <PERSON>Blake Farenthold</PERSON> who previously announced that he would not seek re election after sexual harassment alleg Those who oppose the school closures say they worry about transportation logistics and the needs of special educati https t co g0tnYXUvH8 Scientists Down Under have come up with a sunscreen of sorts that they say could help protect <LOCATION>Australia</LOCATION> s Great Bar https t co VFWuTk7ZmX <PERSON>Keleher</PERSON> says enrollment has dropped by more than 38 700 students since just last May and that nearly half of the sc https t co wKBX0xyEie Space scientists have big plans to avert an asteroid apocalypse https t co sMZ4WyHlUN via NBCNewsMACH We know it s a difficult and painful process Education Secretary <PERSON>Keleher</PERSON> says Our children deserve the best ed https t co qiwHz1OGUc WATCH <ORGANIZATION>White House</ORGANIZATION> staff say goodbye to <PERSON>H R McMaster</PERSON> on his last day as national security adviser https t co ZlGABp7f6t <LOCATION>Puerto Rico</LOCATION> currently has more than 1 100 public schools that serve 319 000 students After the closures 828 publi https t co ypz23fTQsZ LIVE Dow heads into the close down nearly 600 points Friday https t co YjkZqrH5U2 https t co JOzlNTGcu7 A <LOCATION>Utah</LOCATION> man is accused of murdering a teen couple and dumping their bodies in an abandoned mine shaft https t co DS0gr92C2e <ORGANIZATION>White House</ORGANIZATION> economic adviser <PERSON>Kudlow</PERSON> on <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> tariffs We re not running a trade war https t co TAAfPWQ2XY Education Secretary <PERSON>Julia Keleher</PERSON> says there will be no layoffs with teachers and other employees being reassigned https t co PG0H5DTEOV <ORGANIZATION>Puerto Rico s Dept of Education</ORGANIZATION> announces that it will close 283 schools this summer following a sharp drop in enr https t co 9Mr8owq2wa <LOCATION>Oklahoma</LOCATION> teachers walkout expected to continue next week https t co d0BdP18coG <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> will now require political advertisers to verify their identities and locations before they are approved t https t co BOTE6qAoL7 Markets sink as slower job growth trade war fears spook investors https t co maxjzD8eVG Follow the Dow in real https t co V45BVlyFJA In a spiral galaxy more than halfway across the universe astronomers have discovered what they say is the most dis https t co dPeoX88C08 RT NBCLeftField Hundreds of thousands of people took part in the recent MarchforOurLives rally but what does it actually take for a mar LIVE Dow down more than 650 points Friday https t co JOzlNTGcu7 Reporter Does President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> still think that trade wars are easy to win Press <PERSON>Sec Sanders</PERSON> I think the presi https t co MAOb6kAr4L RT <ORGANIZATION>MSNBC White House</ORGANIZATION> says sending between 2 000 4 000 <ORGANIZATION>National Guard</ORGANIZATION> troops to the border will be a good first step https t co mAm LIVE <ORGANIZATION>White House</ORGANIZATION> press briefing https t co aSZGP6tqFK <ORGANIZATION>EPA</ORGANIZATION> chief <PERSON>Pruitt</PERSON> doing great job but is totally under siege President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> says https t co HGlojeobXU JUST IN Dow falls more than 600 points Friday https t co J2lZZW5XJI NBCNewsBETTER Depression is a complex disease Here s exactly what happens inside your brain when you feel depre https t co O5fp1tZM9Y Rat poison chemical linked to synthetic pot smoker death https t co GDpmuWSbkF Job growth stumbled in March with only 103 000 Americans finding new jobs according to data released by the Depar https t co C9dScXWzQp <PERSON>Howell Raines Scott Pruitt</PERSON> s <ORGANIZATION>EPA</ORGANIZATION> deregulation is destroying a conservative environmental legacy lead by <PERSON>Richard Ni</PERSON> https t co BITq8pCM1c New electric planes will mean quieter more comfortable flights and a lot less pollution https t co BN2gYuAitY NBCNewsMACH NBCNewsBETTER Springtime allergies aren t curable but these doctor recommended tips will make the season a whol https t co CPdVXpm0YH <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> administration announces sweeping sanctions against members of President <PERSON>Putin</PERSON> s inner circle along with top https t co dJnbIg2Jo8 <PERSON>Jill Filipovic</PERSON> Since <ORGANIZATION>Chappaquiddick Democrats</ORGANIZATION> views of women have evolved Republicans still need to https t co wDVl4BTVkF Facebook potentially endangered hundreds of thousands of people in conflict ridden <LOCATION>Myanmar</LOCATION> with its inadequate at https t co HytZyBqv4h WATCH <PERSON>Conor McGregor</PERSON> exits precinct after arrest following incident in <LOCATION>Brooklyn</LOCATION> He has been charged with assault https t co LVlBsrttVr Woman has parental rights in same sex split <LOCATION>Mississippi</LOCATION> court rules https t co 6wkGpFSCv1 via <ORGANIZATION>NBCOUT RT</ORGANIZATION> NBCNightlyNews 360 VIDEO Take a rare look around the underground of the <ORGANIZATION>Lincoln Memorial Known</ORGANIZATION> as the undercroft it s home to ch Former South Korean President <PERSON>Park Geun</PERSON> hye sentenced to 24 years in prison in corruption scandal https t co 8mvgOOckMv via <ORGANIZATION>NBCNewsWorld RT MSNBC</ORGANIZATION> JUST IN <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> economic adviser <PERSON>Larry Kudlow</PERSON> insists <LOCATION>US</LOCATION> is not running a trade war with <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> Nothing s happened nothing The use of Spanglish or other language combinations has been seen by many as a sign of laziness or poor language sk https t co XkleTcaIFG President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> admits that the trade actions he s announced against <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> could cause some pain in the markets https t co 2tVhH0Ri0z RT <ORGANIZATION>NBCNews Puerto Rico s Department of Education</ORGANIZATION> announces it will close 283 schools following a sharp drop in enrollment amid the island A woman says her family was booted off an <ORGANIZATION>Alaska Airlines</ORGANIZATION> flight to <LOCATION>Seattle</LOCATION> because her teenage brother with Down s https t co Nk3g0ISqoS Poisoned ex spy <PERSON>Sergei Skripal</PERSON> is improving rapidly and no longer critically ill health officials say https t co 5p7sZNax3R In today s NBCFirstRead Why Thursday when <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> s sole scheduled public appearance was a roundtable to discuss https t co CStOTO21dr NEW U S announces sanctions on oligarchs top officials and several businesses including a bank and a state owne https t co Of6RUT7aX5 President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> admits that the trade actions he has announced against <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> could cause some pain in the markets https t co ERfuGh2qKW NEW Job growth stumbled in March with only 103 000 Americans finding new jobs according to data released by the D https t co wHyUeXHgzp RT <ORGANIZATION>NBCNews BREAKING US Treasury</ORGANIZATION> says it sanctions numerous Russian oligarchs gov t officials and companies over malign activity around President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> says he is weighing an additional 100 billion in tariffs on <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> raising the stakes in a potenti https t co GjdA47AQ7R BREAKING Hospital Former Russian spy <PERSON>Sergei Skripal</PERSON> who was targeted by nerve agent attack in <LOCATION>UK</LOCATION> is improving https t co OtbWpKSBwI RT <ORGANIZATION>MSNBC</ORGANIZATION> JUST IN U S economy adds 103 000 jobs in March Unemployment remains at 4 1 https t co uenozotMVi BREAKING <ORGANIZATION>US Treasury</ORGANIZATION> says it sanctions numerous Russian oligarchs gov t officials and companies over malign acti https t co apHN3w3o57 Teenage couple found bound and stabbed down an abandoned mine shaft in <LOCATION>Utah</LOCATION> https t co FnUZhhWRXc RT TODAYshow In most organizations when you have a breach and a problem that s this big and this costly heads roll Should heads roll a One study found that those with chronic selfitis also had lower self confidence scores https t co 6AMVGutKjX NBCNewsBETTER Opinion <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> s plan to confront the migrant caravan with troops is not smart https t co <ORGANIZATION>LhEc2YbNfJ NBCNewsTHINK Puerto Rico s Department of Education</ORGANIZATION> announces it will close 283 schools following a sharp drop in enrollment amid https t co iluIXxeVpv RT TODAYshow Watch savannahguthrie s full interview with <ORGANIZATION>Facebook COO Sheryl Sandberg</ORGANIZATION> https t co RQ4dsecfes <PERSON>Sheryl Sandberg</PERSON> discusses steps the company is taking to secure user data in an exclusive interview on TODAYShow https t co u3BL09PYTu RT TODAYshow We thought that the data had been deleted and we should have checked <PERSON>Sheryl Sandberg</PERSON> on <ORGANIZATION>Cambridge Analytica</ORGANIZATION> breach Wh RT TODAYshow What we weren t focused enough on was protecting <PERSON>Sheryl Sandberg</PERSON> talks latest <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> data breach https t co xWtbOeepeg RT TODAYshow On a scale of 1 10 this breach of trust with your users where would you put it savannahguthrie asks <ORGANIZATION>Facebook COO Shery Users</ORGANIZATION> data are the lifeblood of <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> and if they wanted to opt out of all of the platform s data driven adver https t co aNPMt0GkGW The U S is expected to impose its most aggressive sanctions yet on Russian oligarchs https t co e0z9opU82N Some 300 to 350 migrants set off for the Mexican U S border via caravan Since peaking at around 1 500 people https t co LcsoT5Rzl2 RT TODAYshow What is the reason it took so long <PERSON>SavannahGuthrie</PERSON> asks <ORGANIZATION>SherylSandberg</ORGANIZATION> about <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> s handling of data breach Full RT TODAYshow Today on TODAY Are there more <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> breaches we don t know about SavannahGuthrie talks to <PERSON>Sheryl Sandberg</PERSON> about that a Former South Korean President <PERSON>Park Geun</PERSON> hye sentenced to 24 years in prison after being found guilty of abuse of po https t co lU2U9XomkH An <ORGANIZATION>EPA</ORGANIZATION> lawyer says he wasn t given all the facts when he ruled that there was no ethics violation in Administrator https t co VpLEgSYVmP Mixed martial arts fighter <PERSON>Conor McGregor</PERSON> has been arrested and is expected to be charged with assault https t co KwENEzIWWy <PERSON>Richard Branson</PERSON> s Virgin Galactic venture announces that its passenger spacecraft Virgin Space Ship Unity had suc https t co gXXJbCuGlP They would rather give up a 500 000 house than sign a piece of paper that symbolized that they were violating wha https t co Pr1yvAcPB9 Six police officers injured after trying to help a man who lit himself on fire inside a gas station convenience sto https t co nxgfo3xEiz <ORGANIZATION>Trump</ORGANIZATION> addresses 130 000 payment for the first time since <PERSON>Stormy Daniels</PERSON> said she was paid keep quiet about alleged https t co gTbwRvulXS Thousands of Palestinians are preparing to march in <LOCATION>Gaza</LOCATION> https t co s8kh4XcGhm NBCNewsWorld NEW Former South Korean President <PERSON>Park Geun</PERSON> hye sentenced to 24 years in prison https t co zPLd0DUdSO Springtime allergies aren t curable but these doctor recommended tips will make the season a whole lot more bearab https t co GFloeY3AGU The U S is expected to impose its most aggressive sanctions yet on Russian oligarchs https t co NDyFR0Wl0d NBCNewsWorld New electric planes will mean quieter more comfortable flights and a lot less pollution https t co SLfEQd1Kd4 NBCNewsMACH Opinion <PERSON>Kurt Bardella</PERSON> The case for banning <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> from the <ORGANIZATION>White House</ORGANIZATION> Correspondents Dinner https t co hwtxg78wF1 NBCNewsTHINK When it comes to nutrition the former <ORGANIZATION>White House</ORGANIZATION> chef wants people to eat better not right https t co PsjNJtLrw2 NBCNewsBETTER JUST IN <LOCATION>South Korea</LOCATION> s former President <PERSON>Park Geun</PERSON> hye sentenced to 24 years in prison over corruption scandal <LOCATION>Brazil</LOCATION> s top court voted narrowly to turn down an attempt by former President <PERSON>Luiz Inacio Lula da Silva</PERSON> to stay out https t co GieqXmuDQl Chemical layer is seen as a way to protect the Great Barrier Reef from effects of global warming https t co JeA4ultqlC NBCNewsMACH At least 18 Palestinians were killed and more than 750 wounded by Israeli bullets on the first day of a six week si https t co 7kirhqltys <PERSON>Yulia Skripal</PERSON> the daughter of ex Russian spy <PERSON>Sergei Skripal</PERSON> called the experience somewhat disorientating and t https t co 7wFVEzlxf1 Bollywood superstar <PERSON>Salman Khan</PERSON> was convicted of poaching rare deer in a wildlife preserve two decades ago and sent https t co WPmVBC6WqA <LOCATION>Maryland</LOCATION> lawmakers voted to prohibit health professionals from practicing gay conversion therapy on minors The https t co 1Nb7GRVFAQ Forty three Cambodians arrived in <LOCATION>Phnom Penh Cambodia</LOCATION> s capital after being deported from the <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> under https t co eOzaTBnFtd UPDATE <ORGANIZATION>Ontario Police</ORGANIZATION> say bomb squad personnel have determined that the suspect <PERSON>Hugo Gonzalez</PERSON> of <ORGANIZATION>Fontana Califor</ORGANIZATION> https t co oWKEDTDfTr WATCH While discussing migrants and border security at a <LOCATION>West Virginia</LOCATION> event President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> claimed Women are https t co AQqRWFDCc2 The use of Spanglish or other language combinations has been seen by many as a sign of laziness or poor language sk https t co yyn5Dv7j93 <PERSON>Isao Takahata</PERSON> co founder of the prestigious Japanese animator Studio Ghibli which stuck to a hand drawn manga l https t co mRYJ6fq5Of Scientists Down Under have come up with a sunscreen of sorts that they say could help protect <LOCATION>Australia</LOCATION> s Great Bar https t co S2SXnKvddh <ORGANIZATION>MMA</ORGANIZATION> fighter <PERSON>Conor McGregor</PERSON> has been arrested after he allegedly went on a caught on camera rampage after a <ORGANIZATION>UFC</ORGANIZATION> pres https t co ATuxsrM7dz <PERSON>Bob Dylan Kesha</PERSON> and <PERSON>St Vincent</PERSON> are among the musical artists who have reimagined popular love songs to honor the https t co NB4pVBLRjg A <LOCATION>Tennessee</LOCATION> teacher who set off a nationwide manhunt after he fled with a 15 year old student broke down in court a https t co C8R5DKm44q The country s largest association of physicians sent a letter to <ORGANIZATION>Defense</ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON>Jim Mattis</PERSON> this week opposing th https t co rIPwnFIJq5 NBCNewsBETTER Starting April 20 your company can download your conversations without notifying you https t co JOJmFy4OjN A woman says her family was booted off an <ORGANIZATION>Alaska Airlines</ORGANIZATION> flight to <LOCATION>Seattle</LOCATION> because her teenage brother with Down s https t co Z4ipZbqSvK MORE <PERSON>McGregor</PERSON> was captured on video throwing an item at a bus inside the <ORGANIZATION>Barclay s Center</ORGANIZATION> following a pre fight pr https t co Yo5Dv5VrQ3 Champion <ORGANIZATION>UFC</ORGANIZATION> fighter <PERSON>Conor McGregor</PERSON> is in custody and is at the NYPD s 78th precinct where he is expected to be cha https t co PJtfUFoBMt WATCH Former professional WWE wrestler Luscious <PERSON>Johnny Valiant</PERSON> was killed after being struck by a car while cros https t co aXM6tZV9Bv In a spiral galaxy more than halfway across the universe astronomers have discovered what they say is the most dis https t co fnGQKaYLR7 NBCNewsBETTER Depression is a complex disease Here s exactly what happens inside your brain when you feel depre https t co zq7nCX9yrw Copyright is there to promote creativity not to protect ownership Here s what the Blurred Lines verdict mean https t co 2VcGmUNdc0 In November 2017 the <ORGANIZATION>FCC</ORGANIZATION> under <PERSON>Ajit Pai</PERSON> voted to eliminate longstanding restrictions on media consolidation pavin https t co mvfUMBt2y5 The body of <PERSON>Timothy Cunningham</PERSON> a missing <ORGANIZATION>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention</ORGANIZATION> employee who mysteriously vani https t co lY6eWRtfxZ We are not going to allow negative rhetoric to define our actions Mexican President Enrique Pe a Nieto addresse https t co ASMqaKCS2m The <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> attorney general opened an investigation into the fatal shooting of a black <LOCATION>Brooklyn</LOCATION> man who police be https t co NVdslpgmJD <ORGANIZATION>Delta Airlines</ORGANIZATION> said that some of its customers payment information may have been breached in a cyberattack last fa https t co KJHwWNzoQH If you have a baby on our land congratulations that baby is a <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> citizen We re the only one Presid https t co BAhR1kfYx1 President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> said that voter fraud is widespread and again claimed that millions and millions of votes were ca https t co bgVBApWBKA President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> says he did not know about 130 000 payment to <PERSON>Stormy Daniels</PERSON> and tells reporters they would have https t co y7cJa02l4b The U S is expected to impose its most aggressive sanctions yet on Russian oligarchs likely targeting people with https t co 1GS565G45y <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> s <PERSON>Sheryl Sandberg</PERSON> says users would have to pay to opt out of all data targeted ads https t co uJl8d42WT8 President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> looks to impose additional 100 billion in <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> tariffs https t co uMvYYfZ9I2 RT NBCLeftField They would rather give up a 500 000 house than sign a piece of paper that symbolized that they were violating what they NEW <LOCATION>Nebraska</LOCATION> Senator <PERSON>Ben Sasse</PERSON> says This is the dumbest possible way to do this in a statement on proposed 100B https t co 7U8fzPPGna MORE The filing states that <PERSON>Manafort</PERSON> has been served with seven search warrants for his property banks a hard dr https t co <ORGANIZATION>EzEfBflowh NEW Federal</ORGANIZATION> investigators obtained a search warrant tied to <PERSON>Paul Manafort</PERSON> on March 9 according to a Special Couns https t co MZUwSNJtrN A nonprofit that helps request and analyze government documents filed a FOIA request with the <ORGANIZATION>FCC</ORGANIZATION> four months ago https t co y82u0oW5FK Multiple administration officials familiar with the president s thinking told <ORGANIZATION>NBC News</ORGANIZATION> on Thursday that the preside https t co ZdJmSPlXJF <PERSON>Sheryl Sandberg</PERSON> speaks out on <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> data breach scandal https t co Kshtv3Hsi0 via <ORGANIZATION>NBCNightlyNews</ORGANIZATION> https t co Au1TTFQCUM The <ORGANIZATION>Marines Corps</ORGANIZATION> identified the four Marines who died when their helicopter crashed during a training mission in S https t co YYdMKs6DjM MORE Dow futures indicate more than 400 point drop at market open after President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> threatens more tariffs on https t co uU9CQXqJGP President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> urging tougher security measures along the U S <LOCATION>Mexico</LOCATION> border claimed that women are being raped https t co WwyGZ4kO7H More than 70 million square feet of retail space is slated to close in 2018 <ORGANIZATION>CNBC</ORGANIZATION> has reported largely attributabl https t co q23zR5CCpu JUST IN President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> has instructed the <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> Trade Representative to consider 100 billion of addition https t co CMcBNxCdOT How <PERSON>Nixon</PERSON> s legal decisions during <LOCATION>Watergate</LOCATION> may help us understand the trouble <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> is in now <ORGANIZATION>Suzanne Garment</ORGANIZATION> wr https t co r0oWS4vlG5 <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> has asked several U S hospitals to share anonymized data about their patients such as illnesses and pres https t co htmFk8NTKp Surgeon General Dr <PERSON>Jerome Adams</PERSON> said anybody who knows someone at risk of an opioid overdose should be carrying na https t co 4lSxXMep6m President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> estimated that he could send anywhere from 2 000 to 4 000 troops and that they would remain indefi https t co LE7QR7TuoY Love it or hate it Spanglish is here to stay and it s good exercise for your brain https t co xTM2XN6UsB via <ORGANIZATION>NBCLatino Police</ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION>Ontario California</LOCATION> determined a small explosive device detonated in a store Police report that there https t co sWMtu7zY7B NBCNewsBETTER If you re afraid of applying for a new credit card don t be Here s how to choose the best one fo https t co zTfWWY6fta President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> refers back to controversial 2015 rapists comment at <LOCATION>West Virginia</LOCATION> event https t co 9C1YNdR2Kf <PERSON>Lisa Selin Davis Gluten</PERSON> free diets may be popular with the GOOP crowd but wellness is more than a fad https t co qMqM3t7Jp7 Some visitors to the <ORGANIZATION>Detroit Zoo</ORGANIZATION> will soon be able to add animal droppings to their souvenir list via free bucket https t co LkuqTu4fel <ORGANIZATION>FCC</ORGANIZATION> blocks reveal of emails with conservative news site about <ORGANIZATION>Harlem Shake</ORGANIZATION> net neutrality video https t co siZWOAzqLQ <LOCATION>Maryland</LOCATION> set to become 11th state to ban gay conversion therapy https t co UGQLFrogeb via <ORGANIZATION>NBCOUT</ORGANIZATION> Did this Patriots player thwart a school shooting GadiNBC has the details on Stay Tuned Watch more https t co zDeUxbsqPO NBCNewsBETTER You probably want to think twice before doing taxes on your cellphone https t co Bc9MvjXDBQ President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> on <ORGANIZATION>EPA</ORGANIZATION> Admin <PERSON>Pruitt</PERSON> I think that <PERSON>Scott</PERSON> has done a fantastic job I think he s a fantastic person https t co dUPwUyQko3 RT NBCNews Reporter Mr President did you know about the 130 000 payment to <ORGANIZATION>Stormy Daniels</ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> No https t co wHT NEW President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> says he did not know about 130 000 payment to <ORGANIZATION>Stormy Daniels</ORGANIZATION> https t co qJKeAbdiqL corrects link Large parts of <LOCATION>Australia</LOCATION> s <LOCATION>Great Barrier Reef</LOCATION> are dying Can this ultra thin sunscreen save it https t co rg5tLAgLtp via NBCNewsMACH Reporter Mr President did you know about the 130 000 payment to <ORGANIZATION>Stormy Daniels</ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> No https t co wHTR7o5lqB Suzanne Garment What <PERSON>Nixon</PERSON> s Watergate blunders suggest about the trouble <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> is in now https t co jYYvDcIEjR via NBCNewsTHINK JUST IN President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> says he did not know about 130 000 payment to <PERSON>Stormy Daniels</PERSON> and tells reporters they wo