<ner>RT TODAYshow Is it <PERSON>Michael Skakel</PERSON> s position that his brother committed this crime savannahguthrie asks <PERSON>Michael Skakel</PERSON> s attorney abo RT TODAYshow Gratified elated and very thankful <PERSON>Michael Skakel</PERSON> s attorney <PERSON>Michael Fitzpatrick</PERSON> tells savannahguthrie of <PERSON>Skakel</PERSON> s re Remember <LOCATION>Alabama</LOCATION> In tweet <PERSON>Pres Trump</PERSON> tells West Virginians to not vote for ex coal boss and ex convict <PERSON>Blanke</PERSON> https t co A29duY0TfS Opinion <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> s unilateral power to withdraw from treaties comes from <ORGANIZATION>Congress</ORGANIZATION> https t co PNxxuI6IML NBCNewsTHINK <PERSON>Pres Trump</PERSON> says his <ORGANIZATION>CIA</ORGANIZATION> director nominee who sources says has considered withdrawing has come under fire becaus https t co AumbwRv1Y4 British Foreign Secretary <PERSON>Boris Johnson</PERSON> travels to <LOCATION>Washington</LOCATION> in a last ditch bid to persuade President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> not t https t co Vu4Kzfvecr President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> comes out against <PERSON>Blankenship</PERSON> in morning tweet urging voters to vote for <PERSON>Jenkins</PERSON> or <PERSON>Morrisey</PERSON> in th https t co TWibSnJ7u1 When the <ORGANIZATION>Senate</ORGANIZATION> reconvenes this week one of the first items of business will be the confirmation of six more of Pr https t co EKiOZnaJoO The number of homes damaged by a volcanic eruption on <LOCATION>Hawaii</LOCATION> s <LOCATION>Big Island</LOCATION> rises to 26 as thousands of residents rem https t co aet97MFOyC RT TODAYshow Today on TODAY Latest on the lava damaging homes in <LOCATION>Hawaii</LOCATION> JennaBushHager sits down with music legend <PERSON>HueyLewis</PERSON> amp amp we att A historic three year drought has forced <LOCATION>Cape Town</LOCATION> residents to radically change their relationship with water https t co 910FFHpqOZ Tuesday s contest for the right to take on <ORGANIZATION>Democratic Sen Joe Manchin</ORGANIZATION> has <LOCATION>Washington</LOCATION> Republicans nervous https t co l7faROlKly Opinion I once thought a woman s life peaked at 40 I was wrong https t co sbzUeIO1Ht NBCNewsTHINK Thousands take part in the rally in <LOCATION>Moscow</LOCATION> where some protesters were detained by police and thrown into buses as https t co qCyZHq35Cj Local police departments are turning to private training organizations that specialize in military combat technique https t co iosGjJQ1Bo <PERSON>Vladimir Putin</PERSON> has taken the oath of office for his 4th term as <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> s president <PERSON>Gina Haspel</PERSON> President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> s nominee to be the permanent <ORGANIZATION>CIA</ORGANIZATION> director broached the idea of withdrawing her nomin https t co rhi3pJ0lKU After breaking opening weekend records Avengers Infinity War continues to dominate in its second weekend in the https t co GF4nRo8ldB The number of homes damaged by a volcanic eruption on <LOCATION>Hawaii</LOCATION> s <LOCATION>Big Island</LOCATION> rises to 26 as thousands of residents rem https t co PAS8rkBbjQ President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> sparks anger across after suggesting that <LOCATION>London</LOCATION> s knife problem is worse than gun violence in Amer https t co BRVS3kBLQE <PERSON>Rudy Giuliani</PERSON> says that he can t rule out the possibility of President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> invoking his Fifth Amendment right ag https t co 64v5vbVL78 <LOCATION>Iran</LOCATION> s President <PERSON>Rouhani</PERSON> says the U S would regret a decision to exit the nuclear agreement https t co nV9UUxIpnA NBCNewsWorld Science shows that placing one foot in front of the other leads to some seriously impressive mental and physical be https t co 9ErYuitpmf Opinion Maureen Shaw <LOCATION>Iowa</LOCATION> just passed the most restrictive abortion bill in <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> https t co qWyq60Rdve NBCNewsTHINK Scientists in the U K have developed a green concrete that they say is more environmentally friendly https t co U6UklVhy3T Doctors are puzzling over dozens of cases mostly women in their 20s and 30s of a rare eye cancer in two Souther https t co ttIBIyNmxu A recent study shows the effects of drinking too much alcohol and how it can take a toll on your overall health https t co 0K4YCzsuAQ Rockefeller auction is poised to set a record as the biggest estate sale in U S history https t co FY5UTsYtNr New paper argues that some extraterrestrials may be struggling to make it off their planets https t co ZJueZ4Pg3l NBCNewsMACH One year on is <LOCATION>France</LOCATION> s golden boy <PERSON>Macron</PERSON> losing his luster https t co rWvBICe2Jh My father would not ride in an automobile with a woman other than my mother to protect my mother and more impor https t co UT3a1NZmv2 Will <LOCATION>Montana</LOCATION> voters reward <PERSON>Sen Jon Tester</PERSON> for taking on President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> or punish him for bucking the president https t co UFAPhuPNxe <PERSON>Giuliani</PERSON> accuses <PERSON>Mueller</PERSON> of setting the president up for perjury https t co gRy03ZVaRN Pizza or grilled cheese One of these foods is healthier than the other and the answers may surprise you via https t co JjKqxcoMVr <PERSON>Dershowitz Trump</PERSON> team playing into the hands of <PERSON>Mueller</PERSON> investigation https t co Wtt3FX35Og No sign of slowing down Lava damages 26 homes in <LOCATION>Hawaii</LOCATION> eruption https t co 8M8UVdvx59 Among all the living things on our planet we assume Homo sapiens is the only species ever to have developed advanc https t co Pf9ipBzv3Y <LOCATION>North Korea</LOCATION> says U S is ruining mood of detente ahead of <PERSON>Trump Kim</PERSON> summit https t co rs57EIzaLL Jessica Luther The <ORGANIZATION>NFL</ORGANIZATION> s next big scandal is its disgusting treatment of its cheerleaders https t co nfSs3nZhVr via <ORGANIZATION>NBCNewsTHINK RT</ORGANIZATION> PeterAlexander <PERSON>Giuliani</PERSON> a former <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> campaign advisor also told me he hasn t been interviewed by <PERSON>Mueller</PERSON> in <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> inquiry amp amp hasn RT PeterAlexander Spoke to <PERSON>Rudy Giuliani</PERSON> by phone tonight He accused <PERSON>Robert Mueller</PERSON> amp amp his investigators of being heavy handed amp amp set No place in <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> has been hit harder by the opioid epidemic than <LOCATION>West Virginia</LOCATION> And no place in <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> was less https t co 6jegyR6L2R The nightmares are over but <PERSON>Michelle Knight</PERSON> is still recovering 5 years after being freed from <PERSON>Ariel Castro</PERSON> https t co XQzuwSelqK Endangered <ORGANIZATION>House GOP</ORGANIZATION> members are running away from President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> In the <ORGANIZATION>Senate</ORGANIZATION> it s a much different story https t co <LOCATION>Dw8glk1Hta America</LOCATION> is making a mistake if it leaves the nuclear accord Iranian President <PERSON>Rouhani</PERSON> said https t co HDFP6cGMUW In photos Sputtering lava strong earthquakes and toxic gas jolted the southern part <LOCATION>Hawaii</LOCATION> s <LOCATION>Big Island</LOCATION> as magma https t co I31H3v9APi <PERSON>Gina Haspel</PERSON> considered withdrawing as <ORGANIZATION>CIA</ORGANIZATION> nominee sources say https t co pTfNdBFnlK Hepatitis C can be cured But patients still find they have to fight to get the treatment they need https t co bhtUSQiaar New radar scans have provided conclusive evidence that there are no hidden rooms inside King <PERSON>Tut</PERSON> s burial chamber https t co zBtTGqklTQ <PERSON>Rudy Giuliani</PERSON> said he can t rule out the possibility of President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> taking the Fifth Amendment in <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> invest https t co ekRcv54hK5 More than 50 000 <ORGANIZATION>University of California</ORGANIZATION> workers prepare to go on strike citing income disparity https t co Da94GjQZ5p TUNE IN LesterHoltNBC speaks exclusively with MeekMill in the rapper s first in depth interview since being rele https t co 80iNBr0YVZ Stormy Daniels makes surprise Saturday Night Live cameo in <PERSON>Michael Cohen</PERSON> skit https t co oUjelahWzP NBCNewsBETTER How to use dating apps after age 40 https t co 0iMy29nRhF Parkland s seniors find a fragment of normality at prom https t co iF0ZfRWzai RT NBCNewsPictures Photos <LOCATION>Hawaii</LOCATION> volcano Residents evacuate as lava fissures destroy homes https t co ipJuPgf59O <ORGANIZATION>USGS</ORGANIZATION> marcoinha Move over Rover New laws crack down on fake service dogs https t co DodUN7SDNb RT NBCNewsBETTER Why walking is the most underrated form of exercise https t co QPXO7SF9AP Rockefeller auction which includes pieces from <PERSON>Picasso</PERSON> to <PERSON>Monet</PERSON> is poised to set records in the art world https t co n0hsqFFWNo <PERSON>Mona Eltahawy</PERSON> I swear to make men uncomfortable And I m proud of it https t co nm6UkT5zMm via NBCNewsTHINK Aliens might be trapped on their own super Earths according to a new study https t co HqITYyfFEu via <ORGANIZATION>NBCNewsMACH RT MSNBC</ORGANIZATION> JUST IN <LOCATION>White House</LOCATION> officials went to <ORGANIZATION>CIA</ORGANIZATION> headquarters to encourage <PERSON>Gina Haspel</PERSON> to remain <ORGANIZATION>CIA</ORGANIZATION> director nominee sources tell <ORGANIZATION>N LesterHoltNBC</ORGANIZATION> speaks exclusively with Meek Mill in the rapper s first in depth interview since being released fro https t co QmhQ3UzTJa Hepatitis C can be cured But patients still find they have to fight to get the treatment they need https t co 2I7B1TKWIn Authorities in <LOCATION>Hawaii</LOCATION> continued to warn residents that volcanic eruptions earthquakes and poisonous gases were sti https t co dlfaUjTYLW People close to Sen <PERSON>John McCain</PERSON> have told the <ORGANIZATION>White House</ORGANIZATION> that he does not want President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> to attend his fune https t co L0DA0nKpKl Why rapper <PERSON>Meek Mill</PERSON> wants to fix broken justice system https t co 4IYDzIQrcn RT NBCLeftField In high school I had to tell her that I was gay and I remember hearing my mother scream And I remember seeing my fath NBCNewsBETTER Spring cleaning Here s what to do with all your old stuff https t co K2LOjc2hlw <PERSON>Syreeta McFadden Rachel Dolezal</PERSON> s claim that she is black is the whitest possible way to deal with her issues https t co cFo22wakSH RT LesterHoltNBC Tune in to DatelineNBC tonight at 7p 6c for Dreams and Nightmares The Meek Mill Story my exclusive in depth interv Toxic gas replaces lava as top concern on <LOCATION>Hawaii</LOCATION> s <LOCATION>Big Island</LOCATION> https t co AhkvdznBDP https t co Z7iJz0v1dr RT NBCNewsTHINK In my experience almost nothing can match the power of profanity delivered by a woman at a podium unapologetically say <PERSON>Rudy Giuliani</PERSON> said he can t rule out the possibility of President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> taking the Fifth Amendment in <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> invest https t co qT8SwybqL2 Stormy Daniels makes surprise Saturday Night Live cameo in <PERSON>Michael Cohen</PERSON> skit https t co z7Mg9MCHok RT NBCLeftField Mass shootings are claiming more lives than ever before So local police departments are turning to private training orga <ORGANIZATION>NFL</ORGANIZATION> owner buys Alcoholics Anonymous document for more than 2 million https t co hx4yibSDAp via NBCSports Dozens killed in mosque explosion in eastern <LOCATION>Afghanistan</LOCATION> https t co BkOw0zN6VX President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> is at his <LOCATION>Virginia</LOCATION> golf club marking his 111th visit to one of his golf properties since taking of https t co 0WvxPUdQT7 RT NBCNewsTHINK <PERSON>Rachel Dolezal</PERSON> s claim that she is black is the whitest possible way to deal with her issues argues reetamac https t <PERSON>Dershowitz Trump</PERSON> team playing into the hands of <PERSON>Mueller</PERSON> investigation https t co 1eBRRCks2J RT NBCLatino Meet Edmundito R os the proud third generation charro keeping an old Mexican tradition alive When you put on that suit RT MeetThePress WATCH <PERSON>Michael Avenatti</PERSON> calls <PERSON>Rudy Giuliani</PERSON> s latest comments ridiculous Just another absurdity that s being trotted <PERSON>Stormy Daniels</PERSON> makes surprise Saturday Night Live cameo in <PERSON>Michael Cohen</PERSON> skit https t co jmpiuG7ajz RT MeetThePress WATCH AlanDersh responds to <PERSON>Giuliani</PERSON> s comments Tells ChuckTodd that the <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> team plays into the hands of <ORGANIZATION>Muelle RT</ORGANIZATION> NBCNewsBETTER Create your own at home gym with these products under 20 https t co h0YgvXqQoc RT MeetThePress WATCH AlanDersh responds to <PERSON>Giuliani</PERSON> s comments Tells ChuckTodd that the <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> team plays into the heads of <ORGANIZATION>Muelle RT</ORGANIZATION> MeetThePress FULL INTERVIEW MichaelAvenatti joins <PERSON>Chuck</PERSON> to discuss the <PERSON>Stormy Daniels</PERSON> case and the <ORGANIZATION>White House</ORGANIZATION> s conflicting statem RT chucktodd AlanDersh tells me This was a very bad week for the <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> team this is not the way to handle a complicated case bu In <LOCATION>West Virginia</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Indiana</LOCATION> the Republican <ORGANIZATION>Senate</ORGANIZATION> primary fights have morphed into multi candidate battle royals w https t co 5mtmjFgmrx RT chucktodd I asked <PERSON>MichaelAvenatti</PERSON> why his case is important to the American people It centers on a cover up by the President <PERSON>Micha RT MeetThePress</PERSON> WATCH This morning MichaelAvenatti tells chucktodd Cover ups should always matter to the <ORGANIZATION>American People MTP</ORGANIZATION> https RT MeetThePress This should matter to the American people because have the right to be told the truth by their elected officials they h Stranded in a foreign airport for nearly 60 days trying not to lose hope of ever getting out That s the reality https t co ySVrBtskB6 For the most part President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> s campaign to oust red state Democratic senators in November is just standard is https t co HxIWXbgNWy President <PERSON>Hassan Rouhani</PERSON> said on Sunday <LOCATION>Iran</LOCATION> had plans to respond to any move by President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> on the 2015 nuclea https t co S6uuDQiroK Stormy <PERSON>Daniels</PERSON> made a surprise SNL cameo calling for President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> s resignation in a skit spoofing his lawyer https t co 0EaKooRbX7 Spring cleaning season is in full swing and there are so many great tips out there to help you purge belongings an https t co t0OSmEz0kK The nightmares are over but <PERSON>Michelle Knight</PERSON> is still recovering 5 years after being freed from <PERSON>Ariel Castro</PERSON> https t co BiIzTpYv6X She was the most excited to go to prom Parkland s seniors celebrate a milestone but four are missing https t co UaF8a4pL7y <LOCATION>North Korea</LOCATION> says U S ruining mood of detente ahead of <PERSON>Trump Kim</PERSON> summit https t co kRNJHNM1la Opinion <PERSON>Rachel Dolezal</PERSON> s claim to blackness is the whitest possible thing https t co 2CSGj6hV1f Endangered <ORGANIZATION>House GOP</ORGANIZATION> members can t run from <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> fast enough In the <ORGANIZATION>Senate</ORGANIZATION> it s different https t co OpIuCrNUZe One year on from his comprehensive election victory <PERSON>Emmanuel Macron</PERSON> still enjoys an international reputation as Fr https t co xOpIoxF9Z7 Struggling to lose weight A dietitian says her two treat rule can help https t co 038XoAaGdb NBCNewsBETTER Stormy Daniels calls for <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> s resignation in SNL skit https t co gilp7gI2QQ New royal baby altered line to British throne Here s what it looks like now https t co 5sG7iTEkFU via <ORGANIZATION>NBCNewsWorld Five</ORGANIZATION> homes were destroyed in <LOCATION>Hawaii</LOCATION> s <PERSON>Leilani Estates</PERSON> on the <LOCATION>Big Island</LOCATION> but a quieter <LOCATION>Kilauea</LOCATION> volcano has authorit https t co KvQqiKyz7d NBCNewsBETTER Nutritionists swear by these healthy Trader <PERSON>Joe</PERSON> s products https t co cpMnbLC3gk Fake Uber drivers are kidnapping and assaulting unsuspecting passengers How can you avoid becoming a victim of an https t co 8Ij89i8IBZ Meet the man behind the <ORGANIZATION>TSA</ORGANIZATION> s hilarious Instagram account https t co GC6NrJN7TR The mystery of who had been leaving a daily pile of feces on a <LOCATION>New Jersey</LOCATION> high school s football field and track wa https t co REWZRX1NBl Wearing a red shirt emblazoned with <PERSON>Jesus</PERSON> former transgender rights activist <PERSON>Jeffrey McCall</PERSON> stood before a smal https t co HDtOlEvWql With unemployment down and corporate tax breaks where s the wage growth https t co dOGEuy3pzf Pulse survivor says he is no longer gay has found <PERSON>Christ</PERSON> https t co gPXGdAiMf3 via NBCOUT Justify conquered the field and a heavy rain to claim victory in the <ORGANIZATION>144th Kentucky Derby</ORGANIZATION> at <ORGANIZATION>Churchill Downs</ORGANIZATION> and se https t co UGMQqfAiBI Self help guru denies enslaving branding women in Nxivm sex cult https t co mR13eLVut4 Authorities released the first installment of police video from the deadliest mass shooting in modern U S history https t co dzEruStXMB Court orders new murder trial for <PERSON>Kennedy</PERSON> cousin <PERSON>Michael Skakel</PERSON> https t co easGNRuJsd A second photo released by <ORGANIZATION>Kensington Palace</ORGANIZATION> shows Princess <PERSON>Charlotte</PERSON> and <LOCATION>Prince Louis</LOCATION> on May 2 the princess 3rd https t co 6QPBkosZ3d JUST IN <LOCATION>Kensington Palace</LOCATION> releases photo of Prince <PERSON>Louis</PERSON> taken by <PERSON>Kate</PERSON> the Duchess of <LOCATION>Cambridge</LOCATION> on April 26 https t co XvFBkMPxu9 <ORGANIZATION>Ford</ORGANIZATION> to stop making all passenger cars except one https t co 3yiIeP7d24 https t co ssIB7L8Oc8 JUST IN Justify wins 2018 Kentucky Derby Christians in the Holy Land feel abandoned by American evangelicals https t co ACQhHyUhpn WATCH LIVE 144th annual <ORGANIZATION>Kentucky Derby</ORGANIZATION> at <ORGANIZATION>Churchill Downs NBCSports</ORGANIZATION> https t co jj1b73vdII <ORGANIZATION>Ex Redskins</ORGANIZATION> cheerleaders defend team and deny pimping situation during <LOCATION>Costa Rica</LOCATION> trip https t co 9ywEQa5T6j President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> said reports of stabbings in <LOCATION>London</LOCATION> showed that gun control isn t effective at preventing violence https t co oWfFJx1u6R RT NBCNewsPictures Photos Competitive cry babies a summit of the Koreas May Day rallies and more of the weeks best photos https t co Young Texan keeps charrer a which preceded rodeo alive through three generations https t co m8XiHYZEFq Former Presidents <PERSON>Barack Obama</PERSON> and <PERSON>George W Bush</PERSON> plan to be eulogists at Sen <PERSON>McCain</PERSON> s funeral according to a sou https t co CbPvfKfDoi <PERSON>John McCain</PERSON> doesn t want President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> at his funeral friends tell the <ORGANIZATION>White House</ORGANIZATION> https t co cPMosJBdKw Political world braces for the next generation of fake news https t co dBhpyMUmor Watching disasters might actually have benefits for the brain up to a point NBCNewsBETTER https t co ZWsLrqe8PT New laws crack down on people who falsely claim their pets as service and support animals https t co jeEHZ8XZXc Syrian man <PERSON>Hassan al Kontar</PERSON> is stranded at Malaysian airport for nearly 60 days https t co E9vzVZ06z5 Here s what to expect in the 2018 <ORGANIZATION>Kentucky Derby</ORGANIZATION> https t co Nv333uNygz NBCSports <PERSON>Mueller</PERSON> team questions longtime <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> friend <PERSON>Tom Barrack</PERSON> https t co 7DEXyYqflX LIVE President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> speaks on tax reform in <LOCATION>Cleveland Ohio</LOCATION> https t co q3nqfdGArH InSight lander will take <ORGANIZATION>NASA</ORGANIZATION> where it s never gone before NBCNewsMACH https t co MBbWaWSS7w After Golden State Killer arrest Zodiac Killer case could be cracked by decades old DNA https t co UbBuFpLrTS Protesters detained in <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> as thousands rally ahead of <PERSON>Putin</PERSON> s inauguration https t co V9b2jCkEkV A Japanese robotics company just unveiled a real life Transformer NBCNewsMACH https t co H6Ylnfy6QL RT NBCNewsTHINK I never felt time was on my side and as a result I spent a lot of my life rushing against what has turned out to be a f WATCH <ORGANIZATION>NASA</ORGANIZATION> sends InSight spacecraft to <LOCATION>Mars</LOCATION> for first geological survey https t co s2PCKm7pS8 Female Mariachis flourish as they follow in the footsteps of the Godmother https t co WpYlOmrzyn There s a mother lode of young eligible Latino voters in <LOCATION>Texas</LOCATION> that could fortify the political party that snags t https t co aKBqAWx6mX Fmr President <PERSON>George H W Bush</PERSON> is doing well after returning home from the hospital his spokesperson says https t co zdPdDowK52 WATCH President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> does not answer shouted questions from reporters as he boards Marine One en route to Joint B https t co 634GEj31Ob From juleps to fascinators the <LOCATION>Kentucky Derby</LOCATION> is good for small businesses across the U S https t co VHfLT6onF6 RT NBCNewsBETTER We ve got your cincodemayo party trick How to cut an Instagram worthy avocado https t co uwPl7CkYF5 WATCH LIVE SpaceX Dragon resupply ship to be released from the <LOCATION>International Space Station</LOCATION> and return to <LOCATION>Earth</LOCATION> https t co <ORGANIZATION>9iU3asj2GL Jack Jacobs Being</ORGANIZATION> a president s chief is a tough job in the best of administrations but trying to curb <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> s i https t co q68Mp2sXzd Opinion Maureen Shaw <LOCATION>Iowa</LOCATION> just passed the most restrictive abortion bill in <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> in a blatant attempt to reve https t co tt1DyJCMDB It s easier than ever to make high quality manipulations to audio and video and that has experts worried https t co M7ZuybLWrB Collared New laws crack down on fake service dogs https t co bEri3Xiq8y In high school I had to tell her that I was gay and I remember hearing my mother scream And I remember seeing m https t co nZfSTDNaJj The InSight lander will launch from <LOCATION>Vandenberg Air Force Base</LOCATION> in central <LOCATION>California</LOCATION> Its primary goal to give scie https t co VbKYsqHAha WATCH LIVE <ORGANIZATION>NASA</ORGANIZATION> s InSight Mars mission launches from <LOCATION>Vandenberg Air Force Base</LOCATION> in <LOCATION>California</LOCATION> on a mission to stud https t co oJJ9y3Exgk <ORGANIZATION>Brothers Jose</ORGANIZATION> and Irad will compete on top of Good Magic and <PERSON>Hofburg</PERSON> respectively while <PERSON>Velazquez</PERSON> will ride Vino https t co Nre6di17j3 NBCNewsBETTER has got you covered on <ORGANIZATION>Cinco de Mayo</ORGANIZATION> or whenever the mood for Mexican food strikes https t co omWp2kAAQN The new probe will be able to answer questions about whether the <LOCATION>Red Planet</LOCATION> is alive or dead via NBCNewsMACH https t co HSL4ZzsKw9 Stranded in a foreign airport for nearly 60 days trying not to lose hope of ever getting out That s the reality https t co HUKy62JRy9 Crying reverse racism and feminism the trolls lobbied for other entrants in the contest and encouraged their https t co ytoZBsqnE3 Have you ever wondered what <LOCATION>Buckingham Palace</LOCATION> would look like if it were built in a Bauhaus style See more iconic https t co yIaJjvbjr7 Opinion Of course Swedish meatballs are Turkish All our food comes from elsewhere https t co TiOaWTicBr Religious anxiety is intrinsic to <LOCATION>Israel</LOCATION> and the Palestinian territories with their tapestry of competing faiths https t co uZGg99yDMQ The Good Place star <PERSON>Jameela Jamil</PERSON> launched the I Weigh campaign as a way to inspire women to define themselves https t co Tspyqg4C6s The <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> has warned <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> that there will be consequences for its growing militarization of disputed isl https t co B6wNYvfSas Former cheerleaders pushed back against explosive allegations in which fellow squad members said they had to pose t https t co jbsmpVpV69 A new front in the fight surrounding the <ORGANIZATION>Deferred Action for Childhood Arrivals DACA</ORGANIZATION> program is opening up this https t co p6u57MrqcU The projected 3 D image looks real from any angle and to multiple viewers from different angles said a professor https t co 6Vng8tgnob NBCNewsBETTER Why does it take longer for women to lose weight especially after 40 Find out https t co CsOjjLsNEi WATCH A magnitude 6 9 earthquake rattled <LOCATION>Hawaii</LOCATION> as <LOCATION>Kilauea</LOCATION> continues to erupt https t co UXKm9LTPXU https t co <ORGANIZATION>ngepFj8fbU State</ORGANIZATION> lawmakers in <LOCATION>Oklahoma</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Kansas</LOCATION> have approved legislation to grant legal protections to faith based adoption https t co luaweRYpgf A 52 year old man will likely spend the rest of his life in prison for fatally shooting a bar patron in <LOCATION>Kansas</LOCATION> and https t co HOxSI1G6FY Weeks after publishing his own story of sexual abuse in the New Yorker Pulitzer Prize winning author <PERSON>Junot Diaz</PERSON> is https t co xxCD5Sks7w <PERSON>Albert Pujols</PERSON> made history collecting his 3 000th career hit with a base hit off of <PERSON>Mike Leake</PERSON> in the fifth inning https t co oNEDhGmHgO As a gay Latino climber <PERSON>Bam Mendiola</PERSON> says he s climbing two mountains His immigrant parents weren t ready to acce https t co oPh8VKhj8L Opinion <PERSON>David Faris</PERSON> author of It s Time to Fight Dirty says Republicans have all but destroyed Democratic norm https t co 6G53RDZF0v President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> defended <PERSON>Giuliani</PERSON> and insisted he was still learning the subject matter as it relates to the <PERSON>Dani</PERSON> https t co qq1B0njR1g Vice President <PERSON>Mike Pence</PERSON> s <LOCATION>White House</LOCATION> doctor who raised concerns about disgraced <ORGANIZATION>White House</ORGANIZATION> physician <PERSON>Ronny Jac</PERSON> https t co ZDhoXW8pPK The 2018 award has been postponed following a controversy over alleged sexual misconduct that has seen a string of https t co uS191riKkq Months before an accident claimed the life of a <ORGANIZATION>Southwest Airlines</ORGANIZATION> passenger the <ORGANIZATION>FAA</ORGANIZATION> found that distrust between m https t co 9zCbXCIw4R The nation s unemployment rate fell to 3 9 percent for the first time since 2000 with the economy gaining 164 000 https t co wodYoaZyS8 <PERSON>Alex Tausanovitch</PERSON> First the <ORGANIZATION>NRA</ORGANIZATION> stated categorically that it did not accept money from Russian donors for electio https t co wlQkvKHXet Prosecutors say that instead the children were subject to starvation torture endangerment and imprisonment at th https t co SpYuePkSVi Three women who worked for former <ORGANIZATION>CBS News</ORGANIZATION> television anchor <PERSON>Charlie Rose</PERSON> filed a sexual harassment lawsuit against https t co VfztNB7wmg <ORGANIZATION>NBC Asian America</ORGANIZATION> Presents A to Z meet 2018 s emerging voices and rising stars as we kick off Asian Pacific Amer https t co P3htLUV5Pd RT NBCNightlyNews ACROSS <LOCATION>AMERICA</LOCATION> Starting Monday <PERSON>Lester Holt</PERSON> sets out on a nation wide journey to report on stories impacting <ORGANIZATION>Americans National Weather Service</ORGANIZATION> reports magnitude 4 6 earthquake offshore of the <LOCATION>Kalapana</LOCATION> region of <LOCATION>Kilauea</LOCATION> https t co VdQ6ibUOOb For some including many firefighters from municipalities protection from a deadly wildfire isn t something that https t co pZ4e0L7kgI The <ORGANIZATION>Connecticut Supreme Court</ORGANIZATION> overturned the murder conviction of <PERSON>Kennedy</PERSON> family cousin <PERSON>Michael Skakel</PERSON> and ordered https t co Btm5iJTey3 <LOCATION>Hawaii County Civil Defense</LOCATION> authorities warned that first responders may not be able to come to the aid of residen https t co hAzOphhdhI RT NBCNightlyNews WATCH 48 years ago today May 4 1970 <LOCATION>Ohio National Guardsmen</LOCATION> opened fire on student protesters at <ORGANIZATION>Kent State Univ</ORGANIZATION> i Photos of <PERSON>Daum</PERSON> in the red dress recently caused an uproar on social media where many people accused her of cultura https t co m4fd46zp57 A self help guru accused of running an upstate <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> sex cult that included Smallville actress <PERSON>Allison Mack</PERSON> pl https t co JWPe0nqmdb A U S federal judge made it clear that he is skeptical over the ability of special counsel <PERSON>Robert Mueller</PERSON> to bring https t co B4os28GqNz Former President <PERSON>George H W Bush</PERSON> has been discharged from <ORGANIZATION>Methodist Hospital</ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION>Houston</LOCATION> after treatment for an inf https t co bY591rqlKp <ORGANIZATION>USGS</ORGANIZATION> reports magnitude 6 9 earthquake near <LOCATION>Leilani Estates</LOCATION> in <LOCATION>Hawaii</LOCATION> This is in almost exactly the same location https t co A2FC5JRhz9 President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> thanks <LOCATION>Kanye West</LOCATION> during <ORGANIZATION>NRA</ORGANIZATION> convention speech Kanye West must have some power because you proba https t co cJrsFEw1n9 The <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> administration is shutting off protections for people who have lived in the U S for nearly two decades a https t co <ORGANIZATION>MhsvyRz8Wc National Weather Service</ORGANIZATION> reports magnitude has increased to a 6 4 magnitude earthquake on south flank of <LOCATION>Kilauea</LOCATION> N https t co <ORGANIZATION>RhE5ydSUwq Hawaii Emergency Management Agency</ORGANIZATION> reports magnitude 6 0 earthquake on south flank of <LOCATION>Kilauea</LOCATION> No tsunami is expect https t co sxhI78qwKG President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> doubled down on his support for the <ORGANIZATION>NRA</ORGANIZATION> at the group s annual conference after previously vowing to https t co uyreAwrD6T Young Texan keeps charrer a which preceded rodeo alive through three generations https t co 1ieAE1eeqh via <ORGANIZATION>NBCLatino USGS</ORGANIZATION> upgrades earthquake near <LOCATION>Kilauea</LOCATION> volcano in <LOCATION>Hawaii</LOCATION> to magnitude 5 7 https t co Ssf4vwrPIf Palestinian leader <PERSON>Abbas</PERSON> apologizes for speech condemned as anti Semitic https t co G7thj9ffm8 via NBCNewsWorld JUST IN Preliminary magnitude 5 3 earthquake strikes <LOCATION>Hawaii</LOCATION> s <LOCATION>Big Island</LOCATION> near <LOCATION>Kilauea</LOCATION> volcano <ORGANIZATION>USGS</ORGANIZATION> says https t co 1SuTJROs8T Growing up I thought a woman s life peaked at 40 Now 51 I m so glad I was wrong writes morningmika for https t co ge0lGI0lae President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> credits <LOCATION>Kanye</LOCATION> with boosting black support https t co izarOPaw67 https t co yBQExIPHYJ <PERSON>Rudy Giuliani</PERSON> issues statement attempting to clarify remarks he d made in recent days about a 130 000 payment that https t co KZkolQuWit <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> administration ends protected status for 60 000 Hondurans https t co 9JIcO7YAo6 RT NBCNewsTHINK Growing up I thought a woman s life peaked at 40 Now 51 I m so glad I was wrong writes morningmika https t co ENB3U Twitter scorned for password issue but praised for disclosing it https t co Z4VkLSUk5z Be the first to know about important issues as they unfold across the world Sign up for NBCNews breaking news a https t co qDOVmjivYc Ani Bundel Happy Star Wars Day a fake holiday <ORGANIZATION>Disney</ORGANIZATION> turned into a marketing blitz fans actually love https t co geIDvBWaZN U S warns <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> that there will be consequences for its growing militarization of disputed islands in the <LOCATION>South</LOCATION> https t co gEfqmRnznM A self help guru accused of running an upstate <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> sex cult that included Smallville actress <PERSON>Allison Mack</PERSON> pl https t co EjuvvNLZ2K Did another advanced species exist on Earth before humans https t co UFLbsJJElA via NBCNewsMACH Hurricane heroes gone too soon <LOCATION>Puerto Rico</LOCATION> mourns the deaths of 9 <ORGANIZATION>National Guard</ORGANIZATION> airmen https t co OBtyhpMRTl via NBCLatino WATCH 48 years ago today May 4 1970 <LOCATION>Ohio National Guardsmen</LOCATION> opened fire on student protesters at <ORGANIZATION>Kent State Uni</ORGANIZATION> https t co o90Fujy66D 61 000 reward offered after federal agent shot in the face Friday morning on <LOCATION>Chicago</LOCATION> s <LOCATION>South Side</LOCATION> https t co gpDQd7zHaO nbcchicago Economists look for wage gains as unemployment falls to 3 9 a level not seen since 2000 https t co <ORGANIZATION>NTaxXlJ2UY BREAKING Connecticut Supreme Court</ORGANIZATION> rules that <PERSON>Kennedy</PERSON> cousin <PERSON>Michael Skakel</PERSON> was deprived of a fair trial and is e https t co vWQSh4sD0t RT NBCNews President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> at <ORGANIZATION>NRA</ORGANIZATION> convention If we re going to outlaw guns like so many people want to do we are going to have to BREAKING <ORGANIZATION>US Homeland Security</ORGANIZATION> says it is terminating Temporary Protected Status TPS designation for Hondurans w https t co lYiBUd5Vgt RT <ORGANIZATION>MSNBC</ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> speaks about the Parkland shooting at <ORGANIZATION>NRA</ORGANIZATION> convention stresses the need to harden certain schools https t c NBCNewsBETTER Are you guilty of bad travel etiquette These are the most annoying behaviors according to new su https t co qkrNv8vLIb President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> at <ORGANIZATION>NRA</ORGANIZATION> convention If we re going to outlaw guns like so many people want to do we are going https t co oi1g1YbuYl NBCNewsBETTER Entering management requires a whole different set of skills and just because someone is good at https t co Rge35FyXjl President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> thanks <LOCATION>Kanye West</LOCATION> during <ORGANIZATION>NRA</ORGANIZATION> convention speech https t co iQ7Valojmm RT NBCNews LIVE President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> speaks at <ORGANIZATION>NRA</ORGANIZATION> leadership forum in <LOCATION>Dallas</LOCATION> https t co QNsjbXyJTX RT <ORGANIZATION>MSNBC</ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> endorses <PERSON>Sen Cruz</PERSON> s re election bid at <ORGANIZATION>NRA</ORGANIZATION> convention Full endorsement for this man <PERSON>Ted Cruz</PERSON> https t co LIVE President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> speaks at <ORGANIZATION>NRA</ORGANIZATION> leadership forum in <LOCATION>Dallas</LOCATION> https t co QNsjbXyJTX VaughnHillyard VP Pence s <LOCATION>White House</LOCATION> doctor who raised concerns about disgraced <ORGANIZATION>White House</ORGANIZATION> physician <PERSON>Ronny Jack</PERSON> https t co igcN76lHTv RT NBCNews LIVE VP Pence speaks at <ORGANIZATION>NRA</ORGANIZATION> leadership forum in <LOCATION>Dallas</LOCATION> https t co V0rrwwhZdc In new statement on the <PERSON>Stormy Daniels</PERSON> case <PERSON>Rudy Giuliani</PERSON> says My references to timing were not describing my un https t co jZgLL0Zmlq LIVE VP Pence speaks at <ORGANIZATION>NRA</ORGANIZATION> leadership forum in <LOCATION>Dallas</LOCATION> https t co V0rrwwhZdc RT NBCPolitics Former President <PERSON>Obama</PERSON> is endorsing <PERSON>Sen Feinstein</PERSON> in her reelection campaign I m proud to give <PERSON>Dianne Feinstein</PERSON> my str JUST IN VP Pence s physician Dr <PERSON>Jennifer Pena</PERSON> has resigned from the <ORGANIZATION>White House</ORGANIZATION> Medical Unit Pence s physicia https t co R62P2bfIVf Is rodeo really an American sport It stems from a centuries old Mexican tradition called charrer a A group of Me https t co 6qpddiWATf High levels of dangerous sulfur dioxide gas were detected in the air early Friday morning in an area of <LOCATION>Hawaii</LOCATION> wh https t co QXIZ58DSM5 President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> on sitting for <PERSON>Mueller</PERSON> interview Nobody wants to speak more than me https t co Ukej8Rzwdm Why <PERSON>John Bolton</PERSON> could soon become the second most powerful man in <LOCATION>Washington</LOCATION> <PERSON>Jack Jacobs</PERSON> writes for NBCNewsTHINK https t co EOUt5PrILa <PERSON>Alex Tausanovitch</PERSON> The <ORGANIZATION>NRA</ORGANIZATION> can be so secretive about its Russian donors because it blocked campaign finance reform https t co fFHSU8ZqrR The judge said that he believes the special counsel is only interested in <PERSON>Manafort</PERSON> to squeeze him for information https t co GeuHCFw3SZ NEW U S federal judge made it clear in court on Friday that he is skeptical over the ability of Special Counsel M https t co F2zcMdDUQx Sophia A Nelson When West a successful black man with a massive platform implied that slavery is a choice he https t co 2wD5O7wLwv Among all the living things on our planet we assume Homo sapiens is the only species ever to have developed advanc https t co jO9J03EqCf President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> on <PERSON>Rudy Giuliani</PERSON> comments He started yesterday He ll get his facts straight https t co jC6XDEId5d Actress <PERSON>Jameela Jamil</PERSON> wants to use her platform to change the discussion around body image https t co Df1WdjM2ns via <ORGANIZATION>NBCAsianAmerica</ORGANIZATION> A new front in the fight surrounding the DACA program is opening up this time around employment https t co UOXxVt4SOe via NBCLatino President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> on <PERSON>Rudy Giuliani He</PERSON> ll get his facts straight https t co zTie0uu3gS https t co <ORGANIZATION>TqPq1Gl9Gd State</ORGANIZATION> lawmakers in <LOCATION>Oklahoma</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Kansas</LOCATION> have approved legislation to grant legal protections to faith based adoption https t co G86mlOZr1S Former <ORGANIZATION>Washington Redskins</ORGANIZATION> cheerleaders push back against explosive allegations in which fellow squad members said https t co 7lu1yJCkfx RT NBCNews President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> says he would love to speak with Special Counsel <PERSON>Mueller</PERSON> If I thought it was fair I would override my la RT NBCLeftField As a gay Latino climber <PERSON>Bam Mendiola</PERSON> says he s climbing two mountains His immigrant parents weren t ready to accept him President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> I will tell you this When <PERSON>Rudy</PERSON> made the statements <PERSON>Rudy</PERSON> s great but <PERSON>Rudy</PERSON> had just started and https t co gLn8F3nDb1 <PERSON>Meghan Markle</PERSON> s parents to visit queen have roles in royal wedding https t co WBmkKQiBXx via <ORGANIZATION>NBCNewsWorld NEW</ORGANIZATION> President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> says we now have a date and we have a location for <LOCATION>North Korea</LOCATION> summit https t co CYMZYqqckV President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> says he would love to speak with Special Counsel <PERSON>Mueller</PERSON> If I thought it was fair I would ove https t co nafeLWcxbU President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> on <PERSON>Rudy Giuliani</PERSON> He started yesterday He ll get his facts straight He s a great guy https t co mTjYdcMCCX The challenging thing about being a queer person of color that s also a climber is that I m constantly climbing tw https t co 7frFsH4J7u RT NBCNightlyNews ACROSS <LOCATION>AMERICA</LOCATION> Starting Monday LesterHoltNBC sets out on a nation wide journey to report on stories impacting Americ Unnamed agent shot early Friday and taken to hospital in critical condition police say https t co D4unijSXfN NBCChicago Palestinian President <PERSON>Mahmoud Abbas</PERSON> offers an apology after being accused of anti Semitism https t co zY6qnUWwPo NEW President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> met with Sessions Nielsen Coats <PERSON>Kelly Bolton McGahn</PERSON> and <PERSON>Wray</PERSON> Thursday to discuss the <ORGANIZATION>Adm</ORGANIZATION> https t co qYwt8o8uVr In an investigation of whistleblower complaints from <ORGANIZATION>Southwest</ORGANIZATION> mechanics the <ORGANIZATION>FAA</ORGANIZATION> determines that <ORGANIZATION>Southwest</ORGANIZATION> supervi https t co L3oJIILHeB The U S warns <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> that there will be consequences for its growing militarization of disputed islands in the So https t co f7hqkVjmHK In today s NBCFirstRead It s not all that hard to see how Democrats could gain the net of two seats they need to https t co 92PdRfXyrj NEW <LOCATION>US</LOCATION> unemployment rate falls to 3 9 in April lowest since 2000 https t co uo7ybyBGJk JUST IN U S added 164 000 jobs in April with unemployment rate dropping to 3 9 according to <ORGANIZATION>Bureau of Labor Statistics Rudy Giuliani</ORGANIZATION> says President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> seemed surprised to hear about <PERSON>Stormy Daniels</PERSON> reimbursement <PERSON>Giuliani</PERSON> said the https t co l8Cv6Du4Kv RT NBCNews DEVELOPING Mandatory evacuations are under way in <LOCATION>Hawaii</LOCATION> as lava emerges from <LOCATION>Kilauea</LOCATION> volcano authorities say https t co The <ORGANIZATION>Denver Post</ORGANIZATION> editor who oversaw an editorial critical of budget and staff cuts resigns after another piece criti https t co MLOZogsW0e 2018 Nobel Prize in Literature postponed following controversy over alleged sexual misconduct https t co awWKiugu1c RT TODAYshow I read that an average cheerleader makes 150 per game is that ridiculous to you guys <PERSON>HodaKotb</PERSON> asks <ORGANIZATION>Redskins</ORGANIZATION> cheerlead Be the first to know about important issues as they unfold across the world Sign up for NBCNews breaking news a https t co 9RDxvkKjlB RT TODAYshow In terms of being an escort that was never a perception that I had two <ORGANIZATION>Redskins</ORGANIZATION> cheerleaders talk about a trip to shoot U S forces fighting terror in the <LOCATION>Horn of Africa</LOCATION> are facing a new threat lasers fired from the new Chinese milit https t co Lr0OLhCoRH Twitter advises its 330 million users to change their passwords after some of them were accidentally stored in plai https t co EOVUNDBv41 DEVELOPING Mandatory evacuations are under way in <LOCATION>Hawaii</LOCATION> as lava emerges from <LOCATION>Kilauea</LOCATION> volcano authorities say https t co FQKB8ZgZRT <PERSON>Rudy Giuliani</PERSON> says President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> seemed surprised to hear about <PERSON>Stormy Daniels</PERSON> reimbursement <PERSON>Giuliani</PERSON> said the https t co yR6KQ7uyh1 RT TODAYshow Today on TODAY Emergency evacuations in <LOCATION>Hawaii</LOCATION> as a volcano erupts new details about the royalwedding and a big announce Lava from <LOCATION>Hawaii</LOCATION> s <LOCATION>Kilauea</LOCATION> volcano forces mandatory evacuation and chases locals from their homes https t co EOrMMcQh57 The <ORGANIZATION>Missouri Legislature</ORGANIZATION> will call itself into a special session to consider impeaching Gov <PERSON>Eric Greitens</PERSON> followin https t co Qg76P3uYnj Opinion <PERSON>Steve Vladeck Trump</PERSON> says he can fire anyone Here s why he s wrong https t co WY78vNgmJe NBCNewsTHINK DEVELOPING Mandatory evacuations are under way in <LOCATION>Hawaii</LOCATION> as lava emerges from <LOCATION>Kilauea</LOCATION> volcano authorities say https t co KkiF8gujtT NEW 2018 Nobel Prize in Literature postponed following controversy over alleged sexual misconduct https t co BhPKq7VYGL A debate has ignited over the use of private firefighting teams deployed by insurance companies and used to protect https t co mXUOPwxcC2 Insurance fraud body brokering and sex trafficking these are the schemes that have emerged in <LOCATION>Florida</LOCATION> s substan https t co vshhX8n97C The <ORGANIZATION>U S State Department</ORGANIZATION> is investigating reports that detainees <PERSON>Kim Hak</PERSON> song <PERSON>Kim Dong chul</PERSON> and <PERSON>Tony Kim</PERSON> could be https t co iAesjXpMtq Scientists in the U K have developed a green concrete that they say is more environmentally friendly https t co m10ZCBYQM8 A simple way to reduce how much you spend on gas is to shop around for the best price something most motorists don https t co 0B4kTym0vo Chinese feminists are trying to stay one step ahead of censors as they push the country s fledgling MeToo movement https t co UDtsiJGFg0 Researchers in <LOCATION>Singapore</LOCATION> have developed robotic arms that can assemble an <ORGANIZATION>Ikea</ORGANIZATION> chair in about 20 minutes https t co oE4m0CxSzn Opinion <PERSON>Jack Jacobs John Kelly</PERSON> s fall from grace is <PERSON>John Bolton</PERSON> s gain https t co RSmVtHOPNF NBCNewsTHINK JUST IN Swedish Academy to postpone 2018 Nobel Prize in Literature following allegations of sexual misconduct As the largest muscle group in your body your glutes are key to making everyday tasks easier https t co ZMMFBhdo2D NBCNewsBETTER Around 700 000 refugees fleeing persecution in <LOCATION>Myanmar</LOCATION> are living under perilous conditions in <LOCATION>Bangladesh</LOCATION> https t co dXqiiUJEAb NEW <PERSON>Rudy Giuliani</PERSON> says President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> seemed surprised to hear about Stormy Daniels reimbursement <PERSON>Giuliani</PERSON> said https t co h6iuaxdj94 A Guant namo Bay prisoner has been transferred to his native <LOCATION>Saudi Arabia</LOCATION> where he will serve the rest of his 13 ye https t co <ORGANIZATION>AyCZYHmtRZ Hawaii Electric Light</ORGANIZATION> says it expects to have sufficient power for customers despite the emergency shutdown of P https t co HKEWyB9q3o Chinese feminists are trying to stay one step ahead of censors as they push the country s fledgling MeToo movement https t co tK5nxFVQ8d Severe dust storms have claimed the lives of at least 91 people in <LOCATION>India</LOCATION> https t co MK8qfvcOfx https t co d5MbAiK4aP <LOCATION>Iran</LOCATION> s foreign minister took to YouTube to criticize President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> s threat to withdraw from the nuclear deal sa https t co aSo1yJc7r7 The Cosby case has amplified accusers voices and legal experts expect that that will encourage more victims to sp https t co OE5fBTRDOW Much of the conference s opening day was spent reassuring developers to stick with <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> https t co yP5fRB3ceO <LOCATION>Hawaii County</LOCATION> civil defense officials ordered some of the 1 500 residents of <ORGANIZATION>Leilani Estates</ORGANIZATION> to evacuate as steam a https t co NTa3etp4fV Earthquakes around the <LOCATION>Kilauea</LOCATION> volcano in <LOCATION>Hawaii</LOCATION> have cracked streets and rattled residents https t co zri9WLH5EX The <ORGANIZATION>Academy of Motion Picture Arts and Sciences</ORGANIZATION> the organization that puts on the Oscars has voted to expel <PERSON>Bill</PERSON> https t co aesII1HFIm The <ORGANIZATION>U S Department of Commerce</ORGANIZATION> has been ordered to reinstate a Chinese American scientist who had been accused of https t co Ti5f9JB9zN The plane was long a part of the fleet of <LOCATION>Puerto Rico</LOCATION> s <ORGANIZATION>Air National Guard</ORGANIZATION> and had rescued and resupplied U S citi https t co oMpzz200kJ WATCH Lava from <LOCATION>Hawaii</LOCATION> s <LOCATION>Kilauea</LOCATION> volcano erupts near <LOCATION>Leilani Estates Video</LOCATION> by <PERSON>Jeffrey Wise</PERSON> https t co SgzN6LBto7 Reporter How are the American people to trust or believe what is said here or what is said by the president Pr https t co ukr5nbTKsr https t co 1mEJGj48Ad President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> s admitted reimbursement to his lawyer for a payment to <PERSON>Stormy Daniels</PERSON> days before the election cou https t co TaRga9j0Vv RT <ORGANIZATION>NBCNewsPictures Photos Mujeres de Mariachi Women</ORGANIZATION> take center stage on male tradition https t co JSl3a3q6JA IlanaPL MariachiAlte What s it like to be Instagram famous by accident via <ORGANIZATION>NBCLeftField</ORGANIZATION> https t co PtFZH1yA23 Lava eruption underway at <LOCATION>Hawaii</LOCATION> s <LOCATION>Kilauea</LOCATION> volcano <ORGANIZATION>USGS</ORGANIZATION> reports https t co 2a6gqRw11p NBCNewsBETTER Entering management requires a whole different set of skills and just because someone is good at https t co 6BCw3RbIke Among all the living things on our planet we assume Homo sapiens is the only species ever to have developed advanc https t co HLfr1jy0dj <PERSON>Bill Cosby</PERSON> s wife <PERSON>Camille</PERSON> issued a scathing statement against his accusers <LOCATION>Pennsylvania</LOCATION> prosecutors and the medi https t co t1ysW9jshK A man charged with threatening to shoot up gay clubs in <LOCATION>Chicago</LOCATION> is once again behind bars after being mistakenly re https t co 3SuxBFQCSN <PERSON>Steve Vladeck</PERSON> Despite what <PERSON>McConnell</PERSON> believes the fact that <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> believes he does have unlimited firing power m https t co VuzDOOjOWH The <ORGANIZATION>Missouri Legislature</ORGANIZATION> will call itself into a special session to consider impeaching Gov <PERSON>Eric Greitens</PERSON> followin https t co tz3QMejR0d Ex <ORGANIZATION>NFL</ORGANIZATION> cheerleaders tell NBC News that they were forced to be topless for a calendar shoot and later asked to escor https t co kNv1Y67NVK The <ORGANIZATION>Consumer Product Safety Commission CPSC</ORGANIZATION> has recalled about 19 000 Sharper Image and Frigidaire Mandoline slic https t co XESWh44bMY A food processor that supplies beef to <ORGANIZATION>Kroger</ORGANIZATION> supermarkets has recalled more than 35 000 pounds of ground beef beca https t co Zcd9ibOpte Average levels of acceptance for LGBTQ people and their rights have increased globally since 1980 according to new https t co ZYeDIPEYXA The bill would ban discrimination based on gender identity in housing employment and public accommodations in add https t co duWYnZkBR3 Women who eat more fast food spend longer trying to get pregnant while those who eat more fruit conceive more quic https t co 5VHMWeHIvw <ORGANIZATION>Missouri Legislature</ORGANIZATION> announces special session beginning on May 18 to consider disciplinary actions against Gov Gr https t co fTWqZPZSip The mystery of who had been leaving a daily pile of feces on a <LOCATION>New Jersey</LOCATION> high school s football field and track wa https t co FpSlZoOCzb The <ORGANIZATION>Arizona Legislature</ORGANIZATION> came to an agreement with the governor s office that provides the state s teachers with a c https t co nvY7ERGc8V <LOCATION>West Virginia</LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION>Senate GOP</ORGANIZATION> candidate <PERSON>Don Blankenship</PERSON> defends his use of <LOCATION>Chinaperson</LOCATION> during debate In order to hav https t co tFfwDzGq1E Sophia A Nelson When West a successful black man with a massive platform implied that slavery is a choice he https t co RpOWP3qABK Former talk show host and anchor <PERSON>Charlie Rose</PERSON> has been accused of sexual harassment by 27 women who worked with him https t co iYOWHGpxZN Twitter advised its 330 million users to change their passwords after some of them were accidentally stored in plai https t co OF54OxWg2B The <ORGANIZATION>Securities and Exchange Commission</ORGANIZATION> said it would seek a court order asking <PERSON>Shawn Carter</PERSON> also known as the rap https t co 3P24Eh5BaH Many distressing questions must still be answered about the motivations behind Father <PERSON>Conroy</PERSON> s unwarranted and unj https t co 8jnPGbPRZl Rapper <PERSON>Meek Mill</PERSON> was freed on bail from a <LOCATION>Pennsylvania</LOCATION> prison more than a week ago but says he continues to live i https t co a1UqjisPH7 Crying reverse racism and feminism the trolls lobbied for other entrants in the contest and encouraged their https t co dSNUcXbhNP Half of Americans over the age of 65 who are in a relationship are sexually active according to a new poll But no https t co VJQsz7NYBN WorldPressFreedomDay Read more Listen more Understand more Because a variety of information sources broadens https t co Gde3ZkaTKl <ORGANIZATION>Pentagon</ORGANIZATION> accuses Chinese of blinding <LOCATION>Djibouti</LOCATION> based <ORGANIZATION>U S</ORGANIZATION> pilots with lasers https t co ma2I9GurEs <PERSON>Steve Vladeck Trump</PERSON> tweeted that he can fire anyone including <PERSON>Robert Mueller</PERSON> Here s what the law actually says https t co T8LXBcykKs Did another advanced species exist on Earth before humans https t co MsXzqEn42e via NBCNewsMACH Speaker <PERSON>Paul Ryan</PERSON> reversed himself and said that the <PERSON>Rev Patrick Conroy</PERSON> the chaplain of the <ORGANIZATION>House of Representati</ORGANIZATION> https t co mFX9BBfcbY RT NBCLeftField What is <ORGANIZATION>ASMR</ORGANIZATION> and why is your brain tingling We asked the experts and the artists https t co ISRYd4RJvV https t UPDATE Speaker <PERSON>Ryan</PERSON> has accepted Father <PERSON>Conroy</PERSON> s letter and says he will remain in his position as <ORGANIZATION>House</ORGANIZATION> chaplain https t co 7CA2iDdlOH NBCNewsBETTER Are you guilty of bad travel etiquette These are the most annoying behaviors according to new su https t co BUcZBc1kyD The <ORGANIZATION>Arizona Legislature</ORGANIZATION> came to an agreement with the governor s office that provides the state s teachers with a c https t co nmy1tynCrD Correction 3 senior U S officials now dispute <ORGANIZATION>NBCNews</ORGANIZATION> report saying that the monitoring of <PERSON>Cohen</PERSON> s phones was https t co ZsKDr5OqUl <PERSON>Charlie Rose</PERSON> accused by 27 women of sexual harassment https t co voN2GBJDAn A man charged with threatening to shoot up gay clubs in <LOCATION>Chicago</LOCATION> is once again behind bars after being mistakenly re https t co ajqhpxa9CZ RT NBCNews JUST IN <ORGANIZATION>House</ORGANIZATION> chaplain rescinds resignation https t co Dyvjl8kgpa NBCNews has obtained the letter Father <PERSON>Pat Conroy</PERSON> sent Average levels of acceptance for LGBTQ people and their rights have increased globally since 1980 but acceptance h https t co P41Ax9PwSv Rapper <PERSON>Meek Mill</PERSON> was freed on bail from a <LOCATION>Pennsylvania</LOCATION> prison more than a week ago but says he continues to live i https t co LWBWeygb5h JUST IN <ORGANIZATION>House</ORGANIZATION> chaplain rescinds resignation https t co Dyvjl8kgpa NBCNews has obtained the letter Father <PERSON>Pat</PERSON> https t co XYEEv4OS2F One patient transported to hospital in critical condition <ORGANIZATION>Nashville Fire Dept</ORGANIZATION> says Photo <LOCATION>Nashville</LOCATION> FD https t co u79QIDy1Df UPDATE One person shot at <LOCATION>Nashville</LOCATION> mall police say Suspected shooter in custody per police No additiona https t co LzPiOdBTdg JUST IN <ORGANIZATION>ATF</ORGANIZATION> says it s responding to the scene of a shooting at <LOCATION>Opry Mills Mall</LOCATION> in <LOCATION>Nashville</LOCATION> DEVELOPING Police responding to security incident Opry <LOCATION>Mills Mall</LOCATION> in <LOCATION>Nashville Tennessee</LOCATION> Transgender anti discrimination bill set to become law in <LOCATION>New Hampshire</LOCATION> https t co dLFXt38vLa via NBCOUT Female Mariachis flourish as they follow in the footsteps of the Godmother https t co jzc1wo7whh via NBCLatino Campaign finance experts <PERSON>Trump Giuliani</PERSON> comments could backfire https t co PMxwRmOH71 <ORGANIZATION>Scott Lemieux Liberals</ORGANIZATION> must accept that beating <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> was never going to be easy or they ll lose to him again https t co sQRFFSCgXp The <ORGANIZATION>Academy of Motion Picture Arts and Sciences</ORGANIZATION> has voted to expel <PERSON>Bill Cosby</PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION>Roman Polanski</ORGANIZATION> from its membershi https t co 7hDOF8epCY Reporter How are the American people to trust or believe what is said here or what is said by the president Pr https t co l2pOyyX7zC Reporter Does the president believe he s above the law Press Sec Sanders No https t co 1C8nNSgSN4 Press <PERSON>Sec Sanders</PERSON> says the <ORGANIZATION>White House</ORGANIZATION> can t confirm the validity of reports about the release of 3 Americans fr https t co X5x1GIMu4j RT NBCNews Reporter When did you know that President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> repaid <PERSON>Michael Cohen</PERSON> the 130 000 Press Sec Sanders The first awareness RT <ORGANIZATION>MSNBC White House</ORGANIZATION> responds to shifting rationale for firing former <ORGANIZATION>FBI</ORGANIZATION> Director <ORGANIZATION>James Comey Bottom</ORGANIZATION> line is <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> doesn t have t This was information that the president didn t know at the time but eventually learned Press Sec <PERSON>Sarah Sanders</PERSON> https t co 7MHjVudSLJ Reporter When did you know that President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> repaid <PERSON>Michael Cohen</PERSON> the 130 000 Press Sec Sanders The first https t co n9y2aYaveR A Democratic congressman has proposed outlawing military style semiautomatic assault weapons and forcing existing https t co RuR9NMy1jx LIVE <ORGANIZATION>White House</ORGANIZATION> press briefing https t co NAMLKkvn9x NEW The <ORGANIZATION>Academy of Motion Picture Arts and Sciences</ORGANIZATION> board votes to expel <PERSON>Bill Cosby</PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION>Roman Polanski</ORGANIZATION> from its membership Snapchat s focus on the future is becoming a present day struggle https t co dR3jpo5nYE RT NBCNews NEW Exclusive Federal investigators have wiretapped the phone lines of <PERSON>Michael Cohen</PERSON> according to two people with knowledge <ORGANIZATION>SEC</ORGANIZATION> seeks court order to force <PERSON>Jay Z</PERSON> s testimony in <ORGANIZATION>Rocawear</ORGANIZATION> probe https t co hCAO2gfUVc https t co V9Dbv73SCh Two sources close to <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> s newest attorney <PERSON>Rudy Giuliani</PERSON> say he learned that days after the raid the president https t co VwJo5f891f At least one phone call between a phone line associated with <PERSON>Cohen</PERSON> and the <LOCATION>White House</LOCATION> was intercepted according t https t co viiF9Htlot https t co JvZA1nvHKC NEW Exclusive Federal investigators have wiretapped the phone lines of <PERSON>Michael Cohen</PERSON> according to two people wit https t co UW6AlGcOf2 How Asian American women are driving the growth of the skincare industry https t co In5FkkUAPY via <ORGANIZATION>NBCAsianAmerica RT</ORGANIZATION> NBCNewsMACH The transition to self driving cars may be bumpier than you think https t co y41WFrT6os https t co n9zHI1LVWP <PERSON>Bill Cosby</PERSON> s wife <PERSON>Camille</PERSON> issued a scathing statement against his accusers <LOCATION>Pennsylvania</LOCATION> prosecutors and the medi https t co JAC3eNqkHm U S military members conduct dignified transfer of service member killed in action https t co CvUpiivcM6 Scientists have developed a green concrete that they say is more environmentally friendly than the ordinary mater https t co L5R3vBv1S8 RT <ORGANIZATION>MSNBC</ORGANIZATION> On National Prayer Day President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> signs an executive order launching a faith based initiative at the <ORGANIZATION>White House</ORGANIZATION> https t Fugitive grandma <PERSON>Lois Ann Riess</PERSON> is a good lady with demons son says https t co n1Ww6O57rQ NBCNewsBETTER Want to climb the management ladder You ll need to work on honing effective communication skills https t co NIJfulB9oa LIVE President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> speaks at National Day of Prayer event https t co v9eRtm3b6l LIVE President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> participates in a National Day of Prayer event at the <LOCATION>White House</LOCATION> https t co v9eRtm3b6l Leftist candidate L pez Obrador still leads <LOCATION>Mexico</LOCATION> s presidential race amid losing momentum https t co zcZF2JpJUp via <ORGANIZATION>NBCLatino RT</ORGANIZATION> NBCNewsBETTER This is your brain on prayer and meditation NationalDayOfPrayer https t co ao1RQ0pWUc Why <PERSON>John Bolton</PERSON> could soon become the second most powerful man in <LOCATION>Washington</LOCATION> <PERSON>Jack Jacobs</PERSON> writes for NBCNewsTHINK https t co nMqmsI2vUq Elon Musk reprimands analysts for bonehead questions on <PERSON>Tesla</PERSON> s record losses https t co i9A5h73udh RT NBCNewsTHINK Black Americans do not abhor <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> because he is a Republican I am a Republican and I do not support <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> argues <ORGANIZATION>IA Iran</ORGANIZATION> s foreign minister warns no renegotiating nuclear deal as <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> decision looms https t co 1s67VeWgfi via NBCNewsWorld WorldPressFreedomDay Read more Listen more Understand more Because a variety of information sources broadens https t co RrrBkBHIQo RT NBCNewsBETTER Think you re cut out for management 5 questions to ask yourself if you want to be a manager https t co MsV2qkwNvY In today s NBCFirstRead Not only did <PERSON>Giuliani</PERSON> s disclosure contradict <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> s previous denial about the Stormy Da https t co GAVfJL0odc Authorities have reluctantly released police video from the deadliest mass shooting in modern U S history https t co ZS8oNxjyDi A group of <ORGANIZATION>House</ORGANIZATION> Republicans is seeking the Nobel Peace Prize for President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> because of his work to ease nucle https t co h5Vo2j7myC President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> s lawyer <PERSON>Rudy Giuliani</PERSON> We ve got <PERSON>Kim Jong</PERSON> Un impressed enough to release three prisoners today https t co rA6Adxc2eJ Severe dust storms have claimed the lives of at least 91 people in <LOCATION>India</LOCATION> https t co MK8qfvupE7 https t co vlNy6ay9P0 The former policeman accused of being the Golden State Killer heads back to court to fight prosecutors efforts to https t co QrEjfU0Psd A <LOCATION>Guantanamo Bay</LOCATION> prisoner has been transferred to his native <LOCATION>Saudi Arabia</LOCATION> where he will serve the rest of his 13 ye https t co urpCnbt77e President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> says no campaign funds were used to reimburse lawyer for payment to <PERSON>Stormy Daniels</PERSON> https t co XhsSO5oaKq President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> repaid his attorney <PERSON>Michael Cohen</PERSON> the 130 000 he paid <PERSON>Stormy Daniels Giuliani</PERSON> says https t co 3rMvPLh4L2 <LOCATION>Australia</LOCATION> s PM <PERSON>Malcolm Turnbull</PERSON> says his wife was flattered and charmed to be described by <LOCATION>France</LOCATION> s President Mac https t co 5OdAF32cAK Want to climb the ladder Ask yourself these important questions before you make a pitch for that promotion https t co T3KZVLql3y Be the first to know about important issues as they unfold across the world Sign up for NBCNews breaking news a https t co YXQOWImKac Chinese feminists are trying to stay one step ahead of censors as they push the country s fledgling MeToo movement https t co uZ6q5h62h1 President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> hints that three Americans detained in <LOCATION>North Korea</LOCATION> could soon be released https t co Jekayu4p58 President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> affirms <PERSON>Giuliani</PERSON> s claims in morning tweets says <PERSON>Cohen</PERSON> received a monthly retainer not from the https t co WZOYFTBNsh President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> repaid his attorney <PERSON>Michael Cohen</PERSON> the 130 000 he paid <PERSON>Stormy Daniels Giuliani</PERSON> says https t co phoN6FGlUQ As President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> addresses the <ORGANIZATION>NRA</ORGANIZATION> this week a leading gun safety group is looking to make an example out of sub https t co 1akBz6jB5p RT TODAYshow Today on TODAY What <PERSON>Rudy Giuliani</PERSON> s new admission means for President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> big changes for the Boy Scouts plus Tina Fe A powerful storm in <LOCATION>India</LOCATION> has left at least 91 people dead and more than 160 injured authorities say https t co 0VueNxlloI The two black men whose arrest at a <LOCATION>Philadelphia</LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION>Starbucks</ORGANIZATION> last month set off a wave of protests have reached a sym https t co QX7p85fd8m RT TheLastWord EXCLUSIVE MichaelAvenatti responds to <PERSON>Rudy Giuliani</PERSON> claiming <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> repaid <PERSON>Stormy Daniels</PERSON> hush money https t co d56nAQ <ORGANIZATION>Nine National Guard</ORGANIZATION> members aboard a decommissioned <ORGANIZATION>Puerto Rico National Guard</ORGANIZATION> cargo plane were killed when it cras https t co QKzZg09FED Opinion <PERSON>Jack Jacobs John Kelly</PERSON> s fall from grace is <PERSON>John Bolton</PERSON> s gain https t co aTmXbJCK0K NBCNewsTHINK Opinion <PERSON>Jeremy Bash</PERSON> Confirming <PERSON>Gina Haspel</PERSON> sends exactly the right signal to <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> https t co vk9HZlnze7 NBCNewsTHINK NEW As President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> addresses the <ORGANIZATION>NRA</ORGANIZATION> this week a leading gun safety group is looking to make an example out o https t co 8pg0XObmdI What s it like to be a 13 year old growing up in <LOCATION>Gaza</LOCATION> https t co ZlMy1QKnFD NBCLeftField NEW Powerful storm leaves at least 72 people dead and more than 100 injured in <LOCATION>India</LOCATION> officials say https t co 10hFOuMn6b President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> repaid his attorney <PERSON>Michael Cohen</PERSON> the 130 000 he paid Stormy Daniels <PERSON>Rudolph Giuliani</PERSON> says https t co <ORGANIZATION>F7lbbB98zc Cambridge Analytica</ORGANIZATION> and its parent company <ORGANIZATION>SCL</ORGANIZATION> are shutting down citing a siege of media coverage that drove awa https t co 3h7QRjjLuz Vacations aren t just about letting loose and having a good time they re actually necessary for your health https t co HcVRtdU2DB Opinion Kanye s historical revisionism isn t just ignorant it s dangerous https t co LebASzlRlT NBCNewsTHINK A new paper explains how we might go about looking for evidence of earlier civilizations https t co ehDk3wumvi NBCNewsMACH A far right mayor in <LOCATION>Hungary</LOCATION> is hailing the success of a new border fence saying it has protected the country from https t co I6EUA97QDt The 2018 Airplane and Hotel Etiquette Study has determined the five most annoying travel behaviors https t co bhC51C39Sr NBCNewsBETTER A right to die activist says a 104 year old Australian scientist is on his way to <LOCATION>Switzerland</LOCATION> to end his life throu https t co pNrYQnJgR8 Scientists in the U K have developed a green concrete that they say is more environmentally friendly as well as https t co UvrrtEOCQM Protesters blocked some routes into <LOCATION>Armenia</LOCATION> s capital and a road to the airport after an opposition lawmaker who le https t co <ORGANIZATION>0CiwUEj5Df Human Rights Watch</ORGANIZATION> is calling on politicians to reform a law surrounding gender identity so <LOCATION>Japan</LOCATION> can join the rank https t co <ORGANIZATION>BX2YdjFqeb Cambridge Analytica</ORGANIZATION> and its parent company <ORGANIZATION>SCL</ORGANIZATION> are shutting down citing a siege of media coverage that drove awa https t co Ol5gSl1UM5 <ORGANIZATION>San Francisco Board of Supervisors</ORGANIZATION> approved a resolution creating the Leather and LGBTQ Cultural District as a way https t co vznM88icVy As costs keep rising many experts are now advising some students to think hard about whether a four year degree is https t co 6pEXKEPDm6 The president s characterization of catch and release is misleading and while his administration vilifies asylum https t co g9cTd21JB4 Jurors recommended a sentence of 10 years for <PERSON>Jacob Scott Goodwin</PERSON> in the Aug 12 attack on <PERSON>DeAndre Harris</PERSON> Some of https t co qZajBMYznB The Iraqi journalist who threw his shoes at former President <PERSON>George W Bush</PERSON> is now hoping to be elected as a lawmak https t co ssYbHUQdj7 The issue nearly derailed a <ORGANIZATION>Washington City Council</ORGANIZATION> meeting and resulted in the resignation of a city official who https t co 4U6Crxbya4 Presidents have been subpoenaed before <PERSON>Thomas Jefferson</PERSON> for documents <PERSON>Richard Nixon</PERSON> for tapes and <PERSON>Bill Clinton</PERSON> f https t co 0R4qERDVsZ Sophia A Nelson Slavery was not a choice Let s be clear on this It was the most dehumanizing and destructive i https t co ZhSxq3iFIT New forms of concrete can trap and store the greenhouse gas carbon dioxide break down pollutants from exhaust fume https t co o7q2NCFonD MORE That money was not campaign money <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> lawyer <PERSON>Rudy Giuliani</PERSON> asserted https t co XhsSO5FLBY Archaeologists have unearthed tools and a rhino skeleton on the island of <LOCATION>Luzon</LOCATION> that may point to the existence of https t co v2F7mPUUhp BREAKING President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> reimbursed 130 000 Stormy Daniels payment <PERSON>Giuliani</PERSON> says https t co 1EUBlYPPCR Following several high profile pet related incidents <ORGANIZATION>United</ORGANIZATION> is tightening its cargo rules and banning some breed https t co 6gMdIxNQol NBCNewsBETTER Fellow travelers may be breaking the golden rule of treating others as they want to be treated bu https t co g5JJplAFZi Two Black men arrested at a <LOCATION>Philadelphia</LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION>Starbucks</ORGANIZATION> are settling with the city for 2 and the creation of a 200 000 https t co R01atAUgem Meet 2018 s emerging voices and rising stars as <ORGANIZATION>NBCAsianAmerica</ORGANIZATION> kicks off <ORGANIZATION>Asian Pacific American Heritage Month</ORGANIZATION> https t co Kb6lIhY6xT President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> said he was considering using his executive power to get involved in a document dispute between t https t co z5ghnsPPOr President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> has tapped a <PERSON>Clinton</PERSON> impeachment lawyer to assist in the <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> investigation after <PERSON>Ty Cobb</PERSON> who ha https t co vD66rk3IxV <PERSON>Karen Greenberg Haspel</PERSON> may be a <ORGANIZATION>CIA</ORGANIZATION> loyalist but her appointment is a slap in the face to the rule of law in the https t co 8rdt2ueJr0 This virtual reality experience lets someone view life through the eyes of a black man encountering racism as a chi https t co 69fVP9pv6l It s been 34 years since <PERSON>Ralph Macchio</PERSON> s <PERSON>Daniel</PERSON> kicked <PERSON>William Zabka</PERSON> s <PERSON>Johnny</PERSON> into submission in Karate Kid but https t co DYLeaf5YPE Watch as choreographed drones display Chinese characters in the sky to mark the May holiday https t co haQzoPkxjk <PERSON>Jacob Goodwin</PERSON> was found guilty in the malicious wounding of a counterprotester at the <LOCATION>Charlottesville</LOCATION> rally last ye https t co hTaJ4lgbjV At least 2 are dead after a military C 130 plane crashes near the <LOCATION>Savannah Georgia</LOCATION> airport A local county coroner https t co hUaqZsRQRF One person has died and 23 more people have been reported sick in an outbreak of E coli food poisoning linked to r https t co nI45B3toLb Authorities released the first installment of police video from the deadliest mass shooting in modern U S history https t co AsZHjr02N1 A majority of Americans overall 61 percent think President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> regularly has trouble telling the truth a new https t co l8QOvAugCc Technology originally developed for <ORGANIZATION>NASA</ORGANIZATION> has revealed letters invisible to the naked eye on fragments of the 2 000 https t co R8C8SK0ivY The caravan of migrants seeking asylum in the U S reached the border at the end of a grueling monthslong journey t https t co XDSmBYQLbG A group of <ORGANIZATION>House</ORGANIZATION> Republicans is seeking the Nobel Peace Prize for President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> because of his work to ease nucle https t co <ORGANIZATION>PQHewXemxu State Department</ORGANIZATION> spokesperson issues statement on <LOCATION>North Korea</LOCATION> Freedom Week We must not forget the millions of Nor https t co mdMEWNcgPA Officials give update on military C 130 plane crash near <LOCATION>Savannah</LOCATION> airport https t co as0fGRYH2O https t co NNK7ASagjz For 108 years the <ORGANIZATION>Boy Scouts of America</ORGANIZATION> s flagship program has been known simply as the Boy Scouts With girls soo https t co RtCFCS8oWE <LOCATION>Iowa</LOCATION> lawmakers fast tracked a bill that would ban most abortions once a fetal heartbeat is detected sending what c https t co GhkKESEpcC NBCNewsBETTER 5 simple exercises that will tone your butt for summer https t co mofaNrQSaJ <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> has quietly installed anti ship cruise missiles and surface to air missile systems on three of its fortified https t co Eb43hK3kFH Fact check President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> s misleading claims about catch and release https t co NhIKfuIjlp Two Black men arrested at <ORGANIZATION>Philadelphia Starbucks</ORGANIZATION> are settling with city for 2 and the creation of a 200 000 fund https t co CyhY67HoIT Alleged gay panic defense in <LOCATION>Texas</LOCATION> murder trial stuns advocates https t co IlYKKzPgCP via <ORGANIZATION>NBCOUT Chris Mohney Men</ORGANIZATION> wash your hands after using the bathroom https t co ds8taFNlM6 via NBCNewsTHINK WATCH <PERSON>Pompeo</PERSON> sworn in as Secretary of <ORGANIZATION>State</ORGANIZATION> as President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> expresses absolute confidence https t co UhSZU43WZG Over 50 caravan migrants seeking asylum have entered U S for processing organizers say https t co CoJ2PhSARy via <ORGANIZATION>NBCLatino U S Air Force</ORGANIZATION> We are saddened by the tragic news of an <ORGANIZATION>Air National Guard</ORGANIZATION> C 130 crash earlier today Our thought https t co V3xVgAQ2mT This virtual reality experience puts you in someone else s shoes to experience life as a different race or gender https t co Eafrna1Wu6 1 person has died and 23 more people have been reported sick in an E coli outbreak linked to romaine lettuce fede https t co pBEZJHwwUk Be the first to know about important issues as they unfold across the world Sign up for NBCNews breaking news a https t co cnYNQ20j5M President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> says he s been briefed on the <ORGANIZATION>Puerto Rico National Guard</ORGANIZATION> C 130 crash Please join me in thoughts https t co y2MLXfTpjc When presidents have been subpoenaed here s what they ve done https t co jdr8QlEJl0 The sibling supermassive black holes are thought to come about as galaxies bump into one another and coalesce to https t co teGmYYgFuf An Iraqi journalist who made headlines worldwide after throwing his shoes at President <PERSON>George W Bush</PERSON> is now hoping https t co MnQyL03xLz French President <PERSON>Macron</PERSON> thanks Australian PM s delicious wife https t co 9bJas0MdF8 via NBCNewsWorld A spiraling controversy over anti Semitic comments and conspiracy theories has roiled the D C city government see https t co kqJmSLp2Aw Scientists have developed a green concrete that they say is more environmentally friendly than the ordinary mater https t co <ORGANIZATION>YEz6lFiuNs Cambridge Analytica</ORGANIZATION> and its parent company <ORGANIZATION>SCL</ORGANIZATION> are shutting down operations https t co WPZ4n5pbf9 The <ORGANIZATION>Pentagon</ORGANIZATION> has ordered stores at U S military bases to stop selling two brands of Chinese made cellphones and mo https t co uHeG5Nqurv NEW Emmet Flood to join <ORGANIZATION>White House</ORGANIZATION> staff to represent the President and the administration against the <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> wi https t co QDklA2BGMw <ORGANIZATION>NEW Cambridge Analytica</ORGANIZATION> is immediately ceasing all operations following <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> data controversy company says A cracked window on a <ORGANIZATION>Southwest Airlines</ORGANIZATION> plane forced an emergency landing in <LOCATION>Cleveland</LOCATION> just two weeks after a jet https t co rehzClyKIT Following a series of pet deaths and shipping mishaps <ORGANIZATION>United Airlines</ORGANIZATION> has issued revised policies for its PetSafe https t co mIXDVRfA7m 18 lawmakers nominate President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> for Nobel Peace Prize We can think of no one more deserving of the Committ https t co zE7UWLaPLq Two Black men arrested at <ORGANIZATION>Philadelphia Starbucks</ORGANIZATION> are settling with city for 2 and the creation of a 200 000 fund https t co XwnfDmfRCS RT NBCNewsMACH This green concrete could be game changer for construction industry https t co vPYeaOwXTr https t co gibZtan5Dk President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> flexes executive power says he may get involved in <ORGANIZATION>DOJ</ORGANIZATION> document dispute https t co LWCkeD18RM https t co 6R0J7I5kBp <PERSON>Jeremy Bash</PERSON> Confirming <PERSON>Gina Haspel</PERSON> as <ORGANIZATION>CIA</ORGANIZATION> director would send exactly the right signal to both the intelligence co https t co iW369e8c9q JUST IN 2 people dead in <LOCATION>Puerto Rico</LOCATION> National Guard C 130 crash coroner s office says https t co GTWYbHiaqj LATEST Ty Cobb President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> s main lawyer in <PERSON>Mueller</PERSON> investigation to retire https t co yhRref8BaZ C 130 that crashed in <LOCATION>Savannah Georgia</LOCATION> is a <ORGANIZATION>Puerto Rico National Guard</ORGANIZATION> aircraft officials say 5 people were on b https t co cjwlMtnsC4 LATEST Military C 130 plane crashes near airport in <LOCATION>Savannah Georgia</LOCATION> https t co as0fGRH6bg https t co 93RT3uLWEs For several weeks <PERSON>Ty Cobb</PERSON> has been discussing his retirement and last week he let Chief of Staff <PERSON>Kelly</PERSON> know he wou https t co B0XUDwNQvg JUST IN <PERSON>Ty Cobb</PERSON> is leaving President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> s legal team <ORGANIZATION>Press Sec Sanders</ORGANIZATION> says NBCNewsBETTER Alcohol changes the balance of bacteria in your mouth And that could leave you predisposed to dis https t co AtPsKsEqg8 DEVELOPING An <ORGANIZATION>Air National Guard</ORGANIZATION> C 130 has crashed in <ORGANIZATION>Savannah Georgia Air Force</ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION>Georgia National Guard</ORGANIZATION> say https t co PEOoalsm2S https t co QXh67r8vLS DEVELOPING Military plane crashes in <LOCATION>Savannah Georgia</LOCATION> airport officials say Photo IAFF574 <LOCATION>Savannah</LOCATION> https t co Oha3JLIfpY Technology originally developed for <ORGANIZATION>NASA</ORGANIZATION> has revealed letters invisible to the naked eye on fragments of the 2 000 https t co 8wryoOWDKB RT NBCNewsTHINK Democrats and progressive organizations should be encouraged that a nonpartisan professional woman has been nominated to NBCNewsBETTER Are you guilty of bad travel etiquette These are the most annoying behaviors according to new su https t co Vng8wPYHW6 WATCH Secretary of State <PERSON>Pompeo</PERSON> takes oath of office administered by VP Pence https t co vN87hbfxoH Forced surgery sterilization <LOCATION>Japan</LOCATION> s trans community faces uphill battle https t co yfB89lMv2x via <ORGANIZATION>NBCOUT</ORGANIZATION> LIVE President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> participates in swearing in ceremony of Secretary of State <PERSON>Pompeo</PERSON> https t co RxK6haQu4E For 108 years the <ORGANIZATION>Boy Scouts of America</ORGANIZATION> s flagship program has been known simply as the Boy Scouts With girls soo https t co QDz9pCcY7I RT NBCLeftField <PERSON>Jacob Goodwin</PERSON> was found guilty in the malicious wounding of a counterprotester at the <LOCATION>Charlottesville</LOCATION> rally last year ht <PERSON>Jacob Scott Goodwin</PERSON> s parents <PERSON>Tamera</PERSON> and <PERSON>Scott Goodwin</PERSON> were subjects of a NBCLeftField documentary published las https t co tjYCypiLcI NBCNewsBETTER Real Housewives star on what it means to be an accountability coach saying no to fries and to https t co PWFZbggf7B A white man who prosecutors say came for battle when he took part in the brutal beating of a black man during las https t co bnVGy9hzAP Republican lawmakers with control of <LOCATION>Iowa</LOCATION> statehouse fast tracked bill that would ban most abortions once fetal hea https t co je48wIertI Former President <PERSON>George H W Bush</PERSON> will remain in the hospital today as he continues to regain strength spokesperso https t co nECv0XVYkt RT NBCNewsBETTER The most annoying people you ll encounter on a flight and how to handle them https t co wpVi8290KF In today s NBCFirstRead If you re a vulnerable red state Democratic senator up for re election this year Republi https t co YDuib7MFrl Dr <PERSON>Harold Bornstein</PERSON> tells <ORGANIZATION>NBC News</ORGANIZATION> that he felt raped frightened and sad when <PERSON>Keith Schiller</PERSON> and another large https t co lBBONZq8MQ Authorities are hunting for a paroled sex offender who led them on an hours long chase through <LOCATION>California</LOCATION> in a moto https t co 5tzfn0Ak3o An Iraqi journalist who made headlines worldwide in 2008 after throwing his shoes at President <PERSON>George W Bush</PERSON> is no https t co oqrM7rkrxX <PERSON>Mueller</PERSON> raised the prospect of subpoenaing President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> in March to answer questions in his investigation of all https t co La0oUieZn4 RT NBCNewsPictures Month in Space Pictures Falling stars and rising rockets https t co YWR4B4ROG6 nasa https t co WwKvaGyRB9 NEW Traumatized survivors of <ORGANIZATION>Waffle House</ORGANIZATION> shooting begin the long process towards healing https t co Wb0sngNE8i <ORGANIZATION>Michigan State University</ORGANIZATION> admits that it knew about accusations of impropriety against <PERSON>Larry Nassar</PERSON> s boss in 2015 https t co 5pTtD6GlHr The American Values Atlas has found a big increase in support for LGBTQ issues across all races and ethnicities and https t co K2MvXcQKSK RT NBCLeftField DOGS In slow motion Because sometimes you just need to see a cute puppy to get through the day https t co JmT2Jg7 Deputy Attorney General <PERSON>Rosenstein</PERSON> says that the <ORGANIZATION>Justice Department</ORGANIZATION> is not going to be extorted as some <ORGANIZATION>House</ORGANIZATION> Rep https t co TEAGW5mtYR <PERSON>Daniel Nyikos</PERSON> 33 says the lessons of the collapse of Communism and the fall of the <LOCATION>Berlin Wall</LOCATION> appear to have bee https t co XaDhH5QLTJ Be the first to know about important issues as they unfold across the world Sign up for NBCNews breaking news a https t co hOMdZY8mvQ U S intelligence officials say that nothing from documents that <PERSON>Netanyhu</PERSON> says were smuggled out of <LOCATION>Tehran</LOCATION> has caus https t co 4FUhPU5Tju We are all people and this barrier is just horrible to refugees It has just pushed the problem to other places li https t co axFG9nHKJ1 When you hear about slavery for 400 years For 400 years That sounds like a choice <PERSON>Kanye West</PERSON> said in an interv https t co wIr92RYVYz <LOCATION>Hungary</LOCATION> s handling of migrants has been heavily criticized in a report by the <ORGANIZATION>Council of Europe</ORGANIZATION> the continent s ma https t co EvuvLApk4p At least eight people were arrested and a number of people were injured including fifteen police officers during https t co ACNmgKV3hu An estimated 3 600 migrants are sleeping in forests or abandoned buildings and trying to cross into <LOCATION>Hungary</LOCATION> illegal https t co KKdnbOCorJ Most Republicans who think President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> is loose with the truth still approve of the job he s doing as president https t co NquOxcU516 More than 400 people mostly families are waiting at 11 reception shelters run by <LOCATION>Serbia</LOCATION> s official <ORGANIZATION>Commissariat</ORGANIZATION> f https t co GnNNU1by2C RT TODAYshow Today on TODAY Will President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> be forced to testify in <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> investigation Plus a special surprise for a remarkab While his siblings and parents stay at an official shelter farther south of the <LOCATION>Serbia Hungary</LOCATION> border <PERSON>Rohollah Moh</PERSON> https t co f2X90o4tJY <PERSON>Mueller</PERSON> raised the prospect of subpoenaing President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> in March to answer questions in his investigation of all https t co <PERSON>WWmuiTKNAR Rohollah Mohammadi</PERSON> and his family fled to <LOCATION>Europe</LOCATION> after facing deportation from <LOCATION>Iran</LOCATION> to their native <LOCATION>Afghanistan</LOCATION> https t co Wk7q6lo1fV <ORGANIZATION>Michigan State University</ORGANIZATION> admits that it knew about accusations of impropriety against <PERSON>Larry Nassar</PERSON> s boss in 2015 https t co n9aH5G9Tfl Technology originally developed for <ORGANIZATION>NASA</ORGANIZATION> has revealed letters invisible to the naked eye on fragments of the 2 000 https t co u1iwNKzM5I Crossing into <LOCATION>Hungary</LOCATION> from <LOCATION>Serbia</LOCATION> represents the last major hurdle for thousands on their way to prosperous countri https t co I4M7kBR1JA L szl Toroczkai Mayor of sotthalom in <LOCATION>Hungary</LOCATION> believes President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> should be encouraged by the success of t https t co zeabbwsCT6 A far right mayor in <LOCATION>Hungary</LOCATION> is hailing the success of a new border fence saying it has protected the country from https t co Y2rkUCarT0 Opinion <PERSON>Jillian York</PERSON> Without viable alternatives deleting <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> is a privilege https t co dvCTSEzHL8 NBCNewsTHINK Most Republicans who think President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> is loose with the truth still approve of the job he s doing as president https t co KIhyoH6dBF <LOCATION>Kanye West</LOCATION> in an interview on Tuesday described slavery as a choice and attributed his 2016 mental breakdown to o https t co 8WB3f54BNN Local police departments are turning to private training organizations that specialize in military combat technique https t co YGwqhXnDMx Whether you are going through a job loss or divorce this practice of fixing broken things may help heal what s bro https t co WCb6elHIPq Protesters block routes into <LOCATION>Armenia</LOCATION> s capital and the road to the airport after an opposition lawmaker who led we https t co CWY18nBLV6 New paper explains how we might go about looking for evidence of earlier civilizations https t co 8mHBFtcWyD NBCNewsMACH <LOCATION>Israel</LOCATION> seems to be preparing for war with <LOCATION>Iran</LOCATION> U S officials say https t co X4REhjSCHh A simple way to reduce how much you spend on gas is to shop around for the best price something most motorists don https t co bcb0xLHE2A Opinion <PERSON>Franklin Graham</PERSON> My father avoided scandal by never being alone with women https t co dfNfAOrF4s NBCNewsTHINK This proposed tower might sound like something from the distant future but it s intended to address a problem of t https t co TlrdQCK2QY The most senior <LOCATION>Vatican</LOCATION> official to be charged in the <ORGANIZATION>Catholic Church</ORGANIZATION> sex abuse crisis will stand trial Cardinal https t co XnGMsNMfKg WATCH <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> CEO <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> says new features will give users greater control over how their data is shared https t co qeYIb4f4yR Cond Nast is not has never been and will not be for sale As rumors swirled that tech giant <ORGANIZATION>Apple</ORGANIZATION> is readyin https t co tdoFEr4u2Z Grandmaster <PERSON>Jhoon Rhee</PERSON> the man known as the father of American <PERSON>Taekwondo</PERSON> died after a long illness He was 86 https t co JR5o414czm WATCH Thousands of Puerto Ricans took to the streets in a May Day march to protest school closures and austerity m https t co VfGJucXCIw Organizers of the caravan of migrants seeking asylum in the <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> said that the <ORGANIZATION>Department of Justice</ORGANIZATION> s ann https t co HwpUwZt4Am <ORGANIZATION>Michigan State University</ORGANIZATION> plunged into turmoil by the <PERSON>Larry Nassar</PERSON> sex abuse scandal admitted that it knew about https t co kmTDWpINmz The three U S officials said <LOCATION>Israel</LOCATION> now seems to be preparing for military action and is seeking U S help and sup https t co qcBVH5XgH9 Doctors are puzzling over dozens of cases mostly women in their 20s and 30s of a rare eye cancer in two Souther https t co OnhMrrhAv6 Large crowds gathered in cities across the globe to demonstrate in support of workers rights https t co uUpIh3jFp5 Support for same sex relationships is rising sharply among all major ethnic and racial groups and most religious gr https t co <ORGANIZATION>SbV5xJYVh4 Facebook</ORGANIZATION> has fired a security engineer who allegedly took advantage of his position to access information he then u https t co NshHO0xFU5 <PERSON>Tina Fey</PERSON> s high school morality tale Mean Girls and the goofy undersea cartoon SpongeBob SquarePants lead the T https t co fWvUiXNVGA Pulse survivor says he is no longer gay has found <PERSON>Christ</PERSON> https t co 90vrkugnZn via <ORGANIZATION>NBCOUT Facebook</ORGANIZATION> plans to launch a new dating feature CEO <PERSON>Mark Zuckerberg</PERSON> wants the tool to help users build meaningful https t co dVE5enffHi Police are now turning to private training organizations that specialize in military combat techniques These group https t co <ORGANIZATION>0nGMafLvEn Facebook</ORGANIZATION> said that it will soon allow users to wipe their browsing histories from the platform and prevent the comp https t co WSSWm2wHUe RT NBCNewsPictures Photos Workers activists mark May Day with defiant rallies https t co 0pKIhc3egR GettyImages AP_Images reutersp Deputy Attorney General <PERSON>Rod Rosenstein</PERSON> said that the <ORGANIZATION>Justice Department</ORGANIZATION> is not going to be extorted as some <ORGANIZATION>House</ORGANIZATION> https t co vevb51kco6 A father whose daughter was killed in the Feb 14 mass shooting in <LOCATION>Parkland Florida</LOCATION> has filed a wrongful death la https t co CETQOOV15L Dr <PERSON>Harold Bornstein</PERSON> said he was not given a form authorizing the release of the records and signed by the presiden https t co hXgGzsRFbb New research shows the Milky Way and galaxies like it may contain several supermassive black holes Read more at https t co GHHKOQsW2a <ORGANIZATION>United Airlines</ORGANIZATION> is scaling back its animal transportation program after several pet deaths and mix ups via <ORGANIZATION>CNBC</ORGANIZATION> https t co ozRI0TYniC Researchers at <ORGANIZATION>Boston University</ORGANIZATION> found a strong connection between the age at which athletes begin to play football https t co vwxPw0J8VI <PERSON>Noah Berlatsky Sherlock Holmes</PERSON> isn t the only focus of Elementary That s why it s so good https t co hJlD14tXg2 via <ORGANIZATION>NBCNewsTHINK Special</ORGANIZATION> counsel <PERSON>Robert Mueller</PERSON> raised the prospect of subpoenaing President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> last month to answer questions in https t co uIMtdf9Vu6 <PERSON>Sabrina Vega</PERSON> filed a lawsuit against coaches <PERSON>Bela</PERSON> and <PERSON>Martha Karolyi</PERSON> saying they should have known she was being s https t co sonAeIoptI NBCNewsBETTER Prices at the pump are going up but these everyday behaviors are also costing you money Here s a https t co yuLGE2o9pT Meet 2018 s emerging voices and rising stars as <ORGANIZATION>NBCAsianAmerica</ORGANIZATION> kicks off <ORGANIZATION>Asian Pacific American Heritage Month</ORGANIZATION> https t co eBfVzhU7S9 The <ORGANIZATION>Time</ORGANIZATION> s Up campaign is taking aim at R <PERSON>Kelly</PERSON> over allegations he has sexually abused women https t co FHeVlwAMUj Seventeen states and the <LOCATION>District of Columbia</LOCATION> are going to court to protect fuel efficiency and greenhouse gas redu https t co KozgpAH8Tp Support for same sex relationships is rising sharply among all major ethnic and racial groups and most religious gr https t co BBTMxqwqKA Some protesters threw rocks and other objects toward police and there were reports of vandalism Officers threw tea https t co IKFuAhRVES We ll be ready to go back by Thursday <ORGANIZATION>Arizona Educators United</ORGANIZATION> organizer and teacher <PERSON>Noah Karvelis</PERSON> says teachers https t co TsfRoLmeSf Dr <PERSON>Harold Bornstein</PERSON> tells NBCNews that a 2015 letter released under his name which described then candidate <PERSON>Trum</PERSON> https t co pvL2Sf0Hsu Two top aides have resigned from the <ORGANIZATION>Environmental Protection Agency</ORGANIZATION> amid a growing series of federal ethics invest https t co XLFH5NghvD In an upcoming memoir Senator <PERSON>John McCain</PERSON> reveals that he is serving his last term in the <ORGANIZATION>Senate</ORGANIZATION> He also opens up https t co TuadE55rA5 Synthetic opioids like fentanyl have overtaken prescription painkillers as the most common drug involved in fatal o https t co BEAdY8CGtE Migrants at the Mexican border celebrate after eight people were allowed to enter the U S https t co 9kDURkM5Ax https t co wKHl5LyLQS Researchers hope to learn why some escape illness and others don t and better customize ways to prevent and treat https t co OB1zah19MZ More and more Americans are being infected with diseases carried by ticks and mosquitoes federal researchers repor https t co OPmgyHIhMe My father would not ride in an automobile with a woman other than my mother to protect my mother and more impor https t co KlmQsEqUrN I m honored to have you here Vice President <PERSON>Mike Pence</PERSON> recognizes ex sheriff <PERSON>Joe Arpaio</PERSON> during a tax policy ev https t co oZODUuhzYn Pulse survivor says he is no longer gay has found <PERSON>Christ</PERSON> https t co HT5oqmSHTI via NBCOUT NBCNewsBETTER The Real Housewives of <LOCATION>Beverly Hills</LOCATION> star <PERSON>Teddi Mellencamp</PERSON> talks about her weight loss journey https t co 1LsA8hRscu This robot can help assemble your Ikea furniture https t co WZg4Y38T6L via NBCNewsMACH https t co OururmBFG4 <LOCATION>Hollywood</LOCATION> brands like Mean Girls and Spongebob dominate <PERSON>Tony</PERSON> nominations https t co AUpAPYRQV6 Cardinal <PERSON>George Pell</PERSON> to face trial on sexual abuse charges in <LOCATION>Australia</LOCATION> https t co T4R2N8QQpM via NBCNewsWorld <PERSON>Noah Berlatsky Sherlock Holmes</PERSON> isn t the only focus of Elementary That s why it s so good https t co 150gs581SS via <ORGANIZATION>NBCNewsTHINK Facebook</ORGANIZATION> investigating claim engineer used access to stalk women https t co eMgnbauSsx WATCH Thousands join May Day marches around the world https t co wtE8fvZ4QM Protesters clash with police in <LOCATION>Puerto Rico</LOCATION> https t co Q7WSwiJiXf WATCH <PERSON>Pompeo</PERSON> addresses department on first day as Secretary of <ORGANIZATION>State</ORGANIZATION> https t co <ORGANIZATION>UOlXj4HOC4 Conde Nast</ORGANIZATION> denies rumors it is being purchased by <ORGANIZATION>Apple</ORGANIZATION> https t co ISjBos4YxH Deputy <PERSON>AG Rosenstein</PERSON> says that the <ORGANIZATION>Justice Department</ORGANIZATION> is not going to be extorted as some <ORGANIZATION>House</ORGANIZATION> Republicans raise https t co MaUh9C5efe RT NBCNewsWorld GALLERY Slain photographer s portraits of war torn <LOCATION>Afghanistan</LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION>AFP</ORGANIZATION> photographer <PERSON>Shah Marai</PERSON> was one of nine journalists A popular <LOCATION>Toronto</LOCATION> restaurant has been fined 10 000 for a case of racial profiling that was deemed a violation of O https t co KxyYbN1oJR Synthetic opioids like fentanyl have overtaken prescription painkillers as the most common drug involved in fatal o https t co uhdb5D37Xw <PERSON>Chris Mohney</PERSON> Men wash your hands after using the bathroom https t co ELUdEkEFVG via <ORGANIZATION>NBCNewsTHINK Elite</ORGANIZATION> gymnast <PERSON>Sabrina Vega</PERSON> files suit against the <ORGANIZATION>Karolyis</ORGANIZATION> https t co uKdfyF6HAz <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> doc says <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> bodyguard lawyer raided his office took medical files https t co Zkma42QqUe Organizers of the caravan of migrants seeking asylum in the U S say that the <ORGANIZATION>Dept of Justice</ORGANIZATION> s announcement that https t co HzH0zd24ne 17 states and D C are going to court to protect fuel efficiency and greenhouse gas reduction standards that were a https t co hdRj1kNxdg The sibling supermassive black holes are thought to come about as galaxies bump into one another and coalesce to https t co zv3jbuE8nI <LOCATION>Scotland</LOCATION> tackles alcohol crisis with minimum price law https t co BpaXdmy68G via <ORGANIZATION>NBCNewsWorld</ORGANIZATION> Grandmaster <PERSON>Jhoon Rhee</PERSON> the man known as the father of <ORGANIZATION>American Taekwondo</ORGANIZATION> has died after a long illness He was https t co 7Z1PygSKI9 More and more Americans are being infected with diseases carried by ticks and mosquitoes federal researchers repor https t co E3saUOz8Fp The federal government wants 1 000 000 people for a giant health study https t co tbs6IikK6V RT NBCLeftField Mass shootings are claiming more lives than ever before So local police departments are turning to private training orga RT NBCNewsTHINK The number of men who secretly don t wash their hands after using the bathroom would horrify you says chrismohney https HallieJackson Why did <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> s bodyguard take medical records from <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> s personal doctor <ORGANIZATION>Press Sec Sanders</ORGANIZATION> https t co DnsO8Z2pQS LIVE <ORGANIZATION>White House</ORGANIZATION> press briefing https t co 7bY3wLoAVz <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> plans to launch a new dating feature for meaningful long term relationships https t co ApMApatt7N https t co zNni3tooex NEW President <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> says location and date of <LOCATION>North Korea</LOCATION> summit is probably going to be announced over the next https t co pVig7KhqYE <ORGANIZATION>WATCH Facebook</ORGANIZATION> unveils new online dating feature https t co BeMzaBgbEq <LOCATION>Pennsylvania</LOCATION> s top prosecutor announces he is appealing to have 5 former members of a now disbanded <ORGANIZATION>Penn State Univ</ORGANIZATION> https t co rSjv06lJsa <PERSON>Franklin Graham</PERSON> My father <PERSON>Billy Graham</PERSON> avoided scandal by being transparent and never alone with women https t co B5ZA9Jz1d4 2 top aides have resigned from the <ORGANIZATION>EPA</ORGANIZATION> amid a growing series of federal ethics investigations <ORGANIZATION>EPA</ORGANIZATION> chief <PERSON>Pruitt</PERSON> ann https t co 82C22ZUOsL RT NBCPolitics Secretary <PERSON>Pompeo</PERSON> talks about <ORGANIZATION>State Department</ORGANIZATION> getting its swagger back during first address to department staff https NBCNewsBETTER Gasoline prices keep creeping up Here s how to save more at the pump https t co 6BE1rc2Utc RT NBCNewsTHINK While <PERSON>Trump</PERSON> may not send troops into orbit for his Space Force he s unlikely to commit to maintaining a peace in the h In a major policy change <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> says it will soon allow users to flush their personal browsing histories what https t co cmUCMA23Il UPDATE <ORGANIZATION>Federal Protective Service</ORGANIZATION> responded and cleared the room <ORGANIZATION>EPA</ORGANIZATION> official says all 