<ner>image EconPapers image Economics at your fingertips EconPapers Home About EconPapers Working Papers Journal Articles Books and Chapters Software Components Authors JEL codes New Economics Papers Advanced Search EconPapers FAQ Archive maintainers FAQ Cookies at EconPapers Format for printing The RePEc blog The RePEc plagiarism page image Improving Customer Complaint Management by Automatic Email Classification Using Linguistic Style Features as Predictors <PERSON>Kristof Coussement</PERSON> and <PERSON>Dirk Van</PERSON> den Poel Working Papers of <ORGANIZATION>Faculty of Economics and Business Administration Ghent University</ORGANIZATION> <LOCATION>Belgium</LOCATION> from <ORGANIZATION>Ghent University Faculty of Economics and Business Administration Abstract Customer</ORGANIZATION> complaint management is becoming a critical key success factor in today s business environment This study introduces a methodology to improve complaint handling strategies through an automatic email classification system that distinguishes complaints from non complaints As such complaint handling becomes less time consuming and more successful The classification system combines traditional text information with new information about the linguistic style of an email The empirical results show that adding linguistic style information into a classification model with conventional text classification variables results in a significant increase in predictive performance In addition this study reveals linguistic style differences between complaint emails and others <ORGANIZATION>Keywords Customer Complaint Handling Call Center Email Voice of Customers VOC</ORGANIZATION> Singular Value Decomposition SVD Latent Semantic Indexing <ORGANIZATION>LSI</ORGANIZATION> Automatic Email Classification search for similar items in EconPapers New Economics Papers this item is included in nep ict and nep mkt Date 2007 09 References Add references at CitEc Citations View citations in EconPapers 3 Track citations by RSS feed Downloads external link http wps feb ugent be Papers wp_07_481 pdf application pdf Related works This item may be available elsewhere in EconPapers Search for items with the same title Export reference BibTeX RIS EndNote ProCite RefMan HTML Text Persistent link https EconPapers repec org RePEc rug rugwps 07 481 Access Statistics for this paper More papers in Working Papers of <ORGANIZATION>Faculty of Economics and Business Administration Ghent University</ORGANIZATION> <LOCATION>Belgium</LOCATION> from <ORGANIZATION>Ghent University Faculty of Economics and Business Administration Contact</ORGANIZATION> information at EDIRC Bibliographic data for series maintained by <PERSON>Nathalie Verhaeghe</PERSON> Share image RePEc This site is part of RePEc and all the data displayed here is part of the RePEc data set Is your work missing from RePEc Here is how to contribute Questions or problems Check the EconPapers FAQ or send mail to image rebro University EconPapers is hosted by the rebro <ORGANIZATION>University School of Business Page</ORGANIZATION> updated 2018 03 30 Handle RePEc rug rugwps 07 481</ner>
