<ner>Home Contact Us Sponsors Login LIBER Intranet Header menu <ORGANIZATION>WebsiteLinkedinRssTwitterFacebook Scholarly Communication Digital Skills amp Services Research Infrastructure Events</ORGANIZATION> image image About Us Network Strategy Activities Join Login image image image Login image Join a Forum image Join a Group image Jobs image image Update Profile image Chat to Members image About Us Governance amp <ORGANIZATION>Structure Mission amp Values History Executive Board Executive Board Meeting Minutes Executive Board Members Conference Programme Committee Office Staff Office Staff Activities International Projects AARC</ORGANIZATION> EOSCpilot EUDAT FOSTER Plus HuMetricsHSS OpenAIRE2020 OpenMinTed Completed Projects Leadership amp Skills Building Emerging Leaders Programme Testimonials Live s 2013 2014 Leadership Seminar Experience <PERSON>Corinne Hendrik</PERSON> amp <PERSON>Stefan</PERSON> s Leadership Seminar Experience LIBER Journ es for <ORGANIZATION>Library Directors International Alignment amp Coordination Network Strategy Strategy 2018 2022 Strategic Directions Innovative Scholarly Communication Steering Committee for Innovative Scholarly Communication Digital Skills amp Services Steering Committee for Digital Skills amp Services Research Infrastructure Steering Committee for Research Infrastructure</ORGANIZATION> Working Groups Architecture Members of the Architecture Group Freiburg 2016 18th Seminar <LOCATION>Helsinki</LOCATION> 2014 17th Seminar Prague 2012 16th Seminar Madrid 2010 15th Seminar <LOCATION>Budapest</LOCATION> amp <PERSON>Debrecen</PERSON> 14th Seminar Utrecht amp Gent 13th Seminar <LOCATION>Bolzano</LOCATION> amp <LOCATION>Venice</LOCATION> 2004 12th Seminar Leipzig 2002 11th Seminar <LOCATION>Warsaw</LOCATION> 2000 10th Seminar Copyright amp Legal Matters Members of the <ORGANIZATION>Copyright amp Legal Matters Working Group Digital Humanities amp Digital Cultural Heritage Members of the Digital Humanities amp Digital Cultural Heritage Working Group Digital Skills Members of the Digital Skills Working Group Innovative Metrics Members of the Metrics Working Group Leadership Programmes Members</ORGANIZATION> of the Leadership Programmes Working Group Open Access Members of the <ORGANIZATION>Open Access Working Group Research Data Management Members of the Research Data Management Working Group</ORGANIZATION> Previous Strategies 2013 2017 Reshaping The <ORGANIZATION>Research Library Working Group on Digital Collections Working Group on Leadership and Workforce Development Working Group on Research and Education Advocacy and Communications Steering Committee Working Group on Copyright Working Group</ORGANIZATION> on <ORGANIZATION>Open Access Scholarly Communication amp Research Infrastructures Working Group on Metrics Working Group on Scientific Information Infrastructures</ORGANIZATION> 2010 2012 News News Resources Webinars Quarterly Mailings LIBER Quarterly Journal Join LIBER Benefits of Joining Application Form Annual Contribution Fees List of <ORGANIZATION>LIBER Libraries Scholarly Communication Digital Skills amp Services Research Infrastructure Events</ORGANIZATION> LIBER Annual Conference Emerging Leaders Programme Journ es Programme for Library Directors Events Calendar image image image About Us Governance amp <ORGANIZATION>Structure Mission amp Values History Executive Board Executive Board Meeting Minutes Executive Board Members Conference Programme Committee Office Staff Office Staff Activities International Projects AARC</ORGANIZATION> EOSCpilot EUDAT FOSTER Plus HuMetricsHSS OpenAIRE2020 OpenMinTed Completed Projects Leadership amp Skills Building Emerging Leaders Programme Testimonials Live s 2013 2014 Leadership Seminar Experience <PERSON>Corinne Hendrik</PERSON> amp <PERSON>Stefan</PERSON> s Leadership Seminar Experience LIBER Journ es for <ORGANIZATION>Library Directors International Alignment amp Coordination Network Strategy Strategy 2018 2022 Strategic Directions Innovative Scholarly Communication Steering Committee for Innovative Scholarly Communication Digital Skills amp Services Steering Committee for Digital Skills amp Services Research Infrastructure Steering Committee for Research Infrastructure</ORGANIZATION> Working Groups Architecture Members of the Architecture Group Freiburg 2016 18th Seminar <LOCATION>Helsinki</LOCATION> 2014 17th Seminar Prague 2012 16th Seminar Madrid 2010 15th Seminar <LOCATION>Budapest</LOCATION> amp <PERSON>Debrecen</PERSON> 14th Seminar Utrecht amp Gent 13th Seminar <LOCATION>Bolzano</LOCATION> amp <LOCATION>Venice</LOCATION> 2004 12th Seminar Leipzig 2002 11th Seminar <LOCATION>Warsaw</LOCATION> 2000 10th Seminar Copyright amp Legal Matters Members of the <ORGANIZATION>Copyright amp Legal Matters Working Group Digital Humanities amp Digital Cultural Heritage Members of the Digital Humanities amp Digital Cultural Heritage Working Group Digital Skills Members of the Digital Skills Working Group Innovative Metrics Members of the Metrics Working Group Leadership Programmes Members</ORGANIZATION> of the Leadership Programmes Working Group Open Access Members of the <ORGANIZATION>Open Access Working Group Research Data Management Members of the Research Data Management Working Group</ORGANIZATION> Previous Strategies 2013 2017 Reshaping The <ORGANIZATION>Research Library Working Group on Digital Collections Working Group on Leadership and Workforce Development Working Group on Research and Education Advocacy and Communications Steering Committee Working Group on Copyright Working Group</ORGANIZATION> on <ORGANIZATION>Open Access Scholarly Communication amp Research Infrastructures Working Group on Metrics Working Group on Scientific Information Infrastructures</ORGANIZATION> 2010 2012 News News Resources Webinars Quarterly Mailings LIBER Quarterly Journal Join LIBER Benefits of Joining Application Form Annual Contribution Fees List of <ORGANIZATION>LIBER Libraries Scholarly Communication Digital Skills amp Services Research Infrastructure Events</ORGANIZATION> LIBER Annual Conference Emerging Leaders Programme Journ es Programme for Library Directors Events Calendar Text and Data Mining Its importance and the need for change in <LOCATION>Europe</LOCATION> You are here Home 2013 2017 <ORGANIZATION>Strategy Advocacy and Communications Text</ORGANIZATION> and Data Mining Its importance and the need for change in <LOCATION>Europe</LOCATION> Menu News Resources Webinars Quarterly Mailings LIBER Quarterly Journal April 25 2013Leave a comment Text and Data Mining Its importance and the need for change in <LOCATION>Europe Share</LOCATION> this postFacebookGoogle TwitterPinterest April 25 2013Leave a comment image Liber TDM Factsheet images Download our Text and Data Mining Factsheet CC BY LIBER its library members and the researchers they support are actively advocating for a more flexible copyright system that will allow Text and Data Mining to be used to its full potential We have produced a number of documents that explain the importance of Text and Data Mining and our call for a more flexible copyright system Our TDM Factsheet is an excellent place to start It shows how TDM can increase the progress of science exponentially The factsheet also explains why the current copyright system is holding back this progress and what you can do to help You can also read about our withdrawal from the Licenses for <LOCATION>Europe</LOCATION> process This was preceded by a letter of concern sent to the <ORGANIZATION>European Commission</ORGANIZATION> to express the need for a more flexible copyright system It was supported by over 60 influential organisations and individuals representing researchers science organisations and industry read the <ORGANIZATION>EC</ORGANIZATION> s response Our previous advocacy work in the area of copyright includes LIBER signs MoU on Out of <ORGANIZATION>Commerce Works</ORGANIZATION> on behalf of <ORGANIZATION>European Research Libraries</ORGANIZATION> 20 September 2011 EBLIDA LIBER and ENCES Statement on the <ORGANIZATION>EC</ORGANIZATION> Proposal for a Draft Directive on Orphan Works 27 May 2011 LIBER Response to Commissioner <PERSON>Barroso</PERSON> on the proposed changes to the European Copyright Directive regarding Orphan Works 16 August 2010 About the author image LIBER <LOCATION>Europe</LOCATION> LIBER <LOCATION>Europe</LOCATION> is a network of 400 research libraries across <LOCATION>Europe</LOCATION> Leave Comment Cancel reply Your email address will not be published Required fields are marked Comment Name Email Website clear formSubmit Posts image LIBER Webinar Turning FAIR Data Into Reality April 9 2018 image LIBER Joins Call For A Better TDM Exception March 27 2018 image Join Our Copyright amp Legal Matters Working Group March 22 2018 image Introducing the Digital Skills Working Group March 9 2018 image IARLA Develops Values Statement March 8 2018 image A Digital Humanities Reading List Part 4 March 8 2018 Events image Workshop How Research Institutions and Libraries can help deliver the European Open Science Cloud Registration is open December 11 2017 image EUDAT Conference Putting the EOSC Vision Into Practice December 7 2017 image LIBER presents at Open Access Belgium Event October 9 2017 image Some highlights from the ILIDE 2017 conference April 20 2017 image Impact and Sustainability Panel at the PREFORMA Innovation workshop February 23 2017 All Events Contact us Would you like to get involved with LIBER or do you have questions Send us a message We ll be happy to help Your Name required Your Email required Your Message Sponsors GOLD SPONSORS image sponsors 2 image sponsors 3 SILVER SPONSORS image digital science logo image openedition Footer image EUROPE S RESEARCH LIBRARY NETWORK In collaboration with our network of 400 research libraries in over 40 European countries LIBER is Powering Sustainable Knowledge in the Digital Age We have a strong vision for the role of research libraries in 2022 based on <ORGANIZATION>Innovative Scholarly Communication Digital Skills and Services and Research Infrastructure Join LIBER</ORGANIZATION> ABOUT US STRATEGY ACTIVITIES NETWORK PRESS CENTRE CONTACT US SITEMAP image image image image LIBER c o <ORGANIZATION>Koninklijke Bibliotheek National Library</ORGANIZATION> of the Netherlands PO Box 90407 2509 <LOCATION>LK The Hague</LOCATION> The NetherlandsPhone 31 70 314 07 67 Email liber kb nl Copyright LIBER All site content except where otherwise noted is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution CC BY license This is in line with LIBER s Open Access Publication Guidelines See also LIBER s Takedown Policy</ner>
