<ner>Skip to main content This service is more advanced with JavaScript available learn more at http activatejavascript org SpringerLink Search Home Contact us Log in image Neural Processing Letters Neural Processing Letters October 2017 Volume 46 Issue 2 pp 379 409 Cite as A New Evolving Tree Based Model with Local Re learning for Document Clustering and <ORGANIZATION>Visualization Authors Authors</ORGANIZATION> and affiliations <PERSON>Wui Lee Chang Kai Meng TayEmail</PERSON> author <PERSON>Chee Peng Lim</PERSON> ArticleFirst Online 06 February 2017 248 Downloads Abstract The Evolving tree ETree is a hierarchical clustering and visualization model that allows the number of clusters to grow and evolve with new data samples in an online learning manner While many hierarchical clustering models are available in the literature ETree stands out because of its visualization capability It is an enhancement of the Self Organizing Map a famous and useful clustering and visualization model ETree organises the trained data samples in the form of a tree structure for better presentation and visualization especially for high dimensional data samples Even though ETree has been used in a number of applications its use in textual document clustering and visualization is limited In this paper ETree is modified and deployed as a useful model for undertaking textual documents clustering and visualization problems We introduce a new local re learning procedure that allows the tree structure to grow and adapt to new features i e new words from new textual documents The performance of the proposed ETree model is evaluated with two one benchmark and one real document data sets A number of key aspects of the proposed ETree model which include its topology representation learning time as well as recall and precision rates are evaluated The results show that the proposed local re learning procedure is useful for handling increasing number of features incrementally In summary this study contributes towards a modified ETree model and its use in a new domain i e textual document clustering and visualization Keywords Evolving tree Textual documents <ORGANIZATION>Clustering Visualization Local</ORGANIZATION> re learning This is a preview of subscription content log in to check access Notes Acknowledgements To 2nd Regional Engineering Conference 2008 EnCon 2008 and the organizing committee Special thanks to Miss <PERSON>Liew Hui Chang</PERSON> who had helped during information collections and compilations The authors had the permission to use the collection of abstracts from EnCon 2008 in which the authors would like to express gratitude for Appendix See Tables 7 8 9 and 10 Table 7 Textual documents mapped onto N_ 81 14 i <ORGANIZATION>Topics Places People Organizations Text 221 China Japan Worldbank China</ORGANIZATION> will receive loans totalling 390 mln dlrs from <LOCATION>Japan</LOCATION> and the <ORGANIZATION>World Bank</ORGANIZATION> for investment in new highways and port facilities The <ORGANIZATION>Japan Overseas Economic Co</ORGANIZATION> operation Fund is to provide 260 mln dlrs towards <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> s plans to improve its road network the official <ORGANIZATION>New China News Agency</ORGANIZATION> reported A 130 mln dlr <ORGANIZATION>World Bank</ORGANIZATION> loan will be used to build 12 new berths incorporating container handling systems at the northeast <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> port of <LOCATION>Tianjin</LOCATION> the agency said It gave no details of the repayment terms of the loans REUTER amp 3 1185 <ORGANIZATION>Usa Norfolk Southern Corp</ORGANIZATION> said it entered into a joint venture with <ORGANIZATION>Sovran Financial Corp</ORGANIZATION> amp lt SOVN gt to build the Sovran III Building which will be renamed <ORGANIZATION>Norfolk Southern Tower Norfolk Southern</ORGANIZATION> said it will locate its headquarters in the tower and occupy the 17th through 21st floors It did not disclose the financial terms of the venture The company said construction of the building adjacent to the <LOCATION>Royster Building</LOCATION> in downtown <LOCATION>Norfolk</LOCATION> begain in October 1986 Another story has been added to the original plans making a 21 story tower <ORGANIZATION>Reuter</ORGANIZATION> amp 3 5687 Usa The <ORGANIZATION>Federal Home Loan Bank Board</ORGANIZATION> said it voted to transfer one billion dlrs cash from the <ORGANIZATION>Federal Savings and Loan Insurance Corp FSLIC</ORGANIZATION> to the <ORGANIZATION>Dallas Federal Home Loan</ORGANIZATION> bank tomorrow to correct a collateral deficiency The infusion was needed because the value of collateral behind <ORGANIZATION>FSLIC</ORGANIZATION> loans to savings and loan associations in the region had declined an <ORGANIZATION>FHLBB</ORGANIZATION> official said The official said that as a result auditors of the <LOCATION>Dallas</LOCATION> bank one of the 12 regional federal home loan banks would be able to give an unqualified opinion on the bank s condition <ORGANIZATION>Reuter</ORGANIZATION> amp 3 6046 Earn Usa net 65 mln vs 57 mln year shr preferred 14 87 dlrs vs 12 51 dlrs shr common 236 77 dlrs vs 197 40 dlrs net 247 mln vs 208 mln NOTE <ORGANIZATION>Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corp FHLMC</ORGANIZATION> had 14 998 210 preferred shares outstanding in 1986 vs 14 998 379 in 1985 owned by about 3 000 member institutions of the 12 <ORGANIZATION>Federal Home Loan Banks FHLMC</ORGANIZATION> also has 100 000 shares of common owned by the <ORGANIZATION>Home Loan Banks Reuter</ORGANIZATION> amp 3 6088 <LOCATION>Usa Mexico</LOCATION> Petricioli Mexican Finance Minister <PERSON>Gustavo Petriccioli</PERSON> said <LOCATION>Mexico</LOCATION> will sign its 7 7 billion dlr commercial bank loan on Friday Petriccioli speaking to reporters after a visit to the <ORGANIZATION>World Bank</ORGANIZATION> said the loan was currently 98 5 pct subscribed a figure <ORGANIZATION>Treasury</ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON>James Baker</PERSON> used in <ORGANIZATION>Congressional</ORGANIZATION> testimony yesterday <ORGANIZATION>Reuter</ORGANIZATION> amp 3 6383 Usa The <ORGANIZATION>Federal Home Loan Bank Board</ORGANIZATION> said it put the <ORGANIZATION>Perpetual Savings Bank</ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION>Santa Ana Calif Into</LOCATION> receivership because it was insolvent and replaced it with a new federally chartered <ORGANIZATION>Perpetual Savings Association</ORGANIZATION> This is the 15th federal action assisting troubled U S Savings institutions this year REUTER amp 3 6461 Acq Usa The <ORGANIZATION>Federal Home Loan Bank Board FHLBB</ORGANIZATION> announced today the replacement of a closed <LOCATION>Santa Ana Calif</LOCATION> savings bank in the 15th federal action assisting troubled U S savings institutions this year The <ORGANIZATION>FHLBB</ORGANIZATION> said <ORGANIZATION>Perpetual Savings Bank</ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION>Santa Ana</LOCATION> was put into receivorship because it was insolvent and was replaced by a new federally chartered <ORGANIZATION>Perpetual Savings Association</ORGANIZATION> It said the savings bank s insolvency was a direct result of losses on speculative investments in real estate which were not supported by appraisals The <ORGANIZATION>FHLBB</ORGANIZATION> said it appointed <ORGANIZATION>Great American First Savings Bank</ORGANIZATION> amp lt GTA gt of <LOCATION>San Diego</LOCATION> to manage Perpetual Savings It said as of January 31 Perpetual had assets of 61 9 mln dlrs <ORGANIZATION>Reuter</ORGANIZATION> amp 3 9846 Earn Usa The <ORGANIZATION>Federal Home Loan Bank Board</ORGANIZATION> said that it closed <ORGANIZATION>Equitable Savings and Loan Association of Fountain Valley California</ORGANIZATION> on Friday due to insolvency amongst other complaints The bank board said in a statement that <ORGANIZATION>Equitable</ORGANIZATION> s insured deposits have been transfered to a unit of <LOCATION>Buffalo</LOCATION> based <ORGANIZATION>Empire of America Federal Savings Bank amp lt EOA</ORGANIZATION> gt in <LOCATION>Woodland Hills California</LOCATION> Consequently <ORGANIZATION>Equitable</ORGANIZATION> s offices will open as <ORGANIZATION>Empire</ORGANIZATION> branches today <ORGANIZATION>Equitable</ORGANIZATION> had assets of 59 12 mln dlrs <ORGANIZATION>Reuter</ORGANIZATION> amp 3 10005 Usa The <ORGANIZATION>Federal Home Loan Bank Board</ORGANIZATION> said it had closed <ORGANIZATION>Equitable Savings and Loan Association of Fountain Valley Calif</ORGANIZATION> and transferred its insured deposits to <ORGANIZATION>Empire of America California FSB</ORGANIZATION> a federal savings bank in <LOCATION>Woodland Hills Calif</LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION>Equitable</ORGANIZATION> had assets of 59 12 mln dlrs Empire is a subsidiary of <ORGANIZATION>Empire of America FSB Buffalo N</ORGANIZATION> Y which has 9 1 billion dlrs in assets and 143 offices in five states The former offices of <ORGANIZATION>Equitable</ORGANIZATION> will open as branches of Empire and <ORGANIZATION>Equitable</ORGANIZATION> s depositors will have immediate access to their insured funds <ORGANIZATION>Equitable</ORGANIZATION> was insolvent and had substantially dissipated assets and earnings resulting in an unsafe and unsound condition to transact business the bank board said It was the seventh closing of a thrift in the nation this year and the first liquidation in <LOCATION>California</LOCATION> The <ORGANIZATION>FHLBB</ORGANIZATION> said <ORGANIZATION>Equitable</ORGANIZATION> had deposits of 79 2 mln dlrs all of which was insured except for about 300 000 dlrs A spokeswoman for the board said information on the cost of the transfer to the <ORGANIZATION>Federal Savings and Loan Insurance Corp</ORGANIZATION> was unavailable <ORGANIZATION>Reuter</ORGANIZATION> amp 3 11005 Earn <ORGANIZATION>Usa Equicor Equitable HCA Corp</ORGANIZATION> said that the company will likely attain revenues in excess of two billion dlrs in its first year of operations The company created last October with initial equity of 400 mln dlrs is owned equally by the <ORGANIZATION>Equitable Life Assurance Society of the U S and Hospital Corp of America amp</ORGANIZATION> lt <ORGANIZATION>HCA</ORGANIZATION> gt Financial results for the first six months of the company s operations were not disclosed <ORGANIZATION>Equicor</ORGANIZATION> provides employee group plans to 1 500 corporations nationwide It said it aims to double its marketshare in five years from the about 3 5 pct of the employee benefits industry it controls <ORGANIZATION>Reuter</ORGANIZATION> amp 3 Table 8 Textual documents mapped onto N_ 82 14 i <ORGANIZATION>Topics Places People Organizations Text</ORGANIZATION> 243 <LOCATION>Egypt</LOCATION> Congo Representatives of nine African countries will meet here on March 11 to discuss the African debt crisis the <LOCATION>Chad</LOCATION> political situation and other issues <LOCATION>Egypt</LOCATION> s Minister of State for Foreign Affairs <PERSON>Boutros Boutros Ghali</PERSON> said He told reporters on his return from <LOCATION>Ethiopia</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Djibouti</LOCATION> that the meeting and venue had been agreed by the <ORGANIZATION>Organisation of African Unity OAU</ORGANIZATION> He said <LOCATION>Egypt Zambia Djibouti Zaire Uganda Sierra Leone Congo Algeria</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Mali</LOCATION> would be represented <ORGANIZATION>Foreign Ministry</ORGANIZATION> sources said <LOCATION>Congo</LOCATION> President <PERSON>Denis Sassou Nguesso</PERSON> would chair the meeting REUTER amp 3 201 <LOCATION>Italy</LOCATION> Leaders of <LOCATION>Italy</LOCATION> s five coalition parties have agreed to meet today to try to settle their differences which are mainly between Prime Minister <PERSON>Bettino Craxi</PERSON> s <ORGANIZATION>Socialist Party</ORGANIZATION> and the majority <ORGANIZATION>Christian Democrats</ORGANIZATION> Sources close to Deputy Prime Minister <PERSON>Arnaldo Forlani</PERSON> said <PERSON>Craxi</PERSON> told him he would announce his resignation next week allowing negotiations on a new government leader The conservative <ORGANIZATION>Christian Democrats</ORGANIZATION> demanded the meeting after <PERSON>Craxi</PERSON> said a pact agreed during a government crisis last August under which he was to hand over the prime minister s job next month was unlikely to be fulfilled Political sources said the <ORGANIZATION>Christian Democrats</ORGANIZATION> are likely to leave the coalition which also includes Republicans Social Democrats and Liberals unless they get the prime minister s job They said <PERSON>Craxi</PERSON> s plans to resign show he has decided to stick to the pact but talks on a leader a government program and sharing of ministries will not be easy They said there is dissent among the partners and that <PERSON>Forlani</PERSON> has been trying to mediate to avoid a crisis They said the five are likely to begin talks tomorrow on whether formation of a new government is feasible or early elections are inevitable Elections are not due until 1988 REUTER amp 3 1046 <LOCATION>Italy</LOCATION> Socialist Prime Minister <PERSON>Bettino Craxi</PERSON> said his five party coalition government would resign <PERSON>Craxi Italy</PERSON> s prime minister for a postwar record of 3 1 2 years told the <ORGANIZATION>Senate</ORGANIZATION> upper house he would hand his and the government s resignation to President <PERSON>Francesco Cossiga</PERSON> immediately after leaving the chamber <PERSON>Craxi</PERSON> has been prime minister at the head of two separate but identical five party coalitions since August 1983 <ORGANIZATION>Reuter amp</ORGANIZATION> 3 1094 <LOCATION>Italy</LOCATION> Italian Prime Minister <PERSON>Bettino Craxi</PERSON> and his five party coalition government have resigned officials said A statement from the Quirinal presidential palace said head of state <PERSON>Francesco Cossiga</PERSON> had reserved his decision on whether to accept the resignation normal procedure when a government stands down The statement said <PERSON>Cossiga</PERSON> had asked <PERSON>Craxi</PERSON> who has been prime minister for a post war record of three and a half years to continue to handle current government business REUTER amp 3 1762 <LOCATION>Italy</LOCATION> Cossiga President <PERSON>Francesco Cossiga</PERSON> meets political leaders to discuss how to form a new government following the resignation of Prime Minister <PERSON>Bettino Craxi Craxi</PERSON> s <ORGANIZATION>Socialist Party</ORGANIZATION> has said it will not serve under Foreign Minister <PERSON>Giulio Andreotti</PERSON> who has been prime minister five times previously and whom the majority <ORGANIZATION>Christian Democratic Party</ORGANIZATION> has said it wants to take on the job again The <ORGANIZATION>Socialist Party</ORGANIZATION> the second biggest in the outgoing five party coalition said it would accept only <ORGANIZATION>Ciriaco De Mita Christian Democratic Party</ORGANIZATION> secretary or the party s president <PERSON>Arnaldo Forlani</PERSON> for the job of prime minister Political sources said talks are likely to be difficult and could take several days due to rivalry between the two leading parties In <PERSON>Craxi</PERSON> s 3 1 2 years as prime minister the <ORGANIZATION>Christian Democrats</ORGANIZATION> have become increasingly irritated at being denied the prime minister s job The sources said early general elections are likely unless agreement can be reached <PERSON>Cossiga</PERSON> is due to meet former presidents before holding talks with party leaders including the opposition Communists and the junior coalition members Republicans Liberals and Social Democrats After the consultations <PERSON>Cossiga</PERSON> will name a prime minister designate who will try to form a government REUTER amp 3 2048 <ORGANIZATION>Usa Japan Nakasone Commerce</ORGANIZATION> Secretary <PERSON>Malcolm Baldrige</PERSON> said he may recommend that the <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> retaliate against <LOCATION>Japan</LOCATION> if the Japanese do not permit U S construction firms to participate in building the eight billion dlr <ORGANIZATION>Kansai</ORGANIZATION> airport But he said he had a personal commitment from Japanese Prime Minister <PERSON>Yasuhiro Nakasone</PERSON> that <LOCATION>US</LOCATION> firms would have a chance at the work I think he will honor that commitment <PERSON>Baldrige</PERSON> told the <ORGANIZATION>Senate Appropriations</ORGANIZATION> subcommittee on commerce affairs He said one form of retaliation could be to curb Japanese firms two billion dlr construction work in the <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> reuter amp 3 2862 <LOCATION>Italy</LOCATION> Italian President <PERSON>Francesco Cossiga</PERSON> asked veteran Christian Democrat politician <PERSON>Giulio Andreotti</PERSON> to try to form a new government officials said They said <PERSON>Andreotti</PERSON> had reserved his reply on whether to accept the mandate normal procedure until he has ascertained whether he can form a government <PERSON>Cossiga</PERSON> nominated <PERSON>Andreotti</PERSON> sole candidate of the majority Christian Democrats despite stiff opposition from the Socialists of outgoing Prime Minister <PERSON>Bettino Craxi</PERSON> REUTER amp 3 4456 <LOCATION>Italy</LOCATION> Italian Prime Minister designate <PERSON>Giulio Andreotti</PERSON> expressed cautious optimism about his chances of forming a government amid concern by industrialists that a lengthy political crisis could cause economic damage <PERSON>Andreotti</PERSON> today wound up his first round of political consultations aimed at finding a way out of the crisis His Christian Democrats and the Socialists of outgoing premier <PERSON>Bettino Craxi</PERSON> whose row caused last week s collapse of the five party coalition remained deeply divided <PERSON>Andreotti</PERSON> said he would spend the weekend considering the situation before a second round of consultations next week Meanwhile <LOCATION>Italy</LOCATION> s top industrialists expressed concern that a long drawn out crisis or continuing squabbling between the five coalition partners could jeopardise the major economic progress made in three and a half stable years under <PERSON>Craxi Luigi Lucchini</PERSON> president of the employers organisation <ORGANIZATION>Confindustria</ORGANIZATION> said in a speech yesterday What is certain is that a precarious political situation is damaging to the economy to the objectives of companies to competitivity His remarks were supported by <ORGANIZATION>Fiat</ORGANIZATION> chairman <PERSON>Giovanni Agnelli</PERSON> who said in a radio interview that he hoped for a reconstruction of the coalition REUTER amp 3 8676 <LOCATION>Italy</LOCATION> Veteran politician <PERSON>Giulio Andreotti</PERSON> abandoned his attempts to form a government putting <LOCATION>Italy</LOCATION> on course for early elections political sources said <PERSON>Christian Democrat Andreotti</PERSON> told President <PERSON>Francesco Cossiga</PERSON> he was unable to reconstruct the five party coalition after two weeks of negotiations they said <ORGANIZATION>Reuter amp</ORGANIZATION> 3 9473 <LOCATION>Italy</LOCATION> Veteran politician <PERSON>Giulio Andreotti</PERSON> abandoned his attempts to form a government putting <LOCATION>Italy</LOCATION> on course for early elections political sources said <PERSON>Christian Democrat Andreotti</PERSON> told President <PERSON>Francesco Cossiga</PERSON> he was unable to reconstruct the five party coalition after two weeks of negotiations they said <ORGANIZATION>Reuter amp</ORGANIZATION> 3 Table 9 Summary of textual documents mapped onto N_ 4 2 <ORGANIZATION>Doc Keywords Texts</ORGANIZATION> 1 Fuzzy inference system FMEA A fuzzy inference system fis based failure mode and effect analysis fmea methodology is presented fmea methodology was introduced as a formal and systematic procedure for evaluation of risk associated to potential failure modes in the 1960s bowles and pel Open image in new window image ez further proposed an fis based risk priority number rpn model as an alternative to the conventional rpn model 1 the use of the fis based rpn in a semiconductor manufacturing process i e underfill dispensing is further reported 98 Fuzzy modeling Monotonic property FMEA Occurrence score Many real world engineering problems of interest revolve around a system that satisfied the monotonicity property between its input and output thus specific fuzzy model that preserves monotonicity constraints better approximates than the conventional fuzzy model in the recent year methods that improve the performance of fuzzy model that satisfy the monotonic constraints have been reported in this paper we investigate on the conditions for a single input fuzzy model to fulfill the monotone output property using a derivative approach from the derivation a guideline on how the input membership functions should be tuned is provided we demonstrate the use of the derived conditions with an application of fuzzy model to my proposed fuzzy occurrence model in failure mode and effect analysis fmea methodology i construct the fuzzy occurrence model with information collected from a semiconductor manufacturing plant for flip chip ball grid array fcbga products analysis and concluding remarks are then presented 100 Fuzzy modeling Monotonic property FMEA Bowles fuzzy rpn model This paper focuses on the modeling of a monotone multi input fuzzy model it can be viewed as a continuation from the part i which focus on single input fuzzy model again i try to investigate the use of derivative approach to find the conditions of a multi input fuzzy model to fulfill the monotonous property from the derivation a guideline on how the input membership functions should be tuned is provided we demonstrate the use of the derived conditions with an application of fuzzy model to bowles fuzzy rpn model in failure mode and effect analysis fmea methodology in this paper the fuzzy fmea model is conducted with information collected from a semiconductor manufacturing plant for flip chip ball grid array fcbga products analysis and concluding remarks are then presented 101 Fuzzy logic Context aware system <ORGANIZATION>FIS</ORGANIZATION> Fuzzy owl In the context awareness information would be retrieved processed shared and reused in the maximum automatic way possible our study in the context awareness application has shown that these are rarely a matter of true or false but rather procedures that require degrees of relatedness similarity or ranking apart from the wealth of applications that are inherently imprecise information itself is many times imprecise or uncertain for example temperature is cold warm hot and tourist is low medium high are examples of such concepts dealing with such type of information would yield more realistic intelligent and effective applications in this paper we propose a fuzzy owl web ontology language in order to be able to capture and represent with such type of uncertain concepts 159 Qualitative technique Semi quantitative technique Quantitative technique Risk based assessment Risk analysis Reliability method Corrosion is a common form of degradation in pipelines that reduces both the static and cyclic strength of a pipeline in the structural engineering field metal corrosion is considered as one of the most dominant failure mechanisms that significantly affects the reliability of structure this paper presents a methodology for the assessment of corrosion in pipelines known as risk based assessment rba rba has been a topic of interest among structure owners and inspection vendors due to its great capability in ensuring pipeline safety and integrity as well as enhancing the cost effectiveness rba is a systematic approach which aims to reduce the overall risk exposure by focusing on the areas of higher risk this approach reduces the total scope of work and inspection costs in a structured and justifiable way the paper reviews about three types of risk assessment techniques which are qualitative q semi quantitative sq and quantitative risk assessment qra however the paper mainly focused on qra which focusing on risk estimation likelihood analysis and consequence analysis this technique can be utilised to avoid unnecessary inspection and extend the inspection intervals based on the risks associated with the pipelines therefore inspection personnel can prioritise the inspection schedule on the high risk areas 278 External factors Cause of the problems Corrective action Corporate performance Construction industry as a sector that contribute 4 8 to gross domestic product gdp need to improve their ability both state own contractors and private contractors with the improvement of ability contruction company will able to compete in domestic and international in order to improve company ability construction company need as early as possible to make corrective action in form of control system toward factors that can influence successfullness of the company Few factors that affected and be determined of company successfulness are internal factors external factors and market forces external factors are a factor that is out of stakeholders control and need to anticipate early external factors commonly are dominated by government regulation which is giving legal aspect outside monetary aspect material ability project safety low cost competitors money depreciation technological changes natural disasters lack of material and worker The research objective discussed in this paper is to identify the corrective action of the problems arise in a construction company s external factors that influence the company s success performance The methods used are literature studies and survey for identifying the problems and lesson learned corrective action Analyses used in this research are statistical analysis and delphi method the results show the corrective actions are implemented toward the cause of the problems by regarding its effects as a risk factor whether the highest risk or the lowest risk and also considering that those corrective actions are preventive and anticipative actions in order to decrease the external problems in the construction company 279 <ORGANIZATION>Rusunawa Build</ORGANIZATION> operate transfer Investment Risk To fulfil the needs of proper housing for public the government have made some strategies that set on the national plan of mid term development year 2004 2009 the plan containing the availability of facility and infrastructure of low budgeted housing area in which one of the project is the construction of 60 000 units low cost apartments rusunawa and 250 000 low cost leased apartment rusunami that dedicated for public with low income The construction is involving private sector the limited budget has pushed the government to persuade the private sector to involve on the construction project one of the cooperation schemes that offered to the private sector is build operate transfer this scheme is become an alternative to attract the private sector to involve on the construction project however build operate transfer scheme has an uncertainty on the investment return Risk assessment should be made in order to the answer the uncertainty of investment return identification and analysis of the risk factor is become the subject of this research that expected can be a consideration to the private sector in risk simulating and therefore can produce a clear picture on the opportunity and risk on the investment this picture is expected can attract the private sector to join on the rusunawa investment interpretation of identification on the research is carried out through analysis on stake holder and rank sorting with analytical hierarchy process ahp also regression analysis that applied to investment risk research complicated bureaucracy difficulties on licenses issuance and uncontrollable inflation are identified as the significant risk factors that affect the rusunawa investment this research is also expected can assist the government to attract the private sector in succeeding the public housing project Table 10 Summary of textual documents mapped onto N_ 5 2 <ORGANIZATION>Doc Keywords Texts</ORGANIZATION> 3 Curve synthesis High quality curves Spiral Monotonic curvature curves A planar curve called generalised log aesthetic curve segment glac has been proposed using the curve synthesis process with two types of formulation vert shift and vert shift both methods were carried out by extending the formulation of generalized cornu spiral gcs in a similar manner to the log aesthetic curve lac the family of glac comprises of planar curves of high quality such as gcs lac clothoid logarithmic spiral circle involute and etc the glac segment has an additional parameter to determine its shape as compared to gcs and lac segment hence an extra constraint can be satisfied when shaping the glac segment the final section of this paper shows some numerical examples 13 Wire electrical discharge machining 304 stainless steel Surface roughness Tolerance Machining time Wire electrical discharge machining wedm is a process which has been implemented widely in various applications it works very effectively in machining of difficultto cut materials and alloys in die and aerospace industries with high dimensional accuracies however this capability is affected by the parameters being used for the cutting the optimum selection of manufacturing conditions is very important in wire edm processes this research presents a study on wedm on stainless steel 304 using mitsubishi ra 90 series particularly this study investigate the significance of several parameters including voltage gap peak current wire tension and wire speed toward the surface quality tolerance and machining time a two level full factorial design of experiment method was used to determine the significance of the parameters 20 Acoustic emission Low speed bearing Lubrication condition This paper investigates the capability of acoustic emission technique in monitoring and accessing the lubrication condition in a low speed rolling element bearing reb operating with constant speed of 47 rpm the rig consists of a motor gearbox system a test bearing 47 rpm and a hydraulic cylinder ram the bearing test rig employed for this study is a spherical roller bearing selected from a split cooper bearing and subjected to 1000 psi and 2000 psi load via a hydraulic cylinder ram measurements have been carried out using of a physical acoustic corporation pac broad band ae transducer model wdi and the amplification is provided with by a pac pre amplifier type 1220a four simulations of various grease fillings up to full a quarter full half full capacity and dry condition have been carried out the time domain parameters which have been utilized are rms and energy the results of this study can be exploited to bring information from the lubrication condition to determine the suitable lubrication filling for the bearing thus the lubrication of the bearing can be improved and the lifetime of the bearing lengthen it is expected that the properly lubricated bearing element will transmit more energy of ae signal compared to a poorly lubricated bearing as there would be more contact between asperity points and lubricant the results of the experiment indicate that the values of rms and energy are capable to distinguish various lubricant conditions in the bearing the obtained results show that the rms and energy values increase with the increment of lubricant amount in the low speed bearing housing this phenomenon is different from the results normally obtained in a high speed reb References 1 <PERSON>Rui X Wunsch</PERSON> DC 2009 Clustering <PERSON>Wiley</PERSON> IEEE PressGoogle Scholar 2 Kohonen T 2001 Self organizing maps 3rd edn Springer BerlinCrossRefMATHGoogle Scholar 3 Kohonen T 1990 The self organizing map Proc IEEE 78 9 1464 1480CrossRefGoogle Scholar 4 Rauber A <PERSON>Merkl</PERSON> D Dittenbachm M 2002 The growing hierarchical self organizing map exploratory analysis of high dimensional data IEEE Trans Neural Netw 13 6 1331 1341CrossRefGoogle Scholar 5 <ORGANIZATION>Carpenter GA Grossberg S Rosen</ORGANIZATION> DB 1991 ART 2 A an adaptive resonance algorithm for rapid category learning and recognition Neural Netw 4 493 504CrossRefGoogle Scholar 6 <ORGANIZATION>Carpenter GA Grossberg S Markuzon N Reynolds JH Rosen</ORGANIZATION> DB 1992 Fuzzy ARTMAP a neural network architecture for incremental supervised learning of analog multidimensional maps <ORGANIZATION>IEEE Trans Neural Netw</ORGANIZATION> 3 5 698 713CrossRefGoogle Scholar 7 Pal NR Pal <PERSON>K Keller</PERSON> JM <PERSON>Bezdek</PERSON> JC 2005 A possibilistic fuzzy c means clustering algorithm <ORGANIZATION>IEEE Trans Fuzzy Syst</ORGANIZATION> 13 4 517 530CrossRefGoogle Scholar 8 <ORGANIZATION>Kanungo T Mount DM Nethanyahu NS Piatko</ORGANIZATION> CD <PERSON>Silverman</PERSON> R Wu AY 2002 An efficient k means clustering algorithm analysis and implementation <ORGANIZATION>IEEE Trans Pattern Anal Mach Intell</ORGANIZATION> 24 7 881 892CrossRefGoogle Scholar 9 Xu C Tao D Xu C 2015 Multi view self paced learning for clustering In Proceedings of 24th international conference on artificial intelligence pp 3974 3980Google Scholar 10 <PERSON>Arora R Gupta MR Kapila</PERSON> A Fazel M 2013 Similarity based clustering by left stochastic matrix factorization <ORGANIZATION>Mach Learn Res</ORGANIZATION> 14 1 1715 1746MathSciNetMATHGoogle Scholar 11 <PERSON>Hsu</PERSON> CC Lin SH Tai WS 2011 Apply extended self organizing map to cluster and classify mixed type data Neurocomputing 74 18 3832 3842CrossRefGoogle Scholar 12 <PERSON>Tai WS Hsu</PERSON> CC Chen JC 2010 A mixed type self organizing map with a dynamic structure In International conference on neural networks pp 1 8Google Scholar 13 Matharage S <PERSON>Alahakoon D Rajapakse J Huang</PERSON> P 2011 Fast growing self organizing map for text clustering In Lecturer notes computer science neural information processing 7063 pp 406 415Google Scholar 14 <PERSON>Kuo RJ Wang CF Chen</PERSON> ZY 2012 Integration of growing self organizing and continuous genetic algorithm for grading lithium ion battery cells Appl Soft Comput 8 12 2012 2022CrossRefGoogle Scholar 15 <PERSON>Huang</PERSON> SY Tsaih RH 2012 The prediction approach with growing hierarchical self organizing map In International conference on neural networks pp 1 7Google Scholar 16 Hosseini HS 2011 Binary tree time adaptive self organizing map Neurocomputing 74 11 1823 1839MathSciNetCrossRefGoogle Scholar 17 Allahyar A Yazdi HS Harati A 2015 Constrained semi supervised growing self organizing map Neurocomputing 147 456 471CrossRefGoogle Scholar 18 <PERSON>Pakkanen J Iivarinen J Oja</PERSON> E 2006 The evolving tree analysis and applications <ORGANIZATION>IEEE Trans Neural Netw</ORGANIZATION> 17 3 591 603CrossRefGoogle Scholar 19 <PERSON>Pakkanen J Iivarinen J Oja</PERSON> E 2004 The evolving tree a novel self organizing network for data analysis Neural Process Lett 20 33 199 211CrossRefGoogle Scholar 20 Fabrizio S 2005 Text cetegorization In <PERSON>Alessandro</PERSON> Z ed Text mining and its applications <ORGANIZATION>WIT Press Southampton</ORGANIZATION> pp 109 129Google Scholar 21 Fabrizio S 2002 Machine learning in automated text categorization ACM Comput Surv 34 1 1 47CrossRefGoogle Scholar 22 <PERSON>Lagus K Kaski S Kohonen</PERSON> T 2004 Mining massive document collections by the WEBSOM method Inf Sci 163 1 135 156CrossRefGoogle Scholar 23 <PERSON>Kaski S Honkela T Lagus K Kohonen</PERSON> T 1998 WEBSOM self organizing maps of document collections Neurocomputing 21 1 101 117CrossRefMATHGoogle Scholar 24 <PERSON>Lewis</PERSON> DD 1998 Na ve <PERSON>Bayes</PERSON> at forty the independence as assumption in information retrieval Lect Notes Comp Sci 1398 4 15CrossRefGoogle Scholar 25 Hotho A Maedche A Staab S 2002 Ontology based text document clustering KI 16 4 48 54Google Scholar 26 <ORGANIZATION>Witten IH Frank E Hall</ORGANIZATION> MA 2011 Data mining practical machine learning tools and techniques 3rd edn <ORGANIZATION>Morgan Kaufmann BurlingtonGoogle Scholar 27 Dhillon IS 2001 Co</ORGANIZATION> clustering documents and words using bipartite spectral graph partitioning In Proceedings of 7th international conference on knowledge discovery data mining pp 269 274Google Scholar 28 Liu Y Loh HT Sun A 2009 Imbalanced text classification a term weighting approach Expert Syst Appl 36 1 690 701CrossRefGoogle Scholar 29 Wold S Esbensen K Geladi P 1987 Principal component analysis <ORGANIZATION>Chemom Intell Lab Syst</ORGANIZATION> 2 1 3 37 52CrossRefGoogle Scholar 30 <PERSON>Ye J Li</PERSON> Q 2004 LDA QR an efficient and effective dimension reduction algorithm and its theoretical foundation Pattern Recognit 37 4 851 854CrossRefGoogle Scholar 31 <ORGANIZATION>Roweis ST Saul</ORGANIZATION> LK 2000 Nonlinear dimensionality reduction by locally linear embedding Science 290 5500 2323 2326CrossRefGoogle Scholar 32 <PERSON>Belkin</PERSON> M Niyogi P 2003 Laplacian eigenmaps for dimensionality reduction and data representation Neural Comput 15 6 1373 1396CrossRefMATHGoogle Scholar 33 <PERSON>Yu J Tao D Wang</PERSON> M 2012 Adaptive hypergraph learning and its application in image classification IEEE Trans Image Process 21 7 3262 3272MathSciNetCrossRefGoogle Scholar 34 <PERSON>Yu J Hong R Wang</PERSON> M You J 2014 Image clustering based on sparse patch alignment framework Pattern Recognit 47 11 3512 3519CrossRefGoogle Scholar 35 <PERSON>Tao D Tang X Li X Wu</PERSON> X 2006 Asymmetric bagging and random subspace for support vector machines based relevance feedback in image retrieval IEEE Trans Pattern Anal Mach <ORGANIZATION>Intell</ORGANIZATION> 28 7 1088 1099CrossRefGoogle Scholar 36 <PERSON>Yu J Rui Y Tao</PERSON> D 2014 Click prediction for web image reranking using multimodal sparse coding IEEE Trans Image Process 23 5 2019 2032MathSciNetCrossRefGoogle Scholar 37 <PERSON>Tao D Li X Wu</PERSON> X <ORGANIZATION>Maybank</ORGANIZATION> SJ 2007 General tensor discriminant analysis and gabor features for gait recognition <ORGANIZATION>IEEE Trans Pattern Anal Mach Intell</ORGANIZATION> 29 10 1700 1715CrossRefGoogle Scholar 38 <PERSON>Luo Y Tao D Ramamohanarao K Xu</PERSON> C Wen Y 2015 Tensor canonical correlation analysis for multi view dimension reduction <ORGANIZATION>IEEE Trans Knowl Data Eng</ORGANIZATION> 27 11 3111 3124CrossRefGoogle Scholar 39 <PERSON>Luo Y Tang J Yan J Xu C Chen</PERSON> Z 2014 Pre trained multi view word embedding using two side neural network In Proceedings of 28th AAAI conference pp 1982 1988Google Scholar 40 <PERSON>Moore</PERSON> BC 1981 Principle component analysis in linear systems controllability observability and model reduction <ORGANIZATION>IEEE Trans Automat Control</ORGANIZATION> 26 1 17 32MathSciNetCrossRefMATHGoogle Scholar 41 <PERSON>Bingham</PERSON> E Mannila H 2001 Random projection in dimensionality reduction applications to image and text data In Proceedings of 7th international conference on knowledge discovery data mining pp 245 250Google Scholar 42 <PERSON>Sammon</PERSON> JW 1969 A nonlinear mapping for data structure analysis IEEE Trans Comput 18 5 401 409CrossRefGoogle Scholar 43 <PERSON>Kohonen T Kaski S Lagus K Salojarvi J Honkela J Paatero V Saarela</PERSON> A 2000 Self organization of a massive document collection <ORGANIZATION>IEEE Trans Neural Netw</ORGANIZATION> 11 3 574 586CrossRefGoogle Scholar 44 Bourgeois N <PERSON>Cottrell</PERSON> M Deruelle B Lamasse S Letremy P 2015 How to improve robustness in <LOCATION>Kohonen</LOCATION> maps and display additional information in factorial analysis application to text mining Neurocomputing 147 120 135CrossRefGoogle Scholar 45 <PERSON>Liu Y Wang X Wu</PERSON> C 2008 ConSOM a conceptional self organizing map model for text clustering Neurocomputing 71 4 857 862CrossRefGoogle Scholar 46 Lughofer E 2011 Evolving fuzzy systems methodologies advanced concepts and applications 1st edn <PERSON>Springer BerlinCrossRefMATHGoogle</PERSON> Scholar 47 <PERSON>Kim HJ Kim</PERSON> JU Ra YG 2005 Boosting Na ve <PERSON>Bayes</PERSON> text classification using uncertainty based selective sampling Neurocomputing 67 4 403 410CrossRefGoogle Scholar 48 <ORGANIZATION>Pan SJ Yang</ORGANIZATION> Q 2010 A survey on transfer learning <ORGANIZATION>IEEE Trans Knowl Data Eng</ORGANIZATION> 22 10 1345 1359CrossRefGoogle Scholar 49 <PERSON>Bezdek JC Keller J Krisnapuram</PERSON> R Pal NR 1999 Fuzzy models and algorithms for pattern recognition and image processing <PERSON>Kluwer DordrechtCrossRefMATHGoogle</PERSON> Scholar 50 <ORGANIZATION>Chang WL Tay KM Lim CP</ORGANIZATION> 2014 A new evolving tree for text document clustering and visualization In Soft computing in industrial applications <PERSON>Springer</PERSON> pp 141 151Google Scholar 51 <ORGANIZATION>Chang WL Tay KM Lim CP</ORGANIZATION> 2013 Enhancing an evolving tree based text document visualization model with fuzzy c means clustering In IEEE international conference fuzzy pp 1 6Google Scholar 52 The <ORGANIZATION>Reuters</ORGANIZATION> 21578 Distribution 1 0 test collection is available from http www daviddlewis com resources testcollections reuters21578 53 Porter MF 1980 An algorithm for suffix stripping <ORGANIZATION>Program Electron Lib</ORGANIZATION> 14 3 130 137Google Scholar 54 The Default English Stop words List is available from http www ranks nl resources stopwords html 55 Debole F Sebastiani F 2005 An analysis of the relative hardness of Rueters 21578 subsets J Am Soc Inf Sci Technol 56 6 584 586CrossRefGoogle Scholar 56 <PERSON>Yang Y Liu</PERSON> X 1999 A re examination of text categorization methods In Proceedings of the 22nd annual international ACM SIGIR conference on Research and development in information retrieval pp 42 49Google Scholar 57 King A 2012 Online k means clustering of nonstationary data Prediction Project ReportGoogle Scholar 58 Lin YS <PERSON>Jiang JY Lee</PERSON> SJ 2014 A similarity measure for text classification and clustering <ORGANIZATION>IEEE Trans Knowl Data Eng</ORGANIZATION> 26 7 1575 1590CrossRefGoogle Scholar 59 Nagwani NK 2015 A comment on a similarity measure for text classification and clustering <ORGANIZATION>IEEE Trans Knowl Data Eng</ORGANIZATION> 27 9 2589 2590CrossRefGoogle Scholar Copyright information <ORGANIZATION>Springer Science Business Media New York 2017 Authors and Affiliations</ORGANIZATION> <PERSON>Wui Lee Chang</PERSON> 1 <PERSON>Kai Meng Tay</PERSON> 1 Email author <PERSON>Chee Peng Lim</PERSON> 2 1 Faculty of <ORGANIZATION>EngineeringUniversiti Malaysia SarawakKota SamarahanMalaysia</ORGANIZATION> 2 <ORGANIZATION>Institute for Intelligent Systems Research and InnovationDeakin UniversityGeelongAustralia About</ORGANIZATION> this article CrossMark Cite this article as <PERSON>Chang W L Tay</PERSON> K M amp Lim C P Neural Process Lett 2017 46 379 https doi org 10 1007 s11063 017 9597 3 <ORGANIZATION>DOI</ORGANIZATION> https doi org 10 1007 s11063 017 9597 3 Publisher Name Springer <LOCATION>US</LOCATION> Print ISSN 1370 4621 Online ISSN 1573 773X About this journal Reprints and Permissions Personalised recommendations Cite article How to cite RIS Papers Reference Manager RefWorks Zotero ENW EndNote BIB BibTeX JabRef Mendeley Buy options Actions Log in to check access Buy PDF USD 39 95 Unlimited access to the full article Instant download Include local sales tax if applicable Subscribe to Journal Get Access to Neural Processing Letters for the whole of 2018 Rent this article via <ORGANIZATION>DeepDyve Learn</ORGANIZATION> about institutional subscriptions Cite article How to cite RIS Papers Reference Manager RefWorks Zotero ENW EndNote BIB BibTeX JabRef Mendeley Cookies We use cookies to improve your experience with our site More information Accept Over 10 million scientific documents at your fingertips Switch Edition Academic Edition Corporate Edition Home Impressum Legal information Accessibility Contact us <ORGANIZATION>Springer Nature 2017 Springer International Publishing AG</ORGANIZATION> Part of Springer Nature Not logged in Not affiliated 99 65 190 47</ner>
