<ner>image Text Mining and Agriculture AgroNLP projects Natural Language Processing applied to AGRicultural dOmain Contact image image UMR TETIS AgroParisTech Cirad Cnrs Irstea 500 rue J F Breton 34093 <ORGANIZATION>Montpellier Cedex</ORGANIZATION> 5 <LOCATION>France</LOCATION> image image image LIRMM CNRS Univ Montpellier 860 rue de St Priest 34095 <ORGANIZATION>Montpellier Cedex</ORGANIZATION> 5 <LOCATION>France</LOCATION> image image image Animal Disease Surveillance image The new and exotic infectious animal diseases are an incising threat to countries due to globalisation movement of passengers and international trade Traditionally disease outbreaks are reported through structured multilevel health infrastructure that can lead to delays in transmission of information Food and Agricultural Organization 2013 Our project proposes a new methodology in the domain of epidemic intelligence in animal health in order to discover knowledge in web documents dealing with animal disease outbreaks To address this issue our global process is based on <ORGANIZATION>Information Retrieval IR</ORGANIZATION> and Information Extraction IE approaches see figure below image Staff <PERSON>Elena Arsevska Cirad CMAEE Renaud Lancelot Cirad CMAEE Thierry Lefran</PERSON> ois Cirad CMAEE <PERSON>Sylvain Falala</PERSON> INRA CMAEE <PERSON>Mathieu Roche Cirad</PERSON> TETIS Pascal Hendrikx Anses UCAS <PERSON>Barbara Dufour</PERSON> ENVA Web page Research results Cirad Publications <PERSON>Elena Arsevska Mathieu Roche Pascal Hendrikx David Chavernac Sylvain Falala Renaud Lancelot Barbara Dufour</PERSON> Identification of terms for detecting early signals of emerging infectious disease outbreaks on the web Computers and Electronics in Agriculture Elsevier 123 104 115 2016 <PERSON>Elena Arsevska Mathieu Roche Pascal Hendrikx David Chavernac Sylvain Falala Renaud Lancelot Barbara Dufour</PERSON> Identification of associations between clinical signs and hosts to monitor the web for detection of animal disease outbreaks <ORGANIZATION>International Journal of Agricultural and Environmental Information Systems IGI</ORGANIZATION> 7 3 1 10 2016 Terminology Extraction for Document Matching and Open Data in Agrictural Domain image In the context of large amounts of textual data related to agriculture now available indexing becomes a crucial issue for research organizations One way to index documents consists of extracting terminology Our project investigates the use and combination of Text Mining methodologies to highlight and publish in Open Data systems the most appropriate terms extracted with BioTex in French and in English Moreover these terms are used to match heterogeneous data of agricultural domain Staff <PERSON>Mathieu Roche Cirad TETIS Jacques Fize TETIS Sophie Fortuno Cirad TETIS Juan Antonio Lossio Ventura</PERSON> LIRMM Maguelonne Teisseire Irstea TETIS Clement Jonquet UM <ORGANIZATION>LIRMM Publications Juan Antonio Lossio Ventura Clement Jonquet Mathieu Roche Maguelonne Teisseire Biomedical</ORGANIZATION> term extraction overview and a new methodology Information Retrieval Journal Special Issue Medical Information Retrieval Springer Volume 19 Issue 1 p 59 99 2016 <PERSON>Mathieu Roche Sophie Fortuno Juan Antonio Lossio Ventura Amira Akli Salim Belkebir Thinhinan Lounis Serigne Toure</PERSON> Extraction automatique des mots cl s partir de publications scientifiques pour l indexation et l ouverture des donn es en agronomie <ORGANIZATION>Cahiers Agricultures Volume</ORGANIZATION> 24 num ro 5 p 313 320 2015 <PERSON>Mathieu Roche Sophie Fortuno</PERSON> La fouille de texte au service de la documentation Arabesques 76 p 13 14 2014 Information Extraction from Experimental Data of Agricultural Domain image Our work deals with knowledge engineering issues of experimental data extracted from scientific articles in order to reuse them in decision support systems Experimental data can be represented by n ary relations which link a studied object e g food packaging transformation process with its features e g oxygen permeability in packaging biomass grinding and capitalized in an Ontological and Terminological Ressource OTR An <ORGANIZATION>OTR</ORGANIZATION> associates an ontology with a terminological and or a linguistic part in order to establish a clear distinction between the term and the notion it denotes the concept Our work focuses on n ary relation extraction from scientific documents in order to populate a domain <ORGANIZATION>OTR</ORGANIZATION> with new instances Our contributions are based on Natural Language Processing <ORGANIZATION>NLP</ORGANIZATION> together with data mining approaches guided by the domain <ORGANIZATION>OTR</ORGANIZATION> Staff <PERSON>Patrice Buche</PERSON> INRA IATE <PERSON>Juliette Dibie Barth</PERSON> lemy <ORGANIZATION>AgroParisTech Mathieu Roche Cirad TETIS Soumia Lilia Berrahou LIRMM Publications Soumia Lilia Berrahou Patrice Buche Juliette Dibie Mathieu Roche Xart Discovery</ORGANIZATION> of correlated arguments of n ary relations in text Expert Systems with Applications Elsevier Volume 73 p 115 124 2017 <PERSON>Soumia Lilia Berrahou Patrice Buche Juliette Dibie Barth</PERSON> lemy <ORGANIZATION>Mathieu Roche How</ORGANIZATION> to extract unit of measure in scientific documents In Proceedings of <ORGANIZATION>KDIR</ORGANIZATION> 13 <ORGANIZATION>International Conference on Knowledge Discovery</ORGANIZATION> and Information Retrieval Text Mining Session p 249 256 <LOCATION>Vilamoura Portugal</LOCATION> 2013 BIRTHDAY BIg Data for Agriculture and biodiversitY image This project aims at providing new efficient decision making tools for helping agricultural development as well as biodiversity protection in <LOCATION>Peru</LOCATION> More precisely it aims at developing a new platform for helping to acquire new data to share data to extract knowledge and to share useful information and knowledge among different actors that are involved in agriculture or biodiversity domains in <LOCATION>Peru</LOCATION> Staff <PERSON>Juan Antonio Lossio Ventura LIRMM Pascal Poncelet</PERSON> UM <PERSON>LIRMM Mathieu Roche Cirad</PERSON> <LOCATION>TETIS Sophia Ananiadou Univ Mancherster UK</LOCATION> Hugo Alastrista Salas PUCP Peru <PERSON>Armando Ferm</PERSON> n P rez UNMSM <LOCATION>Peru</LOCATION> <PERSON>Cesar Beltr</PERSON> n <PERSON>Casta</PERSON> n <ORGANIZATION>PUCP Peru Cayo Leon Univ San Marcos Peru</ORGANIZATION> Web page http atix innovations com verde Publication <PERSON>Laura Cruz Jose Ochoa Mathieu Roche Pascal Poncelet</PERSON> Dictionary Based Sentiment Analysis Applied to a Specific Domain In Proceedings of selected papers of SIMBig 2015 and 2016 International Symposium on Information Management and Big Data Springer 2017 Web design by Free Templates Online http www textmining biz 2017</ner>
