<ner>We use cookies to customise content for your subscription and for analytics If you continue to browse Lexology we will assume that you are happy to receive all our cookies For further information please read our Cookie Policy Lexology Newsfeed Blog Events Popular About Login Register Search Your Basket Toggle navigation Blog Events Popular About Login Register Newsfeed Navigator Hubs Webinars Store Analytics Insights Track Create Newsfeed Navigator Hubs Webinars Store Analytics Insights Track Create Back Forward Save amp file View original <ORGANIZATION>Forward Print Share Facebook Twitter Google</ORGANIZATION> Plus Linked In Follow Please login to follow content Like add to folder image My saved default Read later image Register now for your free tailored daily legal newsfeed service Questions Please contact customerservices lexology com Register Judge grants summary judgment in favor of <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> Books a fair use victory <ORGANIZATION>Antonelli Law Ltd</ORGANIZATION> USA November 19 2013 Judge <PERSON>Denny Chin</PERSON> in the <ORGANIZATION>Southern District of New York</ORGANIZATION> issued an opinion and order granting defendant <ORGANIZATION>Google Books</ORGANIZATION> motion for summary judgment and dismissing the case Judge <PERSON>Chin</PERSON> engaged in in depth analysis of the fair use factors and found that the copying and distribution performed by <ORGANIZATION>Google Books</ORGANIZATION> falls squarely within the purview of the fair use doctrine Notably Judge <PERSON>Chin</PERSON> devoted a significant portion of the decision to discussing the gains that <ORGANIZATION>Google Books</ORGANIZATION> affords to scholarly researchers and the field of education Additionally he quotes several of the amicus briefs that were filed in the case This decision represents a solid victory in favor of fair use generally and bolsters the causes of education and scholarly research Fair use analysis has four factors 1 purpose and character of the use 2 nature of the copyrighted work 3 amount and substantiality used 4 the effect of the use upon the potential market of the copyrighted work Purpose and Character of the Use Transformativeness A key factor in the fair use analysis is whether the use of the copyrighted work is transformative or whether the new work supplants or supersedes the original While a finding of transformativeness is not required for a use to be fair where a work is transformative the factors may tend to weigh in favor of a fair use finding Here Judge <PERSON>Chin</PERSON> found that there were several transformative uses particularly uses that use the words of the original work for a completely different purpose than that of the original such as for data mining and text mining These uses serve to open up new fields of research This factor weighs in favor or fair use even when considering that <ORGANIZATION>Google Books</ORGANIZATION> is a commercial enterprise The judge found that <ORGANIZATION>Google Books</ORGANIZATION> did not make efforts to directly commercially profit from the works at issue either through selling them or putting advertising on the pages Nature of the Copyrighted Works According to the undisputed facts of the case the vast majority of the books 93 percent in <ORGANIZATION>Google Books</ORGANIZATION> are non fiction which enjoy a lesser level of copyright protection than works of fiction therefore tipping this factor toward fair use Amount and Substantiality of the Portion Used While <ORGANIZATION>Google Books</ORGANIZATION> scans the entirety of a work for its use that does not necessarily mean that the use is not fair Judge <PERSON>Chin</PERSON> balanced that full text scan against the fact that <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> limits the amount of text or snippets that are viewable in response to a search Effect of the Use Upon the Potential Market or Value The plaintiffs The <ORGANIZATION>Authors Guild</ORGANIZATION> argued seemingly most strenuously on this factor stating that the <ORGANIZATION>Google Books</ORGANIZATION> service would serve as a replacement market for the original works Judge <PERSON>Chin</PERSON> found this argument unconvincing in light of the undisputed facts and stated a reasonable factfinder could only find that <ORGANIZATION>Google Books</ORGANIZATION> enhances the sales of books to the benefit of copyright holders An important factor in the success of an individual title is whether it is discovered whether potential readers learn of its existence <ORGANIZATION>Google Books</ORGANIZATION> provides a way for authors works to become noticed much like traditional in store book displays <ORGANIZATION>Further Google</ORGANIZATION> provides convenient links to booksellers to make it easy for a reader to order a book In this day and age of on line shopping there can be no doubt but that <ORGANIZATION>Google Books</ORGANIZATION> improves book sales Opinion page 25 Promoting the Arts and Sciences The stated goal of copyright is to promote the arts and sciences Here Judge <PERSON>Chin</PERSON> notes that not only is the use by <ORGANIZATION>Google Books</ORGANIZATION> squarely within the realm of fair use but it also substantially furthers the goal of copyright Making available books for the purposes of research scholarly study and other educational uses undoubtedly furthers the goal of promoting the arts and sciences Finally Judge <PERSON>Chin</PERSON> found that other claims by the plaintiffs in particular any allegation of secondary liability due to <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> providing digital copies to libraries would fail due to fair use as well The libraries were only provided with digital copies of books they already owned in situations where they originally provided the physical copy for scanning to <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> The judge cites <ORGANIZATION>Authors Guild Inc</ORGANIZATION> v HathiTrust 902 F Supp 2d 445 460 61 464 S D N Y 2012 which held that the library defendant s digitization project fell under fair use I f there is no liability for copyright infringement on the libraries part there can be no liability on <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> s part Opinion page 28 The full opinion can be viewed here <ORGANIZATION>Authors Guild</ORGANIZATION> v <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> Books 05 cv 8136 Summary Judgment Granted for <ORGANIZATION>Google Books Back Forward Save amp</ORGANIZATION> file View original <ORGANIZATION>Forward Print Share Facebook Twitter Google</ORGANIZATION> Plus Linked In Follow Please login to follow content Like add to folder image My saved default Read later image Filed under <ORGANIZATION>USA Copyrights Litigation Antonelli Law Ltd</ORGANIZATION> Tagged with Copyright infringement <ORGANIZATION>Google US District Court</ORGANIZATION> for SDNY Fair use <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> Books Transformativeness Popular articles from this firm <ORGANIZATION>Stan Lee Media Inc</ORGANIZATION> loses copyright infringement case against <ORGANIZATION>Disney</ORGANIZATION> If you would like to learn how Lexology can drive your content marketing strategy forward please email enquiries lexology com Send to Create image Powered by Lexology Related topic hubs <ORGANIZATION>Google Copyright infringement USA Litigation Copyrights Lexology Navigator Q amp A Compare</ORGANIZATION> jurisdictions Arbitration <LOCATION>USA Greece</LOCATION> Belgium More image <PERSON>Martha</PERSON> van den <ORGANIZATION>Beld Legal Counsel TOTAL Nederland NV</ORGANIZATION> What our clients say Lexology is a high quality service the articles are very relevant and always useful Back to Top RSS feeds Contact Submissions About Testimonials Cookies Disclaimer Privacy policy Login Register Follow on Twitter Search image <ORGANIZATION>Globe Business Media Group</ORGANIZATION> Copyright 2006 2018 Globe Business Media Group</ner>
