<ner>image textmining biz Text Mining Research in <LOCATION>Montpellier France</LOCATION> Contact image image UMR TETIS AgroParisTech Cirad Irstea 500 rue J F Breton 34093 <ORGANIZATION>Montpellier Cedex</ORGANIZATION> 5 <LOCATION>France</LOCATION> image image image LIRMM CNRS Univ Montpellier 860 rue de St Priest 34095 <ORGANIZATION>Montpellier Cedex</ORGANIZATION> 5 <LOCATION>France</LOCATION> image image image image Locations of visitors to this page Presentation Text mining refers to the process of deriving high quality information from text Typical text mining tasks include text categorization text clustering concept entity extraction production of granular taxonomies sentiment analysis document summarization and entity relation modeling i e learning relations between named entities textmining biz enumerates some research scientists in <ORGANIZATION>Montpellier TETIS</ORGANIZATION> and LIRMM labs working in text mining domain A joint group with both laboratories will be proposed soon see ADVanced Analytics for data SciencE Advanse contact <PERSON>Pascal Poncelet</PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION>Sandra Bringay Staff Mathieu Roche Research</ORGANIZATION> scientist TETIS <ORGANIZATION>Cirad Maguelonne Teisseire Research</ORGANIZATION> scientist TETIS Irstea Pascal Poncelet Professor <PERSON>LIRMM Univ Montpellier Sandra Bringay</PERSON> Associate Professor <PERSON>LIRMM Univ Paul Val</PERSON> ry News Text Mining and Agriculture Description of AgroNLP projects Natural Language Processing applied to AGRicultural dOmain BIRTHDAY project BIg Data for Agriculture and biodiversitY A research project in collaboration with <LOCATION>Peru</LOCATION> SONGES project has been accepted 2016 2018 Project supported by <LOCATION>Languedoc Roussillon</LOCATION> and <ORGANIZATION>European Union FEDER</ORGANIZATION> 88milSMS A corpus of authentic text messages SMS in French is available BioTex A term extraction software is available Contact Juan Antonio Lossio Ventura Web design by Free Templates Online http www textmining biz 2015</ner>
