<ner>1911 Encyclop dia Britannica American Literature From Wikisource lt 1911 Encyclop dia Britannica Jump to navigation search American Law 1911 Encyclop dia Britannica Volume 1 American Literature by <PERSON>George Edward Woodberry</PERSON> American War of Independence See also American literature on <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> and our 1911 Encyclop dia Britannica disclaimer 17760951911 Encyclop dia Britannica Volume 1 American Literature AMERICAN LITERATURE The earliest books which are commonly described as the beginnings of American literature were written by men born and bred in <LOCATION>England</LOCATION> they were published there they were in fact an Begin nings undivided part of English literature belonging to the province of exploration and geographical description and entirely similar in matter and style to other works of voyagers and colonizers that illustrate the expansion of <LOCATION>England</LOCATION> They contain the materials of history in a form of good Elizabethan narrative always vigorous in language often vivid and picturesque <PERSON>John Smith</PERSON> 1579 1631 wrote the first of these A True Relation of such Occurrences and Accidents of Note as hath happened in <LOCATION>Virginia</LOCATION> 1608 and he later added other accounts of the country to the north <PERSON>William Strachey</PERSON> a Virginian official of whom little is known biographically described 1610 the shipwreck of Sir <PERSON>Thomas Gates</PERSON> on the Bermudas which is believed to have yielded <PERSON>Shakespeare</PERSON> suggestions for The Tempest Colonel <PERSON>Henry Norwood</PERSON> d 1689 hitherto unidentified of <LOCATION>Leckhampton Gloucestershire</LOCATION> a person eminent for loyalty in the reign of <PERSON>Charles</PERSON> I and distinguished in the civil wars later governor of <LOCATION>Tangiers</LOCATION> and a member of parliament for <LOCATION>Gloucester</LOCATION> wrote an account of his voyage to <LOCATION>Virginia</LOCATION> as an adventurer in 1649 These are characteristic works of the earliest period and illustrate variously the literature of exploration which exists in numerous examples and is preserved for historical reasons The settlement of the colonies was in general attended by such narratives of adventure or by accounts of the state of the country or by documentary record of events Thus <PERSON>George Alsop</PERSON> b 1638 wrote the Character of the Province of <LOCATION>Maryland</LOCATION> 1666 and <PERSON>Daniel Denton</PERSON> a Brief Description of <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> 1670 and in <LOCATION>Virginia</LOCATION> the progress of affairs was dealt with by <PERSON>William Stith</PERSON> 1689 1755 <PERSON>Robert Beverly</PERSON> f 1700 and <PERSON>William Byrd</PERSON> 1674 1744 Each settlement in turn as it came into prominence or provoked curiosity found its geographer and annalist and here and there sporadic pens essayed some practical topic The product however is now an indistinguishable mass and titles and authors alike are found only in antiquarian lore The distribution of literary activity was very uneven along the sea board it was naturally greatest in the more thriving and important colonies and bore some relation to their commercial prosperity and political activity and to the closeness of the connexion with the home culture of <LOCATION>England</LOCATION> From the beginning <LOCATION>New England</LOCATION> owing to the character of its people and its ecclesiastical rule was the chief seat of the early literature and held a position apart from the other colonies as a community characterized by an intellectual life There the first printing press was set up the first college founded and an abundant literature was produced The characteristic fact in the Puritan colonies is that literature there was in the hands of its leading citizens and was a chief concern in their minds There were books of exploration and description as in the other colonies such as <PERSON>William Wood</PERSON> s d 1629 <LOCATION>New England</LOCATION> s Prospect 1634 and <PERSON>John Josselin</PERSON> s <LOCATION>New England</LOCATION> s Rarities 1672 and tales of adventure in the wilderness and on the sea most commonly described as remarkable providences in the vigorous Elizabethan narrative but besides all this the magistracy and the clergy normally set themselves to the labour of history controversy and counsel and especially to the care of religion The governors beginning with <PERSON>William Bradford</PERSON> 1590 1657 of <LOCATION>Plymouth</LOCATION> and <PERSON>John Winthrop</PERSON> 1588 1649 of <LOCATION>Massachusetts Bay</LOCATION> wrote the annals of their times and the line of historians was continued by <ORGANIZATION>Winslow Nathaniel Morton</ORGANIZATION> Prince <PERSON>Hubbard</PERSON> and <PERSON>Hutchinson</PERSON> The clergy headed by <PERSON>John Cotton</PERSON> 1585 1652 <PERSON>Thomas Hooker</PERSON> 1586 1647 <PERSON>Nathaniel Ward</PERSON> 1579 1652 <PERSON>Roger Williams</PERSON> 1600 1683 Richard Mather 1596 1669 <PERSON>John Eliot</PERSON> 1604 1690 produced sermons platforms catechisms theological dissertations tracts of all sorts and their line also was continued by <ORGANIZATION>Shepard Norton Wise</ORGANIZATION> the later <PERSON>Mathers</PERSON> and scores of other ministers The older clergy were not inferior in power or learning to the leaders of their own communion in <LOCATION>England</LOCATION> and they commanded the same prose that characterizes the Puritan tracts of the mother country nor did the kind of writing deteriorate in their successors This body of divines in successive generations gave to early <LOCATION>New England</LOCATION> literature its overwhelming ecclesiastical character it was in the main a church literature and its secular books also were controlled and coloured by the Puritan spirit The pervasiveness of religion is well illustrated by the three books which formed through the entire colonial period the most popular domestic reading of the Puritan home These were The Bay Psalm Book 1640 which was the first book published in <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> Michael Wigglesworth s 1631 1705 Day of Doom 1662 a doggerel poem and the New England Primer c 1690 called the Little Bible The sole voice heard in opposition was <PERSON>Thomas Morton</PERSON> s satirical New English Canaan 1637 whose author was sent out of the colony for the scandal of <LOCATION>Merrymount</LOCATION> but satire itself remained religious in <LOCATION>Ward</LOCATION> s Simple Cobbler of Agawam 1647 Poetry was represented in <PERSON>Anne Bradstreet</PERSON> s 1612 1672 The Tenth <PERSON>Muse</PERSON> lately sprung up in <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> 1650 and was continued by a succession of doggerel writers mostly ministers or schoolmasters <PERSON>Noyes Oakes Folger Tompson Byles</PERSON> and others The world of books also included a good proportion of Indian war narratives and treatises relating to the aborigines The close of the 17th century shows literature however still unchanged in its main position as the special concern of the leaders of the state It is Chief Justice <PERSON>Samuel Sewall</PERSON> s 1652 1730 Diary which remained in manuscript until 1878 that affords the most intimate view of the culture and habits of the community and he was known to his contemporaries by several publications one of which The Selling of <PERSON>Joseph</PERSON> 1700 was the first American anti slavery tract The literature of the first century exemplified by these few titles is considerable in bulk and like colonial literature elsewhere is preserved for historical reasons In general it records the political progress and Puritanism social conditions of the <LOCATION>Puritan</LOCATION> state and the contents of the Puritan mind The development of the original settlement took place without any violent check Though the colony was continually recruited by fresh immigration the original 20 000 who arrived before 1640 had established the principles of the state and their will and ideas remained dominant after the Restoration as before It was a theocratic state controlled by the clergy and yet containing the principle of liberty The second and third generations born on the soil nevertheless showed some decadence notwithstanding the effort to provide against intellectual isolation and mental poverty by the foundation of <ORGANIZATION>Harvard College</ORGANIZATION> they felt the effects of their situation across the sea and on the borders of a wilderness The people were a hard faring folk and engaged in a material struggle to establish the plantations and develop commerce on the sea their other life was in religion soberly practised and intensely felt They were a people of one book in the true sense the Bible it was the organ of their mental life as well as of their spiritual feelings For them it was in the place of the higher literature But long resident there in the strip between the sea and the forest cut off from the world and consigned to hard labour and to spiritual ardours they developed a fanatical temper their religious life hardened and darkened intolerance and superstition grew <ORGANIZATION>Time</ORGANIZATION> nevertheless ripened new changes and the colony was to be brought back from its religious seclusion into the normal paths of modern development The sign was contained perhaps most clearly in the change effected in the new charter granted by King <PERSON>William</PERSON> which made property the basis of the franchise in place of church membership and thus set the state upon an economic instead of a religious foundation It is rather by men than by books that these times are remembered but it is by the men who were writers of books In general the career of the three <PERSON>Mathers</PERSON> coincides with the history of the older Puritanism and their personal characteristics reflect its stages as their writings contain its successive traits <PERSON>Richard Mather</PERSON> the emigrant had been joint author in the composition of The Bay Psalm Book and served the colony among the first of its leaders It was in his son Increase Mather 1639 1723 that the theocracy properly speaking culminated He was not only a divine president of <ORGANIZATION>Harvard College</ORGANIZATION> and a prolific writer but he was dominant in the state the chief man of affairs It was he who sent to represent the colony in <LOCATION>England</LOCATION> received from King <PERSON>William</PERSON> the new charter His son <PERSON>Cotton Mather</PERSON> 1663 1728 succeeded to his father s distinction but the changed condition is reflected in his non participation in affairs he was a man of the study and led there a narrower life than his father s had been He was nevertheless the most broadly characteristic figure of the Puritan of his time He was able and learned abnormally laborious leaving over 400 titles attributed to him and at the same time he was an ascetic and visionary The work by which he is best remembered the Magnalia Christi Americana or the Ecclesiastical History of <LOCATION>New England</LOCATION> from its First Planting in the Year 1620 unto the Year of our Lord 1698 1702 is the chief historical monument of the period and the most considerable literary work done in <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> up to that time It is encyclopaedic in scope and contains an immense accumulation of materials relating to life and events in the colony There the <LOCATION>New England</LOCATION> of the 17th century is displayed His numerous other works still further amplify the period and taken all together his writings best illustrate the contents of Puritanism in <LOCATION>New England</LOCATION> The power of the clergy was waning but even in the political sphere it was far from extinction and it continued under its scheme of church government to guard jealously the principles of liberty In <PERSON>John Wise</PERSON> s 1652 1725 Vindication of the Government of <LOCATION>New England</LOCATION> Churches 1717 a precursor of the Revolution is felt It was in another sphere however that Puritanism in <LOCATION>New England</LOCATION> was to reach its height intellectually and spiritually alike in the brilliant personality of <PERSON>Jonathan Edwards</PERSON> 1703 1758 its last great product He was free of affairs and lived essentially the private life of a thinker He displayed in youth extraordinary precocity and varied intellectual curiosity and showed at the same early time a temperament of spiritual sensitiveness and religious ideality which suggests the youth of a poet rather than of a logician It was not without a struggle that he embraced sincerely the Calvinistic scheme of divine rule but he was able to reconcile the doctrine in its most fearful forms with the serenity and warmth of his own spirit for his soul at all times seems as lucid as his mind and his affections were singularly tender and refined He served as minister to the church at <LOCATION>Northampton</LOCATION> and driven from that post he was for eight years a missionary to the Indians at <LOCATION>Stockbridge</LOCATION> finally he was made president of <ORGANIZATION>Princeton College</ORGANIZATION> where after a few weeks incumbency he died The works upon which his fame is founded are Treatise concerning the Religious Affections 1746 On the Freedom of the Will 1754 Treatise on Original Sin 1758 They exhibit extraordinary reasoning powers and place him among the most eminent theologians He contributed by his preaching great inspiring force to the revival known as the Great Awakening which swept over the dry and formal Puritanism of the age and was its last great flame In him <LOCATION>New England</LOCATION> idealism had come to the birth He illustrates better than all others the power of Puritanism as a spiritual force and in him only did that power reach intellectual expression in a memorable way for the larger world The ecclesiastical literature of Puritanism abundant as it was produced no other work of power nor did the Puritan patronage of literature prove fruitful in other fields If Puritanism was thus infertile it nevertheless prepared the soil It impressed upon <LOCATION>New England</LOCATION> the stamp of the mind the entire community was by its means intellectually as well as morally bred and to its training and the predisposition it established in the genius of the people may be ascribed the respect for the book which has always characterized that section the serious temper and elevation of its later literature and the spiritual quality of the imagination which is so marked a quality of its authors The secularization of life in <LOCATION>New England</LOCATION> which went on concurrently with the decline of the clergy in social power was incidental to colonial growth The practical force of the people had always been Franklinstrong material prosperity increased and a powerful class of merchants grew up public questions multiplied in variety and gained in importance The affairs of the world had definitely obtained the upper hand The new spirit found its representative in the great figure of <PERSON>Benjamin Franklin</PERSON> 1706 1790 who born in <LOCATION>Boston</LOCATION> early emigrated to <LOCATION>Philadelphia</LOCATION> an act which in itself may be thought to forecast the transfer of the centre of interest to the west and south and specifically to that city where the congress was to sit <PERSON>Franklin</PERSON> was a printer and the books he circulated are an index to the uses of reading in his generation Practical works such as almanacs were plentiful and it is characteristic that <ORGANIZATION>Franklin</ORGANIZATION> s name is in literature first associated with Poor <PERSON>Richard</PERSON> s Almanack 1732 The literature of the 18th century outside of <LOCATION>New England</LOCATION> continued to be constituted of works of exploration description colonial affairs with some sprinkling of crude science and doctrines of wealth but it yields no distinguished names or remembered titles <ORGANIZATION>Franklin</ORGANIZATION> s character subsumes the spirit of it In him thrift and benevolence were main constituents scientific curiosity of a useful sort and invention distinguished him after he had secured a competence public interests filled his mature years In him was the focus of the federating impulses of the time and as the representative of the colonies in <LOCATION>England</LOCATION> and during the Revolution in <LOCATION>France</LOCATION> he was in his proper place as the greatest citizen of his country He was first of men broadly interested in all the colonies and in his mind the future began to be comprehended in its true perspective and scale and for these reasons to him properly belongs the title of the first American The type of his character set forth in the Autobiography 1817 was profoundly American and prophetic of the plain people s ideal of success in a democracy It is by his character and career rather than by his works or even by his great public services that he is remembered he is a type of the citizen man Older than his companions and plain while they were of an aristocratic stamp he greatens over them in the popular mind as age greatens over youth but it was these companions who were to lay the foundations of the political literature of <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> With the increasing political life lawyers as a class had naturally come into prominence as spokesmen and debaters A young generation of orators sprang up of whom <PERSON>James Otis</PERSON> 1725 1783 in the north and <PERSON>Patrick Henry</PERSON> 1736 1799 in the south were the most brilliant and a group of statesmen of whom the most notable were <PERSON>Thomas Jefferson</PERSON> 1743 1826 <PERSON>James Madison</PERSON> 1751 1836 and <PERSON>Alexander Hamilton</PERSON> 1757 1804 held the political direction of the times in the speeches and state papers of these orators and statesmen and their fellows the political literature of the colonies came to hold the first place The chief memorials of this literature are The Declaration of Independence 1776 The Federalist 1788 a treatise on the principles of free government and <LOCATION>Washington</LOCATION> s Addresses 1789 1793 1796 Thus politics became in succession to exploration and religion the most important literary element in the latter half of the 18th century The more refined forms of literature also began to receive intelligent attention towards the close of the period The Revolution in passing struck out some sparks of balladry and song but the inspiration of18th century poetry and fiction the spirit of nationality was first felt in poetry by <PERSON>Philip Freneau</PERSON> 1752 1832 whose Poems 1786 marked the best political achievement up to his time Patriotism was also a ruling motive in the works of the three poets associated with <ORGANIZATION>Yale College John Trumbull</ORGANIZATION> 1750 1831 <PERSON>Timothy Dwight</PERSON> 1752 1817 and <PERSON>Joel Barlow</PERSON> 1754 1812 authors respectively of McFingal 1782 a Hudibrastic satire of the Revolution The Conquest of Canaan 1785 an epic and The Vision of <LOCATION>Columbus</LOCATION> 1787 later remade into The Columbiad also an epic These poets gathered about them a less talented company and all were denominated in common the <LOCATION>Hartford</LOCATION> Wits by which name rather than by their works they are remembered The national hymn Hail Columbia was composed by <PERSON>Joseph Hopkinson</PERSON> 1770 1842 in 1798 Fiction in turn was first cultivated by <PERSON>Charles Brockden Brown</PERSON> 1771 1810 a Philadelphian who wrote six romantic novels 1798 1801 after the style of <PERSON>Godwin</PERSON> but set in the conditions of the new world and mixing local description and observation with the material of mystery and terror Fiction had been earlier attempted by <PERSON>Mrs Susanna Haswell Rowson</PERSON> whose <LOCATION>Charlotte</LOCATION> Temple 1790 is remembered and contemporaneously by <PERSON>Mrs Hannah Webster Foster</PERSON> in The Coquette 1797 and by <PERSON>Royall Tyler</PERSON> 1758 1826 in The Algerian Captive 1799 but to <PERSON>Brown</PERSON> properly belongs the title of the first American novelist nor are his works without invention and intensity and a certain distinction that secure for them permanent remembrance The drama formally began its career on a regular stage and with an established company in 1786 at <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> with the acting of <PERSON>Royall Tyler</PERSON> s comedy The Contrast but the earliest American play was <PERSON>Thomas Godfrey</PERSON> s 1736 1763 tragedy The Prince of <LOCATION>Parthia</LOCATION> acted in <LOCATION>Philadelphia</LOCATION> in 1767 <PERSON>William Dunlap</PERSON> 1766 1839 is however credited with being the father of the American theatre on the <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> stage where his plays were produced One other earlier book deserves mention <PERSON>John Woolman</PERSON> s 1720 1772 Journal 1775 an autobiography with much charm With these various attempts the 18th century was brought to an end In 200 years no literary classic had been produced in <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> The new nation which with the 19th century began its integral career still retained the great disparities which originally existed between the diverse colonies Political unity the simplest of the social unities The new nation had been achieved a more perfect union in the language of the founders had been formed but even in the political sphere the new state bore in its bosom disuniting forces which again and again threatened to rive it apart until they were dissipated in the Civil War and in the other spheres of its existence intellectually morally socially its unity was far from being accomplished The expansion of its territory over the continental area brought new local diversity and prolonged the contrasts of border conditions with those of the long settled communities This state of affairs was reflected in the capital fact that there was no metropolitan centre in which the tradition and forces of the nation were concentrated <LOCATION>Washington</LOCATION> was a centre of political administration but that was all The nation grew slowly indeed into consciousness of its own existence but it was without united history without national traditions of civilization and culture and it was committed to the untried idea of democracy It was founded in a new faith yet at the moment that it proclaimed the equality of men its own social structure and habit north and south contradicted the declaration not merely by the fact of slavery but by the life of its classes The south long remained oligarchic in the north aristocracy slowly melted away The coincidence of an economic opportunity with a philosophic principle is the secret of the career of American democracy in its first century The vast resources of an undeveloped country gave this opportunity to the individual while the nation was pledged by its fundamental idea to material prosperity for the masses popular education and the common welfare as the supreme test of government In this labour subduing the new world to agriculture trade and manufactures the forces of the nation were spent under the complication of maintaining the will of the people as the directing power the subjugation of the soil and experience in popular government are the main facts of American history In the course of this task the practice of the fine arts was hardly more than an incident When anyone thinks of <LOCATION>Greece</LOCATION> he thinks first of her arts when anyone thinks of <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> he thinks of her arts last Literature in the sense of the printed word has had a great career in <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> as the vehicle of use books journals literary communication educational works and libraries have filled the land nowhere has the power of the printed word ever been so great nowhere has the man of literary genius ever had so broad an opportunity to affect the minds of men contemporaneously But in the artistic sense literature at most has been locally illustrated by a few eminent names The most obvious fact with regard to this literature is that to adopt a convenient word it has been regional It has flourished in parts of the country very distinctly marked and is in each case affected by its environment and local culture if it incorporates national elements at times it seems to graft them on its own stock The growth of literature in these favoured soils was slow and humble There was no outburst of genius no sudden movement no renaissance but very gradually a step was taken in advance of the last generation as that had advanced upon its forefathers The first books of true excellence were experiments they seem almost accidents The cities of <LOCATION>Boston New York</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Philadelphia</LOCATION> were lettered communities they possessed imported books professional classes men of education and taste The tradition of literature was strong especially in <LOCATION>New England</LOCATION> there were readers used to the polite letters of the past It was however in the main the past of Puritanism both in <LOCATION>England</LOCATION> and at home and of the 18th century in general on which they were bred with a touch ever growing stronger of the new European romanticism All the philosophic ideas of the 18th century were current What was most lacking was a standard self applied by original writers and in the absence of a great national centre of standards and traditions and amid the poverty of such small local centres as the writers were bred in they sought what they desired not in <LOCATION>England</LOCATION> not in any one country nor in any one literature but in the solidarity of literature itself in the republic of letters the world state itself the master works of all European lands they became either actual pilgrims on foreign soil or pilgrims of the mind in fireside travels The foreign influences that thus entered into American literature are obvious and make a large part of its history but the fact here brought out is that European literature and experience stood to American writers in lieu of a national centre it was there that both standard and tradition were found American literature first began to exist for the larger world in the persons of <LOCATION>Washington</LOCATION> Irving 1785 1859 and <PERSON>James Fenimore Cooper</PERSON> 1789 1851 Their recognition was almost contemporaneous The Sketch BookEarly 19th century classics 1810 was the first American book to win a great reputation in <LOCATION>England</LOCATION> and The Spy 1821 was the first to obtain a similar vogue on the continent The fame of both authors is associated with <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> and that city took the first place as the centre of the literature of the period It was not that <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> was more intellectual than other parts of the country but it was a highly prosperous community where a mercantile society flourished and consequently a certain degree of culture obtained The first American literature was not the product of a raw democracy nor of the new nationality in any sense there was nothing sudden or vehement in its generation but as always it was the product of older elements in the society where it arose and flourished under the conditions of precedent culture The family of <PERSON>Irving</PERSON> were in trade <PERSON>Cooper</PERSON> s father was in the law A third writer <PERSON>William Cullen Bryant</PERSON> 1794 1878 is associated with them and though he announced his poetic talent precociously by Thanatopsis 1807 his Poems 1832 immediately republished in <LOCATION>London</LOCATION> were the basis of his true fame Born in <LOCATION>Massachusetts</LOCATION> he lived his long life in <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> and was there a distinguished citizen His father was a physician All three men were not supremely endowed they do not show the passion of genius for its work which marks the great writers they were like most American writers men with the literary temperament characteristically gentlemen who essayed literature with varying power If the quality of this early literature is to be appreciated truly the fact of its provenance from a society whose cultivation was simple and normal a provincial bourgeois society of a prosperous democracy must be borne in mind It came not from the people but from the best classes developed under preceding conditions <PERSON>Irving</PERSON> all his life was in the eyes of his countrymen whatever their pride might be in him more a travelled gentleman than one of themselves He had come home to end his days at <LOCATION>Sunnyside</LOCATION> by <PERSON>Irving the Hudson</PERSON> but he had won his fame in foreign fields In his youth the beginnings of his literary work were most humble light contributions to the press He was of a most social nature warm refined humorous a man belonging to the town He was not seriously disposed idled much and surprised his fellow citizens suddenly by a grotesque History of <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> 1809 an extravaganza satirizing the Dutch element of the province He discovered in writing this work his talent for humour and also one part of his literary theme the Dutch tradition but he did not so convince himself of his powers as to continue and it was only after the failure of his commercial interests that being thrown on himself for support he published in <LOCATION>London</LOCATION> ten years later at the age of thirty six the volume of sketches which by its success committed him to a literary career In that work he found himself sentiment and distinction of style characterized it and these were his main traits He remained abroad always favoured in society and living in diplomatic posts in <LOCATION>Spain</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>England</LOCATION> for seventeen years and he later spent four years in <LOCATION>Spain</LOCATION> as minister <LOCATION>Spain</LOCATION> gave him a larger opportunity than <LOCATION>England</LOCATION> for the cultivation of romantic sentiment and he found there his best themes in Moorish legend and history On his return to <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> he added to his subjects the exploration of the west and he wrote besides biographies of <PERSON>Goldsmith</PERSON> and <LOCATION>Washington</LOCATION> He was as it turned out a voluminous writer yet his books successively seem the accident of his situation The excellence of his work lies rather in the treatment than the substance primarily there is the pellucid style which he drew from his love of <PERSON>Goldsmith</PERSON> and the charm of his personality shown in his romantic interest his pathos and humour ever growing in delicacy and his familiar touch with humanity He made his name American mainly by creating the legend of the <LOCATION>Hudson</LOCATION> and he alone has linked his memory locally with his country so that it hangs over the landscape and blends with it for ever he owned his nativity too by his pictures of the prairie and the fur trade and by his life of <LOCATION>Washington</LOCATION> who had laid his hand upon his head but he had spent half his life abroad in the temperamental enjoyment of the romantic suggestion of the old world and by his writings he gave this expansion of sympathy and sentiment to his countrymen If his temperament was native born and his literary taste home bred and if his affections gave a legend to the countryside and his feelings expanded with the view of prairie and wilderness and if he sought to honour with his pen the historic associations and memory of the land which had honoured him it was nevertheless the trans <LOCATION>Atlantic</LOCATION> touch that had loosed his genius and mainly fed it and this fact was prophetic of the immediate course of American literature and the most significant in his career <PERSON>Cooper</PERSON> s initiation into literature was similar to that of Irving He had received perhaps something more of scanty formal education since he attended <ORGANIZATION>Cooper Yale College</ORGANIZATION> for a season but he early took to the sea and was a midshipman He was thirty years old before he began to write and it was almost an accident that after the failure of his first novel he finished The Spy so deterring was the prejudice that no American book could succeed He was however a man of great energy of life great force of will it was his nature to persist The way once opened he wrote voluminously and with great unevenness His literary defects both of surface and construction are patent It was not by style nor by any detail of plot or character that he excelled but whatever imperfections there might be his work was alive it had body motion fire He chose his subjects from aspects of life familiar to him in the woods or on the sea or from patriotic memories near to him in the fields of the Revolution He thus established a vital connexion with his own country and in so far he is the most national by his themes of any of the American writers What he gave was the scene of the new world both in the forest and by the fires of the Revolution and on the swift and daring American ships but it was especially by his power to give the sense of the primitive wilderness and the ocean weather and adventure there that he won success In <LOCATION>France</LOCATION> where he was popular this came as an echo out of the real world of the west to the dream of nature that had lately grown up in French literature and besides of all the springs of interest native to men in every land adventure in the wild is perhaps the easiest to touch the quickest and most inflaming to respond <PERSON>Cooper</PERSON> stood for a true element in American experience and conditions for the romance in the mere presence of primeval things of nature newly found by man and opening to his coming this was an imaginative moment and <PERSON>Cooper</PERSON> seized it by his imagination He especially did so in the Indian elements of his tale and gave permanent ideality to the Indian type The trait of loftiness which he thus incorporated belongs with the impression of the virgin forest and prairie the breadth the silence and the music of universal nature The distinction of his work is to open so great a scene worthily to give it human dignity in rough and primitive characters seen in the simplicity of their being and to fill it with peril resourcefulness and hardihood It is the only brave picture of life in the broad from an American pen <PERSON>Scott</PERSON> in inventing the romantic treatment of history in fiction was the leader of the historical novel but <PERSON>Cooper</PERSON> except in so far as he employed the form was not in a true sense an imitator of <PERSON>Scott</PERSON> he did not create nor think nor feel in <PERSON>Scott</PERSON> s way and he came far short of the deep human power of <PERSON>Scott</PERSON> s genius He was not great in character but he was great in adventure manly spirit and the atmosphere of the natural world an Odysseyan writer who caught the moment of the American planting in vivid and characteristic traits This same spirit but limited to nature in her most elemental forms and having the simplest generic relations to human life characterizes <PERSON>Bryant</PERSON> He too had slender academic training <PERSON>Bryantand</PERSON> came from the same social origins as <PERSON>Irving</PERSON> and <PERSON>Cooper</PERSON> but owing to his extraordinary boyish precocity the family influences upon him and the kind of home he was bred in are more clearly seen He framed his art in his boyhood on the model of 18th century verse and though he felt the liberalizing influences of <PERSON>Wordsworth</PERSON> later there always remained in his verse a sense of form that suggests a severer school than that of his English contemporaries He lived the life of a journalist and public man in <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> but the poet in him was a man apart and he jealously guarded his talent in seclusion Though he was at times abroad he resembled <PERSON>Cooper</PERSON> in being unaffected by foreign residence he remained home bred He wrote a considerable quantity of verse but it is by a quality in it rather than by its contents that his poetry is recalled and this quality exists most highly in the few pieces that are well known To no verse is the phrase native wood notes wild more properly applied His poetry gives this deep impression of privacy high clear brief in voice and yet as it were as of something hidden in the sky or grove or brook or as if the rock spoke it is nature in her haunts it is the voice of the peak the forests the cataracts the smile of the blue gentian the distant rosy flight of the water fowl with no human element less simple than piety death or the secular changes of time It is too an expression of something so purely American that it seems that it must be as uncomprehended by one not familiar with the scene as the beauty of <LOCATION>Greece</LOCATION> or Italian glows it is poetry locked in its own land This presence of the pure the pristine the virginal in the verse this luminousness spaciousness serenity in the land this immemorialness of natural things is the body and spirit of the true wild such as <PERSON>Bryant</PERSON> s eyes had seen it and as it had possessed his soul In no other American poet is there this nearness to original awe in the presence of nature nowhere is nature so slightly humanized so cosmically felt and yet poetized Poetry of this sort must be small in amount a few hundred lines contain it all but they alone shrine the original grandeur not so much of the American landscape as of wild nature when first felt in the primitive American world American romanticism thus began with these three writers who gave it characterization after all by only a few simple traits There was in it no profound passion nor philosophy nor revolt especially there was no morbidness It was sprung from a new soil The breath of the early American world was in <PERSON>Bryant</PERSON> s poetry he had freed from the landscape a Druidical nature worship of singular purity simple and grand unbound by any conventional formulas of thought or feeling but deeply spiritual The new life of the land filled the scene of <PERSON>Cooper</PERSON> prairie forest and sea Indians backwoodsmen and sailors the human struggle of all kinds gave it diversity and detail but its life was the American spirit the epic action of a people taking primitive possession battling with its various foes making its world <ORGANIZATION>Irving</ORGANIZATION> more brooding and reminiscent gave legend to the landscape transformed rudeness with humour and brought elements of picturesqueness into play and in him in whom the new race was more mature was first shown that nostalgia for the past which is everywhere a romantic trait but was peculiarly strong under American conditions He was consequently more free in imagination than the others and first dealt with other than American subjects emancipating literature from provinciality of theme while the modes of his romantic treatment the way he felt about his subjects still owed much to his American birth In all this literature by the three writers there was little complexity and there was no strangeness in their personalities <PERSON>Irving</PERSON> was more genially human <PERSON>Cooper</PERSON> more vitally intense <PERSON>Bryant</PERSON> was the more careful artist in the severe limits of his art which was simple and plain Simplicity and plainness characterize all three they were in truth simple American gentlemen of the breeding and tastes that a plain democracy produced as its best who giving themselves to literature for a career developed a native romanticism which however obvious and uncomplicated with philosophy passion or moods represented the first stage of American life with freshness of power an element of ideal loftiness and much literary charm Though <PERSON>Irving Cooper</PERSON> and <PERSON>Bryant</PERSON> were associated with <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> there was something sporadic in their germination They have no common source they stood apart and their work neither overlapped nor blended but remained self isolated None of them can be said to haveGeneral progress founded a school but <PERSON>Irving</PERSON> left a literary tradition and <PERSON>Cooper</PERSON> had followers in the field of historical fiction The literary product up to the middle of the century presents generally from its early years the appearance of an indistinguishable mass as in colonial days in which neither titles nor authors are eminent The association of American literature with the periodical press is perhaps the most important trait to be observed <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Philadelphia</LOCATION> were book markets and local presses had long been at work issuing many reprints Magazines in various degrees of importance sprang up in succession to the earlier imitations of English 18th century periodicals which abounded at the beginning of the century and as time went on these were accompanied by a host of annuals of the English Keepsake variety <LOCATION>Philadelphia</LOCATION> was especially distinguished by an early fertility in magazines which later reached a great circulation as in the case of <PERSON>Godey</PERSON> s and <PERSON>Graham</PERSON> s the <PERSON>Knickerbocker</PERSON> became prominent in <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> from 1833 when it was founded <LOCATION>Richmond</LOCATION> had in The Southern Literary Messenger the chief patron of southern writers from 1834 and there were abortive ventures still farther south in <LOCATION>Charleston</LOCATION> These various periodicals and like publications were the literary arena the place of ambition for young and old for known and unknown and there literary fame and what little money came of its pursuit were found Minor poetry flourished in it sketches tales essays every sort of writing in prose multiplied there A change in the atmosphere of letters is also to be noted The 18th century was fairly left behind The Philadelphian reprint of <LOCATION>Galignani</LOCATION> s <LOCATION>Paris</LOCATION> edition of <PERSON>Keats Shelley</PERSON> and <PERSON>Coleridge</PERSON> had brought in the new romantic poetry with wide effect and <PERSON>Disraeli Bulwer</PERSON> and later <PERSON>Dickens</PERSON> are felt in the prose in verse especially by women <PERSON>Mrs Hemans</PERSON> and <PERSON>Mrs Browning</PERSON> ruled the moment The product was large In poetry it was displayed on the most comprehensive scale in <PERSON>Rufus Wilmot Griswold</PERSON> s 1815 1857 collections of American verse made in the middle of the century Mrs <PERSON>Lydia Sigourney</PERSON> 1791 1865 a prolific writer and <PERSON>Mrs Maria Gowan Brooks</PERSON> 1795 1845 known as <PERSON>Southey</PERSON> s <ORGANIZATION>Maria del Occidente</ORGANIZATION> a more ambitious aspirant the <PERSON>Davidson</PERSON> sisters 1808 1825 1823 1838 and <PERSON>Alice</PERSON> 1820 1871 and <PERSON>Phoebe Cary</PERSON> 1824 1871 illustrate the work of the women and <PERSON>Richard Henry Wilde</PERSON> 1789 1847 <PERSON>George Pope Morris</PERSON> 1802 1864 <PERSON>Charles Fenno Hoffman</PERSON> 1806 1884 and <PERSON>Willis Gaylord Clark</PERSON> 1810 1841 may serve for that of men In this verse and in the abundant prose as well the sentimentality of the period is strongly marked it continued to the times of the Civil War Two poets of a better type <PERSON>Joseph Rodman Drake</PERSON> 1795 1820 distinguished by delicacy of fancy and <PERSON>Fitz Greene Halleck</PERSON> 1790 1867 who showed ardour and a real power of phrase are remembered from an earlier time for their brotherhood in verse but <PERSON>Drake</PERSON> died young and <PERSON>Halleck</PERSON> was soon sterilized so that the talents of both proved abortive The characteristic figure that really exemplifies this secondary literature at its best is <PERSON>Nathaniel Parker Willis</PERSON> 1806 1867 who though born in <LOCATION>Portland Maine</LOCATION> was the chief litt rateur of the Knickerbocker period He wrote abundantly in both verse and prose and was the first of the journalist type of authors a social adventurer with facile powers of literary entertainment a man of the town and immensely popular He was the sentimentalist by profession and his work transitory as it proved was typical of a large share of the taste talent and ambition of the contemporary crowd of writers Neighbouring him in time and place are the authors of various stripe known as the Literati whom <PERSON>Poe</PERSON> described in his critical papers which in connexion with <PERSON>Griswold</PERSON> s collections mentioned above are the principal current source of information concerning the bulk of American literature in that period This world of the magazines the Literati and sentimentalism was the true milieu of <PERSON>Edgar Allan Poe</PERSON> 1809 1849 Born in <LOCATION>Boston</LOCATION> his mother a pleasing English actress and his father a dissipated stage struck youth of a <LOCATION>Baltimore</LOCATION> family left an orphan in childhood <PERSON>Poe</PERSON> he was reared in the Virginian home of <PERSON>John Allan</PERSON> a merchant of Scottish extraction he received there the stamp of southern character He was all his life characteristically a southerner with southern ideals of character and conduct southern manners towards both men and women and southern passions He showed precocity in verse but made his real d but in prose as editor of The Southern Literary Messenger at <LOCATION>Richmond</LOCATION> in 1835 He was by his talents committed to a literary career and being usually without definite means of support he followed the literary market first to <LOCATION>Philadelphia</LOCATION> and later to <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> He was continuously associated with magazines as editor reviewer or contributor they were his means of sustenance and whether as cause or effect this mode of life fell in with the nature of his mind which was a contemporary mind He was perhaps better acquainted with contemporary work in literature than any of his associates he took his first cues from <PERSON>Disraeli</PERSON> and <PERSON>Bulwer</PERSON> and <PERSON>Moore</PERSON> and he was earliest to recognize <PERSON>Tennyson</PERSON> and <PERSON>Mrs Browning</PERSON> his principal reading was always in the magazines He was however more than a man of literary temperament like <PERSON>Irving</PERSON> and <PERSON>Cooper</PERSON> he was a child of genius As in their case there was something sporadic in his appearance on the scene He had no American origins but only American conditions of life In fact he bore little relation to his period and so far as he was influenced it was for the worse he transcended the period essentially in all his creative work He chose for a form of expression the sketch tale or short story and he developed it in various ways From the start there was a melodramatic element in him itself a southern trait and developed by the literary influence of <PERSON>Disraeli</PERSON> and <PERSON>Bulwer</PERSON> on his mind He took the tale of mystery as his special province and receiving it as a mystery that was to be explained after the recent masters of it he saw its fruitful lines of development in the fact that science had succeeded to superstition as the source of wonder and also in the use of ratiocination as a mode of disentanglement in the detective story Brilliant as his success was in these lines his great power lay in the tale of psychological states as a mode of impressing the mind with the thrill of terror the thrall of fascination the sense of mystery It is by his tales in these several sorts that he won more slowly than <PERSON>Irving</PERSON> or <PERSON>Cooper</PERSON> and effectually only after his death continental reputation at present no American author is so securely settled in the recognition of the world at large and he owes this similarly to <PERSON>Cooper</PERSON> to the power of mystery over the human mind universally that is he owes it to his theme seconded by a marvellous power to develop it by the methods of art He thus added new traits to American romanticism but as in the case of <ORGANIZATION>Irving</ORGANIZATION> s Spanish studies there is no American element in the theme he is detached from his local world and works in the sphere of universal human nature nor in his treatment is there any trace of his American birth He is a world author more purely than any other American writer Though it is on his tales that his continental reputation necessarily rests his temperament is more subtly expressed in his verse in which that fond of which his tales are the logical and intelligible growth gives out images and rhythms the issue of morbid states which affect the mind rather as a form of music than of thought Emotion was in art his constant aim though it might be only so simple a thing as the emotion of colour as in his landscape studies and in his verse by an unconscious integration and flow of elements within him it must be thought he obtained emotional effects by images which have no intellectual value and which float in rhythms so as to act musically on the mind and arouse pure moods of feeling absolutely free of any other contents Such poems must be an enigma to most men but others are accessible to them and derive from them an original and unique pleasure they belong outside of the intellectual sphere It is by virtue of this musical quality and immediacy that his poetry is characterized by genius in proportion as it has meaning of an intelligible sort it begins to fade and lower so far as <PERSON>Lenore</PERSON> and <PERSON>Annie</PERSON> and <PERSON>Annabel Lee</PERSON> are human they are feeble ghosts of that sentimentality which was so rife in <PERSON>Poe</PERSON> s time and so maudlin in his own personal relations and except for a half dozen pieces in which his quality of rhythmical fascination is supreme his verse as a whole is inferior to the point of being commonplace Small as the quantity of his true verse is it more sustains his peculiar genius in American eyes than does his prose and this is because it is so unique He stands absolutely alone as a poet with none like him in his tales as an artist he is hardly less solitary but he has some ties of connexion or likeness with the other masters of mystery <PERSON>Poe</PERSON> lived in poverty and died in misery but without him romanticism in <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> would lose its most romantic figure and American literature the artist who most of all its writers had the passion of genius for its work <PERSON>Poe</PERSON> left even less trace of himself in the work of others than did <PERSON>Irving Cooper</PERSON> and <PERSON>Bryant</PERSON> He stands in succession to them and closed the period so far as it contributed to American romanticism anything distinguished original or permanent The ways already opened had however been trod and most notably in fiction The treatment of manners and customs essentially in <ORGANIZATION>Irving</ORGANIZATION> s vein was pleasingly cultivated in <LOCATION>Maryland</LOCATION> by <PERSON>John Pendleton Kennedy</PERSON> 1795 1870 in Swallow Barn 1832 and similar tales of Old Dominion life In <LOCATION>Virginia Beverly Tucker</LOCATION> 1784 1851 in The Partisan Leader 1836 noticeable for its prophecy of secession and <PERSON>John Esten Cooke</PERSON> 1830 1886 in The Virginia Comedians 1854 also won a passing reputation The champion in the south however was <PERSON>William Gilmore Simms</PERSON> 1806 1870 born in <LOCATION>Charleston</LOCATION> a voluminous writer of both prose and verse who undertook to depict on the same scale as <PERSON>Cooper</PERSON> and in his manner the settlement of the southern territory and its Indian and revolutionary history but of his many novels of which the characteristic examples are The Yemassee 1835 The Partisan 1835 and <PERSON>Beauchampe</PERSON> 1842 none attained literary distinction The sea novel was developed by <PERSON>Herman Melville</PERSON> 1819 1891 in Typee 1846 and its successors but these tales in spite of their being highly commended by lovers of adventure have taken no more hold than the work of <ORGANIZATION>Simms Single</ORGANIZATION> novels of wide popularity appeared from time to time of which a typical instance was The Wide Wide World 1850 by <PERSON>Susan Warner</PERSON> 1819 1885 The grade of excellence was best illustrated perhaps for the best current fiction which was not to be incorporated in literature by the novels of <PERSON>Catharine Maria Sedgwick</PERSON> 1789 1867 of a western <LOCATION>Massachusetts</LOCATION> family in Hope Leslie 1827 and its successors The distinct Knickerbocker strain was best preserved by <PERSON>James Kirke Paulding</PERSON> 1778 1860 among the direct imitators of <ORGANIZATION>Irving</ORGANIZATION> but the better part of the <ORGANIZATION>Irving</ORGANIZATION> tradition its sentiment social grace and literary flavour was not noticeable until it awoke in <PERSON>George William Curtis</PERSON> 1824 1892 born a New Englander but like <PERSON>Bryant</PERSON> a journalist and public man of <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> whose novels notes of travel and casual brief social essays brought that urbane style to an end as in <PERSON>Donald Grant Mitchell</PERSON> born 1822 the school of sentiment descended from the same source died not unbecomingly in the Reveries of a Bachelor 1850 and Dream Life 1851 Two poets just subsequent to <PERSON>Poe George Henry Boker</PERSON> 1823 1890 and <PERSON>Thomas Buchanan</PERSON> Read 1822 1872 won a certain distinction the former especially in the drama in the <LOCATION>Philadelphia</LOCATION> group The single popular songs The Star Spangled Banner 1813 by <PERSON>Francis Scott</PERSON> Key 1779 1843 of <LOCATION>Maryland America</LOCATION> 1832 by <PERSON>Samuel Francis Smith</PERSON> 1808 1895 of <LOCATION>Massachusetts</LOCATION> and Home Sweet Home 1823 by <PERSON>John Howard Payne</PERSON> 1792 1852 of <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> may also be appropriately recorded here The last distinct literary personality to emerge from the miscellany of talent in the middle of the century in the middle <LOCATION>Atlantic</LOCATION> states was <PERSON>James Bayard Taylor</PERSON> 1825 1878 who characteristically a journalist gained reputation by his travels poems and novels but in spite of brilliant versatility and a high ambition failed to obtain permanent distinction His translation of Faust 1870 is his chief title to remembrance but the later cultivation of the oriental motive in American lyrical poetry owes something to his example In <LOCATION>New England</LOCATION> which succeeded to <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> as the chief source of literature of high distinction the progress of culture in the post Revolutionary period was as normal and gradual as elsewhere in the country there was noNew <LOCATION>England</LOCATION> scholar ship violence of development no sudden break but the growth of knowledge and taste went slowly on in conjunction with the softening of the Puritan foundation of thought belief and practice What most distinguished literature in <LOCATION>New England</LOCATION> from that to the west and south was its connexion with religion and scholarship neither of which elements was strong in the literature that has been described The neighbourhood of <ORGANIZATION>Harvard College</ORGANIZATION> to <LOCATION>Boston</LOCATION> was a powerful influence in the field of knowledge and critical culture The most significant fact in respect to scholarship however was the residence abroad of <PERSON>George Ticknor</PERSON> 1791 1871 author of The History of Spanish Literature 1849 of <PERSON>Edward Everett</PERSON> 1794 1865 the orator and of <PERSON>George Bancroft</PERSON> 1800 1891 author of the History of the <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> 1834 1874 who as young men brought back new ideals of learning The social connexion of <LOCATION>Boston</LOCATION> not only with <LOCATION>England</LOCATION> but with the continent was more constant varied and intimate than fell to the fortune of any other city and owing to the serious temper of the community the intellectual commerce with the outer world through books was more profound <PERSON>Coleridge</PERSON> was early deeply influential on the thought of the cultivated class and to him <PERSON>Carlyle</PERSON> who found his first sincere welcome and effectual power there succeeded The influence of both combined to introduce and to secure attention for German writers Translation as time went on followed and German thought was also further sustained and advanced in the community by <PERSON>Frederick Henry Hedge</PERSON> 1805 1890 a philosophical theologian who conducted a propaganda of German ideas The activity of the group about him is significantly marked by the issue of the series of Specimens of Foreign Standard Literature 1838 edited by <PERSON>George Ripley</PERSON> 1802 1880 the critic which was the first of its kind in America French ideas as time went on were also current and the field of research extended to the Orient the writings of which were brought forward especially in connexion with the Transcendental Movement to which all these foreign studies contributed In <LOCATION>New England</LOCATION> in other words a close serious and vital connexion was made for the first time with the philosophic thought of the world and with its tradition even in the remote past Unitarianism which was the form in which the old Puritanism dissolved in the cultivated class came in with the beginning of the century and found its representative in the gentle character refined intelligence and liberal humanity of <PERSON>William Ellery Channing</PERSON> 1780 1842 who has remained its chief apostle It was the expression of a moral maturing and intellectual enlightenment that took place with as little disturbance as ever marked religious evolution in any community The people at large remained evangelical but they also felt in a less degree the softening and liberalizing tendency nevertheless it was mainly in the field of Unitarianism that literature flourished as was natural and Transcendentalism was a phenomenon that grew out of Unitarianism being indeed the excess of the movement of enlightenment and the extreme limit of intuitionalism individualism and private judgment These two factors religion and scholarship gave to <LOCATION>New England</LOCATION> literature its serious stamp and academic quality but the preparatory stage being longer it was slower to emerge than the literature of the rest of the country The first stirrings of romanticism in <LOCATION>New England</LOCATION> were felt as in the country to the south by men of literary temperament in a sympathetic enjoyment and feeble imitation of the contemporary English romantic school of fiction exemplified by <PERSON>Mrs Radcliffe Lewis</PERSON> and <PERSON>Godwin Washington Allston</PERSON> 1779 1843 the painter born in <LOCATION>South Carolina</LOCATION> but by education and adoption a citizen of <LOCATION>Cambridge</LOCATION> showed the taste in Monaldi 1841 and <PERSON>Richard Henry Dana</PERSON> 1787 1879 in <PERSON>Paul Felton</PERSON> 1833 in his poem of the same date The Buccaneer the pseudo Byronic element which belongs to the conception of character and passion in this school of fiction appears These elder writers illustrate rather the stage of imaginative culture at the period and show by their other works also <LOCATION>Allston</LOCATION> by his poems The Sylphs of the Seasons 1813 and <PERSON>Dana</PERSON> by his abortive periodical The Idle Man 1821 issued at <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> their essential sympathy with the literary conditions reigning before the time of Irving They both were post Revolutionary and advanced American culture in other fields rather than imagination <LOCATION>Allston</LOCATION> in art and <PERSON>Dana</PERSON> in criticism as editor of The <ORGANIZATION>North American Review</ORGANIZATION> which was founded in 1815 and was long the chief organ of serious thought and critical learning influential in the dissemination of ideas and in the maintenance of the intellectual life The influence of their personality in the community like that of Channing with whom they were closely connected was of more importance than any of their works The definite moment of the appearance of <LOCATION>New England</LOCATION> in literature in the true sense was marked by <PERSON>Ralph Waldo Emerson</PERSON> s 1803 1882 Nature 1836 <PERSON>Nathaniel Hawthorne</PERSON> s 1804 1864 Twice Told Tales 1837 and <PERSON>Henry Wadsworth Longfellow</PERSON> s 1807 1882 Voices of the Night 1839 Of this group of men <LOCATION>Longfellow</LOCATION> is the most national figure and from the point of view of literary history the most significant by virtue of what he contributed to American romanticism in the large He felt the conscious desire of the people forEmerson <PERSON>Hawthorne Longfellow</PERSON> an American literature and he obeyed it in the choice of his subjects He took national themes and his work is in this respect the counterpart in poetry to that of <PERSON>Cooper</PERSON> in prose In <LOCATION>Hiawatha</LOCATION> 1855 he poetized the Indian life and though the scene and figures of the poem are no more localized than the happy hunting grounds the ideal of the life of the aborigines in the wilderness is given with freshness and primitive charm and with effect on the imagination It is the sole survivor of many poetic attempts to naturalize the Indian in literature and will remain the classic Indian poem In Evangeline 1847 The Courtship of Miles Standish 1858 and The <LOCATION>New England</LOCATION> Tragedies 1868 he depicted colonial life As he thus embodied national tradition in one portion of his work he rendered national character in another and with more spontaneity in those domestic poems of childhood and the affections simple moods of the heart in the common lot which most endeared him as the poet of the household These are American poems as truly as his historical verse though they are also universal for the English race In another large portion of his work he brought back from the romantic tradition of <LOCATION>Europe</LOCATION> after <ORGANIZATION>Irving</ORGANIZATION> s manner motives which he treated for their pure poetic quality detached from anything American and he also translated much foreign verse from the north and the south of <LOCATION>Europe</LOCATION> including <PERSON>Dante</PERSON> s Divine Comedy 1867 He has more than any other single writer reunited <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> with the poetic past of <LOCATION>Europe</LOCATION> particularly in its romance The same serenity of disposition that marked <PERSON>Irving</PERSON> and <PERSON>Bryant</PERSON> characterized his life and his art more varied than <PERSON>Bryant</PERSON> s or <ORGANIZATION>Irving</ORGANIZATION> s has the same refinement being simple and so limpid as to deceive the reader into an oblivion of its quality and sometimes into an unwitting disparagement of what seems so plain and natural as to be commonplace In <LOCATION>Longfellow</LOCATION> as in <ORGANIZATION>Irving</ORGANIZATION> one is struck by that quietude which is so prevailing a characteristic of American literature and which proceeds from its steady and even flow from sources that never knew any disturbance or perturbation The life the art the moods are all calm deep passion is absent <PERSON>Hawthorne</PERSON> was endowed with a soul of more intense brooding but he remained within the circle of this peace He developed in solitude exquisite grace of language and in other respects was an artist the mate of <PERSON>Poe</PERSON> in the tale and exceeding <PERSON>Poe</PERSON> in significance since he used symbolism for effects of truth He like <PERSON>Longfellow</PERSON> embodied the national tradition in this case the Puritan past but he seized the subject not in its historical aspects and diversity of character and event but psychologically in its moral passion in The Scarlet Letter 1850 and less abstractly more picturesquely more humanly in its blood tradition in The House of the Seven Gables In his earlier work as an artist he shows the paucity of the materials in the environment especially in his tales but when his residence in <LOCATION>Italy</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>England</LOCATION> gave into his hands larger opportunity he did not succeed so well in welding <LOCATION>Italy</LOCATION> with <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> in The Marble Faun 1860 or <LOCATION>England</LOCATION> with <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> in his experimental attempts at the work which he left uncompleted as he had done in the Puritan romances He had however added a new domain to American romanticism and most of all these writers he blended moral truth with fiction he indeed spiritualized romance and without loss of human reality a rare thing in any literature Both <PERSON>Longfellow</PERSON> and <PERSON>Hawthorne</PERSON> were happy in reconciling their art with their country both not less than <PERSON>Poe</PERSON> were universal artists but they incorporated the national past in their art and were thereby more profoundly American <PERSON>Emerson</PERSON> whose work lay in the religious sphere not unlike <PERSON>Jonathan Edwards</PERSON> at an earlier time of climax but in a different way marked the issue of Puritanism in pure idealism and was more contemporaneously associated with life in the times than were the purely imaginative writers He was the central figure of Transcendentalism and apart from his specific teachings stood for the American spirit disengaged from authority independent personal responsible only to himself He reached a revolutionary extreme but he had not arrived at it by revolutionary means without storm or stress with characteristic peacefulness he came to the great denials and without much concerning himself with them turned to his own affirmations of spiritual reality methods of life and personal results Serenity was his peculiar trait amid all the agitation about him he was entirely unmoved lived calmly and wrote with placid power concentrating into the slowly wrought sentences of his Essays 1841 1875 the spiritual essence and moral metal of a life lived to God to himself and to his fellow men He more than any other single writer reunited American thought with the philosophy of the world more than all others he opened the ways of liberalism wherever they may lead He was an emancipator of the mind In his Poems 1847 1867 though the abstract and the concrete often find themselves awkward mates his philosophic ideas are put forth under forms of imagination and his personal life is expressed with nobility his poetic originality though so different in kind is as unique as <PERSON>Poe</PERSON> s and reaches a height of imaginative faculty not elsewhere found in American verse His poetry belongs more peculiarly to universal art so pure in general is its philosophic content and so free from any temporal trait is the style but it is as distinguished for the laconic expression of American ideas minted with one blow as his prose is for the constant breathing of the American spirit It is the less possible to define the American traits in <LOCATION>Emerson</LOCATION> because they constituted the man He was as purely an American type as Lincoln The grain of the man is in his work also and the best that his prose and verse contain is his personal force In him alone is genius felt as power in the others it impresses one primarily as culture modes of artistic faculty phases of temperament In this too he brings to mind <PERSON>Jonathan Edwards</PERSON> the other climax of the religious spirit in <LOCATION>New England</LOCATION> in Edwards it was intellectual power in <LOCATION>Emerson</LOCATION> it was moral power in both it was indigenous power springing from what was most profound in the historic life of the community Three other names <PERSON>John Greenleaf</PERSON> Whittier 1807 1892 <PERSON>Oliver Wendell Holmes</PERSON> 1809 1894 <PERSON>James Russell Lowell</PERSON> 1819 1891 complete the group of the greater writers of <LOCATION>New England</LOCATION> <PERSON>Whittier Holmes Lowell Holmes</PERSON> was a more local figure by his humour and wit and his mental acuteness a <ORGANIZATION>Yankee</ORGANIZATION> and having the flavour of race but neither in his verse nor his novels reaching a high degree of excellence and best known by The Autocrat of the Breakfast Table 1858 which is the <ORGANIZATION>Yankee</ORGANIZATION> prose classic His contemporary reputation was largely social and owed much to the length of his life but his actual hold on literature already seems slight and his work of little permanent value <LOCATION>Whittier</LOCATION> stands somewhat apart as the poet of the soil and also because of his Quakerism he was first eminent as the poet of the anti slavery movement to which he contributed much stirring verse and later secured a broader fame by Snowbound 1866 and his religious poems of simple piety welcome to every faith he was also a balladist of local legends In general he is the voice of the plain people without the medium of academic culture and his verse though of low flight is near to their life and faith <PERSON>Lowell</PERSON> first won distinction by The Biglow Papers 1848 which with the second series 1886 is the Yankee classic in verse and is second only to his patriotic odes in maintaining his poetic reputation his other verse variously romantic in theme and feeling and latterly more kindred to English classic style shows little originality and was never popularly received it is rather the fruit of great talent working in close literary sympathy with other poets whom from time to time he valued His prose consists in the main of literary studies in criticism a field in which he held the first rank Together with <PERSON>Holmes</PERSON> and <LOCATION>Whittier</LOCATION> he gives greater body diversity and illustration to the literature of <LOCATION>New England</LOCATION> but in the work of none of these is there the initiative or the presence of single genius that characterize <PERSON>Emerson Hawthorne</PERSON> and <PERSON>Longfellow Lowell</PERSON> was a scholar with academic ties a patriot above party master of prose and verse highly developed and finished and at times of a lofty strain owing to his moral enthusiasm <LOCATION>Whittier</LOCATION> was a <ORGANIZATION>Quaker</ORGANIZATION> priest vigorous in a great cause of humanity with fluent power to express in poetry the life of the farm the roadside and the legends that were like folklore in the memory of the settlement <PERSON>Holmes</PERSON> was a town wit and master of occasional verse with notes here and there of a higher strain in single rare poems The secondary literature that accompanied the work of these writers was abundant It was largely the product of Transcendentalism and much of it gathered about <ORGANIZATION>Emerson</ORGANIZATION> In The Dial 1840 Transcen dentalism the organ of Transcendentalism he introduced to the public his young friend <PERSON>Henry David Thoreau</PERSON> 1817 1862 author of Walden 1854 and the father of the nature writers who as a hermit type has had some European vogue and shows an increasing hold as an exception among men but whose work has little literary distinction and together with him his companion <PERSON>William Ellery Channing</PERSON> 1818 1901 a poet who has significance only in the transcendentalist group With them should be named <PERSON>Emerson</PERSON> s coeval <PERSON>Amos Bronson Alcott</PERSON> 1799 1888 the patriarch of the so called <ORGANIZATION>Concord</ORGANIZATION> philosophers better esteemed for his powers of monologue than as a writer in either prose or verse <PERSON>Emerson</PERSON> s associate editor in The Dial was <PERSON>Sarah Margaret Fuller</PERSON> afterwards Marchioness d <PERSON>Ossoli</PERSON> 1810 1850 a woman of extraordinary qualities and much usefulness who is best remembered by her Woman in the Nineteenth Century 1844 but contributed no permanent work to literature She was a leading figure at <ORGANIZATION>Brook Farm</ORGANIZATION> the socialistic community founded by members of the group and especially by <PERSON>Ripley</PERSON> who like her afterwards emigrated to <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> and together with her began a distinguished critical career in connexion with The <ORGANIZATION>New York Tribune Transcendentalism</ORGANIZATION> produced also its peculiar poet in Jones Very 1813 1881 whose Poems 1839 have original quality though slight merit and its novelist in <PERSON>Sylvester Judd</PERSON> 1813 1853 whose <PERSON>Margaret</PERSON> 1845 is a unique work in American fiction Other transcendentalist poets were <PERSON>Christopher Pearse</PERSON> Cranch 1813 1892 and <PERSON>Charles Timothy Brooks</PERSON> 1813 1883 who translated Faust 1856 besides a score of minor names Outside of this group <PERSON>Thomas William Parsons</PERSON> 1819 1892 who translated <PERSON>Dante</PERSON> s Inferno 1843 was a poet of greater distinction but his product was slight The prose of the movement though abundant yielded nothing that is remembered The literary life of <LOCATION>Boston</LOCATION> was however by no means confined within this circle of thought It was most distinguished in the field of history where indeed the writers rivalled the History imaginative authors in public fame They were besides <PERSON>George Bancroft</PERSON> already mentioned <PERSON>John Gorham Palfrey</PERSON> 1796 1881 author of The History of New England 1858 <PERSON>William Hickling Prescott</PERSON> 1796 1859 whose field was Spanish and Spanish American history <PERSON>John Lothrop Motley</PERSON> 1814 1877 whose attention was given to Dutch history and <PERSON>Jared Sparks</PERSON> 1789 1866 whose work lay in biography In the writings of <PERSON>Prescott</PERSON> and <PERSON>Motley</PERSON> the romanticism of the period is clearly felt and they attained the highest distinction in the literary school of history of the period Oratory also flourished in <PERSON>Daniel Webster</PERSON> 1782 1852 <PERSON>Edward Everett</PERSON> 1794 1865 <PERSON>Rufus Choate</PERSON> 1799 1859 <PERSON>Wendell Phillips</PERSON> 1811 1884 <PERSON>Charles Sumner</PERSON> 1811 1874 and <PERSON>Robert Charles Oratory Winthrop</PERSON> 1809 1894 the last survivor of a long line of fiery or classic oratory in which <LOCATION>New England</LOCATION> was especially distinguished and had rivalry only from <PERSON>Henry Clay</PERSON> 1777 1852 of <LOCATION>Virginia</LOCATION> and <PERSON>John Caldwell Calhoun</PERSON> 1782 1850 of <LOCATION>South Carolina</LOCATION> The church also produced two powerful speakers in <PERSON>Theodore Parker</PERSON> 1810 1860 the protagonist of the liberals in <LOCATION>Boston</LOCATION> and <PERSON>Henry Ward Beecher</PERSON> 1813 1887 who sustained a liberal form of <LOCATION>New England</LOCATION> congregationalism in <LOCATION>Brooklyn New York</LOCATION> where he made <ORGANIZATION>Plymouth Church</ORGANIZATION> a national pulpit The single memorable novel of the period was Mrs <PERSON>Harriet Beecher Stowe</PERSON> s 1811 1896 Fiction Uncle <PERSON>Tom</PERSON> s Cabin 1852 which had a world wide vogue it is the chief contribution of the anti slavery movement to American literature and stands for plantation life in the old south Another female writer <PERSON>Mrs Lydia Maria</PERSON> Child 1802 1880 remembered by her Philothea 1836 deserves mention in the line of notable American women who served their generation in literary ways and by devotion to public causes Criticism was served excellently by <PERSON>Edwin Percy Whipple</PERSON> 1819 1885 and less eminently by <PERSON>Henry Theodore Tuckerman</PERSON> 1813 1871 who emigrated to <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> but scholarship in general flourished under the protection of Scholar ship <ORGANIZATION>Harvard College</ORGANIZATION> where <PERSON>Ticknor Longfellow</PERSON> and <PERSON>Lowell</PERSON> maintained a high ideal of literary knowledge and judgment in the chair they successively filled and were accompanied in English by <PERSON>Francis James</PERSON> Child 1825 1896 whose English and Scottish Ballads first issued in 1858 was brought to its final and monumental form in 1892 <PERSON>Cornelius Conway Felton</PERSON> 1807 1862 president of <ORGANIZATION>Harvard College</ORGANIZATION> stood for Greek culture but the classical influence was little in evidence Elsewhere in <LOCATION>New England</LOCATION> George Perkins Marsh 1801 1882 of <LOCATION>Vermont</LOCATION> long minister to <LOCATION>Italy</LOCATION> and <PERSON>William Dwight Whitney</PERSON> 1827 1894 of <ORGANIZATION>Yale</ORGANIZATION> were linguistic scholars of high distinction The development of the colleges into universities was already prophesied in the presence and work of these men Outside of <LOCATION>New England</LOCATION> scholarship had been illustrated in <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> by <PERSON>Charles Anthon</PERSON> 1797 1867 the classical editor by the Duyckincks Evert Augustus 1816 1878 and George Long 1823 1863 editors of the Cyclopaedia of American Literature 1855 and by <PERSON>Giulian Crommelin Verplanck</PERSON> 1786 1870 editor of Shakespeare 1846 <LOCATION>New England</LOCATION> thus standing somewhat apart produced a characteristic literature more deeply rooted in the community than was the case elsewhere and this literature blending with Character istics of <LOCATION>New England</LOCATION> literature what was produced to the south and west became a predominant share of what has been nationally accepted as standard American literature It is also the more profound and scholarly share and if quantity as well as quality be counted and as is proper <PERSON>Bryant</PERSON> be included as the product of Puritan culture it is the more artistic share American standard literature so constituted belongs to romanticism and is a phase of the romanticism which was then the general mood of literature but it is a native product with traits of its own and inward development from local conditions not only apparent by its themes but by its distinct evolution Though it owed much to contact with <LOCATION>Europe</LOCATION> through its travelled scholars and its intellectual commerce by means of translations and imported books and often dealt with matter detached from <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> both in prose and poetry it was essentially self contained It was in a marked way free from the passions whose source was the French Revolution and its after throes from 1789 to 1848 it is by this fact that it differs most from European romanticism Just as the Puritan Rebellion in <LOCATION>England</LOCATION> left the colonies untouched to their own development the political revolutions in <LOCATION>Europe</LOCATION> left the new nation unaffected to its normal evolution There was never any revolution in the French sense in <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> whether social political religious or literary its great historical changes such as the termination of English rule the passing away of Puritanism the abolition of slavery with the consequent destruction of the old <LOCATION>South</LOCATION> were in a true sense conservative changes normal phases of new life In literature this state of things is reflected in the absence in it of any disturbance its serenity of mood its air of quiet studies It is shown especially in its lack of passion The only ardours displayed by its writers are moral patriotic or religious and in none of them is there any sense of conflict The life which they knew was wholesome regular still free from urban corruption the experience of a plain prosperous and law abiding people None of these writers though like <PERSON>Hawthorne</PERSON> they might deal with sin or like <PERSON>Poe</PERSON> with horror and a lover s despair at death struck any tragic note No tragedy was written no love poetry no novel of passion No literature is so maiden pure It is by refinement rather than power that it is most distinguished by taste and cultivation by conscientiousness in art in poetic and stylistic craft it is romance retrospectively seen in the national past or conjured out of foreign lands by reminiscent imagination or symbolically created out of fantasy and this is supplemented by poetry of the domestic affections the simple sorrows all that has been and may be again in daily human lives and by prose similarly related to a well ordered life If it is undistinguished by any work of supreme genius it reflects broadly and happily and in enduring forms the national tradition and character of the land in its dawning century The original impulse of this literature had spent its force by 1861 that is before the Civil War The greater writers had in general already done their characteristic work and though the survivors continued to produce till toward the close of the century their works contained no new element and were at most mellow fruits of age The war itself like the Revolution left little trace in literature beyond a few popular songs and those occasional poems which the older poets wrote in the course of the conflict Their attitude toward it and with the exception of <LOCATION>Whittier</LOCATION> and <PERSON>Lowell</PERSON> toward the anti slavery movement which led up to it was rather that of citizens than of poets though in the verse of <LOCATION>Longfellow</LOCATION> and <PERSON>Emerson</PERSON> there is the noble stamp of the hour the impress of liberty bravery and sorrow <PERSON>Lowell</PERSON> is the exception he found in the Commemoration Ode 1865 his loftiest subject and most enduring fame The work began to fall into new hands and a literature since the war grew up which was however especially in poetry a continuation of romanticism and contained its declining force It was contributed to from all parts of the older country and also from the west and a generation has now added its completed work to the sum No author in this late period has received the national welcome to the same degree as the men of the elder time none has had such personal distinction eminence or public affection and none has found such honourable favour abroad either in <LOCATION>England</LOCATION> or on the continent Poetry has felt the presence of the art of <LOCATION>Tennyson</LOCATION> which has maintained an extreme sensitiveness among the poets to artistic requirements of both material and technique and it also has taken colour from the later English schools It has however yielded its pre eminent position to prose The novel has displaced romance as the highest form of fiction and the essay has succeeded the review as the form of criticism The older colleges have grown into universities and public libraries have multiplied throughout the north and west The literature of information meant for the popularization of knowledge of all kinds has been put forth in great quantity and the annual increase in the production of books keeps pace with the general growth of the country Literature of distinction however makes but a small part of this large mass In poetry the literary tradition was continued in <LOCATION>Boston</LOCATION> by <PERSON>Thomas Bailey Aldrich</PERSON> 1836 1907 essentially a stylist in verse brief definite delicate who carried the lighter graces of Later writers the art refinement wit polish to a high point of excellence His artistic consanguinity is with <PERSON>Herrick</PERSON> and <PERSON>Landor</PERSON> and he takes motive and colour for his verse from every land as his predecessors had done but with effects less rich He divided attention between drama and lyric but as his dramas look strictly to the stage it is on the lyrics that his reputation rests He was master also of an excellent prose and wrote novels sketches of travel and especially stories strongly marked by humour surprise and literary distinction In <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> <PERSON>Edmund Clarence Stedman</PERSON> 1833 1908 became the chief representative of the literary profession He was both poet and critic and won reputation in the former and the first rank in the latter field His Victorian Poets 1875 and Poets of <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> 1885 followed by comprehensive anthologies 1894 1900 together with The Nature and Elements of Poetry 1892 are the principal critical work of his generation and indeed the sole work that is eminent His verse less practised as time went on was well wrought and often distinguished by flashes of spirited song and balladry With him is associated his elder friend <PERSON>Richard Henry Stoddard</PERSON> 1825 1903 who made his appearance before the Civil War and whose verse belongs in general character to the style of that earlier period and is as rapidly forgotten Both <PERSON>Stedman</PERSON> and <PERSON>Stoddard</PERSON> were of <LOCATION>New England</LOCATION> birth as was also the third to be mentioned <PERSON>William Winter</PERSON> born 1836 better known as the lifelong dramatic critic of the metropolis The last of the <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> poets of established reputation <PERSON>Richard Watson Gilder</PERSON> b 1844 in <LOCATION>New Jersey</LOCATION> d 1909 was at first affiliated with the school of <PERSON>Rossetti</PERSON> and his work in general Five Books of Song 1894 strongly marked by artistic susceptibility is in a high degree refined and delicate In the country at large popular success in <LOCATION>England</LOCATION> as well as in <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> was won by <PERSON>Charles Godfrey Leland</PERSON> 1824 1903 in <PERSON>Hans Breitmann</PERSON> s Ballads 1871 humorous poems in the <LOCATION>Pennsylvania</LOCATION> Dutch dialect Born in <LOCATION>Philadelphia</LOCATION> he spent the greater part of his mature life abroad and wrote numerous works on diverse topics but his reputation is chiefly connected with his books on gypsy life and lore Another foreign resident who deserves mention was <PERSON>William Wetmore</PERSON> Story 1819 1895 the sculptor of <LOCATION>Massachusetts</LOCATION> connected with the <ORGANIZATION>Boston</ORGANIZATION> group whose verse and prose gave him the rank of a litterateur The South again entered into literature with the work of <PERSON>Sidney Lanier</PERSON> 1842 1881 in succession to <PERSON>Henry Timrod</PERSON> 1829 1867 and <PERSON>Paul Hamilton Hayne</PERSON> 1830 1886 who find a place rather by the affection in which they are held at the South than by positive merit <PERSON>Lanier</PERSON> showed originality and a true poetic gift but his talents were little effectual From the West humorous poetry was produced by <PERSON>Francis Bret Harte</PERSON> 1839 1902 born in <LOCATION>Albany</LOCATION> in The Heathen Chinee 1870 and similar verse but he is better remembered as the artistic narrator of western mining life in his numerous stories and novels Verse of a similar kind also first brought into literary notice John Hay 1838 1905 in <LOCATION>Pike County</LOCATION> Ballads 1871 who also wrote in prose but his reputation was rather won as a statesman in the closing years of his life Minor poets of less distinction but with a vein superior to that of the earlier period more excellent in workmanship and more coloured with imagination and mood arose in all parts of whom the most notable are <PERSON>Julia Ward Howe</PERSON> born 1819 in <LOCATION>Boston</LOCATION> the venerable friend of many good causes <PERSON>Henry Howard Brownell</PERSON> 1820 1872 of <LOCATION>Rhode Island</LOCATION> author of the most vigorous and realistic poetry of the Civil War War Lyrics 1866 <PERSON>Edward Rowland Sill</PERSON> 1841 1887 born in <LOCATION>Connecticut</LOCATION> but associated with <LOCATION>California</LOCATION> <PERSON>Henry Van Dyke</PERSON> born 1852 in <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> better known by his prose in tale and essay <PERSON>Silas Weir Mitchell</PERSON> born 1830 in <LOCATION>Philadelphia</LOCATION> whose repute as a novelist has overshadowed his admirable verse Eugene Field 1850 1895 of <LOCATION>Chicago</LOCATION> <PERSON>James Whitcomb Riley</PERSON> born 1853 of <LOCATION>Indiana</LOCATION> both distinguished for their humorous and childhood verse and <PERSON>Joaquin Miller</PERSON> born 1841 of <LOCATION>Oregon</LOCATION> whose first work Songs of the Sierras 1871 had in it much of the spirit of the wild land the colour of the desert the free adventurous character of the filibuster all strangely mixed with pseudo Byronic passions Apart from all these whether minor or major poets stands <PERSON>Walt Whitman</PERSON> 1819 1892 whose Leaves of Grass 1855 first appeared before the war but whose fame is associated rather with its <PERSON>Whitman</PERSON> successive editions and its companion volumes and definitely dated perhaps from 1867 He received attention in <LOCATION>England</LOCATION> as did <PERSON>Miller</PERSON> on an assumption that his works expressed the new and original <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> the unknown democracy and he has had some vogue in <LOCATION>Germany</LOCATION> mainly owing to his naturalism His own countrymen however steadily refuse to accept him as representative of themselves and his naturalism is uninteresting to them while on the other hand a group apparently increasing in critical authority treat his work as significant It is in general only by those few fine lyrics which have found a place in all anthologies of American verse that he is well known and highly valued in his own land The chief field of literary activity has been found in the novel and nowhere has the change been so marked as here The romantic treatment of the novel practically disappeared and in its The later novel place came the realistic or analytic treatment rendering manners by minute strokes of observation or dissecting motives psychologically This amounted to a substitution of the French art of fiction in some of its forms for the English tradition of broad ideality and historical picturesqueness The protagonist of the reform was <PERSON>William Dean Howells</PERSON> born 1837 a cultivated literary scholar and a various writer of essays travel sketches poetry and plays editor of many magazines and books whose career in letters has been more laborious and miscellaneous than any other contemporary but whose main work has been the long series of novels that he has put forth almost annually throughout the period He not only wrote fiction but he endeavoured to make known to Americans fiction as it was practised in other lands <LOCATION>Russia Italy Spain</LOCATION> and to bring the art that was dearest to him into line with the standard of the European world He was an apostle of the realistic school and directed his teaching to the advocacy of the novel of observation which records life in its conditions and attempts to realize what is in the daily lives and experience of man rather than what belongs to adventure imagination or the dreaming part of life Of his works The Lady of the Aroostook 1879 The Rise of <PERSON>Silas Lapham</PERSON> 1885 A Hazard of New Fortunes 1889 are characteristic examples He won a popular vogue and if it is now less than it was it is because after a score of years tastes and fashions change The conscientiousness of his art continues the tradition of American writers in that respect and he is master of an affable style His work including all its phases is the most important body of work done in his generation <PERSON>Henry James</PERSON> born 1843 who mainly resided abroad is his compeer and in a similar way has followed French initiative He also has been a various writer of criticism and travel and the occasional essay but his equally long series of novels sustains his reputation He has developed the psychological treatment of fiction and of his work The Portrait of a Lady 1881 The Princess <PERSON>Casamassima</PERSON> 1886 and The Tragic Muse 1890 are characteristic He has had less vogue owing to both matter and style but in certain respects his power more intellectual than that of <PERSON>Howells</PERSON> has greater artistic elements while the society with which he deals is more complex He is really a cosmopolitan writer and has no other connexion with <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> than the accident of birth A third novelist also a foreign resident <PERSON>Francis Marion Crawford</PERSON> 1854 1909 falls into the same category A prolific novelist in the beaten track of story telling he has always a story to tell and excellent narrative power The work regarded as most important from his hand is Saracinesca 1887 and its sequels but his subjects are cosmopolitan his talent is personal and he has no effectual connexion with his own country The romantic tradition of the older time was continued by <PERSON>Lew Wallace</PERSON> 1827 1905 of <LOCATION>Indiana</LOCATION> a distinguished general and diplomat in his Mexican tale The Fair God 1873 and his oriental romances <PERSON>Ben Hur</PERSON> 1880 one of the most widely circulated of American books and The Prince of <LOCATION>India</LOCATION> 1893 A mode of the novel which was wholly unique was practised by <PERSON>Francis Richard Stockton</PERSON> 1834 1902 in his droll tales of which Rudder Grange 1879 is the best known The principal minor product of the novel lay in the provincial tale The new methods easily lent themselves to the portraiture of local conditions types and colour Every part of the country had its writers who recorded its traits in this way For <LOCATION>New England</LOCATION> Mrs <PERSON>Harriet Beecher Stowe</PERSON> described the older life in <LOCATION>Old Town</LOCATION> Folks 1869 and was succeeded by <PERSON>Sarah Orne Jewett</PERSON> 1849 1909 and <PERSON>Mary Eleanor Wilkins</PERSON> born 1862 The <LOCATION>West</LOCATION> was notably treated by <PERSON>Edward Eggleston</PERSON> 1837 1902 in The Hoosier School Master 1871 <PERSON>Mary Hallock Foote</PERSON> born 1847 in Led Horse Claim 1883 and <PERSON>Hamlin Garland</PERSON> born 1860 in Main Travelled Roads 1891 The <LOCATION>South</LOCATION> was represented by <PERSON>Mary Noailles Murfree Charles Egbert Craddock</PERSON> born 1850 in In the <LOCATION>Tennessee Mountains</LOCATION> 1884 and its successors by <PERSON>Thomas Nelson Page</PERSON> born 1853 in <PERSON>Marse Chan</PERSON> 1887 and other tales of the reconstruction in <LOCATION>Virginia</LOCATION> and with most literary grace by <PERSON>George Washington Cable</PERSON> born 1844 whose novels of <LOCATION>Louisiana</LOCATION> are remarkable for their poetic charm The list is sufficiently illustrative of the general movement which made what was called the dialect novel supreme for the season This was succeeded by a revival of the historical novel in local fields of which <PERSON>Winston Churchill</PERSON> born 1871 in <PERSON>Richard Carvel</PERSON> 1899 is the leading exponent and together with it the sword and dagger tale of the <PERSON>Dumas</PERSON> type the special contemporary plot invented by <PERSON>Anthony Hope</PERSON> and romance in its utmost forms of adventure and extravagance came in like a flood at the close of the Spanish War There were during the period from 1870 to 1900 many other writers of fiction who often proceeded in conventional and time honoured ways to tell their tale but none of them is especially significant for the general view or as showing any tendencies of an original sort The pietistic novel for example was produced with immense popularity by <PERSON>Edward Payson Roe</PERSON> 1838 1888 who shared the same vogue as <PERSON>Josiah Gilbert Holland</PERSON> 1819 1881 and both fell heir to the same audience which in the earlier period had welcomed The Wide Wide World with the same broad acceptance The essay and the miscellaneous work which may be classed with it was cultivated with most distinction by <PERSON>Thomas Wentworth Higginson</PERSON> born 1823 one of the <ORGANIZATION>Boston</ORGANIZATION> group a writer of the greatest versatility as Essayists in his life he followed many employments from that of preaching in a Unitarian pulpit to that of commanding a negro regiment in the Civil War He has written good verse and excellent prose and his familiar style often brilliant with life and wit especially becomes the social essay or reminiscent paper in which he excelled and gives agreeableness to his writings in every form <LOCATION>Atlantic</LOCATION> Essays 1871 is a characteristic book and in general in his volumes is to be found a valuable fund of reminiscence about the literature and the times of his long life not elsewhere so abundant or entertaining <PERSON>Charles Dudley Warner</PERSON> 1829 1900 of <LOCATION>Hartford</LOCATION> also in close touch in the later years with the <ORGANIZATION>Boston</ORGANIZATION> group was more gifted with gentle humour and of a literary temperament that made the social essay his natural expression He won popularity by My Summer in a Garden 1870 and was the author of many volumes of travel and several novels but the familiar essay lighted with humour and touched with a reminiscence of the Irving quality in sentiment was his distinctive work The long life of <PERSON>Edward Everett Hale</PERSON> 1822 1909 minister at <LOCATION>Boston</LOCATION> was fruitful in many miscellaneous volumes including fiction of note The Man Without a Country 1868 but the most useful writing from his pen falls into prose resembling the essay in its form and manner of address though cousin too to the sermon <PERSON>John Burroughs</PERSON> b 1837 of <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> carried on in essay form the nature tradition of <PERSON>Thoreau</PERSON> touched with Emersonianism in the thought and after his example books of mingled observation sentiment and literary quality with an out of door atmosphere have multiplied American humour often cultivates a form akin to the essay but it also falls into the mould of the tale or scene from life In the period before the Civil War to sum up the whole subject in this place it had the traits Humour which it has since maintained as its local tang of burlesque extravaganza violence but it recorded better an actual state of manners and scene of life in raw aspects Its noteworthy writers were <PERSON>Seba Smith</PERSON> 1792 1868 of <LOCATION>Maine</LOCATION> author of the Letters of Major Jack Downing which began to appear in the press in 1830 <PERSON>Augustus Baldwin Longstreet</PERSON> of <LOCATION>Georgia</LOCATION> in <LOCATION>Georgia</LOCATION> Scenes 1835 <PERSON>William Tappan Thompson</PERSON> 1812 1882 born in <LOCATION>Ohio</LOCATION> but associated with the South by descent and residence in Major Jones Courtship 1840 a Georgian publication <PERSON>Joseph G Baldwin</PERSON> 1815 1864 in <ORGANIZATION>Flush Times</ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION>Alabama</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Mississippi</LOCATION> 1853 and <PERSON>Benjamin Penhallow Shillaber</PERSON> 1814 1890 in Life and Sayings of Mrs Partington 1854 A fresh form attended by whimsicality appears in <PERSON>George Horatio Derby</PERSON> s 1823 1861 Phoenixiana 1855 In the war times <PERSON>Robert Henry Newell</PERSON> 1836 1901 and <PERSON>David Ross Locke</PERSON> 1833 1888 respectively known as Orpheus C <PERSON>Kerr</PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION>Petroleum V Nasby</ORGANIZATION> cultivated grotesque orthography in a characteristic vein of wit and with more quaintness and drollery <PERSON>Henry Wheeler Shaw</PERSON> 1818 1885 and <PERSON>Charles Farrar Browne</PERSON> 1834 1867 known as <PERSON>Josh Bi