<ner>image National Book Foundation Presenter of the National Book Awards Contact Us Newsletter FAQ Awards Winners amp Finalists 2010s 2000s 1990s 1980s 1970s 1960s 1950s <ORGANIZATION>NBA</ORGANIZATION> by Genre How the NBAs Work Award Deadlines amp Guidelines Online Exhibitions NBA Fiction Winners NBA Fiction Finalists NBA Poetry Winners NBA Young People s Lit Distinguished Contribution to American Letters Literarian Award NBA Finalists Reading Teen Press Conference Medallions Programs Eat Drink amp Be Literary Innovations in Reading NBA On Campus 5 Under 35 <ORGANIZATION>Education Book Rich Environments BookUp NBA</ORGANIZATION> on Campus Teen Press Conference News About Mission amp <ORGANIZATION>History Board</ORGANIZATION> of Directors Staff Careers Form 990 Privacy Policy Support Us Donate Online Donor Recognition National Book Awards 2016 2015 2014 2013 gt 2012 2011 2010 More Information gt Watch the 2012 NBA Finalists Read from their work gt 2012 <ORGANIZATION>NBA</ORGANIZATION> Entry Rules and Guidelines gt 2012 Judges Bios gt <ORGANIZATION>NBA</ORGANIZATION> Winners by Genre Stats In 2012 1 285 books were submitted for the Awards Fiction 311 Nonfiction 479 Poetry 181 Young People s Lit 314 Important Dates Wed October 10 2012 Announcement of 20 Finalist books <ORGANIZATION>MSNBC</ORGANIZATION> s Morning <PERSON>Joe</PERSON> hosted by <PERSON>Joe Scarborough Mika Brzezinski</PERSON> and <PERSON>Willie Geist</PERSON> Between 6 9 a m Tue November 13 2012 Finalists Reading The New School NYC Wed November 14 2012 National Book Awards Ceremony Cipriani Wall Street NYC National Book Awards 2012 FICTION image Fiction Finalists WINNER <PERSON>Louise Erdrich</PERSON> The Round House Harper an imprint of HarperCollinsPublishers gt Interview gt Video of acceptance speech and from Finalists Reading gt Appreciations on Best of National Book Awards Fiction Blog FINALISTS <PERSON>Junot D</PERSON> az This Is How You Lose Her Riverhead Books a member of <ORGANIZATION>Penguin Group USA Inc Interview gt Video</ORGANIZATION> from Finalists Reading gt <PERSON>Dave Eggers</PERSON> A Hologram for the King <PERSON>McSweeney</PERSON> s Books Interview gt Video from Finalists Reading gt <PERSON>Ben Fountain Billy Lynn</PERSON> s Long Halftime Walk Ecco an imprint of <ORGANIZATION>HarperCollinsPublishers Interview gt Video</ORGANIZATION> from Finalists Reading gt Kevin Powers The <ORGANIZATION>Yellow Birds Little Brown and Company Interview</ORGANIZATION> gt Video from Finalists Reading gt FICTION JUDGES <PERSON>Stacey D Erasmo Dinaw Mengestu Lorrie Moore Janet Peery</PERSON> NONFICTION image 2012 NBA Nonfiction Finalists WINNER <PERSON>Katherine Boo</PERSON> Behind the Beautiful Forevers Life Death and Hope in a <ORGANIZATION>Mumbai Undercity Random House</ORGANIZATION> gt Interview gt Video of acceptance speech and from Finalists Reading FINALISTS <PERSON>Anne Applebaum</PERSON> Iron Curtain The Crushing of <LOCATION>Eastern Europe</LOCATION> 1945 1956 <ORGANIZATION>Doubleday Interview</ORGANIZATION> gt <PERSON>Robert</PERSON> A Caro The Passage of Power The Years of <PERSON>Lyndon Johnson</PERSON> Volume 4 <ORGANIZATION>Knopf Domingo Martinez The Boy Kings of Texas Lyons Press</ORGANIZATION> an imprint of <ORGANIZATION>Globe Pequot Press Interview gt Anthony Shadid House of Stone A Memoir of Home Family</ORGANIZATION> and a Lost <LOCATION>Middle East Houghton Mifflin Harcourt Interview</LOCATION> gt NONFICTION JUDGES <PERSON>Brad Gooch Linda Gordon Woody Holton Susan Orlean Judith Shulevitz</PERSON> POETRY image 2012 NBA Poetry Finalists WINNER <PERSON>David</PERSON> Ferry Bewilderment New Poems and <ORGANIZATION>Translations University of Chicago Press</ORGANIZATION> gt Interview gt Video of acceptance speech and from Finalists Reading gt NBA Poetry Blog Essay and <ORGANIZATION>Archival Material for Ferry FINALISTS Cynthia Huntington Heavenly Bodies Southern Illinois University Press Interview gt Tim Seibles Fast Animal Etruscan Press Interview</ORGANIZATION> gt <PERSON>Alan Shapiro</PERSON> Night of the <ORGANIZATION>Republic Houghton Mifflin Harcourt Interview gt Susan Wheeler Meme University of Iowa Press Interview</ORGANIZATION> gt POETRY JUDGES <PERSON>Laura Kasischke Dana Levin Maurice Manning Patrick Rosal Tracy K Smith</PERSON> YOUNG PEOPLE S LITERATURE image 2012 NBA YPL Finalists WINNER <PERSON>William Alexander Goblin</PERSON> Secrets <PERSON>Margaret K McElderry</PERSON> Books an imprint of <ORGANIZATION>Simon amp Schuster Children s Publishing gt Interview</ORGANIZATION> gt Video of acceptance speech and from Finalists Reading FINALISTS Carrie Arcos Out of Reach Simon Pulse an imprint of <ORGANIZATION>Simon amp Schuster Children s Publishing Interview gt Patricia McCormick Never Fall Down Balzer Bray</ORGANIZATION> an imprint of <ORGANIZATION>HarperCollinsPublishers Interview gt Eliot Schrefer Endangered Scholastic Interview</ORGANIZATION> gt <PERSON>Steve Sheinkin</PERSON> Bomb The Race to Build and Steal the World s Most Dangerous Weapon Flash Point an imprint of <ORGANIZATION>Roaring Brook Press Interview</ORGANIZATION> gt Young People s Literature Judges <PERSON>Susan Cooper Daniel Ehrenhaft Judith Ortiz Cofer Gary D Schmidt Marly Youmans</PERSON> 2012 National Book Awards Finalists Announcement <PERSON>Elmore Leonard</PERSON> and <PERSON>Arthur O Sulzberger Jr</PERSON> to Receive 2012 Lifetime Achievement Awards image <PERSON>Martha Southgate</PERSON> by by <PERSON>Tom Rawe</PERSON> at <LOCATION>Cipriani Wall Street</LOCATION> in <LOCATION>New York City</LOCATION> on Wednesday November 14 2012 <LOCATION>New York New York</LOCATION> September 19 2012 The <ORGANIZATION>National Book Foundation</ORGANIZATION> presenter of the National Book Awards will present its 2012 Medal for Distinguished Contribution to American Letters to <PERSON>Elmore Leonard</PERSON> in recognition of his outstanding achievement in fiction writing For over five decades <PERSON>Leonard</PERSON> s westerns crime novels serialized novels and stories have enthralled generations of readers Author <PERSON>Martin Amis</PERSON> will present the Medal to <PERSON>Leonard</PERSON> at the 63rd National Book Awards Ceremony and Benefit Dinner at <LOCATION>Cipriani Wall Street</LOCATION> in <LOCATION>New York City</LOCATION> on Wednesday November 14 2012 Television and radio host political and pop culture commentator journalist and actor <PERSON>Faith Salie</PERSON> will host the event Today s announcement coincides with the announcement by The <ORGANIZATION>Library of America</ORGANIZATION> that it will publish a three volume edition of <PERSON>Leonard</PERSON> s crime novels in its esteemed series beginning in fall 2014 <ORGANIZATION>National Book Foundation</ORGANIZATION> Executive Director <PERSON>Harold Augenbraum</PERSON> said of the selection For a half century <PERSON>Elmore Leonard</PERSON> has produced vibrant literary work with an inimitable writing style We are particularly pleased that as we at the <ORGANIZATION>National Book Foundation</ORGANIZATION> recognize his achievement the <ORGANIZATION>Library of America</ORGANIZATION> which publishes and keeps permanently in print authoritative editions of <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> s best and most significant writing has announced that <PERSON>Leonard</PERSON> will join other great American authors in its literary pantheon image Save the Date for the 2012 <ORGANIZATION>NBA</ORGANIZATION> Dinner and Ceremony Also on that evening the <ORGANIZATION>National Book Foundation</ORGANIZATION> will bestow its 2012 Literarian Award for Outstanding Service to the American Literary Community on <PERSON>Arthur O Sulzberger Jr</PERSON> chairman and publisher of <ORGANIZATION>The New York Times</ORGANIZATION> for his continuing efforts through the <ORGANIZATION>New York Times Book Review</ORGANIZATION> and online book coverage to ensure an ongoing conversation about books in American culture While re thinking and implementing innovative print and online initiatives at the <ORGANIZATION>Times</ORGANIZATION> <PERSON>Sulzberger</PERSON> and the <ORGANIZATION>Times</ORGANIZATION> staff have shown their devotion to the coverage of books whether by profiling authors and their work or reporting on literary culture as a whole It s hard to overstate the impact of The <ORGANIZATION>New York Times</ORGANIZATION> on the discussion about books in <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> <PERSON>Augenbraum</PERSON> said For well over a century The <ORGANIZATION>New York Times</ORGANIZATION> has been central to <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> s book culture <PERSON>Leonard</PERSON> is the twenty fifth recipient of the Medal for Distinguished Contribution to American Letters which was created in 1988 to recognize a lifetime of literary achievement Previous recipients include <PERSON>John Ashbery Toni Morrison John Updike Norman Mailer Joan Didion Maxine Hong Kingston Gore Vidal</PERSON> and <PERSON>Tom Wolfe</PERSON> This year s ceremony marks the eighth year that the <ORGANIZATION>Foundation</ORGANIZATION> has presented the Literarian Award which was established in 2005 to recognize an individual whose work has enhanced the literary world during a lifetime of service Previous recipients include <PERSON>Lawrence Ferlinghetti Robert B Silvers</PERSON> and <PERSON>Barbara Epstein Terry Gross Barney Rosset Dave Eggers Joan Ganz Cooney</PERSON> and <PERSON>Mitchell Kaplan</PERSON> Nominations for these awards are made by former National Book Award Winners Finalists and Judges as well as other writers and literary professionals from around the country Final selections are made by the <ORGANIZATION>National Book Foundation s Board</ORGANIZATION> of Directors The twenty Finalists for the National Book Awards in Fiction Nonfiction Poetry and Young People s Literature will be announced on Wednesday October 10 2012 63rd National Book Awards Ceremony and Benefit Dinner image Faith Salie Faith <PERSON>Salie Host Faith Salie</PERSON> is a television and national public radio host political and pop culture commentator interviewer ethics expert journalist and actor as well as a Rhodes Scholar who s been a standup comedian She s written for <PERSON>Oprah</PERSON> com Slate com and <ORGANIZATION>CNN</ORGANIZATION> com and The Huffington Post She was the host and co executive producer of the national public radio show Fair Game from <ORGANIZATION>PRI</ORGANIZATION> with <PERSON>Faith Salie</PERSON> and is the co host of a new public radio podcast RelationsShow a slightly nerdy look at love sex and relationships faithsalie com National Book Awards NBA Winners by Genre How the NBAs Work Award Deadlines amp Guidelines Distinguished Contribution to American Letters Literarian Award NBA Finalists Reading Teen Press Conference Medallions <ORGANIZATION>NBA Winners amp Finalists</ORGANIZATION> 2010s 2000s 1990s 1980s 1970s 1960s 1950s Online Exhibitions <ORGANIZATION>NBA Fiction Winners NBA</ORGANIZATION> Fiction Finalists <ORGANIZATION>NBA Poetry Winners NBA Young People s Lit Education BookUp NBA</ORGANIZATION> on Campus Innovations in Reading Programs Eat Drink amp Be Literary Innovations in Reading NBA On Campus 5 Under 35 What Are You Reading News Press Room Newsletter Support Donate Online Donor <ORGANIZATION>Recognition About Mission amp History Board</ORGANIZATION> of Directors Staff Careers Form 990 Privacy Policy FAQs Follow us image Follow the <ORGANIZATION>NBF</ORGANIZATION> on <ORGANIZATION>Twitter Tumblr Facebook</ORGANIZATION> or Instagram</ner>
