<ner>image Nobelprize org image Nobelprize org Video Podcast About Us menu Home Nobel Prizes and Laureates Nobel Prizes and Laureates Physics Prize Chemistry Prize Medicine Prize Literature Prize Peace Prize Prize in Economic Sciences Quick Facts Nomination Nomination Physics Prize Chemistry Prize Medicine Prize Literature Prize Peace Prize Prize in Economic Sciences Nomination Archive Ceremonies Ceremonies Ceremony Archive Nobel Banquet Menus Nobel Banquet Dress Code The Queen s Gowns Eyewitness Reports Alfred Nobel Alfred Nobel Alfred Nobel s Will Alfred Nobel s Life Private Library of <ORGANIZATION>Alfred Nobel Books on Alfred Nobel Educational Events</ORGANIZATION> Events Nobel Prize Dialogue Nobel Week Dialogue Nobel Prize Inspiration Initiative Nobel Prize Series Nobel Peace Prize Forum Oslo Nobel Prize Concert Exhibitions at the <ORGANIZATION>Nobel Museum Exhibitions</ORGANIZATION> at the <ORGANIZATION>Nobel Peace Center Events Calendar Podcast About Us Nobel Prizes</ORGANIZATION> and Laureates Physics Prizes Chemistry Prizes Medicine Prizes Literature Prizes Peace Prizes Prize in Economic Sciences image image image About the Nobel Prize in Literature 1993 Summary Press Release Award Ceremony Speech image <PERSON>Toni Morrison</PERSON> All Nobel Prizes in Literature All Nobel Prizes in 1993 Nobel Prizes and Laureates Physics Prizes Chemistry Prizes Medicine Prizes Literature Prizes Peace Prizes Prize in Economic Sciences image image image About the Nobel Prize in Literature 1993 Summary Press Release Award Ceremony Speech image <PERSON>Toni Morrison</PERSON> All Nobel Prizes in Literature All Nobel Prizes in 1993 The Nobel Prize in Literature 1993 Toni Morrison Share this Award Ceremony Speech Speech by Professor <PERSON>Sture All</PERSON> n Permanent Secretary of the Swedish Academy Translation from the Swedish text Your Majesties Your Royal Highnesses Ladies and Gentlemen The Nobel Prize awarded by the <ORGANIZATION>Swedish Academy</ORGANIZATION> is as we know a literary prize This year it has been granted to <PERSON>Toni Morrison</PERSON> making her the ninetieth Nobel Laureate in Literature In her volume of essays Playing in the Dark Miss <PERSON>Morrison</PERSON> lucidly pictures the insights that she has gained as an author and a reader in her native country It is as if I had been looking at a fishbowl the glide and flick of the golden scales the green tip the bolt of white careening back from the gills the castles at the bottom surrounded by pebbles and tiny intricate fronds of green the barely disturbed water the flecks of waste and food the tranquil bubbles travelling to the surface and suddenly I saw the bowl the structure that transparently and invisibly permits the ordered life it contains to exist in the larger world In other words she regards the African presence in her country as a vital but unarticulated prerequisite for the fulfilment of the American dream Similarly she sees whiteness in literature as having blackness as its constant companion the racial other as its shadow In her depictions of the world of the black people in life as in legend <PERSON>Toni Morrison</PERSON> has given the Afro American people their history back piece by piece In this perspective her work is uncommonly consonant At the same time it is richly variegated The reader derives vast pleasure from her superb narrative technique shifting from novel to novel and marked by original development although it is related to <PERSON>Faulkner</PERSON> and to the Latin American tradition <PERSON>Toni Morrison</PERSON> s novels invite the reader to partake at many levels and at varying degrees of complexity Still the most enduring impression they leave is of empathy compassion with one s fellow human beings Milkman Dead the protagonist of Song of <PERSON>Solomon</PERSON> reflects one of the basic themes of Miss <PERSON>Morrison</PERSON> s novels in his quest for self <PERSON>Milkman</PERSON> s paternal grandfather was a liberated slave When he was registering his freedom he responded to a question about his father with the word Dead thus acquiring his macabre surname from the drunken official who asked His family was prepared to accept this name It was new and would wipe out the past Wipe it all out The <PERSON>Solomon</PERSON> whose name occurs in the title of the novel Milkman s peculiar southern forefather was to be found even in the song that went with children s games The intensity of his inner life had carried him through the air back to the <LOCATION>Africa</LOCATION> of his origins <PERSON>Solomon</PERSON> s rapture was ultimately Milkman s as well Motifs in space and time continue to be interwoven in Beloved Paradoxically the combination of realism and folklore enhances the novel s credibility In the world which the female protagonist <LOCATION>Sethe</LOCATION> inhabits one does not possess one s own body There is tremendous power in <PERSON>Toni Morrison</PERSON> s description of <LOCATION>Sethe</LOCATION> s act of releasing her child Beloved from the destiny she imagines her facing and of the consequences of this act for her own life in which Beloved s double personifies the burden of <LOCATION>Sethe</LOCATION> s guilt In her latest novel Jazz <PERSON>Toni Morrison</PERSON> s approach is similar to the style in which jazz is performed The opening lines of the novel state its theme the lives of a number of people in <LOCATION>Harlem</LOCATION> in the 1920s In the course of the novel we perceive a first person narrator varying supplementing and intensifying the story The final picture is a highly composite image of events characters and atmospheres mediated in sensual language with a deep inherent sense of musicality <PERSON>Toni Morrison</PERSON> s way of addressing her reader has a compelling lustre in a poetic direction When she was very young her family s landlord set fire to the house in which they lived when her parents fell behind with the rent And while they were in it Her family reacted to this absurd form of crudeness monumental crudeness not with resignation but with laughter This says <PERSON>Toni Morrison</PERSON> is how you can distance yourself from the act and take your life back You take your integrity back In great minds gravity and humour are close neighbours This is reflected in everything <PERSON>Toni Morrison</PERSON> has written and evidenced in her own summary My project rises from delight not disappointment Dear Miss <PERSON>Morrison</PERSON> I have just told the audience that in your own words your project rises from delight not disappointment As you disclose fundamental aspects of hidden reality you make gravity and humour abide side by side in your remarkable work with its verbal music It is my privilege and pleasure on behalf of the <ORGANIZATION>Swedish Academy</ORGANIZATION> to convey to you our warmest congratulations on the Nobel Prize in Literature for 1993 and to invite you to receive the Prize from the hands of His Majesty the King From Nobel Lectures Literature 1991 1995 Editor Sture All n <ORGANIZATION>World Scientific Publishing Co</ORGANIZATION> <LOCATION>Singapore</LOCATION> 1997 Copyright The Nobel Foundation 1993 Share this To cite this page <ORGANIZATION>MLA</ORGANIZATION> style <ORGANIZATION>Nobelprize org Nobelprize org Nobel Media AB</ORGANIZATION> 2014 Web 11 Apr 2018 lt http www nobelprize org nobel_prizes literature laureates 1993 presentation speech html gt Recommended image Find the Authors Game Which Nobel Laureates are hidden within the maze of letters image Facts on the Nobel Prize in Literature All you need to know about the Literature Prize image The Nobel Prize in Literature Read about <PERSON>Alfred Nobel</PERSON> s Will and the Literature Prize image image image image image image image image image image Contact E mail us Press Newsroom Sitemap A Z Index FAQ Frequently Asked Questions Terms Terms of Use Privacy Policy Technical Support For <ORGANIZATION>Developers Copyright Follow Facebook Instagram Twitter YouTube Nobelprize</ORGANIZATION> org Monthly Nobel Prize App image Contact Press Sitemap FAQ Terms Copyright Nobel Media AB 2018 Join us image image image image Contact E mail Us Press Newsroom Sitemap A Z Index FAQ Frequently Asked Questions Terms Terms of Use Privacy Policy Technical Support For Developers Copyright Join us image <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> image Instagram image Twitter image YouTube image Nobelprize org Monthly image Nobel Prize App</ner>
