<ner>NYTimes com no longer supports Internet Explorer 9 or earlier Please upgrade your browser LEARN MORE Sections Home Search Skip to content Skip to navigation View mobile version The <ORGANIZATION>New York Times Archives EXISTENTIALISM</ORGANIZATION> SEMIOTICS AND ICED TEA Search Subscribe Now Log In 0 Settings Close search Site Search Navigation Search NYTimes com Clear this text input Go https nyti ms 29DeRP0 Loading See next articles See previous articles Site Navigation Site Mobile Navigation Advertisement Archives 1985 EXISTENTIALISM SEMIOTICS AND ICED TEA By <PERSON>ROGER KIMBALL</PERSON> Continue reading the main story Share This Page Continue reading the main story image The article as it originally appeared View page in TimesMachine Page 007009 The <ORGANIZATION>New York Times Archives</ORGANIZATION> CONVERSATIONS WITH WALKER PERCY Edited by <PERSON>Lewis A Lawson</PERSON> and <PERSON>Victor A Kramer</PERSON> 325 pp <ORGANIZATION>Jackson University Press of Mississippi Cloth</ORGANIZATION> 17 95 Paper 9 95 THE 27 interviews collected in this volume span the length of <PERSON>Walker Percy</PERSON> s literary career from the publication of his novel The Moviegoer in 1961 through the publication of his second work of nonfiction Lost in the Cosmos The Last Self Help Book which appeared in 1983 Taken together they provide us with something of an inventory of Mr <PERSON>Percy</PERSON> s intellectual and artistic preoccupations over the last two decades and acquaint us with the character and the life of the man behind the works Indeed by the time one finishes Conversations With <PERSON>Walker Percy</PERSON> one can expect to know the highlights of the writer s life by heart We read in several of the interviews that his father committed suicide when he was 13 that he and his two brothers were adopted by his father s cousin the author <PERSON>William Alexander Percy</PERSON> when their mother died in an automobile accident a few years later and that <PERSON>Walker Percy</PERSON> and his wife converted to Roman Catholicism in the 1940 s And we are again and again reminded that Mr <PERSON>Percy</PERSON> studied medicine at <ORGANIZATION>Columbia University</ORGANIZATION> that he contracted tuberculosis while performing an autopsy during his internship at <ORGANIZATION>Bellevue Hospital</ORGANIZATION> and that he discovered his vocation as a writer while reading existential literature during his two years of convalescence But in addition to rehearsing these standard biographical items many of the interviews touch on a wide range of literary social and even philosophical topics This of course is to be expected Mr <PERSON>Percy</PERSON> is generally considered one of our premier philosophical novelists Writing for him is not merely a sophisticated form of entertainment it is an exploration of reality a serious business in which the novelist is out both to give joy and to draw blood In fact Mr <PERSON>Percy</PERSON> began his literary career writing philosophical essays not novels Only in the late 50 s did he begin to write fiction in part to reach a larger audience but also he explains because I was tired of getting paid in reprints Advertisement Continue reading the main story Mr <PERSON>Percy</PERSON> s main philosophical interests are in <LOCATION>Kierkegaard</LOCATION> and the existential tradition that he helped to inaugurate and in the philosophy of language that stems from the late <PERSON>Susanne Langer</PERSON> s work on symbols These two influences are abundantly represented in the interviews Both <PERSON>Marcus Smith</PERSON> and <PERSON>Jo Gulledge</PERSON> for example talk to Mr <PERSON>Percy</PERSON> about his work in semiotics and <PERSON>Bradley R Dewey</PERSON> s annotated conversation with him about <PERSON>Kierkegaard</PERSON> goes into considerable detail about his use of Kierkegaardian themes in his novels Continue reading the main story Advertisement Continue reading the main story The last piece in the book a brief interview that deals with <PERSON>Thomas Merton</PERSON> promised to be of special interest The two had corresponded since the early 60 s when <PERSON>Merton</PERSON> wrote Mr <PERSON>Percy</PERSON> an admiring letter about The Moviegoer but met only once at <LOCATION>Gethsemani Abbey</LOCATION> in <LOCATION>Kentucky</LOCATION> a year or two before <PERSON>Merton</PERSON> s death in 1968 According to Mr <PERSON>Percy</PERSON> however when they finally met they felt uneasy around each other and their conversation never really got off the ground It s amazing how little we found to talk about Newsletter Sign Up Continue reading the main story Please verify you re not a robot by clicking the box Invalid email address Please re enter You must select a newsletter to subscribe to Sign Up You agree to receive occasional updates and special offers for The <ORGANIZATION>New York Times</ORGANIZATION> s products and services Thank you for subscribing An error has occurred Please try again later You are already subscribed to this email View all <ORGANIZATION>New York Times</ORGANIZATION> newsletters See Sample Manage Email Preferences Not you Privacy Policy Opt out or contact us anytime Mr <PERSON>Percy</PERSON> s chief concern as a novelist is with the dislocation of man in the modern age with the sense of ennui and meaninglessness that has shadowed so many lives even or perhaps especially in the midst of affluence The thing that fascinates me he tells one interviewer is the fact that men can be well off judging by their own criteria with all their needs satisfied goals achieved et cetera yet as time goes on life is almost unbearable Amazing Thus in his first and most celebrated work The Moviegoer which won the National Book Award in 1962 we find the bemused protagonist <PERSON>Binx Bolling</PERSON> engaged in the search an amorphous yet desperate struggle to escape from the emptiness that suffuses his quiet everyday life in a <LOCATION>New Orleans</LOCATION> suburb The pieces collected here vary widely in quality Some are earnest thoughtful interviews that attempt to extend our knowledge of Mr <PERSON>Percy</PERSON> s art influences and significance but a good number are hardly more than chatty bagatelles glib occasional products meant primarily to boost his most recent book Over all I believe Conversations With <PERSON>Walker Percy</PERSON> can be said to make a contribution to the literature on him But the reader should be warned that the interviews are presented completely unabridged The editors acknowledge that this entails what they regard as some slight repetition but they insist that the cumulative picture will prove to be of value to scholars I had to wonder about this Surely most readers who are primarily interested in Mr <PERSON>Percy</PERSON> as a novelist will be impatient with so much repetition And scholars How many times do scholars have to accompany interviewers on a trip to this writer s home in <LOCATION>Covington La How</LOCATION> many picturesque descriptions of Mr <PERSON>Percy</PERSON> s picturesque chateau style house do they need And how many glasses of iced tea must they sit through There is a lot of iced tea in this book And if tedium is one problem with the editors decision to leave the interviews unabridged and unedited inconsistency among the pieces is another The reader might well ask Where was Mr <PERSON>Percy</PERSON> s first philosophical essay published In what year did he convert to Catholicism How long was he in analysis There are conflicting accounts of these and other matters and one would expect a volume published with scholars in mind would provide the appropriate clarifying annotations In the end perhaps the most illuminating piece in the book is the interview that the writer conducted with himself in 1977 Question Will you consent to an interview Answer No Q Why not A Interviewers always ask the same questions such as What time of day do you write Do you type or write longhand What do you think of the South What do you think of the New South What do you think of southern writers Please don t ask me about <PERSON>Dostoevski</PERSON> and <PERSON>Kierkegaard Roger Kimball</PERSON> is a frequent contributor to The New Criterion and other journals We are continually improving the quality of our text archives Please send feedback error reports and suggestions to archive_feedback nytimes com A version of this review appears in print on August 4 1985 on Page 7007009 of the National edition with the headline EXISTENTIALISM SEMIOTICS AND ICED TEA Today s Paper Subscribe Continue reading the main story What s Next Loading Go to Home Page Site Index The <ORGANIZATION>New York Times Site Index Navigation News World U S Politics N Y Business Tech Science Health Sports Education Obituaries Today</ORGANIZATION> s Paper Corrections Opinion Today s Opinion Op Ed Columnists Editorials Op Ed Contributors Letters Sunday Review Video Opinion Arts Today s Arts Art amp Design Books Dance Movies Music N Y <ORGANIZATION>C Events Guide Television Theater Video Arts Living Automobiles Crossword Food Education Fashion amp Style Health Jobs Magazine N Y C Events Guide Real Estate T Magazine Travel Weddings amp Celebrations Listings amp More Reader Center Classifieds Tools amp Services N Y C Events Guide Multimedia</ORGANIZATION> Photography Video NYT Store Times Journeys Subscribe Manage My Account NYTCo Subscribe Subscribe Home Delivery Digital Subscriptions Crossword Email Newsletters Alerts Gift Subscriptions Group Subscriptions Education Rate Mobile Applications Replica Edition Site Information Navigation 2018 The <ORGANIZATION>New York Times Company Home</ORGANIZATION> Search Accessibility concerns Email us at accessibility nytimes com We would love to hear from you Contact Us Work With Us Advertise Your Ad Choices Privacy Terms of Service Terms of Sale Site Information Navigation Site Map Help Site Feedback Subscriptions</ner>
