<ner>American literature From Wikipedia the free encyclopedia Jump to navigation search For other uses see American literature disambiguation This article is part of a series on the Culture of the <LOCATION>United States of America</LOCATION> image Greater coat of arms of the <ORGANIZATION>United States svg Society History Language People Nation</ORGANIZATION> of immigrants Race and ethnicity Religion Arts and literature Architecture Art Dance Fashion Literature Comics Poetry Music Sculpture Theater Other Cuisine Festivals <ORGANIZATION>Folklore Media Newspapers Radio Cinema</ORGANIZATION> TV Mythology Sport Symbols Flag Great Seal Monuments Motto Anthem Bird World Heritage Sites image Flag of <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> 19 10 svg <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> portal v t e American literature is literature written or produced in the <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> and its preceding colonies for specific discussions of poetry and theater see Poetry of the <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> and Theater in the <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> Before the founding of the <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> the British colonies on the eastern coast of the present day <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> were heavily influenced by English literature The American literary tradition thus began as part of the broader tradition of English literature The revolutionary period is notable for the political writings of <PERSON>Benjamin Franklin</PERSON> and <PERSON>Thomas Paine Thomas Jefferson</PERSON> s <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> Declaration of Independence solidified his status as a key American writer It was in the late 18th and early 19th centuries that the nation s first novels were published An early example is <PERSON>William Hill Brown</PERSON> s The Power of Sympathy published in 1791 Brown s novel depicts a tragic love story between siblings who fall in love without knowing they are related With an increasing desire to produce uniquely American literature and culture a number of key new literary figures emerged perhaps most prominently <LOCATION>Washington Irving</LOCATION> and <PERSON>Edgar Allan Poe</PERSON> In 1836 <PERSON>Ralph Waldo Emerson</PERSON> started an influential movement known as Transcendentalism Inspired by that movement <PERSON>Henry David Thoreau</PERSON> wrote <LOCATION>Walden</LOCATION> which celebrates individualism and nature and urges resistance to the dictates of organized society The political conflict surrounding abolitionism inspired the writings of <PERSON>William Lloyd Garrison</PERSON> and <PERSON>Harriet Beecher Stowe</PERSON> in her famous novel Uncle <PERSON>Tom</PERSON> s Cabin These efforts were supported by the continuation of the slave narratives such as <PERSON>Frederick Douglass</PERSON> s Narrative of the Life of <PERSON>Frederick Douglass</PERSON> an American Slave In the mid nineteenth century <PERSON>Nathaniel Hawthorne</PERSON> published his masterpiece The Scarlet Letter a novel about adultery <PERSON>Hawthorne</PERSON> influenced <PERSON>Herman Melville</PERSON> who is notable for the books Moby <PERSON>Dick</PERSON> and <PERSON>Billy Budd America</PERSON> s greatest poets of the nineteenth century were <PERSON>Walt Whitman</PERSON> and <PERSON>Emily Dickinson Mark Twain</PERSON> the pen name used by <PERSON>Samuel Langhorne Clemens</PERSON> was the first major American writer to be born away from the East Coast <PERSON>Henry James</PERSON> put American literature on the international map with novels like The Portrait of a Lady At the turn of the twentieth century a strong naturalist movement emerged that comprised writers such as <PERSON>Edith Wharton Stephen Crane Theodore Dreiser</PERSON> and <ORGANIZATION>Jack London American</ORGANIZATION> writers expressed disillusionment following WW I The stories and novels of F <PERSON>Scott Fitzgerald</PERSON> capture the mood of the 1920s and <PERSON>John Dos Passos</PERSON> wrote too about the war <PERSON>Ernest Hemingway</PERSON> became famous with The Sun Also Rises and A Farewell to Arms in 1954 he won the Nobel Prize in Literature <PERSON>William Faulkner</PERSON> became one of the greatest American writers with novels like The Sound and the Fury American poetry reached a peak after World War I with such writers as <PERSON>Wallace Stevens</PERSON> T S <PERSON>Eliot Robert Frost Ezra Pound</PERSON> and E E Cummings American drama attained international status at the time with the works of <PERSON>Eugene O Neill</PERSON> who won four Pulitzer Prizes and the Nobel Prize In the mid twentieth century American drama was dominated by the work of playwrights <PERSON>Tennessee Williams</PERSON> and <PERSON>Arthur Miller</PERSON> as well as by the maturation of the American musical Depression era writers included <PERSON>John Steinbeck</PERSON> notable for his novel The Grapes of Wrath <PERSON>Henry Miller</PERSON> assumed a distinct place in American Literature in the 1930s when his semi autobiographical novels were banned from the <LOCATION>US</LOCATION> From the end of World War II until the early 1970s many popular works in modern American literature were produced like <PERSON>Harper Lee</PERSON> s To Kill a <LOCATION>Mockingbird America</LOCATION> s involvement in World War II influenced works such as <PERSON>Norman Mailer</PERSON> s The Naked and the Dead 1948 <PERSON>Joseph Heller</PERSON> s Catch 22 1961 and <PERSON>Kurt Vonnegut Jr</PERSON> s Slaughterhouse Five 1969 The main literary movement since the 1970s has been postmodernism and since the late twentieth century ethnic and minority literature has sharply increased Contents 1 Colonial literature 1 1 Topics of early writing 1 2 Revolutionary period 2 <ORGANIZATION>Post</ORGANIZATION> independence 2 1 The First American Novel 3 Unique American style 4 Early American poetry 5 Realism <PERSON>Twain</PERSON> and <PERSON>James</PERSON> 6 Beginning of the 20th century 6 1 1920s 7 The rise of American drama 8 Depression era literature 9 Post World War II 9 1 The postwar novel 9 2 Short fiction and poetry 10 Contemporary American literature 11 Minority literatures 12 Nobel Prize in Literature winners American authors 13 American literary awards 14 Literary theory and criticism 15 See also 15 1 Additional genres 15 2 Regional and minority focuses in American literature 16 Notes and references 17 Bibliography 18 External links Colonial literature edit Because of the large immigration to <LOCATION>Boston</LOCATION> in the 1630s the articulation of Puritan ideals and the early establishment of a college and a printing press in <LOCATION>Cambridge</LOCATION> the <LOCATION>New England</LOCATION> colonies have often been regarded as the center of early American literature However the first European settlements in <LOCATION>North America</LOCATION> had been founded elsewhere many years earlier Towns older than <LOCATION>Boston</LOCATION> include the Spanish settlements at <LOCATION>Saint Augustine</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Santa Fe</LOCATION> the Dutch settlements at <LOCATION>Albany</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>New Amsterdam</LOCATION> as well as the English colony of <LOCATION>Jamestown</LOCATION> in present day <LOCATION>Virginia</LOCATION> During the colonial period the printing press was active in many areas from <LOCATION>Cambridge</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Boston</LOCATION> to <LOCATION>New York Philadelphia</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Annapolis</LOCATION> The dominance of the English language was not inevitable 1 The first item printed in <LOCATION>Pennsylvania</LOCATION> was in German and was the largest book printed in any of the colonies before the American Revolution 1 Spanish and French had two of the strongest colonial literary traditions in the areas that now comprise the <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> and discussions of early American literature commonly include texts by lvar N ez <LOCATION>Cabeza de Vaca</LOCATION> and <PERSON>Samuel</PERSON> de Champlain alongside English language texts by <PERSON>Thomas Harriot</PERSON> and <PERSON>John Smith</PERSON> Moreover we are now aware of the wealth of oral literary traditions already existing on the continent among the numerous different Native American groups Political events however would eventually make English the lingua franca for the colonies at large as well as the literary language of choice For instance when the English conquered <LOCATION>New Amsterdam</LOCATION> in 1664 they renamed it <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> and changed the administrative language from Dutch to English From 1696 to 1700 only about 250 separate items were issued from the major printing presses in the American colonies This is a small number compared to the output of the printers in <LOCATION>London</LOCATION> at the time <LOCATION>London</LOCATION> printers published materials written by <LOCATION>New England</LOCATION> authors so the body of American literature was larger than what was published in <LOCATION>North America</LOCATION> However printing was established in the American colonies before it was allowed in most of <LOCATION>England</LOCATION> In <LOCATION>England</LOCATION> restrictive laws had long confined printing to four locations where the government could monitor what was published <ORGANIZATION>London York Oxford</ORGANIZATION> and <LOCATION>Cambridge</LOCATION> Because of this the colonies ventured into the modern world earlier than their provincial English counterparts 1 Back then some of the American literature were pamphlets and writings extolling the benefits of the colonies to both a European and colonist audience Captain <PERSON>John Smith</PERSON> could be considered the first American author with his works A True Relation of Such Occurrences and Accidents of <LOCATION>Noate</LOCATION> as Hath Happened in <LOCATION>Virginia</LOCATION> 1608 and The Generall Historie of <LOCATION>Virginia New England</LOCATION> and the Summer Isles 1624 Other writers of this manner included <PERSON>Daniel Denton Thomas Ash William Penn George Percy William Strachey Daniel Coxe Gabriel Thomas</PERSON> and <PERSON>John Lawson</PERSON> Topics of early writing edit The religious disputes that prompted settlement in <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> were important topics of early American literature A journal written by <PERSON>John Winthrop</PERSON> The History of <LOCATION>New England</LOCATION> discussed the religious foundations of the <ORGANIZATION>Massachusetts Bay Colony</ORGANIZATION> <PERSON>Edward Winslow</PERSON> also recorded a diary of the first years after the Mayflower s arrival A modell of Christian Charity by <PERSON>John Winthrop</PERSON> the first governor of <LOCATION>Massachusetts</LOCATION> was a Sermon preached on the Arbella the flagship of the <ORGANIZATION>Winthrop Fleet</ORGANIZATION> in 1630 This work outlined the ideal society that he and the other Separatists would build in an attempt to realize a Puritan utopia Other religious writers included Increase Mather and <PERSON>William Bradford</PERSON> author of the journal published as a History of <ORGANIZATION>Plymouth Plantation</ORGANIZATION> 1620 47 Others like <PERSON>Roger Williams</PERSON> and <PERSON>Nathaniel Ward</PERSON> more fiercely argued state and church separation And still others like <PERSON>Thomas Morton</PERSON> cared little for the church <PERSON>Morton</PERSON> s The New English Canaan mocked the religious settlers and declared that the Native Americans were actually better people than the British 2 Puritan poetry was highly religious and one of the earliest books of poetry published was the Bay Psalm Book a set of translations of the biblical Psalms however the translators intention was not to create literature but to create hymns that could be used in worship 2 Among lyric poets the most important figures are <PERSON>Anne Bradstreet</PERSON> who wrote personal poems about her family and homelife pastor <PERSON>Edward Taylor</PERSON> whose best poems the Preparatory Meditations were written to help him prepare for leading worship and <PERSON>Michael Wigglesworth</PERSON> whose best selling poem The Day of Doom 1660 describes the time of judgment It was published in the same year that anti Puritan <PERSON>Charles II</PERSON> was restored to the British throne He followed it two years later with God s Controversy With New England <PERSON>Nicholas Noyes</PERSON> was also known for his doggerel verse Other late writings described conflicts and interaction with the Indians as seen in writings by <PERSON>Daniel Gookin Alexander Whitaker John Mason Benjamin Church</PERSON> and <PERSON>Mary Rowlandson John Eliot</PERSON> translated the Bible into the Algonquin language Of the second generation of <LOCATION>New England</LOCATION> settlers <ORGANIZATION>Cotton Mather</ORGANIZATION> stands out as a theologian and historian who wrote the history of the colonies with a view to God s activity in their midst and to connecting the Puritan leaders with the great heroes of the Christian faith His best known works include the <ORGANIZATION>Magnalia Christi Americana</ORGANIZATION> the Wonders of the Invisible World and The Biblia Americana <PERSON>Jonathan Edwards</PERSON> and <PERSON>George Whitefield</PERSON> represented the Great Awakening a religious revival in the early 18th century that emphasized Calvinism Other Puritan and religious writers include <PERSON>Thomas Hooker Thomas Shepard John Wise</PERSON> and <PERSON>Samuel Willard Less</PERSON> strict and serious writers included <PERSON>Samuel Sewall</PERSON> who wrote a diary revealing the daily life of the late 17th century 2 and <PERSON>Sarah Kemble Knight</PERSON> <LOCATION>New England</LOCATION> was not the only area in the colonies with a literature southern literature was also growing at this time The diary of <PERSON>William Byrd</PERSON> and The History of the Dividing Line described the expedition to survey the swamp between <LOCATION>Virginia</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>North Carolina</LOCATION> but also comments on the differences between American Indians and the white settlers in the area 2 In a similar book Travels through <LOCATION>North</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>South Carolina Georgia East</LOCATION> and West <PERSON>William Bartram</PERSON> described the Southern landscape and the Indian tribes he encountered <PERSON>Bartram</PERSON> s book was popular in <LOCATION>Europe</LOCATION> being translated into German French and Dutch 2 As the colonies moved toward independence from <LOCATION>Britain</LOCATION> an important discussion of American culture and identity came from the French immigrant J <PERSON>Hector St John de Cr</PERSON> vec ur whose Letters from an American Farmer addresses the question What is an American by moving between praise for the opportunities and peace offered in the new society and recognition that the solid life of the farmer must rest uneasily between the oppressive aspects of the urban life and the lawless aspects of the frontier where the lack of social structures leads to the loss of civilized living 2 This same period saw the beginning of black literature through the poet <PERSON>Phillis Wheatley</PERSON> and the slave narrative of <ORGANIZATION>Olaudah Equiano</ORGANIZATION> The Interesting Narrative of the <ORGANIZATION>Life of Olaudah Equiano</ORGANIZATION> At this time American Indian literature also began to flourish <PERSON>Samson Occom</PERSON> published his A Sermon Preached at the Execution of <PERSON>Moses Paul</PERSON> and a popular hymnbook Collection of Hymns and Spiritual Songs the first Indian best seller 3 Revolutionary period edit The <ORGANIZATION>Revolutionary</ORGANIZATION> period also contained political writings including those by colonists <PERSON>Samuel Adams Josiah Quincy John Dickinson</PERSON> and <PERSON>Joseph Galloway</PERSON> the last being a loyalist to the crown Two key figures were <PERSON>Benjamin Franklin</PERSON> and <PERSON>Thomas Paine Franklin</PERSON> s Poor <PERSON>Richard</PERSON> s Almanac and The Autobiography of <PERSON>Benjamin Franklin</PERSON> are esteemed works with their wit and influence toward the formation of a budding American identity <PERSON>Paine</PERSON> s pamphlet Common Sense and The American Crisis writings are seen as playing a key role in influencing the political tone of the time During the Revolutionary War poems and songs such as <ORGANIZATION>Yankee Doodle</ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON>Nathan Hale</PERSON> were popular Major satirists included <PERSON>John Trumbull</PERSON> and <PERSON>Francis Hopkinson Philip Morin Freneau</PERSON> also wrote poems about the War During the 18th century writing shifted from the Puritanism of <PERSON>Winthrop</PERSON> and <PERSON>Bradford</PERSON> to Enlightenment ideas of reason The belief that human and natural occurrences were messages from God no longer fit with the new human centered world Many intellectuals believed that the human mind could comprehend the universe through the laws of physics as described by <PERSON>Isaac Newton</PERSON> One of these was Cotton Mather The first book published in <LOCATION>North America</LOCATION> that promoted <PERSON>Newton</PERSON> and natural theology was Mather s The Christian Philosopher 1721 The enormous scientific economic social and philosophical changes of the 18th century called the Enlightenment impacted the authority of clergyman and scripture making way for democratic principles The increase in population helped account for the greater diversity of opinion in religious and political life as seen in the literature of this time In 1670 the population of the colonies numbered approximately 111 000 Thirty years later it was more than 250 000 By 1760 it reached 1 600 000 1 The growth of communities and therefore social life led people to become more interested in the progress of individuals and their shared experience in the colonies These new ideas can be seen in the popularity of <PERSON>Benjamin Franklin</PERSON> s Autobiography Even earlier than <PERSON>Franklin</PERSON> was <PERSON>Cadwallader Colden</PERSON> 1689 1776 whose book The History of the <ORGANIZATION>Five Indian Nations</ORGANIZATION> published in 1727 was one of the first texts critical of the treatment of the Iroquois in upstate <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> by the English <PERSON>Colden</PERSON> also wrote a book on botany which attracted the attention of <PERSON>Linnaeus</PERSON> and he maintained a long term correspondence with <ORGANIZATION>Benjamin Franklin Post</ORGANIZATION> independence edit In the post war period <PERSON>Thomas Jefferson</PERSON> established his place in American literature through his authorship of the <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> Declaration of Independence his influence on the <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> Constitution his autobiography his Notes on the <LOCATION>State of Virginia</LOCATION> and his many letters The Federalist essays by <PERSON>Alexander Hamilton James Madison</PERSON> and <PERSON>John Jay</PERSON> presented a significant historical discussion of American government organization and republican values <PERSON>Fisher Ames James Otis</PERSON> and <PERSON>Patrick Henry</PERSON> are also valued for their political writings and orations Early American literature struggled to find a unique voice in existing literary genre and this tendency was reflected in novels European styles were frequently imitated but critics usually considered the imitations inferior The First American Novel edit In the late 18th and early 19th centuries the first American novels were published These fictions were too lengthy to be printed as manuscript or public reading <ORGANIZATION>Publishers</ORGANIZATION> took a chance on these works in hopes they would become steady sellers and need to be reprinted This scheme was ultimately successful because male and female literacy rates were increasing at the time Among the first American novels are <PERSON>Thomas Attwood Digges</PERSON> Adventures of <PERSON>Alonso</PERSON> published in <LOCATION>London</LOCATION> in 1775 and <PERSON>William Hill Brown</PERSON> s The Power of Sympathy published in 1791 Brown s novel depicts a tragic love story between siblings who fell in love without knowing they were related In the next decade important women writers also published novels <PERSON>Susanna Rowson</PERSON> is best known for her novel <ORGANIZATION>Charlotte A Tale of Truth</ORGANIZATION> published in <LOCATION>London</LOCATION> in 1791 4 In 1794 the novel was reissued in <LOCATION>Philadelphia</LOCATION> under the title <ORGANIZATION>Charlotte Temple Charlotte Temple</ORGANIZATION> is a seduction tale written in the third person which warns against listening to the voice of love and counsels resistance She also wrote nine novels six theatrical works two collections of poetry six textbooks and countless songs 4 Reaching more than a million and a half readers over a century and a half <ORGANIZATION>Charlotte Temple</ORGANIZATION> was the biggest seller of the 19th century before <PERSON>Stowe</PERSON> s Uncle <PERSON>Tom</PERSON> s Cabin Although <PERSON>Rowson</PERSON> was extremely popular in her time and is often acknowledged in accounts of the development of the early American novel <LOCATION>Charlotte Temple</LOCATION> is often criticized as a sentimental novel of seduction Hannah Webster Foster s The Coquette Or the History of <PERSON>Eliza Wharton</PERSON> was published in 1797 and was also extremely popular 5 Told from Foster s point of view and based on the real life of <PERSON>Eliza Whitman</PERSON> the novel is about a woman who is seduced and abandoned <PERSON>Eliza</PERSON> is a coquette who is courted by two very different men a clergyman who offers her a comfortable domestic life and a noted libertine Unable to choose between them she finds herself single when both men get married She eventually yields to the artful libertine and gives birth to an illegitimate stillborn child at an inn The Coquette is praised for its demonstration of the era s contradictory ideas of womanhood 6 even as it has been criticized for delegitimizing protest against women s subordination 7 image <PERSON>Washington Irving</PERSON> and his friends at <LOCATION>Sunnyside Both The Coquette</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Charlotte Temple</LOCATION> are novels that treat the right of women to live as equals as the new democratic experiment These novels are of the Sentimental genre characterized by overindulgence in emotion an invitation to listen to the voice of reason against misleading passions as well as an optimistic overemphasis on the essential goodness of humanity Sentimentalism is often thought to be a reaction against the Calvinistic belief in the depravity of human nature 8 While many of these novels were popular the economic infrastructure of the time did not allow these writers to make a living through their writing alone 9 <PERSON>Charles Brockden Brown</PERSON> is the earliest American novelist whose works are still commonly read He published <PERSON>Wieland</PERSON> in 1798 and in 1799 published <PERSON>Ormond Edgar Huntly</PERSON> and <PERSON>Arthur Mervyn</PERSON> These novels are of the Gothic genre The first writer to be able to support himself through the income generated by his publications alone was <PERSON>Washington Irving He</PERSON> completed his first major book in 1809 entitled A History of <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> from the Beginning of the World to the End of the Dutch Dynasty 10 Of the picaresque genre <PERSON>Hugh Henry Brackenridge</PERSON> published Modern Chivalry in 1792 1815 <PERSON>Tabitha Gilman Tenney</PERSON> wrote Female Quixotism Exhibited in the Romantic Opinions and Extravagant Adventure of <PERSON>Dorcasina Sheldon</PERSON> in 1801 <PERSON>Royall Tyler</PERSON> wrote The Algerine Captive in 1797 8 Other notable authors include <PERSON>William Gilmore Simms</PERSON> who wrote <PERSON>Martin Faber</PERSON> in 1833 Guy Rivers in 1834 and The <LOCATION>Yemassee</LOCATION> in 1835 <PERSON>Lydia Maria Child</PERSON> wrote <PERSON>Hobomok</PERSON> in 1824 and The Rebels in 1825 <PERSON>John Neal</PERSON> wrote <LOCATION>Logan</LOCATION> A Family History in 1822 <PERSON>Rachel Dyer</PERSON> in 1828 and The Down Easters in 1833 <PERSON>Catherine Maria Sedgwick</PERSON> wrote A New England Tale in 1822 <LOCATION>Redwood</LOCATION> in 1824 Hope <PERSON>Leslie</PERSON> in 1827 and The Linwoods in 1835 <PERSON>James Kirke Paulding</PERSON> wrote The Lion of the <LOCATION>West</LOCATION> in 1830 The Dutchman s Fireside in 1831 and Westward Ho in 1832 <PERSON>Robert Montgomery Bird</PERSON> wrote <LOCATION>Calavar</LOCATION> in 1834 and <PERSON>Nick of the Woods</PERSON> in 1837 <PERSON>James Fenimore Cooper</PERSON> was also a notable author best known for his novel The Last of the Mohicans written in 1826 8 <PERSON>George Tucker</PERSON> produced in 1824 the first fiction of <LOCATION>Virginia</LOCATION> colonial life with <LOCATION>The Valley</LOCATION> of Shenandoah He followed in 1827 with one of the country s first science fictions A Voyage to the Moon With Some Account of the Manners and <ORGANIZATION>Customs Science and Philosophy</ORGANIZATION> of the <ORGANIZATION>People of Morosofia</ORGANIZATION> and Other Lunarians Unique American style edit image <PERSON>Edgar Allan Poe</PERSON> After the War of 1812 there was an increasing desire to produce a uniquely American literature and culture and a number of literary figures emerged among them <PERSON>Washington Irving William Cullen Bryant</PERSON> and <PERSON>James Fenimore Cooper Irving</PERSON> wrote humorous works in <LOCATION>Salmagundi</LOCATION> and the satire A History of <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> by <PERSON>Diedrich Knickerbocker 1809 Bryant</PERSON> wrote early romantic and nature inspired poetry which evolved away from their European origins <PERSON>Cooper</PERSON> s Leatherstocking Tales about Natty Bumppo which includes The Last of the Mohicans were popular both in the new country and abroad In 1832 <PERSON>Edgar Allan Poe</PERSON> began writing short stories including The Masque of the Red Death The Pit and the Pendulum The Fall of the <ORGANIZATION>House of Usher</ORGANIZATION> and The Murders in the <LOCATION>Rue Morgue</LOCATION> that explore previously hidden levels of human psychology and push the boundaries of fiction toward mystery and fantasy Humorous writers were also popular and included <PERSON>Seba Smith</PERSON> and <PERSON>Benjamin Penhallow Shillaber</PERSON> in <LOCATION>New England</LOCATION> and <PERSON>Davy Crockett Augustus Baldwin Longstreet Johnson J Hooper Thomas Bangs Thorpe</PERSON> and <PERSON>George Washington Harris</PERSON> writing about the American frontier The <ORGANIZATION>New England Brahmins</ORGANIZATION> were a group of writers connected to <ORGANIZATION>Harvard University</ORGANIZATION> and <LOCATION>Cambridge Massachusetts</LOCATION> They included <PERSON>James Russell Lowell Henry Wadsworth Longfellow</PERSON> and <PERSON>Oliver Wendell Holmes</PERSON> Sr image <PERSON>Ralph Waldo Emerson</PERSON> In 1836 <PERSON>Ralph Waldo Emerson</PERSON> a former minister published his essay Nature which argued that men should dispense with organized religion and reach a lofty spiritual state by studying and interacting with the natural world <PERSON>Emerson</PERSON> s work influenced the writers who formed the movement now known as Transcendentalism while <PERSON>Emerson</PERSON> also influenced the public through his lectures Among the leaders of the Transcendental movement was <PERSON>Henry David Thoreau</PERSON> a nonconformist and a close friend of Emerson After living mostly by himself for two years in a cabin by a wooded pond <PERSON>Thoreau</PERSON> wrote <PERSON>Walden</PERSON> a memoir that urges resistance to the dictates of society <PERSON>Thoreau</PERSON> s writings demonstrate a strong American tendency toward individualism Other Transcendentalists included <PERSON>Amos Bronson Alcott Margaret Fuller George Ripley Orestes Brownson</PERSON> and <PERSON>Jones</PERSON> Very 11 As one of the great works of the Revolutionary period was written by a Frenchman so too was a work about <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> from this generation <PERSON>Alexis de Tocqueville</PERSON> s two volume Democracy in <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> described his travels through the young nation making observations about the relations between American politics individualism and community The political conflict surrounding abolitionism inspired the writings of <PERSON>William Lloyd Garrison</PERSON> and his paper The Liberator along with poet <PERSON>John Greenleaf Whittier</PERSON> and <PERSON>Harriet Beecher Stowe</PERSON> in her world famous Uncle <PERSON>Tom</PERSON> s Cabin These efforts were supported by the continuation of the slave narrative autobiography of which the best known examples from this period include <PERSON>Frederick Douglass</PERSON> s Narrative of the Life of <PERSON>Frederick Douglass</PERSON> an American Slave and <PERSON>Harriet Jacobs</PERSON> s Incidents in the Life of a Slave Girl At the same time American Indian autobiography develops most notably in <PERSON>William Apess</PERSON> s A Son of the Forest and <PERSON>George Copway</PERSON> s The Life History and Travels of <PERSON>Kah</PERSON> ge ga gah bowh Moreover minority authors were beginning to publish fiction as in <LOCATION>William Wells Brown</LOCATION> s Clotel or The President s Daughter <PERSON>Frank J Webb</PERSON> s The Garies and Their Friends <PERSON>Martin Delany</PERSON> s <PERSON>Blake</PERSON> or The Huts of <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> and <PERSON>Harriet E Wilson</PERSON> s Our Nig as early African American novels and <PERSON>John Rollin Ridge</PERSON> s The Life and Adventures of Joaquin Murieta The Celebrated <LOCATION>California Bandit</LOCATION> which is considered the first Native American novel but which also is an early story about Mexican American issues image <PERSON>Nathaniel Hawthorne</PERSON> In 1837 the young <PERSON>Nathaniel Hawthorne</PERSON> 1804 1864 collected some of his stories as Twice Told Tales a volume rich in symbolism and occult incidents <PERSON>Hawthorne</PERSON> went on to write full length romances quasi allegorical novels that explore the themes of guilt pride and emotional repression in <LOCATION>New England</LOCATION> His masterpiece The Scarlet Letter is a drama about a woman cast out of her community for committing adultery <PERSON>Hawthorne</PERSON> s fiction had a profound impact on his friend <PERSON>Herman Melville</PERSON> 1819 1891 who first made a name for himself by turning material from his seafaring days into exotic sea narrative novels Inspired by <PERSON>Hawthorne</PERSON> s focus on allegories and psychology <PERSON>Melville</PERSON> went on to write romances replete with philosophical speculation In Moby <PERSON>Dick</PERSON> an adventurous whaling voyage becomes the vehicle for examining such themes as obsession the nature of evil and human struggle against the elements In the short novel <PERSON>Billy Budd Melville</PERSON> dramatizes the conflicting claims of duty and compassion on board a ship in time of war His more profound books sold poorly and he had been long forgotten by the time of his death He was rediscovered in the early 20th century Anti transcendental works from <LOCATION>Melville Hawthorne</LOCATION> and <PERSON>Poe</PERSON> all comprise the Dark Romanticism sub genre of popular literature at this time American dramatic literature by contrast remained dependent on European models although many playwrights did attempt to apply these forms to American topics and themes such as immigrants westward expansion temperance etc At the same time American playwrights created several long lasting American character types especially the Yankee the Negro and the Indian exemplified by the characters of <PERSON>Jonathan Sambo</PERSON> and <LOCATION>Metamora</LOCATION> In addition new dramatic forms were created in the Tom Shows the showboat theater and the minstrel show Among the best plays of the period are <PERSON>James Nelson Barker</PERSON> s Superstition or the Fanatic Father <PERSON>Anna Cora Mowatt</PERSON> s Fashion or Life in <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> <PERSON>Nathaniel Bannister</PERSON> s Putnam the Iron Son of 76 <PERSON>Dion Boucicault</PERSON> s The Octoroon or Life in <LOCATION>Louisiana</LOCATION> and <PERSON>Cornelius Mathews</PERSON> s Witchcraft or the Martyrs of Salem History of modern literature By decade List of years in literature Early modern by century 16th 17th Mid modern by century 18th 19th 20th 21st century Modernism Structuralism Deconstruction Poststructuralism Postmodernism Post colonialism Hypertexts By region <ORGANIZATION>Africa Nigerian South</ORGANIZATION> African Americas American Argentine Brazilian Canadian Colombian Cuban Jamaican Mexican Peruvian Asia Bengali Bangladeshi English Chinese Gujarati Hindi Indian Indian English Japanese Kannada Kashmiri Korean Malayalam Marathi Pakistani Pakistani English Pashto Punjabi Sindhi Tamil Telugu Urdu Vietnamese <LOCATION>Australasia</LOCATION> Australian <LOCATION>New Zealand Europe</LOCATION> Related topics History of science fiction Literature by country History of theater History of ideas Intellectual history image Books aj svg aj ashton 01 svg Literature portal v t e Early American poetry edit See also American poetry image <PERSON>Walt Whitman</PERSON> 1856 The Fireside Poets also known as the Schoolroom or Household Poets were some of <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> s first major poets domestically and internationally They were known for their poems being easy to memorize due to their general adherence to poetic form standard forms regular meter and rhymed stanzas and were often recited in the home hence the name as well as in school such as <PERSON>Paul Revere</PERSON> s Ride as well as working with distinctly American themes including some political issues such as abolition They included <PERSON>Henry Wadsworth Longfellow William Cullen Bryant John Greenleaf Whittier James Russell Lowell</PERSON> and <PERSON>Oliver Wendell Holmes Sr Longfellow</PERSON> achieved the highest level of acclaim and is often considered the first internationally acclaimed American poet being the first American poet given a bust in <ORGANIZATION>Westminster Abbey</ORGANIZATION> s Poets Corner 12 <PERSON>Walt Whitman</PERSON> 1819 1892 and <PERSON>Emily Dickinson</PERSON> 1830 1886 two of <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> s greatest 19th century poets could hardly have been more different in temperament and style <PERSON>Walt Whitman</PERSON> was a working man a traveler a self appointed nurse during the American Civil War 1861 1865 and a poetic innovator His magnum opus was Leaves of Grass in which he uses a free flowing verse and lines of irregular length to depict the all inclusiveness of American democracy Taking that motif one step further the poet equates the vast range of American experience with himself without being egotistical For example in Song of Myself the long central poem in Leaves of Grass <PERSON>Whitman</PERSON> writes These are really the thoughts of all men in all ages and lands they are not original with me In his words <PERSON>Whitman</PERSON> was a poet of the body electric In Studies in Classic American Literature the English novelist <PERSON>D H Lawrence</PERSON> wrote that <PERSON>Whitman</PERSON> was the first to smash the old moral conception that the soul of man is something superior and above the flesh By contrast <PERSON>Emily Dickinson</PERSON> lived the sheltered life of a genteel unmarried woman in small town <LOCATION>Amherst Massachusetts</LOCATION> Her poetry is ingenious witty and penetrating Her work was unconventional for its day and little of it was published during her lifetime Many of her poems dwell on the topic of death often with a mischievous twist One Because I could not stop for Death begins He kindly stopped for me The opening of another <PERSON>Dickinson</PERSON> poem toys with her position as a woman in a male dominated society and an unrecognized poet I m nobody Who are you Are you nobody too 13 American poetry arguably reached its peak in the early to mid 20th century with such noted writers as <PERSON>Wallace Stevens</PERSON> and his Harmonium 1923 and The Auroras of Autumn 1950 T S <PERSON>Eliot</PERSON> and his The Waste Land 1922 <PERSON>Robert Frost</PERSON> and his North of <LOCATION>Boston</LOCATION> 1914 and <LOCATION>New Hampshire</LOCATION> 1923 <PERSON>Hart Crane</PERSON> and his White Buildings 1926 and the epic cycle The Bridge 1930 <PERSON>Ezra Pound William Carlos Williams</PERSON> and his epic poem about his <LOCATION>New Jersey</LOCATION> hometown <PERSON>Paterson Marianne Moore</PERSON> E E <PERSON>Cummings Edna St Vincent Millay</PERSON> and <PERSON>Langston Hughes</PERSON> in addition to many others Realism <PERSON>Twain</PERSON> and <PERSON>James</PERSON> edit image <PERSON>Mark Twain</PERSON> 1907 <PERSON>Mark Twain</PERSON> the pen name used by <PERSON>Samuel Langhorne Clemens</PERSON> 1835 1910 was the first major American writer to be born away from the <LOCATION>East Coast</LOCATION> in the border state of <LOCATION>Missouri</LOCATION> His regional masterpieces were the memoir Life on the <LOCATION>Mississippi</LOCATION> and the novels Adventures of <PERSON>Tom Sawyer</PERSON> and Adventures of Huckleberry Finn Twain s style influenced by journalism wedded to the vernacular direct and unadorned but also highly evocative and irreverently humorous changed the way Americans write their language His characters speak like real people and sound distinctively American using local dialects newly invented words and regional accents Other writers interested in regional differences and dialect were <PERSON>George W Cable Thomas Nelson Page Joel Chandler Harris Mary Noailles Murfree Charles Egbert Craddock Sarah Orne Jewett Mary E Wilkins Freeman Henry Cuyler Bunner</PERSON> and <PERSON>William Sydney Porter</PERSON> O Henry A version of local color regionalism that focused on minority experiences can be seen in the works of <ORGANIZATION>Charles W Chesnutt African American of Mar</ORGANIZATION> a <PERSON>Ruiz de Burton</PERSON> one of the earliest Mexican American novelists to write in English and in the Yiddish inflected works of <PERSON>Abraham Cahan William Dean Howells</PERSON> also represented the realist tradition through his novels including The Rise of <PERSON>Silas Lapham</PERSON> and his work as editor of The <ORGANIZATION>Atlantic Monthly Henry James</ORGANIZATION> 1843 1916 confronted the Old World New World dilemma by writing directly about it Although he was born in <LOCATION>New York City</LOCATION> <PERSON>James</PERSON> spent most of his adult life in <LOCATION>England</LOCATION> Many of his novels center on Americans who live in or travel to <LOCATION>Europe</LOCATION> With its intricate highly qualified sentences and dissection of emotional and psychological nuance <PERSON>James</PERSON> s fiction can be daunting Among his more accessible works are the novellas <PERSON>Daisy Miller</PERSON> about an American girl in <LOCATION>Europe</LOCATION> and The Turn of the Screw a ghost story Realism began to influence American drama partly through <PERSON>Howells</PERSON> but also through Europeans such as <PERSON>Ibsen</PERSON> and Zola Although realism was most influential in set design and staging audiences loved the special effects offered up by the popular melodramas and in the growth of local color plays it also showed up in the more subdued less romantic tone that reflected the effects of the Civil War and continued social turmoil on the American psyche The most ambitious attempt at bringing modern realism into the drama was <PERSON>James Herne</PERSON> s <PERSON>Margaret Fleming</PERSON> which addressed issues of social determinism through realistic dialogue psychological insight and symbolism The play was not successful and both critics and audiences thought it dwelt too much on unseemly topics and included improper scenes such as the main character nursing her husband s illegitimate child onstage Beginning of the 20th century edit image <PERSON>Ernest Hemingway</PERSON> in World War I uniform At the beginning of the 20th century American novelists were expanding fiction to encompass both high and low life and sometimes connected to the naturalist school of realism In her stories and novels <PERSON>Edith Wharton</PERSON> 1862 1937 scrutinized the upper class Eastern seaboard society in which she had grown up One of her finest books The Age of Innocence centers on a man who chooses to marry a conventional socially acceptable woman rather than a fascinating outsider At about the same time <PERSON>Stephen Crane</PERSON> 1871 1900 best known for his Civil War novel The Red Badge of Courage depicted the life of <LOCATION>New York City</LOCATION> prostitutes in Maggie A Girl of the Streets And in Sister <PERSON>Carrie Theodore Dreiser</PERSON> 1871 1945 portrayed a country girl who moves to <LOCATION>Chicago</LOCATION> and becomes a kept woman <PERSON>Hamlin Garland</PERSON> and <PERSON>Frank Norris</PERSON> wrote about the problems of American farmers and other social issues from a naturalist perspective Political writings discussed social issues and the power of corporations <PERSON>Edward Bellamy</PERSON> s Looking Backward outlined other possible political and social orders and <PERSON>Upton Sinclair</PERSON> most famous for his muck raking novel The Jungle advocated socialism Other political writers of the period included <PERSON>Edwin Markham</PERSON> and <PERSON>William Vaughn</PERSON> <ORGANIZATION>Moody Journalistic</ORGANIZATION> critics including <PERSON>Ida M Tarbell</PERSON> and <PERSON>Lincoln Steffens</PERSON> were labeled The Muckrakers <PERSON>Henry Brooks Adams</PERSON> s literate autobiography The Education of <PERSON>Henry Adams</PERSON> also depicted a stinging description of the education system and modern life Race was a common issue as well as seen in the work of <PERSON>Pauline Hopkins</PERSON> who published five influential works from 1900 to 1903 Similarly <PERSON>Sui Sin Far</PERSON> wrote about Chinese American experiences and <PERSON>Maria Cristina Mena</PERSON> wrote about Mexican American experiences 1920s edit image F <PERSON>Scott Fitzgerald</PERSON> photographed by <PERSON>Carl van Vechten</PERSON> 1937 The 1920s brought sharp changes to American literature Many writers had direct experience of the First World War and they used it to frame their writings 14 Experimentation in style and form soon joined the new freedom in subject matter In 1909 <PERSON>Gertrude Stein</PERSON> 1874 1946 by then an expatriate in <LOCATION>Paris</LOCATION> published Three Lives an innovative work of fiction influenced by her familiarity with cubism jazz and other movements in contemporary art and music <PERSON>Stein</PERSON> labeled a group of American literary notables who lived in <LOCATION>Paris</LOCATION> in the 1920s and 1930s the Lost Generation The poet <PERSON>Ezra</PERSON> Pound 1885 1972 was born in <LOCATION>Idaho</LOCATION> but spent much of his adult life in <LOCATION>Europe</LOCATION> His work is complex sometimes obscure with multiple references to other art forms and to a vast range of literature both Western and Eastern 15 He influenced many other poets notably T S Eliot 1888 1965 another expatriate <PERSON>Eliot</PERSON> wrote spare cerebral poetry carried by a dense structure of symbols In The Waste Land he embodied a jaundiced vision of post World War I society in fragmented haunted images Like Pound s <PERSON>Eliot</PERSON> s poetry could be highly allusive and some editions of The Waste Land come with footnotes supplied by the poet In 1948 <PERSON>Eliot</PERSON> won the Nobel Prize in Literature 16 <PERSON>Henry James Stein Pound</PERSON> and <PERSON>Eliot</PERSON> demonstrate the growth of an international perspective in American literature American writers had long looked to European models for inspiration but whereas the literary breakthroughs of the mid 19th century came from finding distinctly American styles and themes writers from this period were finding ways of contributing to a flourishing international literary scene not as imitators but as equals Something similar was happening back in the <LOCATION>States</LOCATION> as Jewish writers such as <PERSON>Abraham Cahan</PERSON> used the English language to reach an international Jewish audience image <PERSON>William Faulkner</PERSON> in 1954 American writers also expressed the disillusionment following upon the war The stories and novels of F <PERSON>Scott Fitzgerald</PERSON> 1896 1940 capture the restless pleasure hungry defiant mood of the 1920s <PERSON>Fitzgerald</PERSON> s characteristic theme expressed poignantly in The <LOCATION>Great Gatsby</LOCATION> is the tendency of youth s golden dreams to dissolve in failure and disappointment <PERSON>Fitzgerald</PERSON> also elucidates the collapse of some key American Ideals such as liberty social unity good governance and peace features which were severely threatened by the pressures of modern early 20th century society 17 <PERSON>Sinclair Lewis</PERSON> and <PERSON>Sherwood Anderson</PERSON> also wrote novels with critical depictions of American life <PERSON>John Dos Passos</PERSON> wrote about the war and also the U S A trilogy which extended into the Depression 18 <PERSON>Ernest Hemingway</PERSON> 1899 1961 saw violence and death first hand as an ambulance driver in World War I and the carnage persuaded him that abstract language was mostly empty and misleading He cut out unnecessary words from his writing simplified the sentence structure and concentrated on concrete objects and actions He adhered to a moral code that emphasized grace under pressure and his protagonists were strong silent men who often dealt awkwardly with women The Sun Also Rises and A Farewell to Arms are generally considered his best novels in 1954 he won the Nobel Prize in Literature 19 <PERSON>William Faulkner</PERSON> 1897 1962 won the Nobel Prize in 1949 <PERSON>Faulkner</PERSON> encompassed an enormous range of humanity in <LOCATION>Yoknapatawpha County</LOCATION> a Mississippian region of his own invention He recorded his characters seemingly unedited ramblings in order to represent their inner states a technique called stream of consciousness In fact these passages are carefully crafted and their seemingly chaotic structure conceals multiple layers of meaning He also jumbled time sequences to show how the past especially the slave holding era of the Deep South endures in the present Among his great works are <PERSON>Absalom Absalom</PERSON> As I Lay Dying The Sound and the Fury and Light in August 20 The rise of American drama edit See also Theater of the <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> Although the American theatrical tradition can be traced back to the arrival of <PERSON>Lewis Hallam</PERSON> s troupe in the mid 18th century and was very active in the 19th century as seen by the popularity of minstrel shows and of adaptations of Uncle <PERSON>Tom</PERSON> s Cabin American drama attained international status only in the 1920s and 1930s with the works of <PERSON>Eugene O Neill</PERSON> who won four Pulitzer Prizes and the Nobel Prize In the middle of the 20th century American drama was dominated by the work of playwrights <PERSON>Tennessee Williams</PERSON> and <PERSON>Arthur Miller</PERSON> as well as by the maturation of the American musical which had found a way to integrate script music and dance in such works as <LOCATION>Oklahoma</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>West Side</LOCATION> Story Later American playwrights of importance include <PERSON>Edward Albee Sam Shepard David Mamet August Wilson</PERSON> and <PERSON>Tony Kushner</PERSON> Depression era literature edit Further information List of writers of the Lost Generation Depression era literature was blunt and direct in its social criticism <PERSON>John Steinbeck</PERSON> 1902 1968 was born in <LOCATION>Salinas California</LOCATION> where he set many of his stories His style was simple and evocative winning him the favor of the readers but not of the critics <PERSON>Steinbeck</PERSON> often wrote about poor working class people and their struggle to lead a decent and honest life The Grapes of Wrath considered his masterpiece is a strong socially oriented novel that tells the story of the <LOCATION>Joads</LOCATION> a poor family from <LOCATION>Oklahoma</LOCATION> and their journey to <LOCATION>California</LOCATION> in search of a better life Other popular novels include Tortilla Flat Of Mice and Men Cannery Row and East of Eden He was awarded the Nobel Prize in Literature in 1962 <PERSON>Steinbeck</PERSON> s contemporary <PERSON>Nathanael West</PERSON> s two most famous short novels Miss Lonelyhearts which plumbs the life of its eponymous antihero a reluctant and to comic effect male advice columnist and the effects the tragic letters exert on it and The Day of the Locust which introduces a cast of <LOCATION>Hollywood</LOCATION> stereotypes and explores the ironies of the movies have come to be avowed classics of American literature In non fiction <PERSON>James Agee</PERSON> s Let Us Now Praise Famous Men observes and depicts the lives of three struggling tenant farming families in <LOCATION>Alabama</LOCATION> in 1936 Combining factual reporting with poetic beauty <PERSON>Agee</PERSON> presented an accurate and detailed report of what he had seen coupled with insight into his feelings about the experience and the difficulties of capturing it for a broad audience In doing so he created an enduring portrait of a nearly invisible segment of the American population <PERSON>Henry Miller</PERSON> assumed a unique place in American Literature in the 1930s when his semi autobiographical novels written and published in <LOCATION>Paris</LOCATION> were banned from the <LOCATION>US</LOCATION> Although his major works including <ORGANIZATION>Tropic of Cancer</ORGANIZATION> and Black Spring would not be free of the label of obscenity until 1962 their themes and stylistic innovations had already exerted a major influence on succeeding generations of American writers and paved the way for sexually frank 1960s novels by <PERSON>John Updike Philip Roth Gore Vidal John Rechy</PERSON> and <PERSON>William Styron</PERSON> Post World War II edit The postwar novel edit image <PERSON>Norman Mailer</PERSON> photographed by <PERSON>Carl Van Vechten</PERSON> 1948 The period in time from the end of World War II up until roughly the late 1960s and early 1970s saw the publication of some of the most popular works in American history such as To Kill a Mockingbird by <PERSON>Harper Lee</PERSON> The last few of the more realistic modernists along with the wildly Romantic beatniks largely dominated the period while the direct respondents to <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> s involvement in World War II contributed in their notable influence Though born in <LOCATION>Canada Chicago</LOCATION> raised <PERSON>Saul Bellow</PERSON> would become one of the most influential novelists in <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> in the decades directly following World War II In works like The Adventures of Augie March and <PERSON>Herzog Bellow</PERSON> painted vivid portraits of the American city and the distinctive characters that peopled it <PERSON>Bellow</PERSON> went on to win the Nobel Prize for Literature in 1976 From J D <PERSON>Salinger</PERSON> s Nine Stories and The Catcher in the Rye to <PERSON>Sylvia Plath</PERSON> s The Bell Jar the perceived madness of the state of affairs in <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> was brought to the forefront of the nation s literary expression Immigrant authors such as <PERSON>Vladimir Nabokov</PERSON> with Lolita forged on with the theme and at almost the same time the beatniks took a concerted step away from their Lost Generation predecessors developing a style and tone of their own by drawing on Eastern theology and experimenting with recreational drugs The poetry and fiction of the Beat Generation largely born of a circle of intellects formed in <LOCATION>New York City</LOCATION> around <ORGANIZATION>Columbia University</ORGANIZATION> and established more officially some time later in <LOCATION>San Francisco</LOCATION> came of age The term Beat referred all at the same time to the countercultural rhythm of the Jazz scene to a sense of rebellion regarding the conservative stress of post war society and to an interest in new forms of spiritual experience through drugs alcohol philosophy and religion and specifically through Zen Buddhism <PERSON>Allen Ginsberg</PERSON> set the tone of the movement in his poem Howl a Whitmanesque work that began I saw the best minds of my generation destroyed by madness Among the most representative achievements of the Beats in the novel are <PERSON>Jack Kerouac</PERSON> s On the Road 1957 the chronicle of a soul searching travel through the continent and <PERSON>William S Burroughs</PERSON> s Naked Lunch 1959 a more experimental work structured as a series of vignettes relating among other things the narrator s travels and experiments with hard drugs Regarding the war novel specifically there was a literary explosion in <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> during the post World War II era Some of the best known of the works produced included <PERSON>Norman Mailer</PERSON> s The Naked and the Dead 1948 <PERSON>Joseph Heller</PERSON> s Catch 22 1961 and <PERSON>Kurt Vonnegut Jr</PERSON> s Slaughterhouse Five 1969 The Moviegoer 1962 by Southern author <PERSON>Walker Percy</PERSON> winner of the National Book Award was his attempt at exploring the dislocation of man in the modern age 21 image <PERSON>John Updike</PERSON> In contrast <PERSON>John Updike</PERSON> approached American life from a more reflective but no less subversive perspective His 1960 novel Rabbit Run the first of four chronicling the rising and falling fortunes of <ORGANIZATION>Harry Rabbit Angstrom</ORGANIZATION> over the course of four decades against the backdrop of the major events of the second half of the 20th century broke new ground on its release in its characterization and detail of the American middle class and frank discussion of taboo topics such as adultery Notable among <PERSON>Updike</PERSON> s characteristic innovations was his use of present tense narration his rich stylized language and his attention to sensual detail His work is also deeply imbued with Christian themes The two final installments of the Rabbit series Rabbit is Rich 1981 and Rabbit at Rest 1990 were both awarded the Pulitzer Prize for Fiction Other notable works include the <PERSON>Henry Bech</PERSON> novels 1970 98 The Witches of Eastwick 1984 <PERSON>Roger</PERSON> s Version 1986 and In the Beauty of the Lilies 1996 which literary critic <PERSON>Michiko Kakutani</PERSON> called arguably his finest 22 Frequently linked with <PERSON>Updike</PERSON> is the novelist <PERSON>Philip Roth Roth</PERSON> vigorously explores Jewish identity in American society especially in the postwar era and the early 21st century Frequently set in <LOCATION>Newark New Jersey</LOCATION> <PERSON>Roth</PERSON> s work is known to be highly autobiographical and many of <PERSON>Roth</PERSON> s main characters most famously the Jewish novelist <PERSON>Nathan Zuckerman</PERSON> are thought to be alter egos of Roth With these techniques and armed with his articulate and fast paced style <PERSON>Roth</PERSON> explores the distinction between reality and fiction in literature while provocatively examining American culture His most famous work includes the <PERSON>Zuckerman</PERSON> novels the controversial <PERSON>Portnoy</PERSON> s Complaint 1969 and Goodbye Columbus 1959 Among the most decorated American writers of his generation he has won every major American literary award including the Pulitzer Prize for his major novel American Pastoral 1997 In the realm of African American literature <PERSON>Ralph Ellison</PERSON> s 1952 novel Invisible Man was instantly recognized as among the most powerful and important works of the immediate post war years The story of a black Underground Man in the urban north the novel laid bare the often repressed racial tension that still prevailed while also succeeding as an existential character study <PERSON>Richard Wright</PERSON> was catapulted to fame by the publication in subsequent years of his now widely studied short story The Man Who Was Almost a Man 1939 and his controversial second novel Native Son 1940 and his legacy was cemented by the 1945 publication of Black Boy a work in which <PERSON>Wright</PERSON> drew on his childhood and mostly autodidactic education in the segregated South fictionalizing and exaggerating some elements as he saw fit Because of its polemical themes and <PERSON>Wright</PERSON> s involvement with the Communist Party the novel s final part American Hunger was not published until 1977 Perhaps the most ambitious and challenging post war American novelist was <PERSON>William Gaddis</PERSON> whose uncompromising satiric and large novels such as The Recognitions 1955 and J R 1975 are presented largely in terms of unattributed dialog that requires almost unexampled reader participation <PERSON>Gaddis</PERSON> s primary themes include forgery capitalism religious zealotry and the legal system constituting a sustained polyphonic critique of modern American life <PERSON>Gaddis</PERSON> s work though largely ignored for years anticipated and influenced the development of such ambitious postmodern fiction writers as <PERSON>Thomas Pynchon Joseph McElroy</PERSON> and <PERSON>Don DeLillo</PERSON> Another neglected and challenging postwar American novelist albeit one who wrote much shorter works was <PERSON>John Hawkes</PERSON> whose surreal visionary fiction addresses themes of violence and eroticism and experiments audaciously with narrative voice and style Among his most important works is the short nightmarish novel The Lime Twig 1961 Short fiction and poetry edit In the postwar period the art of the short story again flourished Among its most respected practitioners was <PERSON>Flannery O Connor</PERSON> who developed a distinctive Southern gothic esthetic in which characters acted at one level as people and at another as symbols A devout Catholic O <PERSON>Connor</PERSON> often imbued her stories among them the widely studied A Good Man is Hard to Find and Everything That Rises Must Converge and two novels Wise Blood 1952 The Violent Bear It Away 1960 with deeply religious themes focusing particularly on the search for truth and religious skepticism against the backdrop of the nuclear age Other important practitioners of the form include <PERSON>Katherine Anne Porter Eudora Welty John Cheever Raymond Carver Tobias Wolff</PERSON> and the more experimental <PERSON>Donald Barthelme</PERSON> Among the most respected of the postwar American poets are <PERSON>John Ashbery</PERSON> the key figure of the surrealistic <ORGANIZATION>New York School</ORGANIZATION> of poetry and his celebrated Self portrait in a Convex Mirror Pulitzer Prize for Poetry 1976 <PERSON>Elizabeth Bishop</PERSON> and her North amp South Pulitzer Prize for Poetry 1956 and Geography III National Book Award 1970 <PERSON>Richard Wilbur</PERSON> and his Things of This World winner of both the Pulitzer Prize and the National Book Award for Poetry in 1957 <PERSON>John Berryman</PERSON> and his The Dream Songs Pulitzer Prize for Poetry 1964 National Book Award 1968 A R <PERSON>Ammons</PERSON> whose Collected Poems 1951 1971 won a National Book Award in 1973 and whose long poem Garbage earned him another in 1993 <PERSON>Theodore Roethke</PERSON> and his The Waking Pulitzer Prize for Poetry 1954 <PERSON>James Merrill</PERSON> and his epic poem of communication with the dead The Changing Light at Sandover Pulitzer Prize for Poetry 1977 <PERSON>Louise Gl</PERSON> ck for her The Wild Iris Pulitzer Prize for Poetry 1993 W S <PERSON>Merwin</PERSON> for his The Carrier of Ladders Pulitzer Prize for Poetry 1971 and The Shadow of Sirius Pulitzer Prize for Poetry 2009 Mark Strand for Blizzard of One Pulitzer Prize for Poetry 1999 <PERSON>Robert Hass</PERSON> for his <ORGANIZATION>Time</ORGANIZATION> and Materials which won both the Pulitzer Prize and National Book Award for Poetry in 2008 and 2007 respectively and <PERSON>Rita Dove</PERSON> for her <PERSON>Thomas</PERSON> and Beulah Pulitzer Prize for Poetry 1987 In addition in this same period the confessional whose origin is often traced to the publication in 1959 of <PERSON>Robert Lowell</PERSON> s Life Studies 23 and beat schools of poetry enjoyed popular and academic success producing such widely anthologized voices as <PERSON>Allen Ginsberg Charles Bukowski Gary Snyder Anne Sexton</PERSON> and <PERSON>Sylvia Plath</PERSON> among many others Contemporary American literature edit Though its exact parameters remain disputable from the early 1970s to the present day the most salient literary movement has been postmodernism <PERSON>Thomas Pynchon</PERSON> a seminal practitioner of the form drew in his work on modernist fixtures such as temporal distortion unreliable narrators and internal monologue and coupled them with distinctly postmodern techniques such as metafiction ideogrammatic characterization unrealistic names <PERSON>Oedipa Maas Benny Profane</PERSON> etc absurdist plot elements and hyperbolic humor deliberate use of anachronisms and archaisms a strong focus on postcolonial themes and a subversive commingling of high and low culture In 1973 he published Gravity s Rainbow a leading work in this genre which won the National Book Award and was unanimously nominated for the Pulitzer Prize for Fiction that year His other major works include his debut V 1963 The Crying of Lot 49 1966 <PERSON>Mason</PERSON> amp <PERSON>Dixon</PERSON> 1997 and Against the Day 2006 <PERSON>Toni Morrison</PERSON> recipient of the Nobel Prize for Literature writing in a distinctive lyrical prose style published her controversial debut novel The Bluest Eye to critical acclaim in 1970 Coming on the heels of the signing of the Civil Rights Act of 1965 the novel widely studied in American schools includes an elaborate description of incestuous rape and explores the conventions of beauty established by a historically racist society painting a portrait of a self immolating black family in search of beauty in whiteness Since then <PERSON>Morrison</PERSON> has experimented with lyric fantasy as in her two best known later works Song of Solomon 1977 and Beloved 1987 for which she was awarded the Pulitzer Prize for Fiction along these lines critic <PERSON>Harold Bloom</PERSON> has drawn favorable comparisons to <ORGANIZATION>Virginia Woolf</ORGANIZATION> 24 and the Nobel committee to <PERSON>Faulkner</PERSON> and to the Latin American tradition of magical realism 25 Beloved was chosen in a 2006 survey conducted by <ORGANIZATION>The New York Times</ORGANIZATION> as the most important work of fiction of the last 25 years 26 Writing in a lyrical flowing style that eschews excessive use of the comma and semicolon recalling <PERSON>William Faulkner</PERSON> and <PERSON>Ernest Hemingway</PERSON> in equal measure <PERSON>Cormac McCarthy</PERSON> seizes on the literary traditions of several regions of the <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> and includes multiple genres He writes in the Southern Gothic aesthetic in his Faulknerian 1965 debut The Orchard Keeper and Suttree 1979 in the Epic Western tradition with grotesquely drawn characters and symbolic narrative turns reminiscent of <LOCATION>Melville</LOCATION> in Blood Meridian 1985 which <PERSON>Harold Bloom</PERSON> styled the greatest single book since <PERSON>Faulkner</PERSON> s As I Lay Dying calling the character of Judge <PERSON>Holden</PERSON> short of Moby <PERSON>Dick</PERSON> the most monstrous apparition in all of American literature 27 in a much more pastoral tone in his celebrated Border Trilogy 1992 98 of bildungsromans including All the Pretty Horses 1992 winner of the National Book Award and in the post apocalyptic genre in the Pulitzer Prize winning The Road 2007 His novels are noted for achieving both commercial and critical success several of his works having been adapted to film <PERSON>Don DeLillo</PERSON> who rose to literary prominence with the publication of his 1985 novel White Noise a work broaching the subjects of death and consumerism and doubling as a piece of comic social criticism began his writing career in 1971 with Americana He is listed by <PERSON>Harold Bloom</PERSON> as being among the preeminent contemporary American writers in the company of such figures as <PERSON>Philip Roth Cormac McCarthy</PERSON> and <PERSON>Thomas Pynchon</PERSON> 28 His 1997 novel Underworld chronicles American life through and immediately after the Cold War and is usually considered his masterpiece It was also the runner up in a survey that asked writers to identify the most important work of fiction of the last 25 years 26 Among his other important novels are Libra 1988 Mao II 1991 and Falling Man 2007 image <PERSON>Jonathan Franzen</PERSON> at the 2008 Brooklyn Book Festival Seizing on the distinctly postmodern techniques of digression narrative fragmentation and elaborate symbolism and strongly influenced by the works of <PERSON>Thomas Pynchon David Foster Wallace</PERSON> began his writing career with The Broom of the System published to moderate acclaim in 1987 His second novel Infinite Jest 1997 a futuristic portrait of <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> and a playful critique of the media saturated nature of American life has been consistently ranked among the most important works of the 20th century 29 and his final novel unfinished at the time of his death The Pale King 2011 has garnered much praise and attention In addition to his novels he also authored three acclaimed short story collections Girl with Curious Hair 1989 Brief Interviews with Hideous Men 1999 and Oblivion Stories 2004 <PERSON>Jonathan Franzen Wallace</PERSON> s friend and contemporary rose to prominence after the 2001 publication of his National Book Award winning third novel The Corrections He began his writing career in 1988 with the well received The Twenty Seventh City a novel centering on his native <LOCATION>St Louis</LOCATION> but did not gain national attention until the publication of his essay Perchance to Dream in <PERSON>Harper</PERSON> s Magazine discussing the cultural role of the writer in the new millennium through the prism of his own frustrations The Corrections a tragicomedy about the disintegrating <PERSON>Lambert</PERSON> family has been called the literary phenomenon of its decade 30 and was ranked as one of the greatest novels of the past century 29 In 2010 he published Freedom to great critical acclaim 30 31 32 Other notable writers at the turn of the century include <PERSON>Michael Chabon</PERSON> whose Pulitzer Prize winning The Amazing Adventures of <ORGANIZATION>Kavalier</ORGANIZATION> amp Clay 2000 tells the story of two friends <PERSON>Joe Kavalier</PERSON> and <PERSON>Sam Clay</PERSON> as they rise through the ranks of the comics industry in its heyday <PERSON>Denis Johnson</PERSON> whose 2007 novel Tree of Smoke about falsified intelligence during <LOCATION>Vietnam</LOCATION> both won the National Book Award and was a finalist for the Pulitzer Prize for Fiction and was called by critic <PERSON>Michiko Kakutani</PERSON> one of the classic works of literature produced by the Vietnam War 33 and <PERSON>Louise Erdrich</PERSON> whose 2008 novel The Plague of Doves a distinctly Faulknerian polyphonic examination of the tribal experience set against the backdrop of murder in the fictional town of <LOCATION>Pluto North Dakota</LOCATION> was nominated for the Pulitzer Prize and her 2012 novel The Round House which builds on the same themes was awarded the 2012 National Book Award 34 Minority literatures edit image <PERSON>Sandra Cisneros</PERSON> best known for her first novel The <ORGANIZATION>House</ORGANIZATION> on Mango Street 1984 and her subsequent short story collection Woman <LOCATION>Hollering Creek</LOCATION> and Other Stories 1991 She is the recipient of numerous awards including a National Endowment for the Arts Fellowship and is regarded as a key figure in Chicana literature 35 One of the developments in late 20th century American literature was the increase of literature written by and about ethnic minorities beyond African Americans and Jewish Americans This development came alongside the growth of the Civil Rights movements and its corollary the Ethnic Pride movement which led to the creation of Ethnic Studies programs in most major universities These programs helped establish the new ethnic literature as worthy objects of academic study alongside such other new areas of literary study as women s literature gay and lesbian literature working class literature postcolonial literature and the rise of literary theory as a key component of academic literary study After being relegated to cookbooks and autobiographies for most of the 20th century Asian American literature achieved widespread notice through <PERSON>Maxine Hong Kingston</PERSON> s fictional memoir The Woman Warrior 1976 and her novels <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> Men 1980 and Tripmaster Monkey His Fake Book Chinese American author <PERSON>Ha Jin</PERSON> in 1999 won the National Book Award for his second novel Waiting about a Chinese soldier in the <ORGANIZATION>Revolutionary Army</ORGANIZATION> who has to wait 18 years to divorce his wife for another woman all the while having to worry about persecution for his protracted affair and twice won the PEN Faulkner Award in 2000 for Waiting and in 2005 for War Trash Indian American author <PERSON>Jhumpa Lahiri</PERSON> won the Pulitzer Prize for Fiction for her debut collection of short stories Interpreter of Maladies 1999 and went on to write a well received novel The Namesake 2003 which was shortly adapted to film in 2007 In her second collection of stories <LOCATION>Unaccustomed Earth</LOCATION> released to widespread commercial and critical success Lahiri shifts focus and treats the experiences of the second and third generation Other notable Asian American novelists include <PERSON>Amy Tan</PERSON> best known for her novel The Joy Luck Club 1989 tracing the lives of four immigrant families brought together by the game of Mahjong and Korean American novelist <PERSON>Chang Rae Lee</PERSON> who has published Native Speaker A Gesture Life and Aloft Such poets as <PERSON>Marilyn Chin</PERSON> and <PERSON>Li Young Lee Kimiko Hahn</PERSON> and <PERSON>Janice Mirikitani</PERSON> have also achieved prominence as has playwright <PERSON>David Henry Hwang</PERSON> Equally important has been the effort to recover earlier Asian American authors started by <PERSON>Frank Chin</PERSON> and his colleagues this effort has brought Sui Sin Far <PERSON>Toshio Mori Carlos Bulosan John Okada Hisaye Yamamoto</PERSON> and others to prominence Hispanic literature also became important during this period starting with acclaimed novels by <PERSON>Tom</PERSON> s <PERSON>Rivera</PERSON> y no se lo trag la tierra and <PERSON>Rudolfo Anaya Bless Me Ultima</PERSON> and the emergence of Chicano theater with <PERSON>Luis Valdez</PERSON> and <PERSON>Teatro Campesino Latina</PERSON> writing became important thanks to authors such as <PERSON>Sandra Cisneros</PERSON> an icon of an emerging Chicano literature whose 1984 bildungsroman The <ORGANIZATION>House</ORGANIZATION> on <LOCATION>Mango Street</LOCATION> is taught in schools across the <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> <PERSON>Denise Chavez</PERSON> s The Last of the Menu Girls and <PERSON>Gloria Anzald</PERSON> a s Borderlands La Frontera The New Mestiza Dominican American author <PERSON>Junot</PERSON> D az received the Pulitzer Prize for Fiction for his 2007 novel The Brief Wondrous Life of <ORGANIZATION>Oscar Wao</ORGANIZATION> which tells the story of an overweight Dominican boy growing up as a social outcast in <LOCATION>Paterson New Jersey</LOCATION> Another Dominican author <PERSON>Julia Alvarez</PERSON> is well known for How the Garc a Girls Lost Their Accents and In the Time of the Butterflies Cuban American author <PERSON>Oscar Hijuelos</PERSON> won a Pulitzer for The Mambo Kings Play Songs of Love and <PERSON>Cristina Garc</PERSON> a received acclaim for Dreaming in Cuban Celebrated Puerto Rican novelists who write in English and Spanish include <PERSON>Giannina Braschi</PERSON> author of the Spanglish classic Yo Yo Boing and <PERSON>Rosario Ferr</PERSON> best known for Eccentric Neighborhoods 36 37 <LOCATION>Puerto Rico</LOCATION> has also produced important playwrights such as <PERSON>Ren Marqu</PERSON> s <PERSON>Luis Rafael</PERSON> S nchez and <PERSON>Jos Rivera</PERSON> and <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> based poets such as <PERSON>Julia de Burgos Giannina Braschi</PERSON> and <PERSON>Pedro Pietri</PERSON> as well as various members of the Nuyorican Poets Caf 37 Spurred by the success of N <PERSON>Scott Momaday</PERSON> s Pulitzer Prize winning House Made of Dawn Native American literature showed explosive growth during this period known as the Native American Renaissance through such novelists as <PERSON>Leslie Marmon Silko</PERSON> e g Ceremony <PERSON>Gerald Vizenor</PERSON> e g Bearheart The Heirship Chronicles and numerous essays on Native American literature <PERSON>Louise Erdrich Love Medicine</PERSON> and several other novels that use a recurring set of characters and locations in the manner of <PERSON>William Faulkner James Welch</PERSON> e g Winter in the Blood <PERSON>Sherman Alexie</PERSON> e g The Lone Ranger and Tonto Fistfight in Heaven and poets <PERSON>Simon Ortiz</PERSON> and <PERSON>Joy Harjo</PERSON> The success of these authors has brought renewed attention to earlier generations including <PERSON>Zitkala Sa John Joseph Mathews</PERSON> D <PERSON>Arcy McNickle</PERSON> and Mourning Dove More recently Arab American literature largely unnoticed since the <ORGANIZATION>New York Pen League</ORGANIZATION> of the 1920s has become more prominent through the work of <PERSON>Diana Abu Jaber</PERSON> whose novels include <ORGANIZATION>Arabian Jazz and Crescent</ORGANIZATION> and the memoir The Language of Baklava Nobel Prize in Literature winners American authors edit Further information Nobel Prize in Literature 1930 <PERSON>Sinclair Lewis</PERSON> novelist 1936 <PERSON>Eugene O Neill</PERSON> playwright 1938 Pearl S Buck biographer and novelist 1948 T S <PERSON>Eliot</PERSON> poet and playwright 1949 <PERSON>William Faulkner</PERSON> novelist 1954 <PERSON>Ernest Hemingway</PERSON> novelist 1962 <PERSON>John Steinbeck</PERSON> novelist 1976 <PERSON>Saul Bellow</PERSON> novelist 1978 <PERSON>Isaac Bashevis Singer</PERSON> novelist wrote in Yiddish 1987 <PERSON>Joseph Brodsky</PERSON> poet and essayist wrote in English and Russian 1993 <PERSON>Toni Morrison</PERSON> novelist 2016 <PERSON>Bob Dylan</PERSON> songwriter American literary awards edit See also Category American literary awards <ORGANIZATION>American Academy of Arts</ORGANIZATION> and Letters Pulitzer Prize Fiction Drama and Poetry as well as various non fiction and journalist categories National Book Award Fiction Non Fiction Poetry and Young Adult Fiction American Book Awards PEN literary awards multiple awards <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> Poet Laureate Bollingen Prize Pushcart Prize O Henry Award Literary theory and criticism edit See also Category American literary critics <PERSON>Edgar Allan Poe</PERSON> Dark Romanticism Short Story Theory T S <ORGANIZATION>Eliot Modernism Harold Bloom Aestheticism Susan Sontag Against Interpretation On Photography John Updike Literary</ORGANIZATION> realism modernism and aestheticist critic M H Abrams The Mirror and the Lamp study of Romanticism F O <PERSON>Matthiessen</PERSON> originated the concept American Renaissance <PERSON>Perry Miller</PERSON> Puritan studies <PERSON>Henry Nash Smith</PERSON> founder of the Myth and <ORGANIZATION>Symbol School of American</ORGANIZATION> criticism <PERSON>Leo Marx</PERSON> The Machine in the <LOCATION>Garden</LOCATION> study of technology and culture <PERSON>Leslie Fiedler Love</PERSON> and Death in the <ORGANIZATION>American Novel Stanley Fish Pragmatism Henry Louis Gates</ORGANIZATION> African American literary theory <PERSON>Gerald Vizenor</PERSON> Native American literary theory <PERSON>William Dean Howells</PERSON> Literary realism <PERSON>Stephen Greenblatt</PERSON> <ORGANIZATION>New Historicism Geoffrey Hartman Yale school of deconstruction John Crowe Ransom New Criticism Cleanth Brooks New Criticism Kenneth Burke Rhetoric</ORGANIZATION> studies Elaine Showalter Feminist criticism <PERSON>Sandra</PERSON> M <ORGANIZATION>Gilbert Feminist</ORGANIZATION> criticism <PERSON>Susan Gubar</PERSON> Feminist criticism J <PERSON>Hillis Miller</PERSON> Deconstruction <PERSON>Edward Said</PERSON> Postcolonial criticism <PERSON>Jonathan Culler</PERSON> Critical theory deconstruction <PERSON>Judith Butler</PERSON> Post structuralist feminism <PERSON>Gloria E Anzald</PERSON> a Latina literary theory <PERSON>Eve Kosofsky Sedgwick</PERSON> Queer theory <PERSON>Fredric Jameson</PERSON> Marxist criticism See also edit American Literature academic discipline List of 20th century American writers by birth year Additional genres edit Short story Detective fiction Horror fiction Nature writing Romance novel Science fiction and fantasy Western fiction Regional and minority focuses in American literature edit <ORGANIZATION>Literature of New England Chicago</ORGANIZATION> literature <ORGANIZATION>Southern literature Literature of Southern</ORGANIZATION> states <ORGANIZATION>Alabama Arkansas Florida Georgia Kentucky Louisiana Maryland Mississippi North Carolina South Carolina Tennessee Texas Virginia West Virginia Literature</ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION>Hawaii</LOCATION> LGBT literature Deaf American literature <ORGANIZATION>American Catholic</ORGANIZATION> literature American literature in Spanish Ethnic minority literature articles and lists Armenian American literature African American literature List of African American writers Jewish American literature List of Jewish American writers List of Arab American writers List of writers from peoples indigenous to the Americas Native American Renaissance Asian American literature Chinese American literature Korean American writers List of Asian American writers Hispanic American writers Chicano literature Chicano poetry Puerto Rican literature List of Puerto Rican writers List of Cuban American writers List of Mexican American writers Notes and references edit a b c d <PERSON>Baym Nina</PERSON> ed The <ORGANIZATION>Norton Anthology of American Literature New York W W Norton amp Company</ORGANIZATION> 2007 Print a b c d e f <PERSON>Skipp Francis</PERSON> E American Literature Barron s Educational 1992 Gray Richard A History of American Literature Blackwell 2004 a b <PERSON>Parker Patricia</PERSON> L <LOCATION>Charlotte Temple</LOCATION> by <PERSON>Susanna Rowson</PERSON> The English Journal 65 1 1976 59 60 JSTOR Web 1 March 2010 <ORGANIZATION>Schweitzer Ivy Review Early American Literature</ORGANIZATION> 23 2 1988 221 225 JSTOR Web 1 March 2010 <ORGANIZATION>Hamilton Kristie An Assault</ORGANIZATION> on the Will Republican Virtue and the City in <PERSON>Hannah Webster Foster</PERSON> s The Coquette Early American Literature 24 2 1989 135 151 JSTOR Web 1 March 2010 Joudrey Thomas J Maintaining Stability Fancy and Passion in The Coquette New England Quarterly 86 1 2013 60 88 a b c <PERSON>Campbell Donna</PERSON> M The Early American Novel Introductory Notes Literary Movements 14 July 2008 1 March 2010 http www wsu edu campbelld amlit earamnov htm <ORGANIZATION>Rutherford Mildred American Authors Atlanta The Franklin Printing and Publishing Co</ORGANIZATION> 1902 Reynolds Guy The Winning of the <ORGANIZATION>West Washington Irving</ORGANIZATION> s A Tour on the Prairies The Yearbook of English Studies 34 2004 88 99 JSTOR Web 1 March 2010 <ORGANIZATION>Gura Philip F American Transcendentalism A History New York Hill</ORGANIZATION> and Wang 2007 7 8 ISBN 978 0 8090 3477 2 A Brief Guide to the Fireside Poets at Poets org Accessed 10 07 2015 <PERSON>Emily Dickinson</PERSON> Archive 2018 01 24 Retrieved 2018 01 24 <PERSON>Hazel Hutchison</PERSON> The War That Used Up Words American Writers and the <ORGANIZATION>First World War Yale University Press 2015 Noel Stock The Life of Ezra</ORGANIZATION> Pound 1970 <PERSON>Hugh Kenner</PERSON> The invisible poet TS Eliot 1965 <PERSON>Jeffrey Meyers Scott Fitzgerald</PERSON> A Biography HarperCollins 1994 Maxwell Geismar American moderns from rebellion to conformity 1958 <PERSON>Keith Ferrell Ernest Hemingway</PERSON> The Search for Courage Rowman amp <PERSON>Littlefield</PERSON> 2014 <PERSON>John T Matthews William Faulkner</PERSON> seeing through the <ORGANIZATION>South Wiley 2011 Kimball Roger Existentialism Semiotics</ORGANIZATION> and Iced Tea Review of Conversations with <ORGANIZATION>Walker Percy New York Times</ORGANIZATION> August 4 1985 Accessed September 24 2006 <PERSON>Kakutani Michiko</PERSON> January 12 1996 Seeking Salvation On the <ORGANIZATION>Silver Screen The New York Times Books</ORGANIZATION> Retrieved December 3 2009 Groundbreaking Book Life Studies by <PERSON>Robert Lowell</PERSON> 1959 Accessed May 5 2010 Bloom Harold How to Read and Why page 269 Touchstone Press 2000 Nobel Prize Nobel Prize Award Ceremony Speech Nobelprize org 19 Aug 2010 1 a b What Is the Best Work of American Fiction of the Last 25 Years The <ORGANIZATION>New York Times</ORGANIZATION> May 21 2006 Retrieved December 4 2009 Bloom Harold June 15 2009 <PERSON>Harold Bloom</PERSON> on Blood Meridian A V Club Retrieved March 3 2010 Bloom Harold September 24 2003 Dumbing down American readers The <ORGANIZATION>Boston Globe</ORGANIZATION> Retrieved December 4 2009 a b All Time 100 Novels The Complete List Time Magazine October 16 2005 Retrieved December 4 2009 a b <PERSON>Grossman</PERSON> Lev August 12 2010 <PERSON>Jonathan Franzen</PERSON> Great American Novelist Time Magazine Retrieved August 16 2010 <PERSON>Kakutani Michiko</PERSON> August 15 2010 A Family Full of Unhappiness Hoping for Transcendence The <ORGANIZATION>New York Times</ORGANIZATION> Retrieved August 16 2010 <PERSON>Tanenhaus Sam</PERSON> August 19 2010 Peace and War The <ORGANIZATION>New York Times</ORGANIZATION> Retrieved August 19 2010 <PERSON>Kakutani Michiko</PERSON> 2007 08 31 In <LOCATION>Vietnam</LOCATION> Stars and Stripes and Innocence Undone The <ORGANIZATION>New York Times</ORGANIZATION> Retrieved April 17 2010 2012 National Book Awards National Book Foundation November 14 2012 Retrieved December 2 2012 <PERSON>Madsen</PERSON> 2000 p 107 <PERSON>Giannina Braschi</PERSON> National Book Festival Library of <ORGANIZATION>Congress</ORGANIZATION> 2012 Retrieved February 17 2015 <PERSON>Braschi</PERSON> one of the most revolutionary voices in <LOCATION>Latin America</LOCATION> today a b <PERSON>Ilan Stavans</PERSON> 2011 <ORGANIZATION>Norton Anthology of Latino Literature Norton</ORGANIZATION> Retrieved February 17 2015 Bibliography edit <PERSON>Bercovitch Sacvan</PERSON> 1994 2005 The <ORGANIZATION>Cambridge History of American Literature Cambridge Cambridge University Press</ORGANIZATION> CS1 maint Date format link image Wikisource logo svg <PERSON>Chisholm Hugh</PERSON> ed 1911 <ORGANIZATION>American Literature Encyclop dia Britannica 11th ed Cambridge University Press Gray</ORGANIZATION> Richard 2011 A History of American Literature <PERSON>Malden Wiley Blackwell</PERSON> M ller Timo 2017 Handbook of the American Novel of the Twentieth and <ORGANIZATION>Twenty First Centuries Boston de Gruyter External</ORGANIZATION> links edit image Wikiquote has quotations related to American literature 19th Century American Fiction and Poetry The <ORGANIZATION>Ohio State University Libraries Rare Books and Manuscripts Collection Audio</ORGANIZATION> lectures on American Literature in TheEnglishCollection com clickable timeline Electronic Texts in <ORGANIZATION>American Studies</ORGANIZATION> v t e North American literature Sovereign states <LOCATION>Antigua</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Barbuda Bahamas Barbados Belize Canada Costa Rica Cuba Dominica Dominican Republic El Salvador Grenada Guatemala</LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION>Haiti Honduras Jamaica Mexico Nicaragua Panama Saint Kitts</ORGANIZATION> and <LOCATION>Nevis</LOCATION> Saint <PERSON>Lucia Saint Vincent</PERSON> and the <ORGANIZATION>Grenadines Trinidad and Tobago United States Dependencies</ORGANIZATION> and other territories <LOCATION>Anguilla Aruba Bermuda Bonaire British Virgin Islands Cayman Islands Cura</LOCATION> ao <ORGANIZATION>Greenland Guadeloupe Martinique Montserrat Puerto Rico Saint Barth</ORGANIZATION> lemy <ORGANIZATION>Saint Martin Saint Pierre</ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION>Miquelon Saba Sint Eustatius Sint Maarten Turks</ORGANIZATION> and <LOCATION>Caicos Islands United States Virgin Islands</LOCATION> v t e English literature Historical Old English Middle English Early English Jewish Elizabethan Restoration Augustan Victorian Regional American African American <ORGANIZATION>Chicago Jewish American New England Southern Bangladeshi British Scottish Welsh Canadian Caribbean Filipino Indian Irish Oceanic Australian New Zealand Pakistani South</ORGANIZATION> African Related topics Anglo Norman literature Celtic literature English drama English poetry English studies European literature J rriais literature Postcolonial literature Women s writing in English v t e <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> articles History By event <ORGANIZATION>Timeline of U S history Pre Columbian era Colonial era Thirteen Colonies</ORGANIZATION> military history <ORGANIZATION>Continental Congress American Revolution War American</ORGANIZATION> frontier Confederation Period Drafting and ratification of Constitution Federalist Era War of 1812 Territorial acquisitions Territorial evolution Mexican American War Civil War Reconstruction Era Indian Wars Gilded Age Progressive Era African American civil rights movement 1865 1896 1896 1954 1954 1968 Spanish American War Imperialism World War I Roaring Twenties Great Depression World War II home front Nazism in the <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> American Century Cold War Korean War Space Race Feminist Movement Vietnam War Post Cold War 1991 2008 War on Terror War in <LOCATION>Afghanistan</LOCATION> Iraq War Recent events 2008 present By topic Outline of U S history Demographic Discoveries Economic debt ceiling Inventions before 1890 1890 1945 1946 91 after 1991 Military Postal Technological and industrial <LOCATION>Geography Territory</LOCATION> counties federal district federal enclaves Indian reservations insular zones minor outlying islands populated places states Earthquakes Extreme points <LOCATION>Islands Mountains</LOCATION> peaks ranges <ORGANIZATION>Appalachian Rocky National Park Service National Parks Regions East Coast West Coast Great Plains Gulf Mid Atlantic Midwestern New England Pacific Central Eastern Northern Northeastern Northwestern Southern Southeastern Southwestern Western Longest</ORGANIZATION> rivers <ORGANIZATION>Arkansas Colorado Columbia Mississippi Missouri Red South Rio Grande Yukon Time Water</ORGANIZATION> supply and sanitation <ORGANIZATION>Politics Federal Executive Cabinet Civil service Executive departments Executive Office Independent</ORGANIZATION> agencies Law enforcement President of the <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> Public policy <ORGANIZATION>Legislative House of Representatives</ORGANIZATION> current members Speaker Senate current members President pro tempore Vice President <ORGANIZATION>Judicial Courts of appeals District courts Supreme Court</ORGANIZATION> Law Bill of Rights civil liberties Code of Federal Regulations Constitution federalism preemption separation of powers <ORGANIZATION>Federal Reporter United States Code United States Reports Intelligence Central Intelligence Agency Defense Intelligence Agency Federal Bureau of Investigation National Geospatial Intelligence Agency National Reconnaissance Office National Security Agency Office of the Director of National Intelligence Uniformed Armed Forces Army Marine Corps Navy Air Force Coast Guard National Guard NOAA Corps Public Health Service Corps</ORGANIZATION> 51st state political status of <LOCATION>Puerto Rico District of Columbia</LOCATION> statehood movement <ORGANIZATION>Elections Electoral College Foreign</ORGANIZATION> relations Foreign policy Hawaiian sovereignty movement Ideologies anti Americanism exceptionalism nationalism Local government Parties Democratic Republican Third parties Red states and blue states <ORGANIZATION>Purple America Scandals State</ORGANIZATION> government governor state legislature state court Uncle <PERSON>Sam</PERSON> Economy By sector <ORGANIZATION>Agriculture Banking Communications Energy Insurance Manufacturing Mining Tourism Trade Transportation Companies</ORGANIZATION> by state <ORGANIZATION>Currency Exports Federal budget Federal Reserve System Financial</ORGANIZATION> position <ORGANIZATION>Labor</ORGANIZATION> unions <ORGANIZATION>Public debt Social welfare programs Taxation Unemployment Wall Street Society Culture Americana Architecture Cinema Cuisine Dance Demography Education Family</ORGANIZATION> structure Fashion Flag Folklore Languages American English Indigenous languages <ORGANIZATION>ASL Black American Sign Language HSL</ORGANIZATION> Plains Sign Talk Arabic Chinese French German Italian Russian Spanish <ORGANIZATION>Literature Media Journalism Internet Newspapers Radio Television Music Names People Philosophy Public</ORGANIZATION> holidays Religion Sexuality Sports Theater Visual art Social class Affluence American Dream Educational attainment Homelessness Home ownership Household income Income inequality Middle class Personal income Poverty Professional and working class conflict Standard of living Wealth Issues Ages of consent Capital punishment Crime incarceration Criticism of government Discrimination affirmative action antisemitism intersex rights islamophobia LGBT rights racism same sex marriage Drug policy Energy policy Environmental movement Gun politics Health care abortion health insurance hunger obesity smoking Human rights Immigration illegal International rankings National security Mass surveillance Terrorism Separation of church and state Outline Index Book Category Portal image Books aj svg aj ashton 01 svg Literature portal image Flag of the <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> svg <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> portal Authority control NDL 00560164 image Retrieved from https en wikipedia org w index php title American_literature amp oldid 839516090 Categories American literature North American literature English language literature American culture Hidden categories Use American English from May 2015 All <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> articles written in American English Use mdy dates from May 2015 Pages using div col without cols and colwidth parameters CS1 maint Date format <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> articles incorporating a citation from the 1911 Encyclopaedia Britannica with Wikisource reference Region topic template using suffix Navigation menu Personal tools Not logged in Talk Contributions Create account Log in Namespaces Article Talk Variants Views Read Edit View history More Search Navigation Main page Contents Featured content Current events Random article Donate to <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> store Interaction Help About Wikipedia Community portal Recent changes Contact page Tools What links here Related changes Upload file Special pages Permanent link Page information Wikidata item Cite this page Print export Create a book Download as PDF Printable version In other projects Wikimedia Commons Wikibooks Wikiquote Languages Asturianu B n l m g Bosanski Catal e tina <ORGANIZATION>Dansk Deutsch Eesti Espa</ORGANIZATION> ol Fran ais <LOCATION>Hrvatski Bahasa Indonesia Italiano Latina Magyar Nederlands Norsk Polski Portugu</LOCATION> s Simple English <LOCATION>Sloven ina Sloven ina Suomi Svenska Tagalog</LOCATION> T rk e <PERSON>Ti ng Vi</PERSON> t Winaray Edit links This page was last edited on 3 May 2018 at 23 33 Text is available under the Creative Commons Attribution ShareAlike License additional terms may apply By using this site you agree to the Terms of Use and <ORGANIZATION>Privacy Policy Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> is a registered trademark of the <ORGANIZATION>Wikimedia Foundation Inc</ORGANIZATION> a non profit organization Privacy policy <ORGANIZATION>About Wikipedia Disclaimers Contact Wikipedia Developers Cookie</ORGANIZATION> statement Mobile view image <ORGANIZATION>Wikimedia Foundation</ORGANIZATION> image Powered by <PERSON>MediaWiki</PERSON></ner>
