<ner>skip navigation Library of Congress National Book Festival image Library of <ORGANIZATION>Congress</ORGANIZATION> Ask a Librarian Digital Collections Library Catalogs Search GO The Library of <ORGANIZATION>Congress</ORGANIZATION> gt National Book Festival gt Authors gt <PERSON>Giannina Braschi</PERSON> image National Book Festival National Book Festival Image Book Festival Home Festival Information Authors FAQs Sponsors Background Support the Festival Contact Us More National Book Festival Resources Book Festival Blog Kids amp Teachers Guide Related Resources at the Library Book Festival Videos Book Festival Podcasts Books from the Library Shop Read gov Support The Festival DONATE NOW bookmark skip_menu <PERSON>Giannina Braschi Giannina Braschi</PERSON> has been called one of the most revolutionary voices in <LOCATION>Latin America</LOCATION> today by the <ORGANIZATION>PEN</ORGANIZATION> organization Her first published work was a book of poetry Asalto al tiempo written in Spanish prose and published in <LOCATION>Barcelona</LOCATION> in 1980 Since then she has had critical essays a novella and more poetry published in Spanish In 1994 the first English translation of her collected works was published in the poetry trilogy Empire of Dreams She then went on to write Yo Yo Boing written in Spanglish Her new book is <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> of <ORGANIZATION>Banana Amazon Crossing Braschi</ORGANIZATION> is a National Endowment for the Arts fellow Previous National Book Festival Appearances 2012 Book Festival Webcast image <PERSON>Giannina Braschi</PERSON> Connect with the Library All ways to connect Find Us On image <LOCATION>Pinterest</LOCATION> image Facebook image Twitter image YouTube image Flickr Subscribe amp Comment RSS amp E Mail Blogs Download amp Play Apps Podcasts Webcasts iTunesU external link Questions Ask a Librarian Contact Us About Press Jobs Donate Inspector General Legal Accessibility External Link Disclaimer <LOCATION>USA</LOCATION> gov Speech Enabled</ner>
