<ner>American literature Q233762 From Wikidata Jump to navigation search literature written or related to the <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> edit Language Label Description Also known as English American literature literature written or related to the <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> Statements studied by American literature 0 references Commons category Literature of the <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> 0 references topic s main Wikimedia portal Portal American literature 1 reference imported from Dutch <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> topic s main category Category American literature 0 references described by source Small <PERSON>Brockhaus</PERSON> and Efron Encyclopedic Dictionary statement is subject of Q24743525 0 references <PERSON>Brockhaus</PERSON> and Efron Encyclopedic Dictionary statement is subject of Q24494678 0 references Great Soviet Encyclopedia 1926 1947 statement is subject of Q25894778 0 references Dewey Decimal Classification 810 0 references <ORGANIZATION>Library of Congress Classification PS</ORGANIZATION> 0 references Identifiers BNCF Thesaurus ID 7137 1 reference imported from <ORGANIZATION>National Central Library of Florence NDL Auth</ORGANIZATION> ID 00560164 0 references Freebase ID m 01c8sr 1 reference stated in Freebase Data Dumps publication date 28 October 2013 PSH ID 7047 0 references JSTOR topic ID american literature 0 references Quora topic <ORGANIZATION>ID Literature of the United States of America</ORGANIZATION> 0 references BabelNet ID 01263633n 1 reference imported from BabelNet Encyclop dia Universalis Online ID etats unis d amerique arts et culture la litterature 0 references <ORGANIZATION>Sitelinks Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> 44 entries edit arwiki astwiki Lliteratura d <PERSON>Estaos Xun</PERSON> os bewiki bgwiki bnwiki bswiki Ameri ka knji evnost cawiki Literatura dels Estats Units d Am rica cswiki Americk literatura dawiki Amerikansk litteratur dewiki Amerikanische Literatur enwiki American literature eswiki <ORGANIZATION>Literatura de Estados Unidos</ORGANIZATION> etwiki Ameerika hendriikide kirjandus fiwiki Yhdysvaltalainen kirjallisuus frwiki <PERSON>Litt</PERSON> rature am ricaine hiwiki hrwiki Ameri ka knji evnost huwiki Az Amerikai Egyes lt llamok irodalma idwiki Sastra Amerika Serikat itwiki Letteratura statunitense jawiki kawiki kowiki lawiki Litterae Civitatum Foederatarum mlwiki nlwiki Amerikaanse literatuur nowiki Amerikansk litteratur pawiki plwiki Literatura ameryka ska pnbwiki ptwiki <ORGANIZATION>Literatura dos Estados Unidos</ORGANIZATION> ruwiki simplewiki American literature siwiki skwiki Literat ra Spojen ch t tov slwiki Ameri ka knji evnost svwiki <LOCATION>Litteratur i USA</LOCATION> tlwiki Panitikang Amerikano trwiki Amerikan edebiyat ukwiki viwiki V n h c M warwiki Literatura Amerikana zh_min_nanwiki B kok b n ha k zhwiki Wikibooks 2 entries edit enwikibooks American Literature nlwikibooks Amerikaanse literatuur <ORGANIZATION>Wikinews</ORGANIZATION> 0 entries edit Wikiquote 1 entry edit enwikiquote American literature <ORGANIZATION>Wikisource</ORGANIZATION> 0 entries edit <ORGANIZATION>Wikiversity</ORGANIZATION> 0 entries edit <ORGANIZATION>Wikivoyage</ORGANIZATION> 0 entries edit <ORGANIZATION>Wiktionary</ORGANIZATION> 0 entries edit Other sites 0 entries edit image Retrieved from https www wikidata org w index php title Q233762 amp oldid 649217366 Navigation menu Personal tools English Not logged in Talk Contributions Create account Log in Namespaces Item Discussion Variants Views Read View history More Search Navigation Main page Community portal Project chat Create a new item Recent changes Random item Query Service Nearby Help Donate Print export Download as PDF Tools What links here Related changes Special pages Permanent link Page information Concept URI Cite this page This page was last edited on 14 March 2018 at 11 18 All structured data from the main and property namespace is available under the Creative Commons CC0 License text in the other namespaces is available under the Creative Commons Attribution ShareAlike License additional terms may apply By using this site you agree to the Terms of Use and Privacy Policy Privacy policy About Wikidata Disclaimers Developers Cookie statement Mobile view Data access image <ORGANIZATION>Wikimedia Foundation</ORGANIZATION> image Powered by <PERSON>MediaWiki</PERSON></ner>
