<ner>image TIME Time com MY ACCOUNT SIGN IN SIGN OUT SUBSCRIBE SUBSCRIBE Home U S Politics World Business Tech Health TIME Health Motto Entertainment Science Newsfeed Living Sports History The TIME Vault Magazine Ideas TIME Labs Money LIFE The Daily Cut Photography Videos The Goods Shop TIME Press Room TIME Guide to Happiness The 100 Most Influential People American Voices Finding Home The Influencers Looking Forward Next Generation Leaders <PERSON>Person of the Year Top</PERSON> of the World Subscribe Newsletters Feedback Privacy Policy Your California Privacy Rights Terms of Use Ad Choices image Ad Choices RSS TIME Apps TIME for Kids Advertising Reprints and <ORGANIZATION>Permissions Site Map Help Customer Service</ORGANIZATION> 2018 <ORGANIZATION>Time Inc</ORGANIZATION> All rights reserved Subscribe Sign InSubscribe Books All TIME 100 Novels Critics <PERSON>Lev Grossman</PERSON> and <PERSON>Richard Lacayo</PERSON> pick the 100 best English language novels published since 1923 the beginning of TIME Share image Read Later prev1 of 104 nextView AllMaking the ListHow We Picked the List By <PERSON>Richard Lacayo</PERSON> Jan 06 2010 image Best Books of ALL TIME 100 Novels Welcome to the massive anguished exalted undertaking that is the ALL TIME 100 books list The parameters English language novels published anywhere in the world since 1923 the year that TIME Magazine began which before you ask means that Ulysses 1922 doesn t make the cut In May Time com posted a similar list of 100 movies picked by our film critics <PERSON>Richard Corliss</PERSON> and <PERSON>Richard Schickel</PERSON> This one is chosen by me <PERSON>Richard Lacayo</PERSON> and my colleague <PERSON>Lev Grossman</PERSON> whom we sometimes cite as proof that you don t need to be named <PERSON>Richard</PERSON> to be hired as a critic at TIME though apparently it helps Just ask our theater critic <PERSON>Richard Zoglin</PERSON> For the books project <PERSON>Grossman</PERSON> and I each began by drawing up inventories of our nominees Once we traded notes it turned out that more than 80 of our separately chosen titles matched Even some of the less well known ones like At Swim Two Birds We decided then that we would more or less divide the remaining slots between us That would allow each of us to include books that the other might not have chosen Or might not even have read Ubik What s an Ubik And that would extend the list into places where mere agreement wouldn t take it Even so there are many titles we couldn t fit here that we re still anguishing over <PERSON>Djuna Barnes Nightwood</PERSON> dropped in and out <LOCATION>Aldous Huxley</LOCATION> s Point Counter Point hovered for a while at the edges There were writers we had to admit we love more for their short stories than their novels <PERSON>Donald Barthelme Annie Proulx Flannery O Connor Eudora Welty</PERSON> We could agree that some of <PERSON>Gore Vidal</PERSON> s novels are an essential pleasure but it s his non fiction that s essential period Then there was the intellectual massif of <PERSON>Norman Mailer</PERSON> indisputably one of the great writers of our time but his supreme achievements are his headlong reconfigurations of the whole idea of non fiction books like Armies of the Night and The Executioner s <PERSON>Song Dawn Powell Mordechai Richler Thomas Wolfe Peter Carey J F Powers Mary McCarthy Edmund White Larry McMurtry Katherine Ann Porter Amy Tan John Dos Passos Oscar Hijuelos</PERSON> we looked over our bookcases and many more than 100 names laid down a claim This means you <PERSON>Stephen King</PERSON> This project which got underway in January was not just a reading effort It was a re reading effort It meant revisiting a lot of novels both of us had not looked into for some time A few titles that seemed indispensable some years ago turned out on a second tasting to be well dispensable More common was the experience I had with <PERSON>Saul Bellow</PERSON> s <PERSON>Herzog</PERSON> about a man coming to terms with the disappointments of midlife by directing his questions everywhere It was one of the first adult novels I attempted in late adolescence It left its treadmarks on me even then but this time his experienced heart spoke to me differently There were also first time discoveries Having heard for years that <PERSON>Richard Yates</PERSON> Revolutionary Road was one of the great but underappreciated American novels I searched it out I have spent the months since then pressing it into the hands of anybody who will take it including yours Their Eyes Were Watching God <PERSON>Zora Neale Hurston</PERSON> s great story of a black woman surviving whatever God and man throws at her was not part of the required reading list when I was in school It is now part of my personal canon <PERSON>Henry Green</PERSON> Hadn t read <PERSON>Henry Green</PERSON> Finally read Loving Loved it Lists like this one have two purposes One is to instruct The other of course is to enrage We re bracing ourselves for the e mails that start out You moron You pathetic bourgeoise insect How could you have left off insert title here We say <PERSON>Mrs Dalloway You</PERSON> say Mrs Bridge We say Naked Lunch You say Breakfast at Tiffanys Let s call the whole thing off Just the opposite bring it on Sometimes judgment is best formed under fire But please no e mails about Ulysses Rules are rules Next The Adventures of Augie March Full List Making the List How We Picked the List A B The Adventures of Augie March All the King s Men American Pastoral An <ORGANIZATION>American Tragedy Animal Farm Appointment</ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION>Samarra</LOCATION> Are You There God It s Me Margaret The Assistant At Swim Two Birds Atonement Beloved The Berlin Stories The Big Sleep The Blind Assassin Blood Meridian Brideshead Revisited The Bridge of <LOCATION>San Luis</LOCATION> Rey C D Call It Sleep Catch 22 The Catcher in the Rye A Clockwork Orange The Confessions of <ORGANIZATION>Nat Turner</ORGANIZATION> The Corrections The Crying of Lot 49 A Dance to the Music of Time The Day of the Locust Death Comes for the Archbishop A Death in the Family The Death of the Heart Deliverance Dog Soldiers F G Falconer The French Lieutenant s Woman The Golden Notebook Go Tell it on the Mountain Gone With the Wind The Grapes of Wrath Gravity s Rainbow The Great Gatsby H I A Handful of Dust The Heart is A Lonely Hunter The Heart of the Matter Herzog Housekeeping A <ORGANIZATION>House</ORGANIZATION> for Mr <PERSON>Biswas</PERSON> I Claudius Infinite Jest Invisible Man L N Light in August The Lion The Witch and the Wardrobe Lolita Lord of the Flies The Lord of the Rings The Moviegoer Loving Lucky Jim The Man Who Loved Children Midnight s <ORGANIZATION>Children Money Mrs Dalloway Naked Lunch Native Son</ORGANIZATION> Neuromancer Never Let Me Go 1984 O R On the Road One Flew Over the Cuckoo s Nest The Painted Bird Pale Fire A Passage to <LOCATION>India</LOCATION> Play It As It Lays <PERSON>Portnoy</PERSON> s Complaint Possession The Power and the Glory The <ORGANIZATION>Prime of Miss Jean Brodie Rabbit Run</ORGANIZATION> Ragtime The Recognitions Red Harvest Revolutionary Road S T The Sheltering Sky Slaughterhouse Five Snow Crash The Sot Weed Factor The Sound and the Fury The Sportswriter The Spy Who Came in From the Cold The Sun Also Rises Their Eyes Were Watching God Things Fall Apart To Kill a Mockingbird To the Lighthouse Tropic of Cancer U W Ubik Under the Net Under the Volcano Watchmen White Noise White Teeth Wide Sargasso Sea About the List TIME S List of the 100 Best Novels Your Opinion Tell us your thoughts about TIME s ALL TIME 100 Novels Email Print Share Facebook Twitter Tumblr LinkedIn <ORGANIZATION>StumbleUpon Reddit Digg Mixx Delicious Google</ORGANIZATION> Follow TIMECulture Sections Making the List A B C D F G H I L N O R S T U W About the List Your Opinion SubscribePopular Among Subscribers image <LOCATION>Japan</LOCATION> s Booming Sex Niche Elder Porn image Young Kids Old Bodies image <PERSON>Benedict Cumberbatch</PERSON> Talks Secrets Leaks and <PERSON>Sherlock</PERSON> image <PERSON>Obama</PERSON> s Trauma Team Get all access to digital and printSubscribe Most Popular From Entertainment All TIME 100 Novels All TIME 100 Movies The Hunger Games Reaches Another Milestone Top 10 Censored Books The Anniversary You Can t Refuse 40 Things You Didn t Know About The Godfather All TIME 100 Songs From Time com Connect With TIME Home U S Politics World Business Tech Health Science Entertainment Newsfeed Living Ideas Parents Sports History The TIME Vault Magazine Subscribe Give a Gift The Goods Shop TIME Press Room Newsletters Customer Service Site Map Privacy Policy Your California Privacy Rights Terms of Use Advertising Ad Choices image Ad Choices Careers 2018 <ORGANIZATION>Time Inc</ORGANIZATION> All rights reserved image</ner>
