<ner>Create a new account Email Returning user Can t sign in Forgot your password Enter your email address below and we will send you the reset instructions Email Cancel If the address matches an existing account you will receive an email with instructions to reset your password Close Can t sign in Forgot your username Enter your email address below and we will send you your username Email Cancel If the address matches an existing account you will receive an email with instructions to retrieve your username Close Change Password Old Password New Password Too Short Weak Medium Strong Very Strong Too Long Cancel Congrats Your password has been changed Close Login to your account Username Forgot username Password Forgot password Keep me logged in New User Institutional Login image The MIT PressJournals Journals Resources For Librarians Institutional Activation Institutional License Agreement Usage Stats Document Delivery MIT Press Journals VPAT Join Our Librarian Mailing List Quick Guides 2018 Institutional Pricing 2018 Institutional Package Options and Pricing Single Issue Price List For Authors Submitting Publication Agreements Author Posting Guidelines Copyright Information Author Reprints Publishing Open Access <ORGANIZATION>NIH Public Access Policy Author Discounts The MIT Press</ORGANIZATION> and Kudos Quick Guides Guide1 Guide2 Guide3 Request Permissions Give to the Frank Urbanowski Fund Trade Sales Advertising Info Release Schedule FAQ Terminated Journals About The <ORGANIZATION>MIT Press</ORGANIZATION> is the only university press in the <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> whose list is based in science and technology Our goal is to create books and journals that are challenging creative attractive and yet affordable to individual readers About MITPJ Statement Statement of <ORGANIZATION>Publication Ethics Events amp Conferences Publishing Services MIT Press Journals Staff</ORGANIZATION> Contact Location The <ORGANIZATION>MIT Press One Rogers Street Cambridge MA</ORGANIZATION> 02142 1209 image Phone 800 207 8354 <LOCATION>US</LOCATION> amp <LOCATION>Canada</LOCATION> 617 253 2889 Outside <LOCATION>US</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Canada</LOCATION> 617 577 1545 Fax <ORGANIZATION>MIT Press</ORGANIZATION> business hours are M F 9 00 a m 5 00 p m Eastern Time Connect image Facebook image Twitter image <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> image Pinterest image Instagram image YouTube Send us a message Quick Email Links Change Your <ORGANIZATION>Address Advertising Inquiries List Exchange amp Purchasing Rights amp Permissions Payments amp Wire Transfer License Agreements amp Consortia Subscriptions</ORGANIZATION> amp Back Issues Electronic Access Queries To submit proposals to either launch new journals or bring an existing journal to <ORGANIZATION>MIT Press</ORGANIZATION> please contact Director for Journals and Open Access <PERSON>Nick Lindsay</PERSON> To submit an article please follow the submission guidelines for the appropriate journal s Sign In Register Enter words phrases DOI ISBN authors keywords etc Advanced Search 0 Home gt The New England Quarterly gt List of Issues gt Volume 86 Issue 1 gt Maintaining Stability Fancy and Passion in The Coquette Article navigation Previous Next image Publication Cover More About NEQ image Journal Resources Editorial Info Abstracting and Indexing Release Schedule Advertising Info The <LOCATION>New England</LOCATION> Quarterly site Author Resources Submission Guidelines Author Publication Agreement Author Reprints Reader Resources Rights and Permissions NEQ at JSTOR Most Read Most Cited Metrics image Article Metrics Altmetric about article usage data Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet consectetur adipiscing elit Aenean euismod bibendum laoreet Proin gravida dolor sit amet lacus accumsan et viverra justo commodo Proin sodales pulvinar tempor Cum sociis natoque penatibus et magnis dis parturient montes nascetur ridiculus mus Maintaining Stability Fancy and Passion in The Coquette <PERSON>Thomas J Joudrey</PERSON> Posted Online February 20 2013 https doi org 10 1162 TNEQ_a_00257 The <LOCATION>New England</LOCATION> Quarterly Volume 86 Issue 1 March 2013 p 60 88 image Order Subscribe image image Download Options image Maintaining Stability Fancy and Passion in The Coquette <PERSON>Thomas J Joudrey</PERSON> https doi org 10 1162 TNEQ_a_00257 Published Online February 20 2013 Authors PDF PDF Plus bookmark abstract Abstract Hannah Webster Foster s The Coquette performs the ideological task of quelling women s grievances against marriage in order to conserve social stability more broadly The novel s sustained denigration of passion and fancy deprives female readers of the means by which to register their dissatisfaction and to imagine alternative social relations 2013 by The <LOCATION>New England</LOCATION> Quarterly <PERSON>Thomas J Joudrey Thomas J Joudrey</PERSON> is a doctoral candidate in Victorian literature at <ORGANIZATION>Pennsylvania State University</ORGANIZATION> https doi org 10 1162 TNEQ_a_00257 Abstract Authors bookmark abstract Abstract Hannah Webster Foster s The Coquette performs the ideological task of quelling women s grievances against marriage in order to conserve social stability more broadly The novel s sustained denigration of passion and fancy deprives female readers of the means by which to register their dissatisfaction and to imagine alternative social relations 2013 by The <LOCATION>New England</LOCATION> Quarterly <PERSON>Thomas J Joudrey Thomas J Joudrey</PERSON> is a doctoral candidate in Victorian literature at <LOCATION>Pennsylvania</LOCATION> State University Forthcoming Most Read image Free Access <PERSON>Sybil Ludington</PERSON> the Female Paul Revere The Making of a Revolutionary War Heroine 1512 times <PERSON>Paula</PERSON> D Hunt The New England Quarterly Volume 88 Issue 2 pp 187 222 image Free Access A NOTE ON THE ORIGINS OF UNCLE SAM 1810 1820 1218 times <PERSON>Donald R Hickey</PERSON> The New England Quarterly Volume 88 Issue 4 pp 681 692 image Free Access Nationalism and the Nature of <PERSON>Thoreau</PERSON> s Walking 620 times Andrew Menard The New England Quarterly Volume 85 Issue 4 pp 591 621 See More Most Cited image No Access <PERSON>John Farmer</PERSON> and the <ORGANIZATION>Making of American Genealogy</ORGANIZATION> 3 times Fran ois Weil The <LOCATION>New England</LOCATION> Quarterly Volume 80 Issue 3 pp 408 434 image No Access To Tell What God Hath Done for Thy Soul Puritan Spiritual Testimonies as Admission Tests and Means of Edification 2 times <PERSON>Francis J Bremer</PERSON> The New England Quarterly Volume 87 Issue 4 pp 625 665 image Free Access Reason for a Renaissance The Rhetoric of Reformation and Rebirth in the Age of Transcendentalism 2 times <PERSON>Joe</PERSON> B <LOCATION>Fulton The New England</LOCATION> Quarterly Volume 80 Issue 3 pp 383 407 See More image Order Subscribe image image Download Options image Maintaining Stability Fancy and Passion in The Coquette <PERSON>Thomas J Joudrey</PERSON> https doi org 10 1162 TNEQ_a_00257 Published Online February 20 2013 Authors PDF PDF Plus bookmark abstract Abstract Hannah Webster Foster s The Coquette performs the ideological task of quelling women s grievances against marriage in order to conserve social stability more broadly The novel s sustained denigration of passion and fancy deprives female readers of the means by which to register their dissatisfaction and to imagine alternative social relations 2013 by The <LOCATION>New England</LOCATION> Quarterly <PERSON>Thomas J Joudrey Thomas J Joudrey</PERSON> is a doctoral candidate in Victorian literature at <ORGANIZATION>Pennsylvania State University Favorite</ORGANIZATION> image Sign up for Alerts image Download Citation image RSS TOC image RSS Citation image image Journals Books Terms amp Conditions Privacy Statement Contact Us <LOCATION>US</LOCATION> One <ORGANIZATION>Rogers Street Cambridge MA</ORGANIZATION> 02142 1209 <LOCATION>UK</LOCATION> Suite 2 1 <LOCATION>Duchess Street London</LOCATION> W1W 6AN <LOCATION>UK</LOCATION> Connect image Facebook image Twitter image <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> image Pinterest image Instagram image YouTube 2018 The <ORGANIZATION>MIT Press Technology Partner Atypon Systems Inc</ORGANIZATION> CrossRef Member COUNTER Member The <ORGANIZATION>MIT Press</ORGANIZATION> colophon is registered in the <ORGANIZATION>U S Patent and Trademark Office Site Help</ORGANIZATION></ner>
