<ner>image skip to content Your Web browser is not enabled for JavaScript Some features of WorldCat will not be available Home WorldCat Home About WorldCat Help Search Search for <ORGANIZATION>Library Items Search for Lists Search for Contacts Search</ORGANIZATION> for a Library Create lists bibliographies and reviews or image Find in a library with WorldCat Search WorldCat Find items in libraries near you Advanced Search Find a Library image image Your list has reached the maximum number of items Please create a new list with a new name move some items to a new or existing list or delete some items image Your request to send this item has been completed Cite Export image Close Window Cite Export Copy a citation APA 6th ed image Processing Chicago Author Date 15th ed image Processing Harvard 18th ed image Processing MLA 7th ed image Processing Turabian 6th ed image Processing Export a citation Export to RefWorks Export to EndNote Reference Manager Export to EasyBib Export to EndNote Reference Manager non Latin Cancel Note Citations are based on reference standards However formatting rules can vary widely between applications and fields of interest or study The specific requirements or preferences of your reviewing publisher classroom teacher institution or organization should be applied Print E mail image Close Window E mail All fields are required The E mail Address es field is required Please enter recipient e mail address es The E mail Address es you entered is are not in a valid format Please re enter recipient e mail address es You may send this item to up to five recipients Enter recipient e mail address es Separate up to five addresses with commas The name field is required Please enter your name Enter your name The subject field is required Please enter the subject Subject The E mail message field is required Please enter the message E mail Message image amp AllPage SpinnerRetrieving I thought you might be interested in this item at http www worldcat org oclc 607322888 Title The <PERSON>Norton</PERSON> anthology of Latino literature Author <PERSON>Ilan Stavans Edna Acosta Bele</PERSON> n <ORGANIZATION>Publisher New York W W Norton amp Co</ORGANIZATION> 2011 ISBN ISSN 9780393080070 0393080072 9780393975321 0393975320 OCLC 607322888 Please verify that you are not a robot image Processing Cancel Share Permalink image Close Window Permalink Copy this URL to link to this page image Close Add a review Would you also like to submit a review for this item Cancel image Your list has reached the maximum number of items Please create a new list with a new name move some items to a new or existing list or delete some items image You already recently rated this item image Your rating has been recorded Write a review Rate this item 1 2 3 4 5 image The <PERSON>Norton</PERSON> anthology of Latino literature Preview this item image Close Preview this item Nearby libraries Checking Find more libraries Librarian Claim your library to The <PERSON>Norton</PERSON> anthology of Latino literature Author <PERSON>Ilan Stavans Edna Acosta Bele</PERSON> n <ORGANIZATION>Publisher New York W W Norton</ORGANIZATION> amp Co 2011 Edition Format image Print book English 1st edView all editions and formats Summary Overview A dazzling and definitive compendium of the Latino literary tradition This groundbreaking Norton Anthology includes the work of 201 Latino writers from Chicano Cuban Puerto Rican and Dominican American traditions as well as writing from other Spanish speaking countries Under the general editorship of award winning cultural critic <PERSON>Ilan Stavans</PERSON> The Norton Anthology of Latino Literature traces four centuries of writing from letters to the Spanish crown by sixteenth century conquistadors to the cutting edge expressions of twenty first century cartoonistas and artists of reggaeton In six chronological sections Colonization Annexation Acculturation Upheaval Into the Mainstream and Popular Traditions it encompasses all genres featuring such writers as <PERSON>Jose Marti William Carlos Williams Julia Alvarez Oscar Hijuelos Cristina Garcia Piri Thomas Esmeralda Santiago</PERSON> and <PERSON>Junot Diaz</PERSON> Twelve years in the making The <ORGANIZATION>Norton Anthology of Latino Literature</ORGANIZATION> sheds new light on nuestra <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> through a gathering of writing unprecedented in scope and vitality Read more Rating not yet rated 0 with reviews Be the first Subjects American literature Hispanic American authors Hispanic Americans Literary collections Hispanic Americans View all subjects More like this User lists Similar Items Borrow obtain a copy Buy it image Close Add library to Favorites Please choose whether or not you want other users to be able to see on your profile that this library is a favorite of yours Allow this favorite library to be seen by others Keep this favorite library private Save Cancel Find a copy in the library image amp AllPage SpinnerRetrieving Finding libraries that hold this item Details Genre Form Literary collections Anthologies Document Type Book All Authors Contributors <PERSON>Ilan Stavans Edna Acosta Bele</PERSON> n Find more information about <PERSON>Ilan Stavans Edna Acosta Bele</PERSON> n ISBN 9780393080070 0393080072 9780393975321 0393975320 OCLC Number 607322888 Language Note Some text in parallel English and Spanish Notes Maps on endpapers Includes the work of 201 Latino writers from the Chicano Puerto Rican Cuban American and Dominican American tratitions as well as from the traditions of other Spanish speaking countries It traces five centuries of writing from letters to the Spanish crown by sixteenth century conquistadors to the cutting edge expressions of twenty first century cartoonistas and artists of reggaetaon Description lxxi 2489 A177 pages illustrations color maps 25 cm Contents Alternate table of contents Preface Acknowledgments Introduction Search for wholeness Colonization 1537 1810 Fray Bartolome de Las Casas 1484 1566 Devastation of the Indies a brief account Hispaniola That part of the mainland called <LOCATION>Florida</LOCATION> <PERSON>Alvar Nunez Cabeza de Vaca</PERSON> ca 1490 ca 1560 Chronicle of the <PERSON>Narvaez</PERSON> expedition When the fleet left <LOCATION>Spain</LOCATION> and the men who went with it How the governor came to <LOCATION>Xagua</LOCATION> and brought a pilot with him How we arrived in <LOCATION>Florida</LOCATION> How we went to the interior How the <ORGANIZATION>Indians</ORGANIZATION> separated us How we fled How we cured several sick people How the following day they brought other sick people How ready the Indians are with weapons On nations and languages Fray <PERSON>Marcos de Niza</PERSON> ca 1495 1558 Narrative of Fray <PERSON>Marcos de Niza Hernando de Soto</PERSON> ca 1496 1542 Letter of <PERSON>Hernando de Soto</PERSON> at <LOCATION>Tampa Bay</LOCATION> to the justice and board of magistrates in <LOCATION>Santiago</LOCATION> de <LOCATION>Cuba</LOCATION> <PERSON>Pedro Castaneda de Najera</PERSON> ca 1512 death unknown Narrative of the expedition of <ORGANIZATION>Coronado Of</ORGANIZATION> how the army started from <LOCATION>Culiacan</LOCATION> and the arrival of the general at <LOCATION>Cibola</LOCATION> and of the army at <LOCATION>Senora</LOCATION> and of other things that happened Of why <PERSON>Tiguex</PERSON> revolted and how they were punished without being to blame for it Juan de Castellanos 1522 1607 Revolt of the <ORGANIZATION>Borinquenos El Inca Garcilaso de La Vega</ORGANIZATION> ca 1539 1616 <LOCATION>Florida</LOCATION> of the Inca Book 2 Part 1 How they seized vitachuco Outbreak of the battle which occurred between the Spaniards and the Indians Gradual surrender of the conquered Indians and the constancy of seven of them Book 3 Mistress of <LOCATION>Cofachiqui</LOCATION> comes to talk with the governor offering him both provisions and passage for his army <PERSON>Sebastian Vizcaino</PERSON> 1548 1624 Diary of <PERSON>Sebastian Vizcaino</PERSON> Departure from the Bay of the Eleven Thousand Virgins and arrival at the <LOCATION>Port of San Diego</LOCATION> Departure from the <LOCATION>Port of San Diego</LOCATION> and arrival at the Island of <LOCATION>Santa Catalina Juan</LOCATION> de Onate 1550 1626 Letter written by <PERSON>Don Juan de Onate</PERSON> from <LOCATION>New Mexico</LOCATION> to the viceroy the Count of <LOCATION>Monterey</LOCATION> On March 2 1599 Account of the discovery of the <LOCATION>Buffalo</LOCATION> written by <PERSON>Juan Gutierrez Bocanegra Onate</PERSON> s secretary <PERSON>Gaspar Perez de Villagra</PERSON> ca 1555 1620 History of <ORGANIZATION>New Mexico Canto</ORGANIZATION> 1 2 14 Fray <ORGANIZATION>Eusebio Francisco Kino</ORGANIZATION> 1645 1711 Memoir of <ORGANIZATION>Pimeria Alta Book</ORGANIZATION> 1 First entry into Pimeria and the beginnings of its spiritual and temporal conquest and of its conversion to our holy Catholic faith Because of the suspension of the conquest and conversion of <LOCATION>California</LOCATION> two alms are asked for and obtained from the royal treasury for two missionary fathers for this coast and mainland nearest to <LOCATION>California Royal</LOCATION> provision and Royal Cedula which favor the new conversions My arrival at these missions of <LOCATION>Sonora</LOCATION> and my first entry into the Pimeria with the Father Visitor <PERSON>Manuel Gonzales</PERSON> Expedition to <LOCATION>San Ygnacio de Caborica San Joseph de Los Himiris</LOCATION> and <ORGANIZATION>Nuestra Senora de Los Remedios First</ORGANIZATION> opposition experienced in this new conversion Second opposition and discord sown in Pimeria Book 2 Visit and triennium of the Father Visitor <PERSON>Juan Maria Salvatierra</PERSON> 1690 1691 1692 Second and third expeditions to the Sea of <LOCATION>California</LOCATION> Expedition or mission to the north and northwest for more than one hundred leagues as far as to the <LOCATION>Rio Grande</LOCATION> and the casa Grande and the discovery of the two new nations the Opa and the Cocomaricopa Book 3 Arrival of the venerable Father <PERSON>Franciso Xavier Saeta</PERSON> at these new conversions his apostolic fervor work zeal and holy letters his glorious innocent death and various letters prophetic of the great fruit of these conversions Last letter of most tender farewell from the venerable father Concerning three other murders committed in <LOCATION>San Pedro</LOCATION> del <ORGANIZATION>Tubutama Happy</ORGANIZATION> and glorious death of the venerable Father <PERSON>Francisco Xavier Saeta</PERSON> and of his four servants and the plundering of his house Expedition of the <PERSON>Garrison</PERSON> of this province of <LOCATION>Sonora</LOCATION> to punish the delinquents and to remove the body of the venerable father Second and new expedition of the <PERSON>Garrison</PERSON> and new and greater disturbance than before Fray <PERSON>Junipero Serra</PERSON> 1713 1784 Letter to Fray <PERSON>Juan Andres Letter</PERSON> to <PERSON>Francisco Carlos</PERSON> de Croix Fray Juan Crespi 1721 1782 Letter to Fray <PERSON>Francisco Palou Juan Bautista</PERSON> de Anza 1736 1788 Diary of Governor <PERSON>de Anza</PERSON> s expedition against the Comanche nation August 15 September 10 1779 Annexations 1811 1898 <PERSON>Felix Varela</PERSON> 1787 1853 Letters to <PERSON>Elpidio</PERSON> Final observations on the humor of irreligious masks Civil religion in the <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> On the Quakers <PERSON>Eulalia Perez</PERSON> ca 1780 death unknown Old woman remembers <PERSON>Antonio Maria Osio</PERSON> y Higuera 1800 1878 History of <LOCATION>Alta California</LOCATION> Chapter 8 <PERSON>Gaspar Betancourt Cisneros</PERSON> 1803 1866 Letters from <PERSON>Lugareno Jose Maria Heredia</PERSON> 1803 1839 Ode to <ORGANIZATION>Niagara Frontier</ORGANIZATION> Memoirs Juan Nepomuceno Seguin 1806 1890 Personal memoirs of <PERSON>John N Seguin</PERSON> 1834 42 <PERSON>Jose Policarpo Rodriguez</PERSON> 1829 1914 Old guide Boyhood days Surveying <PERSON>Andrew Garcia</PERSON> 1855 1943 Tough trip through paradise 1878 1879 Murder of <PERSON>John Hays</PERSON> Southwestern Newspaper Poetry Juan B Hijar y <ORGANIZATION>Jaro</ORGANIZATION> dates unknown Heaven hands us our fate J M Vigil dates unknown Love and friendship <PERSON>Jose Romulo Ribera</PERSON> birth unknown 1917 Homeland and home <PERSON>Luis A Torres</PERSON> dates unknown Philosophical truths <PERSON>Luis Tafoya</PERSON> aka XXX 1851 1922 Same as usual To <LOCATION>New Mexico</LOCATION> Ramon Emeterio Betances 1827 1898 Arriba Puerto Ricans You shall be free Remembrances of a revolutionary Against Spanish Despotism Tenth of October Realized dream <PERSON>Maria Amparo Ruiz de Burton</PERSON> 1832 1895 Squatter and the <PERSON>Don Squatter Darrell</PERSON> reviews the past <PERSON>Don</PERSON> s view of the treaty of <ORGANIZATION>Guadalupe Hidalgo Eugenio Maria de Hostos</ORGANIZATION> 1839 1903 League of Puerto Rican Patriots Fragment from diary <PERSON>Lola Rodriguez</PERSON> de Tio 1843 1924 Song of <LOCATION>Borinquen Cuba Cuba</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Puerto Rico Sotero Figueroa</LOCATION> 1851 1923 Speech confirming the proclamation of the Cuban <ORGANIZATION>Revolutionary Party</ORGANIZATION> Cubans and Puerto Ricans <PERSON>Jose Marti</PERSON> 1853 1895 <LOCATION>Coney Island Love</LOCATION> in the city <LOCATION>Charleston</LOCATION> earthquake Two homelands Our America <PERSON>Manuel M Salazar</PERSON> 1854 1911 Story of a wayfarer or gervacio and aurora Chapter 19 <PERSON>Luis Munoz Rivera</PERSON> 1859 1916 Northward ho Speech given to the <ORGANIZATION>House of Representatives</ORGANIZATION> <PERSON>Miguel Antonio Otero</PERSON> Jr 1859 1944 My nine years as governor of the territory of <LOCATION>New Mexico</LOCATION> 1897 1906 Folsom train robberies <PERSON>Francisco Gonzalo Pachin Marin</PERSON> 1863 1897 <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> from within One aspect of its Bohemian life the rag Fabio Fiallo 1866 1942 Plenilunio Golgotha Rose Profane rhyme <PERSON>Jose Escobar</PERSON> dates unknown Literary progress in <LOCATION>New Mexico</LOCATION> Jesse Perez 1870 1927 Memoirs <PERSON>Julio G Arce</PERSON> aka <PERSON>Jorge Ulica</PERSON> 1870 1926 Spanish plague <PERSON>Chacon</PERSON> Family <PERSON>Eusebio Chacon</PERSON> 1869 1948 Calm after the storm <PERSON>Felipe Maximiliano Chacon</PERSON> 1873 1949 <PERSON>Senora Adelina Otero Warren Don Julio Berlanga Isidoro Armijo</PERSON> 1871 1949 Sixty minutes in hell Acculturation 1899 1945 Arthur A Schomburg 1874 1938 Negro digs up his past Juan Latino <PERSON>Leonor Villegas</PERSON> de Magnon 1876 1955 Rebel Rebel is a girl <PERSON>Cleofas</PERSON> M Jaramillo 1878 1956 Romance of a little village girl Pleasant outings Territory becomes a state <PERSON>Daniel Venegas</PERSON> ca 1880 ca 1935 Adventures of <PERSON>Don Chipote</PERSON> or a sucker s tale Chapters 1 3 <PERSON>Adelina Nina Otero Warren</PERSON> 1881 1965 Old <LOCATION>Spain</LOCATION> in our Southwest Old Spanish <PERSON>Hacienda William Carlos Williams</PERSON> 1883 1963 <ORGANIZATION>Libertad Igualdad Fraternidad</ORGANIZATION> Apology Sub Terra In The American grain Fountain of eternal youth Autobiography Pop and mother <PERSON>Bernardo Vega</PERSON> 1885 1965 Puerto Rican migration to the <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> Memoirs of <PERSON>Bernardo Vega</PERSON> From my hometown <LOCATION>Cayey</LOCATION> to <LOCATION>San Juan</LOCATION> and how I arrived in <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> without a watch Trials and tribulations of an emigrant in the Iron Tower of Babel on the eve of the World War 1 Proletarians extend a hand but hunger pinches and there is no remedy but to work in a weapons factory <PERSON>Vicente J Bernal</PERSON> 1888 1915 <PERSON>Elvira</PERSON> by the stream To <PERSON>Pedro Albizu Campos</PERSON> 1891 1965 Observations on the Brookings Institution Report <PERSON>Maria Cristina Mena</PERSON> 1893 1965 Emotions of Maria Concepcion Birth of the god of war <PERSON>Fabiola Cabeza de Baca Gilbert</PERSON> ca 1894 1991 We fed them cactus El Cuate Rodeo Fiesta at <LOCATION>San Hilario Luis Munoz Marin</LOCATION> 1898 1980 Sad case of <ORGANIZATION>Porto Rico Speech</ORGANIZATION> Jesus Colon 1901 1974 Puerto Rican in <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> and other sketches Mother the young daughter myself and all of us Grandma please don t come Way it was and other writings Two <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> Jewish people and us My wife doesn t work <PERSON>Felipe Alfau</PERSON> 1902 1999 Locos a comedy of gestures Identity <PERSON>Jose Davila Semprit</PERSON> 1902 1958 <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> One of many Eugenio Florit 1903 1999 In the big city Lonely poets of <LOCATION>Manhattan</LOCATION> Portrait of a man alone Out of the snow <PERSON>Jovita Gonzalez de Mireles</PERSON> 1904 1983 Bullet swallower Ernesto Galarza 1905 1984 Barrio boy Part One In a mountain village Part Five On the edge of the barrio <PERSON>Luis Leal</PERSON> 1907 2010 In search of Aztlan Fray Angelico Chavez 1910 1996 <LOCATION>New Mexico</LOCATION> triptych <PERSON>Hunchback Madonna Josefina Niggli</PERSON> 1910 1983 Mexican Village Quarry Upheaval 1946 1979 <PERSON>Julia de Burgos</PERSON> 1914 1953 To <PERSON>Julia de Burgos</PERSON> Ay ay ay of the kinky haired negress <LOCATION>Pentachrome Rio Grande de Loiza Song</LOCATION> to the Hispanic people of <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> and the world Canto to the free federation Farewell in <LOCATION>Welfare Island Americo Paredes</LOCATION> 1915 1999 With his pistol in his hand Country <PERSON>Guillermo Cotto Thorner</PERSON> 1916 1983 Tropic in <LOCATION>Manhattan</LOCATION> Two arrivals Rene Marques 1919 1979 Oxcart Act 3 Docile Puerto Rican literature and psychological reality Function of the Puerto Rican writer today <PERSON>Sabine R Ulibarri</PERSON> 1919 2003 My Grandma smoked cigars <PERSON>El Apache Jose Yglesias</PERSON> 1919 1995 Home again Chapter 1 <PERSON>Jose Antonio Villarreal</PERSON> b 1924 Pocho Part 1 <PERSON>Mario Suarez</PERSON> 1925 1998 El <PERSON>Hoyo Senor Garza Jose Luis Gonzalez</PERSON> 1926 1994 Night we became people again <PERSON>Bernardo Vega</PERSON> a fighter and his people <PERSON>Cesar Chavez</PERSON> 1927 1993 We shall overcome <PERSON>Jesus</PERSON> s friendship Organizer s tale <PERSON>Rufino Contreras</PERSON> What is democracy <PERSON>Nash Candelaria</PERSON> b 1928 Memories of the Alhambra Chapters 1 2 <PERSON>Rodolfo Corky Gonzales</PERSON> 1928 2005 I am <PERSON>Joaquin Pedro Juan Soto</PERSON> 1928 2002 Spiks Innocents Champ Scribbles <PERSON>Bayaminina Piri Thomas</PERSON> b 1928 Down these mean streets Alien turf <PERSON>Konk Richard Vazquez</PERSON> 1928 1994 Chicano Chapter 1 <PERSON>Rolando Hinojosa</PERSON> b 1929 <PERSON>Becky</PERSON> and her friends <PERSON>Maria Irene Fornes</PERSON> b 1930 <PERSON>Fefu</PERSON> and her friends <PERSON>Rosario Morales</PERSON> and Aurora <PERSON>Levins Morales</PERSON> b 1930 and b 1954 Getting home alive I am what I am RM Child of the <LOCATION>Americas</LOCATION> ALM Puertoricanness ALM Ending poem RM and ALM <PERSON>Jaime Carrero</PERSON> b 1931 Neo Rican Lesson <PERSON>Abelardo Lalo Delgado</PERSON> 1931 2004 Chicano movement some not too objective observations <PERSON>Heberto Padilla</PERSON> 1932 2000 Gift Remembrance of <PERSON>Wallace Stevens</PERSON> in <LOCATION>Florida</LOCATION> Man on the edge <ORGANIZATION>Princeton</ORGANIZATION> cemetery Song of the Prodigal Son <PERSON>Jack Agueros</PERSON> b 1934 Halfway to <PERSON>Dick</PERSON> and <PERSON>Jane</PERSON> a Puerto Rican pilgrimage Sonnet for 1950 Sonnet History of Puerto Rico <PERSON>John Rechy</PERSON> b 1934 City of night City of night Mr King between two lions <PERSON>Oscar Zeta Acosta</PERSON> 1935 1974 Autobiography of a Brown Buffalo Chapter 6 <PERSON>Nicholasa Mohr</PERSON> b 1935 Nilda May 1945 Wrong lunch line early spring 1946 Aunt <PERSON>Rosana</PERSON> s Rocker Zoraida Journey toward a common ground the struggle and identity of Hispanics in the <LOCATION>USA</LOCATION> <PERSON>Tomas Rivera</PERSON> 1935 1984 This migrant earth <PERSON>Luis Rafael Sanchez</PERSON> b 1936 Airbus New Yorkian quartet Estela Portillo Trambley 1936 1999 <LOCATION>Paris</LOCATION> gown <PERSON>Rudolfo A Anaya</PERSON> b 1937 Apple orchard Bless me <ORGANIZATION>Ultima Chapter Uno Chapter Dos Bendiceme America Lourdes Casal</ORGANIZATION> 1938 1981 <LOCATION>Hudson</LOCATION> in winter For Ana Veldford Conversation in a train station with an old man who speaks Spanish <PERSON>Rosario Ferre</PERSON> b 1938 House on the lagoon Thanksgiving Day 1936 Writing in between Arturo Islas 1938 1991 Rain god Judgement day <PERSON>Mary Helen Ponce</PERSON> b 1938 <LOCATION>Hoyt Street</LOCATION> 13011 Hoyt Street <PERSON>Jose Antonio Burciaga</PERSON> 1940 1996 Spilling the beans Spilling the beans Honorable Senator <PERSON>Ralph W Yarborough</PERSON> What s in a Spanish name Bilingual cognates <PERSON>Jose Kozer</PERSON> b 1940 Diaspora Nimia First amp last Final journey <PERSON>Luis Valdez</PERSON> b 1940 Zoot suit <PERSON>Victor Villasenor</PERSON> b 1940 Greatest Christmas gift <PERSON>Ricardo Sanchez</PERSON> 1941 1995 Indict Amerika Stream <PERSON>Teresa</PERSON> last night Fridays belong to friends sometimes Would that I could Nuyorican Poets <PERSON>Miguel Algarin</PERSON> b 1941 <PERSON>Mongo</PERSON> affair Nuyorican literature Nuyorican angel of despair Forget <PERSON>Hiram Morales Pedro Pietri</PERSON> 1944 2004 Puerto Rican obituary Broken English dream <PERSON>Jose Angel Figueroa</PERSON> b 1946 <PERSON>Boricua Cowboynomics Miguel Pinero</PERSON> 1946 1988 Short eyes Act 1 Lower East side poem This is not the place where I was born <PERSON>Sandra Maria Esteves</PERSON> b 1948 Here Puerto Rican discovery number 3 not neither <PERSON>Tato Laviera</PERSON> b 1950 My graduation speech Asimilao AmeRican Lady liberty <PERSON>Jesus Papoleto Melendez</PERSON> b 1951 Of a butterfly in el barrio or a stranger in paradise <LOCATION>San Antonio</LOCATION> Women Poets Angela de Hoyos 1940 2009 La Malinche to <PERSON>Cortes</PERSON> and vice versa <PERSON>La Vie</PERSON> I never said it was simple <PERSON>Evangelina Vigil Pinon</PERSON> b 1949 Apprenticeship Crimson the color Corazon en la palma <PERSON>Carmen Tafolla</PERSON> b 1951 Compliments Marked Letter to Ti Split a human Mitos machos y la Mujer Chicana Chapter 3 Myths machos and the movies will the real Chicana please stand up Puerto Rican Young Lords <PERSON>Iris Morales</PERSON> b 1948 Palante Siempre Palante the young lords <PERSON>Pablo Guzman</PERSON> b 1951 La Vida Pura a lord of the Barrio Into The Mainstream 1980 Present <PERSON>Tino Villanueva</PERSON> b 1941 Cycle bound Scene from the movie Giant My certain burn toward Pale Ashes Catharsis Voice over time At the <ORGANIZATION>Holocaust Museum Washington DC Isabel Allende</ORGANIZATION> b 1942 Paula Part 1 December 1991 to May 1992 <PERSON>Gloria Anzaldua</PERSON> 1942 2004 Borderlands La Frontera the new Mestiza Homeland Aztlan El onto <LOCATION>Mexico</LOCATION> Movimientos de rebeldia y las culturas que traicionan <PERSON>Ariel Dorfman</PERSON> b 1942 Heading South looking North Chapter dealing with the discovery of life and language at an early age Reinaldo Arenas 1943 1990 Mona Before night falls <PERSON>Mariel Dolores Prida</PERSON> b 1943 Coser y cantar a one act bilingual fantasy for two women <PERSON>Edward Rivera</PERSON> 1944 2001 Family installments In black turf <PERSON>Richard Rodriguez</PERSON> b 1944 Hunger of memory the education of <PERSON>Richard Rodriguez</PERSON> Part 1 Aria Days of obligation an argument with my Mexican father Chapter 2 Late Victorians Brown the last discovery of <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> Preface <PERSON>Alma Luz Villanueva</PERSON> b 1944 Bitch bitch bitch bitch Delicious death Warrior in the sand Even the eagles must gather <PERSON>Lucha Corpi</PERSON> b 1945 Winter song Day s work Undocumented anguish Sonata in two voices <PERSON>Octavio Armand</PERSON> b 1946 Braille for left hand Poem with dusk Poetry as Eruv Rene Aloma 1947 1986 Little something to ease the pain <PERSON>Alberto Baltazar Heredia Urista</PERSON> aka <PERSON>Alurista</PERSON> b 1947 Bone Labyrinth of scarred hearts Sometime war As our barrio turns who the yoke b on <PERSON>Juan Luz Maria Umpierre Herrera</PERSON> b 1947 Immanence No hatchet job <PERSON>Denise Chavez</PERSON> b 1948 Face of an angel Long story Sleepwalker Are you wearing a bra <PERSON>Juan Felipe Herrera</PERSON> b 1948 Exiles Literary Asylums <PERSON>Quentino Pablo Medina</PERSON> b 1948 Exiled memories a Cuban childhood Arrival 1960 Calle de la amargura Nothing Nietzsche Return of Felix Nogara Dictionary of Guatemalan bird calls <PERSON>Esmeralda Santiago</PERSON> b 1948 When I was Puerto Rican American invasion of <LOCATION>Macun Island</LOCATION> of lost causes <PERSON>Sherezada Chiqui Vicioso</PERSON> b 1948 Perspectives <PERSON>Haiti Victor Hernandez Cruz</PERSON> b 1949 Latest Latin dance craze <ORGANIZATION>Lunequisticos Poema Chicano Cantinflas</ORGANIZATION> Is it certain or is it not certain <ORGANIZATION>Caso Maravilla Jaime Manrique</ORGANIZATION> b 1949 Latin moon in <LOCATION>Manhattan Little Colombia Jackson Heights</LOCATION> <PERSON>Julia Alvarez</PERSON> b 1950 How the <PERSON>Garcia</PERSON> girls lost their accents Daughter of invention Entre <PERSON>Lucas</PERSON> y Juan Mejia Bilingual sestina Yo Sisters <PERSON>Dagoberto Gilb</PERSON> b 1950 Look on the bright side Down in the <LOCATION>West Texas</LOCATION> town <ORGANIZATION>Carlos M N Eire</ORGANIZATION> b 1951 Waiting for snow in <LOCATION>Havana</LOCATION> Chapter 1 2 14 <PERSON>Roberto G Fernandez</PERSON> b 1951 Raining backwards Retrieving Varadero Holy radishes Last supper <PERSON>Franklin Gutierrez</PERSON> b 1951 <PERSON>Helen Oscar Hijuelos</PERSON> b 1951 Mambo kings play songs of love Chapter 1 Mr Ives Christmas On Madison and Forty First Street <PERSON>Jimmy Santiago Baca</PERSON> b 1952 From violence to peace Place to stand Chapter 1 2 Sixteen ChicaIndio <PERSON>Pat Mora</PERSON> b 1952 Child a child La dulceria Coatlicue s rules advice from an Aztec Goddess <PERSON>Malinche</PERSON> s tips Pique from <LOCATION>Mexico</LOCATION> s mother <ORGANIZATION>Consejos de Nuestra Senora de Guadalupe Counsel</ORGANIZATION> from the <LOCATION>Brown Virgin Cherrie Moraga</LOCATION> b 1952 Giving up the ghost Teatro in two acts <PERSON>Judith Ortiz Cofer</PERSON> b 1952 Story of my body Latin Deli an <ORGANIZATION>Ars Poetica Chameleon Hostages</ORGANIZATION> to fortune To a daughter I cannot console Anniversary Gift of a Cuento May he be bilingual <PERSON>Alberto Alvaro Rios</PERSON> b 1952 Morning Man who became old Mayates Iguana killer <PERSON>Gary Soto</PERSON> b 1952 Level at which the sky begins How an Uncle became Gray At the <ORGANIZATION>Cantina Catalina Trevino</ORGANIZATION> is really from Heaven What are you speaking Charity of La Senora Lara Nickel and dime We ain t asking much <PERSON>Giannina Braschi</PERSON> b 1953 Yo yo boing Pelos en la lengua <PERSON>Ana Castillo</PERSON> b 1953 Mixquiahuala letters Letter 7 15 21 Guardians <PERSON>Regina Eduardo Machado</PERSON> b 1953 Broken eggs Act 1 <PERSON>Kathleen Alcala</PERSON> b 1954 Mrs Vargas and the dead naturalist <PERSON>Flora</PERSON> s complaint <PERSON>Amalia Lorna Dee Cervantes</PERSON> b 1954 Refugee ship Beneath the shadow of the freeway <PERSON>Francisco Goldman</PERSON> b 1954 Ordinary seaman Chapter 3 <PERSON>Elias Miguel Munoz</PERSON> b 1954 From the land of <ORGANIZATION>Machos Journey</ORGANIZATION> to Oz with my father <PERSON>Michael Nava</PERSON> b 1954 How town Chapter 1 <PERSON>Ricardo Pau Llosa</PERSON> b 1954 <ORGANIZATION>Dos Rios Frutas Dulce Charada China Return</ORGANIZATION> to <PERSON>Havana Luis J Rodriguez</PERSON> b 1954 Always running La vida loca Chapter 1 <PERSON>Helena Maria Viramontes</PERSON> b 1954 Under the feet of Jesus Chapter 2 Writers Of Latinidad <PERSON>Silvia Curbelo</PERSON> b 1955 Summer storm If you need a reason <PERSON>Cecilia Rodriguez Milanes</PERSON> b 1961 Muchacha after <PERSON>Jamaica Adrian Castro</PERSON> b 1967 In the tradition of returning <PERSON>Richard Blanco</PERSON> b 1968 <PERSON>Palmita Mia Havanasis Mother</PERSON> picking produce <PERSON>Sandra M Castillo</PERSON> b 1968 Looking South <PERSON>Guillermo Gomez Pena</PERSON> b 1955 Documented undocumented <PERSON>Carlos Morton</PERSON> b 1955 Many deaths of <PERSON>Danny Rosales Jose Rivera</PERSON> b 1955 House of <PERSON>Ramon Iglesia Luis Alberto Urrea</PERSON> b 1955 Lake of sleeping children Devil s highway a true story Rules of the game <PERSON>Roberto Valero</PERSON> 1955 1994 Roberto Phone call <LOCATION>Exile Islands</LOCATION> are evil and nobody knows it <PERSON>Ruth Behar</PERSON> b 1956 <LOCATION>Juban America Hebrew Cemetery</LOCATION> of <PERSON>Guabanacoa Susana Chavez Silverman</PERSON> b 1956 <PERSON>Killer Cronica Dionisio Martinez</PERSON> b 1956 History as a second language In a duplex near the <LOCATION>San Andreas</LOCATION> fault Je te veux Cultivation of orchids <PERSON>Achy Orejas</PERSON> b 1956 Wrecks <PERSON>Martin Espada</PERSON> b 1957 Revolutionary Spanish lesson Niggerlips Imagine the angels of bread My name is <PERSON>Espada Alabanza</PERSON> in praise of local 100 Republic of poetry <PERSON>Rolando Perez</PERSON> b 1957 <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> movie Hotel room Summer evening First experience Canto 10 <ORGANIZATION>Carolina Hospital</ORGANIZATION> b 1957 How the Cubans stole <PERSON>Miami Cristina Garcia</PERSON> b 1958 Dreaming in <LOCATION>Cuban Ocean</LOCATION> blue Meaning of shells <PERSON>Aguero</PERSON> sisters <PERSON>Dulce Fuerte Alicia Gaspar de Alba</PERSON> b 1958 <PERSON>Sor Juana</PERSON> s second dream Bishop s pawn <PERSON>Nilo Cruz</PERSON> b 1959 <PERSON>Anna</PERSON> in the tropics <PERSON>Demetria Martinez</PERSON> b 1960 Fragmentos Fragments Devil s workshop <PERSON>Ars Poetica Abraham Rodriguez</PERSON> b 1961 Boy without a flag <PERSON>Ruben Martinez</PERSON> b 1962 Other side notes from the new L A <LOCATION>Mexico City</LOCATION> and beyond Death in the family Manifesto Crossing over a Mexican family on the Migrant Trail Prologue Passion <PERSON>Virgil Suarez</PERSON> b 1962 Tea leaves caraoles coffee beans Ricochet Floridiana Trouble with some words in English Cucuyo Ghazal Razzmatazz Orthography What we choose of exile <PERSON>Rafael Campo</PERSON> b 1963 Elise Miss Key West 1990 Poet s education I am <PERSON>Mrs Lorca</PERSON> Changing face of AIDS <PERSON>Junot Diaz</PERSON> b 1968 Ysrael Brief wondrous life of <PERSON>Oscar Wao GhettoNerd</PERSON> at the end of the world 1974 1987 <PERSON>Ana Menendez</PERSON> b 1970 In <LOCATION>Cuba</LOCATION> I was a German shepherd <PERSON>Willie Perdomo</PERSON> b 1971 Nigger Reecan blues Brother <PERSON>Lo New Boogaloo Manuel Munoz</PERSON> b 1975 <PERSON>Zigzagger Daniel Alarcon</PERSON> b 1977 War by candlelight <PERSON>Maria Teresa Mariposa Fernandez</PERSON> b 1977 <PERSON>Boricua</PERSON> butterfly Ode to the diasporican Poem for my grifa rican sistah or broken ends broken promises Popular Dimensions Dichos Chistes Cartoonistas Gus Arriola 1917 2008 <PERSON>Gordo Hernandez</PERSON> brothers <PERSON>Mario</PERSON> b 1953 <PERSON>Gilberto</PERSON> b 1957 and <PERSON>Jaime</PERSON> b 1959 Mojado power <PERSON>Lalo Lopez Alcaraz</PERSON> b 1964 Hi Spanic hysteria month Estar Wars the brown menace Teatro popular Culture Clash Mission Act 1 scene 1 <ORGANIZATION>Cuentos</ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON>Leyendas Juan Chilili Paloma Blanca Chirlos Birlos Burro</PERSON> and the coyote Pranks of Pedro de Urdemalas Eyes that come out at night <ORGANIZATION>La Llorona La Llorona</ORGANIZATION> by <PERSON>Alcina Lubitch Domecq Flea Boy</PERSON> and the devil Canciones Children s song Arroz con leche Folk Song De colores <ORGANIZATION>Corrideo Corrido de Gregorio Cortez Corrido de Joaquin Murrieta Narcocorrido Contrabando</ORGANIZATION> y traicion written by <PERSON>Angel Gonzalez Bolero Lamento Borincano</PERSON> written by <PERSON>Rafael Hernandez Marin Salsa Burundanga</PERSON> written by <PERSON>Oscar Munoz Bouffartique</PERSON> and performed by <PERSON>Celia Cruz</PERSON> Merengue Carnaval del Barrio written by <PERSON>Lin Manuel Miranda</PERSON> Chicano Rock Good Morning Aztlan written by <PERSON>David Hidalgo</PERSON> and <PERSON>Louie Perez</PERSON> and performed by <LOCATION>Los Lobos Latin Pop Livin la Vida Loca</LOCATION> written by <PERSON>Desmond Child</PERSON> and <PERSON>Robi Rosa</PERSON> and performed by <PERSON>Ricky Martin Hip Hop Latin Lingo</PERSON> written by <PERSON>Senen Reyes Louis Freeze</PERSON> and <PERSON>Lawrence Muggerud</PERSON> and performed by <ORGANIZATION>Cypress Hill Reggaeton Somos</ORGANIZATION> raperos pero no delincuentes written and performed by Ivy Queen Appendix 1 Chronology Literature And History Appendix 2 Treaties Acts And Propositions Treaty of Guadalupe Hidalgo 1848 Treaty of <LOCATION>Paris</LOCATION> 1898 Jones Act 1917 Bracero Agreement 1942 California Proposition 187 1994 Appendix 3 Influential Essays By Latin American Writers <PERSON>Jose Enrique Rodo</PERSON> 1872 1917 <PERSON>Ariel Jose Vasconcelos</PERSON> 1882 1959 Cosmic race Mestizaje Part 1 2 Octavio Paz 1914 1998 Labyrinth of solitude Pachuco and other extremes <PERSON>Roberto Fernandez Retamar</PERSON> b 1930 <PERSON>Caliban</PERSON> notes toward a discussion of culture in our <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> Question Toward the history of Caliban Our symbol Selected bibliographies Permissions acknowledgments <ORGANIZATION>Index Responsibility Ilan Stavans</ORGANIZATION> general editor editors <PERSON>Edna Acosta Bele</PERSON> n and others Abstract A dazzling and definitive compendium of the Latino literary tradition Read more Reviews Editorial reviews Publisher Synopsis This book is an instant classic a groundbreaking work in the making for thirteen years There is no <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> without Latino doings and sufferings And there is no American literature without Latino voices and visions <ORGANIZATION>Cornel West Princeton University The Norton Anthology of Latino Literature</ORGANIZATION> will be for Latinos what The <ORGANIZATION>Norton Anthology of African American Literature</ORGANIZATION> has been for African Americans a celebration of a culture that has been yearning to sing itself into the canon <ORGANIZATION>Henry Louis Gates Jr Harvard University Nowhere</ORGANIZATION> else can scholars teachers and students find such a broad ranging and accessible collection A crucial and eminently useful resource for any reader hoping to understand the stunning diversity of <PERSON>Latina</PERSON> o experience and expression in the <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION>Jesse Hoffnung Garskof University of Michigan Imaginatively</ORGANIZATION> conceived painstakingly executed stunningly broad profoundly stirring endlessly engaging this book can change the way the world thinks about <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> and the way Americans think about themselves <ORGANIZATION>Felipe Fernandez Armesto University of Notre Dame</ORGANIZATION> This book is an instant classic a groundbreaking work in the making for thirteen years There is no <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> without Latino doings and sufferings And there is no American literature without Latino voices and visions <ORGANIZATION>Cornel West Princeton University The Norton Anthology of Latino Literature</ORGANIZATION> will be for Latinos what The <ORGANIZATION>Norton Anthology of African American Literature</ORGANIZATION> has been for African Americans a celebration of a culture that has been yearning to sing itself into the canon <ORGANIZATION>Henry Louis Gates Jr Harvard University Read</ORGANIZATION> more User contributed reviews Add a review and share your thoughts with other readers Be the first Add a review and share your thoughts with other readers Be the first image Retrieving GoodReads reviews image Retrieving DOGObooks reviews Tags Add tags for The <PERSON>Norton</PERSON> anthology of Latino literature Be the first Similar Items Related Subjects 14 American literature Hispanic American authors Hispanic Americans Literary collections Hispanic Americans Hispanics Amerikaans <ORGANIZATION>Hispanos Literatur USA Literatur Amerikanisches Englisch Chicanos Hispanos Chicano literature Anthologies USA User</ORGANIZATION> lists with this item 26 <ORGANIZATION>Hispanic Heritage Month</ORGANIZATION> 59 items by citruslibrary updated 2017 10 04 chicano collection 18 items by janetgarcia updated 2017 09 25 latino lit 1 items by remadegold updated 2017 09 06 Formerly Popular Picks Collection 153 items by SpragueLibrary updated 2017 04 28 Things to Check Out 1 items by antoniofgr2 updated 2016 09 19 Confirm this request You may have already requested this item Please select Ok if you would like to proceed with this request anyway Linked Data More info about <ORGANIZATION>Linked Data Primary Entity</ORGANIZATION> http www worldcat org oclc 607322888 gt The <PERSON>Norton</PERSON> anthology of Latino literature a schema CreativeWork schema Book bgn translationOfWork http www worldcat org title oclc 607322888 CreativeWork unidentifiedOriginalWork gt library oclcnum 607322888 library placeOfPublication http id loc gov vocabulary countries nyu gt library placeOfPublication http dbpedia org resource New_York_City gt <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> schema about http experiment worldcat org entity work data 476383616 Topic chicano_literature gt Chicano literature schema about http experiment worldcat org entity work data 476383616 Topic hispanics gt Hispanics schema about http experiment worldcat org entity work data 476383616 Topic literatur gt Literatur schema about http experiment worldcat org entity work data 476383616 Topic hispanic_americans gt Hispanic Americans schema about http id worldcat org fast 807169 gt American literature Hispanic American authors schema about http dewey info class 810 80868073 e22 gt schema about http id worldcat org fast 957523 gt Hispanic Americans schema about http id loc gov authorities subjects sh85004350 gt American literature Hispanic American authors schema about http experiment worldcat org entity work data 476383616 Topic amerikanisches_englisch gt Amerikanisches Englisch schema about http experiment worldcat org entity work data 476383616 Topic hispanos gt Hispanos schema about http experiment worldcat org entity work data 476383616 Topic chicanos gt Chicanos schema about http experiment worldcat org entity work data 476383616 Place usa gt <LOCATION>USA</LOCATION> schema about http experiment worldcat org entity work data 476383616 Topic amerikaans gt Amerikaans schema about http experiment worldcat org entity work data 476383616 Topic american_literature_hispanic_american_authors gt American literature Hispanic American authors schema bookEdition 1st ed schema bookFormat bgn PrintBook schema contributor http viaf org viaf 17373977 gt <PERSON>Ilan Stavans</PERSON> schema contributor http viaf org viaf 73902948 gt <PERSON>Edna Acosta Bel</PERSON> n schema copyrightYear 2011 schema datePublished 2011 schema description Upheaval 1946 1979 <PERSON>Julia de Burgos</PERSON> 1914 1953 To <PERSON>Julia de Burgos</PERSON> Ay ay ay of the kinky haired negress <LOCATION>Pentachrome Rio Grande de Loiza Song</LOCATION> to the Hispanic people of <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> and the world Canto to the free federation Farewell in <LOCATION>Welfare Island Americo Paredes</LOCATION> 1915 1999 With his pistol in his hand Country <PERSON>Guillermo Cotto Thorner</PERSON> 1916 1983 Tropic in <LOCATION>Manhattan</LOCATION> Two arrivals Rene Marques 1919 1979 Oxcart Act 3 Docile Puerto Rican literature and psychological reality Function of the Puerto Rican writer today <PERSON>Sabine R Ulibarri</PERSON> 1919 2003 My Grandma smoked cigars <PERSON>El Apache Jose Yglesias</PERSON> 1919 1995 Home again Chapter 1 <PERSON>Jose Antonio Villarreal</PERSON> b 1924 Pocho Part 1 <PERSON>Mario Suarez</PERSON> 1925 1998 El <PERSON>Hoyo Senor Garza Jose Luis Gonzalez</PERSON> 1926 1994 Night we became people again <PERSON>Bernardo Vega</PERSON> a fighter and his people <PERSON>Cesar Chavez</PERSON> 1927 1993 We shall overcome <PERSON>Jesus</PERSON> s friendship Organizer s tale <PERSON>Rufino Contreras</PERSON> What is democracy <PERSON>Nash Candelaria</PERSON> b 1928 Memories of the Alhambra Chapters 1 2 <PERSON>Rodolfo Corky Gonzales</PERSON> 1928 2005 I am <PERSON>Joaquin Pedro Juan Soto</PERSON> 1928 2002 Spiks Innocents Champ Scribbles <PERSON>Bayaminina Piri Thomas</PERSON> b 1928 Down these mean streets Alien turf <PERSON>Konk Richard Vazquez</PERSON> 1928 1994 Chicano Chapter 1 <PERSON>Rolando Hinojosa</PERSON> b 1929 <PERSON>Becky</PERSON> and her friends <PERSON>Maria Irene Fornes</PERSON> b 1930 <PERSON>Fefu</PERSON> and her friends <PERSON>Rosario Morales</PERSON> and Aurora <PERSON>Levins Morales</PERSON> b 1930 and b 1954 Getting home alive I am what I am RM Child of the <LOCATION>Americas</LOCATION> ALM Puertoricanness ALM Ending poem RM and ALM <PERSON>Jaime Carrero</PERSON> b 1931 Neo Rican Lesson <PERSON>Abelardo Lalo Delgado</PERSON> 1931 2004 Chicano movement some not too objective observations <PERSON>Heberto Padilla</PERSON> 1932 2000 Gift Remembrance of <PERSON>Wallace Stevens</PERSON> in <LOCATION>Florida</LOCATION> Man on the edge <ORGANIZATION>Princeton</ORGANIZATION> cemetery Song of the Prodigal Son <PERSON>Jack Agueros</PERSON> b 1934 Halfway to <PERSON>Dick</PERSON> and <PERSON>Jane</PERSON> a Puerto Rican pilgrimage Sonnet for 1950 Sonnet History of Puerto Rico <PERSON>John Rechy</PERSON> b 1934 City of night City of night Mr King between two lions <PERSON>Oscar Zeta Acosta</PERSON> 1935 1974 Autobiography of a Brown Buffalo Chapter 6 <PERSON>Nicholasa Mohr</PERSON> b 1935 Nilda May 1945 Wrong lunch line early spring 1946 Aunt <PERSON>Rosana</PERSON> s Rocker Zoraida Journey toward a common ground the struggle and identity of Hispanics in the <LOCATION>USA</LOCATION> <PERSON>Tomas Rivera</PERSON> 1935 1984 This migrant earth <PERSON>Luis Rafael Sanchez</PERSON> b 1936 Airbus New Yorkian quartet Estela Portillo Trambley 1936 1999 <LOCATION>Paris</LOCATION> gown <PERSON>Rudolfo A Anaya</PERSON> b 1937 Apple orchard Bless me <ORGANIZATION>Ultima Chapter Uno Chapter Dos Bendiceme America Lourdes Casal</ORGANIZATION> 1938 1981 <LOCATION>Hudson</LOCATION> in winter For Ana Veldford Conversation in a train station with an old man who speaks Spanish <PERSON>Rosario Ferre</PERSON> b 1938 House on the lagoon Thanksgiving Day 1936 Writing in between Arturo Islas 1938 1991 Rain god Judgement day <PERSON>Mary Helen Ponce</PERSON> b 1938 <LOCATION>Hoyt Street</LOCATION> 13011 Hoyt Street <PERSON>Jose Antonio Burciaga</PERSON> 1940 1996 Spilling the beans Spilling the beans Honorable Senator <PERSON>Ralph W Yarborough</PERSON> What s in a Spanish name Bilingual cognates <PERSON>Jose Kozer</PERSON> b 1940 Diaspora Nimia First amp last Final journey <PERSON>Luis Valdez</PERSON> b 1940 Zoot suit <PERSON>Victor Villasenor</PERSON> b 1940 Greatest Christmas gift <PERSON>Ricardo Sanchez</PERSON> 1941 1995 Indict Amerika Stream <PERSON>Teresa</PERSON> last night Fridays belong to friends sometimes Would that I could Nuyorican Poets <PERSON>Miguel Algarin</PERSON> b 1941 <PERSON>Mongo</PERSON> affair Nuyorican literature Nuyorican angel of despair Forget <PERSON>Hiram Morales Pedro Pietri</PERSON> 1944 2004 Puerto Rican obituary Broken English dream <PERSON>Jose Angel Figueroa</PERSON> b 1946 <PERSON>Boricua Cowboynomics Miguel Pinero</PERSON> 1946 1988 Short eyes Act 1 Lower East side poem This is not the place where I was born <PERSON>Sandra Maria Esteves</PERSON> b 1948 Here Puerto Rican discovery number 3 not neither <PERSON>Tato Laviera</PERSON> b 1950 My graduation speech Asimilao AmeRican Lady liberty <PERSON>Jesus Papoleto Melendez</PERSON> b 1951 Of a butterfly in el barrio or a stranger in paradise <LOCATION>San Antonio</LOCATION> Women Poets Angela de Hoyos 1940 2009 La Malinche to <PERSON>Cortes</PERSON> and vice versa <PERSON>La Vie</PERSON> I never said it was simple <PERSON>Evangelina Vigil Pinon</PERSON> b 1949 Apprenticeship Crimson the color Corazon en la palma <PERSON>Carmen Tafolla</PERSON> b 1951 Compliments Marked Letter to Ti Split a human Mitos machos y la Mujer Chicana Chapter 3 Myths machos and the movies will the real Chicana please stand up Puerto Rican Young Lords <PERSON>Iris Morales</PERSON> b 1948 Palante Siempre Palante the young lords <PERSON>Pablo Guzman</PERSON> b 1951 La Vida Pura a lord of the Barrio Into The Mainstream 1980 Present <PERSON>Tino Villanueva</PERSON> b 1941 Cycle bound Scene from the movie Giant My certain burn toward Pale Ashes Catharsis Voice over time At the <ORGANIZATION>Holocaust Museum Washington DC Isabel Allende</ORGANIZATION> b 1942 Paula Part 1 December 1991 to May 1992 <PERSON>Gloria Anzaldua</PERSON> 1942 2004 Borderlands La Frontera the new Mestiza Homeland Aztlan El onto <LOCATION>Mexico</LOCATION> Movimientos de rebeldia y las culturas que traicionan <PERSON>Ariel Dorfman</PERSON> b 1942 Heading South looking North Chapter dealing with the discovery of life and language at an early age Reinaldo Arenas 1943 1990 Mona Before night falls <PERSON>Mariel Dolores Prida</PERSON> b 1943 Coser y cantar a one act bilingual fantasy for two women <PERSON>Edward Rivera</PERSON> 1944 2001 Family installments In black turf <PERSON>Richard Rodriguez</PERSON> b 1944 Hunger of memory the education of <PERSON>Richard Rodriguez</PERSON> Part 1 Aria Days of obligation an argument with my Mexican father Chapter 2 Late Victorians Brown the last discovery of <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> Preface <PERSON>Alma Luz Villanueva</PERSON> b 1944 Bitch bitch bitch bitch Delicious death Warrior in the sand Even the eagles must gather <PERSON>Lucha Corpi</PERSON> b 1945 Winter song Day s work Undocumented anguish Sonata in two voices <PERSON>Octavio Armand</PERSON> b 1946 Braille for left hand Poem with dusk Poetry as Eruv Rene Aloma 1947 1986 Little something to ease the pain <PERSON>Alberto Baltazar Heredia Urista</PERSON> aka <PERSON>Alurista</PERSON> b 1947 Bone Labyrinth of scarred hearts Sometime war As our barrio turns who the yoke b on <PERSON>Juan Luz Maria Umpierre Herrera</PERSON> b 1947 Immanence No hatchet job <PERSON>Denise Chavez</PERSON> b 1948 Face of an angel Long story Sleepwalker Are you wearing a bra <PERSON>Juan Felipe Herrera</PERSON> b 1948 Exiles Literary Asylums <PERSON>Quentino Pablo Medina</PERSON> b 1948 Exiled memories a Cuban childhood Arrival 1960 Calle de la amargura Nothing Nietzsche Return of Felix Nogara Dictionary of Guatemalan bird calls <PERSON>Esmeralda Santiago</PERSON> b 1948 When I was Puerto Rican American invasion of <LOCATION>Macun Island</LOCATION> of lost causes <PERSON>Sherezada Chiqui Vicioso</PERSON> b 1948 Perspectives <PERSON>Haiti Victor Hernandez Cruz</PERSON> b 1949 Latest Latin dance craze <ORGANIZATION>Lunequisticos Poema Chicano Cantinflas</ORGANIZATION> Is it certain or is it not certain <ORGANIZATION>Caso Maravilla Jaime Manrique</ORGANIZATION> b 1949 Latin moon in <LOCATION>Manhattan Little Colombia Jackson Heights</LOCATION> <PERSON>Julia Alvarez</PERSON> b 1950 How the <PERSON>Garcia</PERSON> girls lost their accents Daughter of invention Entre <PERSON>Lucas</PERSON> y Juan Mejia Bilingual sestina Yo Sisters <PERSON>Dagoberto Gilb</PERSON> b 1950 Look on the bright side Down in the <LOCATION>West Texas</LOCATION> town <ORGANIZATION>Carlos M N Eire</ORGANIZATION> b 1951 Waiting for snow in <LOCATION>Havana</LOCATION> Chapter 1 2 14 <PERSON>Roberto G Fernandez</PERSON> b 1951 Raining backwards Retrieving Varadero Holy radishes Last supper <PERSON>Franklin Gutierrez</PERSON> b 1951 <PERSON>Helen Oscar Hijuelos</PERSON> b 1951 Mambo kings play songs of love Chapter 1 Mr Ives Christmas On Madison and Forty First Street <PERSON>Jimmy Santiago Baca</PERSON> b 1952 From violence to peace Place to stand Chapter 1 2 Sixteen ChicaIndio <PERSON>Pat Mora</PERSON> b 1952 Child a child La dulceria Coatlicue s rules advice from an Aztec Goddess <PERSON>Malinche</PERSON> s tips Pique from <LOCATION>Mexico</LOCATION> s mother <ORGANIZATION>Consejos de Nuestra Senora de Guadalupe Counsel</ORGANIZATION> from the <LOCATION>Brown Virgin Cherrie Moraga</LOCATION> b 1952 Giving up the ghost Teatro in two acts <PERSON>Judith Ortiz Cofer</PERSON> b 1952 Story of my body Latin Deli an <ORGANIZATION>Ars Poetica Chameleon Hostages</ORGANIZATION> to fortune To a daughter I cannot console Anniversary Gift of a Cuento May he be bilingual <PERSON>Alberto Alvaro Rios</PERSON> b 1952 Morning Man who became old Mayates Iguana killer <PERSON>Gary Soto</PERSON> b 1952 Level at which the sky begins How an Uncle became Gray At the <ORGANIZATION>Cantina Catalina Trevino</ORGANIZATION> is really from Heaven What are you speaking Charity of La Senora Lara Nickel and dime We ain t asking much <PERSON>Giannina Braschi</PERSON> b 1953 Yo yo boing Pelos en la lengua <PERSON>Ana Castillo</PERSON> b 1953 Mixquiahuala letters Letter 7 15 21 Guardians <PERSON>Regina Eduardo Machado</PERSON> b 1953 Broken eggs Act 1 <PERSON>Kathleen Alcala</PERSON> b 1954 Mrs Vargas and the dead naturalist <PERSON>Flora</PERSON> s complaint <PERSON>Amalia Lorna Dee Cervantes</PERSON> b 1954 Refugee ship Beneath the shadow of the freeway <PERSON>Francisco Goldman</PERSON> b 1954 Ordinary seaman Chapter 3 <PERSON>Elias Miguel Munoz</PERSON> b 1954 From the land of <ORGANIZATION>Machos Journey</ORGANIZATION> to Oz with my father <PERSON>Michael Nava</PERSON> b 1954 How town Chapter 1 <PERSON>Ricardo Pau Llosa</PERSON> b 1954 <ORGANIZATION>Dos Rios Frutas Dulce Charada China Return</ORGANIZATION> to <PERSON>Havana Luis J Rodriguez</PERSON> b 1954 Always running La vida loca Chapter 1 <PERSON>Helena Maria Viramontes</PERSON> b 1954 Under the feet of Jesus Chapter 2 en schema description Writers Of <PERSON>Latinidad Silvia Curbelo</PERSON> b 1955 Summer storm If you need a reason <PERSON>Cecilia Rodriguez Milanes</PERSON> b 1961 Muchacha after <PERSON>Jamaica Adrian Castro</PERSON> b 1967 In the tradition of returning <PERSON>Richard Blanco</PERSON> b 1968 <PERSON>Palmita Mia Havanasis Mother</PERSON> picking produce <PERSON>Sandra M Castillo</PERSON> b 1968 Looking South <PERSON>Guillermo Gomez Pena</PERSON> b 1955 Documented undocumented <PERSON>Carlos Morton</PERSON> b 1955 Many deaths of <PERSON>Danny Rosales Jose Rivera</PERSON> b 1955 House of <PERSON>Ramon Iglesia Luis Alberto Urrea</PERSON> b 1955 Lake of sleeping children Devil s highway a true story Rules of the game <PERSON>Roberto Valero</PERSON> 1955 1994 Roberto Phone call <LOCATION>Exile Islands</LOCATION> are evil and nobody knows it <PERSON>Ruth Behar</PERSON> b 1956 <LOCATION>Juban America Hebrew Cemetery</LOCATION> of <PERSON>Guabanacoa Susana Chavez Silverman</PERSON> b 1956 <PERSON>Killer Cronica Dionisio Martinez</PERSON> b 1956 History as a second language In a duplex near the <LOCATION>San Andreas</LOCATION> fault Je te veux Cultivation of orchids <PERSON>Achy Orejas</PERSON> b 1956 Wrecks <PERSON>Martin Espada</PERSON> b 1957 Revolutionary Spanish lesson Niggerlips Imagine the angels of bread My name is <PERSON>Espada Alabanza</PERSON> in praise of local 100 Republic of poetry <PERSON>Rolando Perez</PERSON> b 1957 <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> movie Hotel room Summer evening First experience Canto 10 <ORGANIZATION>Carolina Hospital</ORGANIZATION> b 1957 How the Cubans stole <PERSON>Miami Cristina Garcia</PERSON> b 1958 Dreaming in <LOCATION>Cuban Ocean</LOCATION> blue Meaning of shells <PERSON>Aguero</PERSON> sisters <PERSON>Dulce Fuerte Alicia Gaspar de Alba</PERSON> b 1958 <PERSON>Sor Juana</PERSON> s second dream Bishop s pawn <PERSON>Nilo Cruz</PERSON> b 1959 <PERSON>Anna</PERSON> in the tropics <PERSON>Demetria Martinez</PERSON> b 1960 Fragmentos Fragments Devil s workshop <PERSON>Ars Poetica Abraham Rodriguez</PERSON> b 1961 Boy without a flag <PERSON>Ruben Martinez</PERSON> b 1962 Other side notes from the new L A <LOCATION>Mexico City</LOCATION> and beyond Death in the family Manifesto Crossing over a Mexican family on the Migrant Trail Prologue Passion <PERSON>Virgil Suarez</PERSON> b 1962 Tea leaves caraoles coffee beans Ricochet Floridiana Trouble with some words in English Cucuyo Ghazal Razzmatazz Orthography What we choose of exile <PERSON>Rafael Campo</PERSON> b 1963 Elise Miss Key West 1990 Poet s education I am <PERSON>Mrs Lorca</PERSON> Changing face of AIDS <PERSON>Junot Diaz</PERSON> b 1968 Ysrael Brief wondrous life of <PERSON>Oscar Wao GhettoNerd</PERSON> at the end of the world 1974 1987 <PERSON>Ana Menendez</PERSON> b 1970 In <LOCATION>Cuba</LOCATION> I was a German shepherd <PERSON>Willie Perdomo</PERSON> b 1971 Nigger Reecan blues Brother <PERSON>Lo New Boogaloo Manuel Munoz</PERSON> b 1975 <PERSON>Zigzagger Daniel Alarcon</PERSON> b 1977 War by candlelight <PERSON>Maria Teresa Mariposa Fernandez</PERSON> b 1977 <PERSON>Boricua</PERSON> butterfly Ode to the diasporican Poem for my grifa rican sistah or broken ends broken promises Popular Dimensions Dichos Chistes Cartoonistas Gus Arriola 1917 2008 <PERSON>Gordo Hernandez</PERSON> brothers <PERSON>Mario</PERSON> b 1953 <PERSON>Gilberto</PERSON> b 1957 and <PERSON>Jaime</PERSON> b 1959 Mojado power <PERSON>Lalo Lopez Alcaraz</PERSON> b 1964 Hi Spanic hysteria month Estar Wars the brown menace Teatro popular Culture Clash Mission Act 1 scene 1 <ORGANIZATION>Cuentos</ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON>Leyendas Juan Chilili Paloma Blanca Chirlos Birlos Burro</PERSON> and the coyote Pranks of Pedro de Urdemalas Eyes that come out at night <ORGANIZATION>La Llorona La Llorona</ORGANIZATION> by <PERSON>Alcina Lubitch Domecq Flea Boy</PERSON> and the devil Canciones Children s song Arroz con leche Folk Song De colores <ORGANIZATION>Corrideo Corrido de Gregorio Cortez Corrido de Joaquin Murrieta Narcocorrido Contrabando</ORGANIZATION> y traicion written by <PERSON>Angel Gonzalez Bolero Lamento Borincano</PERSON> written by <PERSON>Rafael Hernandez Marin Salsa Burundanga</PERSON> written by <PERSON>Oscar Munoz Bouffartique</PERSON> and performed by <PERSON>Celia Cruz</PERSON> Merengue Carnaval del Barrio written by <PERSON>Lin Manuel Miranda</PERSON> Chicano Rock Good Morning Aztlan written by <PERSON>David Hidalgo</PERSON> and <PERSON>Louie Perez</PERSON> and performed by <LOCATION>Los Lobos Latin Pop Livin la Vida Loca</LOCATION> written by <PERSON>Desmond Child</PERSON> and <PERSON>Robi Rosa</PERSON> and performed by <PERSON>Ricky Martin Hip Hop Latin Lingo</PERSON> written by <PERSON>Senen Reyes Louis Freeze</PERSON> and <PERSON>Lawrence Muggerud</PERSON> and performed by <ORGANIZATION>Cypress Hill Reggaeton Somos</ORGANIZATION> raperos pero no delincuentes written and performed by Ivy Queen Appendix 1 Chronology Literature And History Appendix 2 Treaties Acts And Propositions Treaty of Guadalupe Hidalgo 1848 Treaty of <LOCATION>Paris</LOCATION> 1898 Jones Act 1917 Bracero Agreement 1942 California Proposition 187 1994 Appendix 3 Influential Essays By Latin American Writers <PERSON>Jose Enrique Rodo</PERSON> 1872 1917 <PERSON>Ariel Jose Vasconcelos</PERSON> 1882 1959 Cosmic race Mestizaje Part 1 2 Octavio Paz 1914 1998 Labyrinth of solitude Pachuco and other extremes <PERSON>Roberto Fernandez Retamar</PERSON> b 1930 <PERSON>Caliban</PERSON> notes toward a discussion of culture in our <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> Question Toward the history of Caliban Our symbol Selected bibliographies Permissions acknowledgments Index en schema description Overview A dazzling and definitive compendium of the Latino literary tradition This groundbreaking Norton Anthology includes the work of 201 Latino writers from Chicano Cuban Puerto Rican and Dominican American traditions as well as writing from other Spanish speaking countries Under the general editorship of award winning cultural critic <PERSON>Ilan Stavans</PERSON> The Norton Anthology of Latino Literature traces four centuries of writing from letters to the Spanish crown by sixteenth century conquistadors to the cutting edge expressions of twenty first century cartoonistas and artists of reggaeton In six chronological sections Colonization Annexation Acculturation Upheaval Into the Mainstream and Popular Traditions it encompasses all genres featuring such writers as <PERSON>Jose Marti William Carlos Williams Julia Alvarez Oscar Hijuelos Cristina Garcia Piri Thomas Esmeralda Santiago</PERSON> and <PERSON>Junot Diaz</PERSON> Twelve years in the making The <ORGANIZATION>Norton Anthology of Latino Literature</ORGANIZATION> sheds new light on nuestra <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> through a gathering of writing unprecedented in scope and vitality en schema description Alternate table of contents Preface Acknowledgments Introduction Search for wholeness Colonization 1537 1810 Fray Bartolome de Las Casas 1484 1566 Devastation of the Indies a brief account Hispaniola That part of the mainland called <LOCATION>Florida</LOCATION> <PERSON>Alvar Nunez Cabeza de Vaca</PERSON> ca 1490 ca 1560 Chronicle of the <PERSON>Narvaez</PERSON> expedition When the fleet left <LOCATION>Spain</LOCATION> and the men who went with it How the governor came to <LOCATION>Xagua</LOCATION> and brought a pilot with him How we arrived in <LOCATION>Florida</LOCATION> How we went to the interior How the <ORGANIZATION>Indians</ORGANIZATION> separated us How we fled How we cured several sick people How the following day they brought other sick people How ready the Indians are with weapons On nations and languages Fray <PERSON>Marcos de Niza</PERSON> ca 1495 1558 Narrative of Fray <PERSON>Marcos de Niza Hernando de Soto</PERSON> ca 1496 1542 Letter of <PERSON>Hernando de Soto</PERSON> at <LOCATION>Tampa Bay</LOCATION> to the justice and board of magistrates in <LOCATION>Santiago</LOCATION> de <LOCATION>Cuba</LOCATION> <PERSON>Pedro Castaneda de Najera</PERSON> ca 1512 death unknown Narrative of the expedition of <ORGANIZATION>Coronado Of</ORGANIZATION> how the army started from <LOCATION>Culiacan</LOCATION> and the arrival of the general at <LOCATION>Cibola</LOCATION> and of the army at <LOCATION>Senora</LOCATION> and of other things that happened Of why <PERSON>Tiguex</PERSON> revolted and how they were punished without being to blame for it Juan de Castellanos 1522 1607 Revolt of the <ORGANIZATION>Borinquenos El Inca Garcilaso de La Vega</ORGANIZATION> ca 1539 1616 <LOCATION>Florida</LOCATION> of the Inca Book 2 Part 1 How they seized vitachuco Outbreak of the battle which occurred between the Spaniards and the Indians Gradual surrender of the conquered Indians and the constancy of seven of them Book 3 Mistress of <LOCATION>Cofachiqui</LOCATION> comes to talk with the governor offering him both provisions and passage for his army <PERSON>Sebastian Vizcaino</PERSON> 1548 1624 Diary of <PERSON>Sebastian Vizcaino</PERSON> Departure from the Bay of the Eleven Thousand Virgins and arrival at the <LOCATION>Port of San Diego</LOCATION> Departure from the <LOCATION>Port of San Diego</LOCATION> and arrival at the Island of <LOCATION>Santa Catalina Juan</LOCATION> de Onate 1550 1626 Letter written by <PERSON>Don Juan de Onate</PERSON> from <LOCATION>New Mexico</LOCATION> to the viceroy the Count of <LOCATION>Monterey</LOCATION> On March 2 1599 Account of the discovery of the <LOCATION>Buffalo</LOCATION> written by <PERSON>Juan Gutierrez Bocanegra Onate</PERSON> s secretary <PERSON>Gaspar Perez de Villagra</PERSON> ca 1555 1620 History of <ORGANIZATION>New Mexico Canto</ORGANIZATION> 1 2 14 Fray <ORGANIZATION>Eusebio Francisco Kino</ORGANIZATION> 1645 1711 Memoir of <ORGANIZATION>Pimeria Alta Book</ORGANIZATION> 1 First entry into Pimeria and the beginnings of its spiritual and temporal conquest and of its conversion to our holy Catholic faith Because of the suspension of the conquest and conversion of <LOCATION>California</LOCATION> two alms are asked for and obtained from the royal treasury for two missionary fathers for this coast and mainland nearest to <LOCATION>California Royal</LOCATION> provision and Royal Cedula which favor the new conversions My arrival at these missions of <LOCATION>Sonora</LOCATION> and my first entry into the Pimeria with the Father Visitor <PERSON>Manuel Gonzales</PERSON> Expedition to <LOCATION>San Ygnacio de Caborica San Joseph de Los Himiris</LOCATION> and <ORGANIZATION>Nuestra Senora de Los Remedios First</ORGANIZATION> opposition experienced in this new conversion Second opposition and discord sown in Pimeria Book 2 Visit and triennium of the Father Visitor <PERSON>Juan Maria Salvatierra</PERSON> 1690 1691 1692 Second and third expeditions to the Sea of <LOCATION>California</LOCATION> Expedition or mission to the north and northwest for more than one hundred leagues as far as to the <LOCATION>Rio Grande</LOCATION> and the casa Grande and the discovery of the two new nations the Opa and the Cocomaricopa Book 3 Arrival of the venerable Father <PERSON>Franciso Xavier Saeta</PERSON> at these new conversions his apostolic fervor work zeal and holy letters his glorious innocent death and various letters prophetic of the great fruit of these conversions Last letter of most tender farewell from the venerable father Concerning three other murders committed in <LOCATION>San Pedro</LOCATION> del <ORGANIZATION>Tubutama Happy</ORGANIZATION> and glorious death of the venerable Father <PERSON>Francisco Xavier Saeta</PERSON> and of his four servants and the plundering of his house Expedition of the <PERSON>Garrison</PERSON> of this province of <LOCATION>Sonora</LOCATION> to punish the delinquents and to remove the body of the venerable father Second and new expedition of the <PERSON>Garrison</PERSON> and new and greater disturbance than before Fray <PERSON>Junipero Serra</PERSON> 1713 1784 Letter to Fray <PERSON>Juan Andres Letter</PERSON> to <PERSON>Francisco Carlos</PERSON> de Croix Fray Juan Crespi 1721 1782 Letter to Fray <PERSON>Francisco Palou Juan Bautista</PERSON> de Anza 1736 1788 Diary of Governor <PERSON>de Anza</PERSON> s expedition against the Comanche nation August 15 September 10 1779 Annexations 1811 1898 <PERSON>Felix Varela</PERSON> 1787 1853 Letters to <PERSON>Elpidio</PERSON> Final observations on the humor of irreligious masks Civil religion in the <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> On the Quakers <PERSON>Eulalia Perez</PERSON> ca 1780 death unknown Old woman remembers <PERSON>Antonio Maria Osio</PERSON> y Higuera 1800 1878 History of <LOCATION>Alta California</LOCATION> Chapter 8 <PERSON>Gaspar Betancourt Cisneros</PERSON> 1803 1866 Letters from <PERSON>Lugareno Jose Maria Heredia</PERSON> 1803 1839 Ode to <ORGANIZATION>Niagara Frontier</ORGANIZATION> Memoirs Juan Nepomuceno Seguin 1806 1890 Personal memoirs of <PERSON>John N Seguin</PERSON> 1834 42 <PERSON>Jose Policarpo Rodriguez</PERSON> 1829 1914 Old guide Boyhood days Surveying <PERSON>Andrew Garcia</PERSON> 1855 1943 Tough trip through paradise 1878 1879 Murder of <PERSON>John Hays</PERSON> Southwestern Newspaper Poetry Juan B Hijar y <ORGANIZATION>Jaro</ORGANIZATION> dates unknown Heaven hands us our fate J M Vigil dates unknown Love and friendship <PERSON>Jose Romulo Ribera</PERSON> birth unknown 1917 Homeland and home <PERSON>Luis A Torres</PERSON> dates unknown Philosophical truths <PERSON>Luis Tafoya</PERSON> aka XXX 1851 1922 Same as usual To <LOCATION>New Mexico</LOCATION> Ramon Emeterio Betances 1827 1898 Arriba Puerto Ricans You shall be free Remembrances of a revolutionary Against Spanish Despotism Tenth of October Realized dream <PERSON>Maria Amparo Ruiz de Burton</PERSON> 1832 1895 Squatter and the <PERSON>Don Squatter Darrell</PERSON> reviews the past <PERSON>Don</PERSON> s view of the treaty of <ORGANIZATION>Guadalupe Hidalgo Eugenio Maria de Hostos</ORGANIZATION> 1839 1903 League of Puerto Rican Patriots Fragment from diary <PERSON>Lola Rodriguez</PERSON> de Tio 1843 1924 Song of <LOCATION>Borinquen Cuba Cuba</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Puerto Rico Sotero Figueroa</LOCATION> 1851 1923 Speech confirming the proclamation of the Cuban <ORGANIZATION>Revolutionary Party</ORGANIZATION> Cubans and Puerto Ricans <PERSON>Jose Marti</PERSON> 1853 1895 <LOCATION>Coney Island Love</LOCATION> in the city <LOCATION>Charleston</LOCATION> earthquake Two homelands Our America <PERSON>Manuel M Salazar</PERSON> 1854 1911 Story of a wayfarer or gervacio and aurora Chapter 19 <PERSON>Luis Munoz Rivera</PERSON> 1859 1916 Northward ho Speech given to the <ORGANIZATION>House of Representatives</ORGANIZATION> <PERSON>Miguel Antonio Otero</PERSON> Jr 1859 1944 My nine years as governor of the territory of <LOCATION>New Mexico</LOCATION> 1897 1906 Folsom train robberies <PERSON>Francisco Gonzalo Pachin Marin</PERSON> 1863 1897 <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> from within One aspect of its Bohemian life the rag Fabio Fiallo 1866 1942 Plenilunio Golgotha Rose Profane rhyme <PERSON>Jose Escobar</PERSON> dates unknown Literary progress in <LOCATION>New Mexico</LOCATION> Jesse Perez 1870 1927 Memoirs <PERSON>Julio G Arce</PERSON> aka <PERSON>Jorge Ulica</PERSON> 1870 1926 Spanish plague <PERSON>Chacon</PERSON> Family <PERSON>Eusebio Chacon</PERSON> 1869 1948 Calm after the storm <PERSON>Felipe Maximiliano Chacon</PERSON> 1873 1949 <PERSON>Senora Adelina Otero Warren Don Julio Berlanga Isidoro Armijo</PERSON> 1871 1949 Sixty minutes in hell Acculturation 1899 1945 Arthur A Schomburg 1874 1938 Negro digs up his past Juan Latino <PERSON>Leonor Villegas</PERSON> de Magnon 1876 1955 Rebel Rebel is a girl <PERSON>Cleofas</PERSON> M Jaramillo 1878 1956 Romance of a little village girl Pleasant outings Territory becomes a state <PERSON>Daniel Venegas</PERSON> ca 1880 ca 1935 Adventures of <PERSON>Don Chipote</PERSON> or a sucker s tale Chapters 1 3 <PERSON>Adelina Nina Otero Warren</PERSON> 1881 1965 Old <LOCATION>Spain</LOCATION> in our Southwest Old Spanish <PERSON>Hacienda William Carlos Williams</PERSON> 1883 1963 <ORGANIZATION>Libertad Igualdad Fraternidad</ORGANIZATION> Apology Sub Terra In The American grain Fountain of eternal youth Autobiography Pop and mother <PERSON>Bernardo Vega</PERSON> 1885 1965 Puerto Rican migration to the <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> Memoirs of <PERSON>Bernardo Vega</PERSON> From my hometown <LOCATION>Cayey</LOCATION> to <LOCATION>San Juan</LOCATION> and how I arrived in <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> without a watch Trials and tribulations of an emigrant in the Iron Tower of Babel on the eve of the World War 1 Proletarians extend a hand but hunger pinches and there is no remedy but to work in a weapons factory <PERSON>Vicente J Bernal</PERSON> 1888 1915 <PERSON>Elvira</PERSON> by the stream To <PERSON>Pedro Albizu Campos</PERSON> 1891 1965 Observations on the Brookings Institution Report <PERSON>Maria Cristina Mena</PERSON> 1893 1965 Emotions of Maria Concepcion Birth of the god of war <PERSON>Fabiola Cabeza de Baca Gilbert</PERSON> ca 1894 1991 We fed them cactus El Cuate Rodeo Fiesta at <LOCATION>San Hilario Luis Munoz Marin</LOCATION> 1898 1980 Sad case of <ORGANIZATION>Porto Rico Speech</ORGANIZATION> Jesus Colon 1901 1974 Puerto Rican in <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> and other sketches Mother the young daughter myself and all of us Grandma please don t come Way it was and other writings Two <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> Jewish people and us My wife doesn t work <PERSON>Felipe Alfau</PERSON> 1902 1999 Locos a comedy of gestures Identity <PERSON>Jose Davila Semprit</PERSON> 1902 1958 <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> One of many Eugenio Florit 1903 1999 In the big city Lonely poets of <LOCATION>Manhattan</LOCATION> Portrait of a man alone Out of the snow <PERSON>Jovita Gonzalez de Mireles</PERSON> 1904 1983 Bullet swallower Ernesto Galarza 1905 1984 Barrio boy Part One In a mountain village Part Five On the edge of the barrio <PERSON>Luis Leal</PERSON> 1907 2010 In search of Aztlan Fray Angelico Chavez 1910 1996 <LOCATION>New Mexico</LOCATION> triptych <PERSON>Hunchback Madonna Josefina Niggli</PERSON> 1910 1983 Mexican Village Quarry schema exampleOfWork http worldcat org entity work id 476383616 gt schema genre Literary collections en schema inLanguage en schema name The <PERSON>Norton</PERSON> anthology of Latino literature en schema productID 607322888 schema publication http www worldcat org title oclc 607322888 PublicationEvent new_york_w_w_norton_ amp _co_2011 gt schema publisher http experiment worldcat org entity work data 476383616 Agent w_w_norton_ amp _co gt <ORGANIZATION>W W Norton amp Co</ORGANIZATION> schema workExample http worldcat org isbn 9780393975321 gt schema workExample http worldcat org isbn 9780393080070 gt wdrs describedby http www worldcat org title oclc 607322888 gt Related Entities http dbpedia org resource New_York_City gt <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> a schema Place schema name <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> http dewey info class 810 80868073 e22 gt a schema Intangible http experiment worldcat org entity work data 476383616 Agent w_w_norton_ amp _co gt <ORGANIZATION>W W Norton amp Co</ORGANIZATION> a bgn Agent schema name <ORGANIZATION>W W Norton amp Co</ORGANIZATION> http experiment worldcat org entity work data 476383616 Place usa gt <LOCATION>USA</LOCATION> a schema Place schema name <LOCATION>USA</LOCATION> schema name <LOCATION>USA</LOCATION> http experiment worldcat org entity work data 476383616 Topic american_literature_hispanic_american_authors gt American literature Hispanic American authors a schema Intangible schema name American literature Hispanic American authors en http experiment worldcat org entity work data 476383616 Topic amerikaans gt Amerikaans a schema Intangible schema name Amerikaans en http experiment worldcat org entity work data 476383616 Topic amerikanisches_englisch gt Amerikanisches Englisch a schema Intangible schema name Amerikanisches Englisch en http experiment worldcat org entity work data 476383616 Topic chicano_literature gt Chicano literature a schema Intangible schema name Chicano literature en http experiment worldcat org entity work data 476383616 Topic chicanos gt Chicanos a schema Intangible schema name Chicanos en http experiment worldcat org entity work data 476383616 Topic hispanic_americans gt Hispanic Americans a schema Intangible rdfs seeAlso http id loc gov authorities subjects sh2008121645 gt schema name Hispanic Americans en http experiment worldcat org entity work data 476383616 Topic hispanics gt Hispanics a schema Intangible schema name Hispanics en http experiment worldcat org entity work data 476383616 Topic hispanos gt Hispanos a schema Intangible schema name Hispanos en http experiment worldcat org entity work data 476383616 Topic literatur gt Literatur a schema Intangible schema name Literatur en http id loc gov authorities subjects sh85004350 gt American literature Hispanic American authors a schema Intangible schema name American literature Hispanic American authors en http id loc gov vocabulary countries nyu gt a schema Place dcterms identifier nyu http id worldcat org fast 807169 gt American literature Hispanic American authors a schema Intangible schema name American literature Hispanic American authors en http id worldcat org fast 957523 gt Hispanic Americans a schema Intangible schema name Hispanic Americans en http viaf org viaf 17373977 gt <PERSON>Ilan Stavans</PERSON> a schema Person schema familyName Stavans schema givenName Ilan schema name <PERSON>Ilan Stavans</PERSON> http viaf org viaf 73902948 gt <PERSON>Edna Acosta Bel</PERSON> n a schema Person schema familyName <ORGANIZATION>Acosta Bel</ORGANIZATION> n schema givenName <PERSON>Edna</PERSON> schema name <PERSON>Edna Acosta Bel</PERSON> n http worldcat org isbn 9780393080070 gt a schema ProductModel schema isbn 0393080072 schema isbn 9780393080070 http worldcat org isbn 9780393975321 gt a schema ProductModel schema isbn 0393975320 schema isbn 9780393975321 http www worldcat org title oclc 607322888 gt a genont InformationResource genont ContentTypeGenericResource schema about http www worldcat org oclc 607322888 gt The <PERSON>Norton</PERSON> anthology of Latino literature schema dateModified 2018 04 09 void inDataset http purl oclc org dataset WorldCat gt http www worldcat org title oclc 607322888 CreativeWork unidentifiedOriginalWork gt a schema CreativeWork schema inLanguage es http www worldcat org title oclc 607322888 PublicationEvent new_york_w_w_norton_ amp _co_2011 gt a schema PublicationEvent schema location http dbpedia org resource New_York_City gt <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> schema organizer http experiment worldcat org entity work data 476383616 Agent w_w_norton_ amp _co gt <ORGANIZATION>W W Norton amp Co Content</ORGANIZATION> negotiable representations Turtle text turtle JSON LD application ld json RDF XML application rdf xml N TRIPLES text plain HTML RDFa text html 607322888 9780393080070 0393080072 9780393975321 0393975320 The <PERSON>Norton</PERSON> anthology of Latino literature <PERSON>Ilan Stavans Edna Acosta Bele</PERSON> n <ORGANIZATION>New York W W Norton amp Co</ORGANIZATION> 2011 21274 book_printbook Languages esky Deutsch English Espa ol Fran ais <LOCATION>Italiano Nederlands Portugu</LOCATION> s You Sign In Register My WorldCat My Lists My Watchlist My Reviews My Tags My Saved Searches WorldCat Home About Help Search Legal Copyright 2001 2018 OCLC All rights reserved Privacy Policy Terms and Conditions WorldCat is the world s largest library catalog helping you find library materials online Learn more Follow WorldCat image Button E mail updates image Button Facebook image Button Twitter image Button YouTube image Close Window Please sign in to WorldCat Don t have an account You can easily create a free account User Name Password Remember me on this computer Cancel Forgot your password</ner>
