<ner>NYTimes com no longer supports Internet Explorer 9 or earlier Please upgrade your browser LEARN MORE Sections Home Search Skip to content Skip to navigation View mobile version The <ORGANIZATION>New York Times Books A Family Full of Unhappiness Hoping for Transcendence Search Subscribe Now Log In</ORGANIZATION> 0 Settings Close search Site Search Navigation Search NYTimes com Clear this text input Go Loading See next articles See previous articles Site Navigation Site Mobile Navigation Advertisement Supported by Books A Family Full of Unhappiness Hoping for Transcendence Books of The Times By <PERSON>MICHIKO KAKUTANI</PERSON> AUG 15 2010 Continue reading the main story Share This Page Continue reading the main story <PERSON>Jonathan Franzen</PERSON> s galvanic new novel Freedom showcases his impressive literary toolkit every essential storytelling skill plus plenty of bells and whistles and his ability to throw open a big Updikean picture window on American middle class life With this book he s not only created an unforgettable family he s also completed his own transformation from a sharp elbowed apocalyptic satirist focused on sending up the socio economic political plight of this country into a kind of 19th century realist concerned with the public and private lives of his characters Whereas Mr <PERSON>Franzen</PERSON> s first novel The Twenty Seventh City borrowed liberally from the likes of <PERSON>Thomas Pynchon</PERSON> and <PERSON>Don DeLillo</PERSON> to create a dark splashy picture of a futuristic <ORGANIZATION>St Louis</ORGANIZATION> his 2001 bestseller The Corrections signaled his determination to write an American sort of <PERSON>Buddenbrooks</PERSON> to conjure contemporary <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> not by going for a cartoonish zeitgeist y epic but by deconstructing a family s history to give us a wide angled portrait of the country as it rumbled into the materialistic 1990s While The Corrections attested to Mr <PERSON>Franzen</PERSON> s discovery of his own limber voice and tamed his penchant for sociological pontification the novel was something of a hybrid in which the author s satiric instincts and misanthropic view of the world sometimes seemed at odds with his new drive to create fully three dimensional people It felt at times as if he were self importantly inflating the symbolic meaning of his characters experiences even as he condescendingly attributed to them every venal quality from hypocrisy and vanity to paranoia and Machiavellian conniving Photo image In the opening pages of Freedom this dynamic seems even more exaggerated as we are introduced to members of the <PERSON>Berglund</PERSON> family as an assortment of disagreeable caricatures who perplex and perturb their neighbors in <LOCATION>St Paul Known</LOCATION> for his niceness <PERSON>Walter Berglund</PERSON> is a weak passive aggressive husband and father who weirdly sells out his nature loving ideals to work with an evil coal company His wife <PERSON>Patty</PERSON> also seems nicey nice on the surface but turns out to be an ill tempered shrew who rages at <PERSON>Walter</PERSON> and inexplicably slashes a neighbor s new snow tires Their cocky teenage son <PERSON>Joey</PERSON> is so unhappy at home that he moves out of the house and in with his girlfriend s family next door Advertisement Continue reading the main story It turns out however that these farcical sketches are simply meant to show how the Berglunds might be perceived by outsiders just as <PERSON>Patty</PERSON> s account of this period of her life which immediately follows in the book reflects her own need to filter everything through the prism of her anger and depression As The Corrections dramatically demonstrated Mr <PERSON>Franzen</PERSON> is extremely adept at depicting those two emotions which not just <PERSON>Patty</PERSON> but nearly every character in this novel suffers from too and which all of them trace back to injustices or slights suffered at the hands of their parents Continue reading the main story Advertisement Continue reading the main story As the novel proceeds however Mr <PERSON>Franzen</PERSON> delves further into the state of mind of his creations developing them into fully imagined human beings not Nietzschean stereotypes easily divided into categories of hard shameless ambitious brutes or soft pathetic sniveling doormats not bitter patsies fueled by ancient grudges but confused searching people capable of change and perhaps even transcendence We come to understand the dynamics between the earnest and eager to please <PERSON>Walter</PERSON> a good soldier reeling with suppressed rage and <PERSON>Patty</PERSON> college athlete turned housewife who indulges in alcohol and sarcasm to assuage her sense of uselessness and loss We also come to intimately know <PERSON>Walter</PERSON> s best friend <PERSON>Richard</PERSON> a cool charming musician and compulsive womanizer whom <PERSON>Patty</PERSON> first fell in love with decades ago and with whom she later has an affair Photo image <PERSON>Jonathan Franzen</PERSON> the author of the novel Freedom Credit <PERSON>Greg Martin</PERSON> Mr <PERSON>Franzen</PERSON> s repeated allusions to War and Peace suggesting that there is some sort of parallel between the <PERSON>Walter Richard Patty</PERSON> triangle and the <PERSON>Pierre Andrei Natasha</PERSON> triangle in <PERSON>Tolstoy</PERSON> s great classic are laughably conceited but he does an agile job of tracing the constantly evolving relationships among his three main characters as well the dynamics between <PERSON>Walter</PERSON> and <PERSON>Patty</PERSON> and their two children <PERSON>Joey</PERSON> and <PERSON>Jessica He</PERSON> understands the improvised game of emotional dominoes that can play out in families and the psychological chutes and ladders that can pop up in their lives out of the blue From the start of his career with The Twenty Seventh City Mr <PERSON>Franzen</PERSON> has been ambitious striving to write a Big American Novel that might capture a national mind set and this novel is no exception Its title Freedom announces a theme that runs like a riptide beneath the narrative lots of talk about what liberty means in terms of being free of familial responsibilities and ideological beliefs and the rootlessness and dislocation that often follow in its wake But it is neither this heavy handed leitmotif nor the twisty Dickensian plot which has <PERSON>Walter</PERSON> and <PERSON>Joey</PERSON> getting involved with a ruthless <ORGANIZATION>Halliburton</ORGANIZATION> like company that lends this novel its narrative heft and hold on the reader Rather it is Mr <PERSON>Franzen</PERSON> s characters and his <PERSON>David Foster Wallace</PERSON> esque ability to capture the absurdities of contemporary life where the planet is heating up like a toaster oven and people use credit cards to buy a pack of gum or a single hot dog I mean cash is so yesterday where rage among liberals and conservatives alike is scorching the country in the <PERSON>George W Bush</PERSON> years and intemperate blog entries and <PERSON>Howard Beale</PERSON> like outbursts are cheered as expressions of a collective distemper Writing in prose that is at once visceral and lapidary Mr <PERSON>Franzen</PERSON> shows us how his characters strive to navigate a world of technological gadgetry and ever shifting mores how they struggle to balance the equation between their expectations of life and dull reality their political ideals and mercenary personal urges He proves himself as adept at adolescent comedy what happens to <PERSON>Joey</PERSON> after he accidentally swallows his wedding ring right before a vacation with his dream girl as he is at grown up tragedy what happens to <PERSON>Walter</PERSON> s assistant and new beloved when she sets off alone on a trip to <LOCATION>West Virginia</LOCATION> coal country as skilled at holding a mirror to the world his people inhabit day by dreary day as he is at limning their messy inner lives In the past Mr <PERSON>Franzen</PERSON> tended to impose a seemingly cynical mechanistic view of the world on his characters threatening to turn them into authorial pawns subject to simple Freudian Darwinian imperatives This time in creating conflicted contrarian individuals capable of choosing their own fates Mr <PERSON>Franzen</PERSON> has written his most deeply felt novel yet a novel that turns out to be both a compelling biography of a dysfunctional family and an indelible portrait of our times FREEDOM By <PERSON>Jonathan Franzen</PERSON> 562 pages <ORGANIZATION>Farrar Straus amp Giroux</ORGANIZATION> 28 Follow <PERSON>Michiko Kakutani</PERSON> on Twitter michikokakutani A version of this review appears in print on August 16 2010 on Page C1 of the <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> edition with the headline A Family Full of Unhappiness Still Hoping for Transcendence Today s Paper Subscribe Continue reading the main story We re interested in your feedback on this page Tell us what you think Related Coverage EXCERPT Freedom By <PERSON>Jonathan Franzen</PERSON> AUG 15 2010 image Book Review Freedom By <PERSON>Jonathan Franzen</PERSON> AUG 19 2010 TIMES TOPIC <PERSON>Jonathan Franzen</PERSON> Books of The <ORGANIZATION>Times Book</ORGANIZATION> reviews by The <ORGANIZATION>Times</ORGANIZATION> s critics <PERSON>Barbara Ehrenreich</PERSON> Urges Us to Accept Accept the Dying of the Light APR 10 <PERSON>Berenice Abbott</PERSON> Captures a Large and <ORGANIZATION>Star Studded Life APR</ORGANIZATION> 9 Inseparable Finds Pride Indignity and Irony in the <ORGANIZATION>Lives of Siamese Twins</ORGANIZATION> <PERSON>Chang</PERSON> and Eng APR 4 Two Sisters About Teenage Girls Who Left <LOCATION>Norway</LOCATION> to Fight With <ORGANIZATION>ISIS</ORGANIZATION> APR 3 <PERSON>Leslie Jamison</PERSON> s Memoir Finds Its Footing in Sobriety APR 2 See More Related Coverage EXCERPT Freedom By <PERSON>Jonathan Franzen</PERSON> AUG 15 2010 Book Review Freedom By <PERSON>Jonathan Franzen</PERSON> AUG 19 2010 image TIMES TOPIC <PERSON>Jonathan Franzen</PERSON> What s Next Loading Go to Home Page Site Index The <ORGANIZATION>New York Times Site Index Navigation News World U S Politics N Y Business Tech Science Health Sports Education Obituaries Today</ORGANIZATION> s Paper Corrections Opinion Today s Opinion Op Ed Columnists Editorials Op Ed Contributors Letters Sunday Review Video Opinion Arts Today s Arts Art amp Design Books Dance Movies Music N Y <ORGANIZATION>C Events Guide Television Theater Video Arts Living Automobiles Crossword Food Education Fashion amp Style Health Jobs Magazine N Y C Events Guide Real Estate T Magazine Travel Weddings amp Celebrations Listings amp More Reader Center Classifieds Tools amp Services N Y C Events Guide Multimedia</ORGANIZATION> Photography Video NYT Store Times Journeys Subscribe Manage My Account NYTCo Subscribe Subscribe Home Delivery Digital Subscriptions Crossword Email Newsletters Alerts Gift Subscriptions Group Subscriptions Education Rate Mobile Applications Replica Edition Site Information Navigation 2018 The <ORGANIZATION>New York Times Company Home</ORGANIZATION> Search Accessibility concerns Email us at accessibility nytimes com We would love to hear from you Contact Us Work With Us Advertise Your Ad Choices Privacy Terms of Service Terms of Sale Site Information Navigation Site Map Help Site Feedback Subscriptions</ner>
