<ner>close fullscreen image Jump to navigation Quick Links Poets org User Log In Become a Member Donate Now Shop follow poets org facebook twitter tumbler youtube cloud Search form Search image Home Academy of American Poets The <ORGANIZATION>Academy of American Poets</ORGANIZATION> is the largest membership based nonprofit organization fostering an appreciation for contemporary poetry and supporting American poets For over three generations the <ORGANIZATION>Academy</ORGANIZATION> has connected millions of people to great poetry through programs such as <ORGANIZATION>National Poetry Month</ORGANIZATION> the largest literary celebration in the world Poets org the <ORGANIZATION>Academy</ORGANIZATION> s popular website American Poets a biannual literary journal and an annual series of poetry readings and special events Since its founding the <ORGANIZATION>Academy</ORGANIZATION> has awarded more money to poets than any other organization Poetry helps me to describe the ineffable the seen and unseen and the heartbreak of living Poetry is a medium that is closest to our hearts and it can give voice to those who have been denied a voice <ORGANIZATION>Marilyn Chin Academy of American Poets Chancellor 2018 Academy of American Poets National Poetry Month American Poets Magazine Main</ORGANIZATION> menu browse poems amp poets poem a day materials for teachers poetry near you read stanza poets org 29 poem a day poem a day Sign up to receive an unpublished poem every day in your inbox today s poet image <PERSON>Valzhyna Mort Valzhyna Mort</PERSON> sign up Guest listen2 Recorded for Poem a Day May 7 2018 poem About this Poem <PERSON>Velimir Khlebnikov</PERSON> wrote somewhere that the State speaks to its people through its statues <LOCATION>Minsk</LOCATION> is full of statues gigantic statues to national poets along with the granite busts of communist officials <PERSON>Maxim Bakhdanovich</PERSON> was a Belarusian modernist poet who died of tuberculosis at the age of twenty five a couple of years after his first book was published He was lucky to die so peacefully In exactly twenty years most Belarusian intellectuals were tortured and murdered by the communist officials In one night in 1937 Bolsheviks shot twenty two young Belarusian writers The statue of <PERSON>Bakhdanovich</PERSON> in <LOCATION>Minsk</LOCATION> is 4 6 meters high and is made out of granite <PERSON>Valzhyna Mort</PERSON> facebook twitter tumblr embed poem add to anthology print more audio fullscreen facebook twitter tumblr embed poem add to anthology print <LOCATION>Guest Valzhyna Mort Here</LOCATION> where I m dying in a white house by a blue harbor <ORGANIZATION>Maxim Bakhdanovich Come</ORGANIZATION> in Maxim This is <LOCATION>Minsk</LOCATION> choked under a pillow of clouds There s you a statue in a heavy coat Here all monuments wear coats not wool but linden bark coats with bee fur collars In their pockets monuments keep belts And under collars monuments have necks In winter shadows insulate the walls Windows and cracks are plucked with shadows In museums on display are coats and nooses And water is pickle juice Come in <LOCATION>Maxim</LOCATION> apartment blocks are wrapped in ammunition staircases and window medals sparkle through the night Every building here is a kind of bust an elevator ascends like vomit Of furniture there is a stump Come in Maxim it s nothing like lie dying by a harbor Take a sit on a stump <PERSON>Don</PERSON> t cast a shadow Keep the coat on Copyright 2018 by <PERSON>Valzhyna Mort</PERSON> Originally published in Poem a Day on May 7 2018 by the <ORGANIZATION>Academy of American Poets</ORGANIZATION> Copyright 2018 by <PERSON>Valzhyna Mort</PERSON> Originally published in Poem a Day on May 7 2018 by the <ORGANIZATION>Academy of American Poets</ORGANIZATION> submit american poets prizes Submissions are now open for the <PERSON>James Laughlin</PERSON> Award and the Lenore Marshall Prize Deadline May 15 Find out more Stanza Jobs for Poets May 2 2018 advertisement poet <PERSON>Matthew Shenoda</PERSON> image collection Classic Books of American Poetry This collection of books showcases the masterpieces of American poetry that have influenced or promise to influence generations of poets Take a look image Poems for Asian Pacific American <ORGANIZATION>Heritage Month</ORGANIZATION> poem My Mama moved among the days My Mama moved among the days like a dreamwalker in a field seemed like what she touched was hers seemed like what touched her couldn t hold she got us almost through the high grass then seemed like she turned around and ran right back in right back on in <PERSON>Lucille Clifton</PERSON> 2017 announcement We re pleased to announce that <PERSON>Joy Harjo</PERSON> has selected <PERSON>Emily Skaja</PERSON> as the recipient of the 2018 <PERSON>Walt Whitman</PERSON> Award for her manuscript Brute Find out more poet <PERSON>Anne Sexton</PERSON> image poem Hours Days Years Unmoor Their Orbits tonight I m cleaning baby portobellos for you my young activist wiping the dirty tops with a damp cloth as carefully as I used to rinse raspberries for you to adorn your fingertips before eating each blood red prize these days you rarely look me in the eye amp your long shagged hair hides your smile I don t expect you to remember or understand the many ways I ve kept you alive or the life my love for you has made me live <PERSON>Rachel Zucker</PERSON> 2017 Poems for Mother s Day image Glacier National Park videos poetry breaks An archival series of classic poets reading their poems image poem Things We Carry on the Sea We carry tears in our eyes good bye father good bye mother We carry soil in small bags may home never fade in our hearts We carry names stories memories of our villages fields boats We carry scars from proxy wars of greed We carry carnage of mining droughts floods genocides We carry dust of our families and neighbors incinerated in mushroom clouds We carry our islands sinking under the sea We carry our hands feet bones hearts and best minds for a new life We carry diplomas medicine engineer nurse education math poetry even if they mean nothing to the other shore We carry railroads plantations laundromats bodegas taco trucks farms factories nursing homes hospitals schools temples built on our ancestors backs We carry old homes along the spine new dreams in our chests We carry yesterday today and tomorrow We re orphans of the wars forced upon us We re refugees of the sea rising from industrial wastes And we carry our mother tongues ai hubb libe amor love ping an salaam shalom paz peace xi wang amal hofenung esperanza hope hope hope As we drift in our rubber boats from shore to shore to shore <PERSON>Wang Ping</PERSON> 2018 featured interview This year we welcomed three new poets to our Board of Chancellors <PERSON>Marilyn Chin Kwame Dawes</PERSON> and <PERSON>Marie Howe</PERSON> In this new Q amp A on Poets org they discuss their poetic lineage their favorite poets and more Read more announcement We re excited to announce that we ve invited twelve new guest editors to each curate a month of Poem a Day in 2018 The guest editor for May is <PERSON>Matthew Shenoda</PERSON> Find out more about the program and the other guest editors collection Poetic Forms Refresh and expand your poetic vocabulary with this collection of poetic forms complete with historical contexts examples and more For more on poetic forms browse our selection of terms from <PERSON>Edward Hirsch</PERSON> s A Poet s Glossary or check out our quick teaching guide on essential poetic terms read selections from a poet s glossary read our poetry glossary poet <PERSON>Jenny Xie</PERSON> image collection Lesson Plans for <ORGANIZATION>Asian Pacific American Heritage Month</ORGANIZATION> As part of your celebration of <ORGANIZATION>Asian Pacific American Heritage Month</ORGANIZATION> in May and all year round take a look at this collection of lesson plans featuring poems by Asian American and Pacific American poets poet <PERSON>Yone Noguchi</PERSON> image image AASL Best Website for Teaching amp Learning poet <PERSON>Aimee Nezhukumatathil</PERSON> image poet <PERSON>Chen Chen</PERSON> image poem How Alone <PERSON>Barbie Chang</PERSON> s Mother How alone <PERSON>Barbie Chang</PERSON> s mother must have felt doing nothing but dying her mother actually stopped dying her hair in January stopped being an actuary for her money she must have known her time was limited did the diseased birch tree know they were going to cut it down how quickly the air around it filled in the space it does no good to know a mother s face who would have known that a mother s face could be erased too at some point we are all eliminated from this earth at some point most of us give birth at some point we lose a mother at some point we are all disappointments who can t possibly care for others when our mothers die we are all lost and there are no words for it some want to name us as grieving others wrongly name us heroes <PERSON>Victoria Chang</PERSON> 2017 2018 national poetry month sponsors We d like to thank the following publishers and organizations that have helped make <ORGANIZATION>National Poetry Month</ORGANIZATION> possible this year <ORGANIZATION>New York State Council on the Arts Nightboat Books North American Review Northwestern University Press</ORGANIZATION> O <LOCATION>Miami</LOCATION> and Penguin Books collection Mother Knows Best The poets in this collection present poems about their mothers and discuss their mothers responses to the poems written about them poet <PERSON>Bei Dao</PERSON> image collection A Poet s Glossary Read about poetic terms and forms from <PERSON>Edward Hirsch</PERSON> s A Poet s Glossary Harcourt 2014 a book ten years in the making that defines the art form of poetry image poet <PERSON>Fady Joudah</PERSON> image poem Duet Night time is the right time <PERSON>Ray Charles</PERSON> and <PERSON>Margie Hendricks</PERSON> She had me in the car I came forward like a song We did it before temple after temple between prayers The windows echoed her mantras our cries warmed the air Two peaks merged then sank below the clouds We did it before temple after temple between prayers Her stomach began to show and people asked us not to come Two peaks merged then sank below the clouds Night and day everything was changing Her stomach began to show and people asked her not to come My mother was all alone when I was born Night and day Everything was changing The radio started playing rhythm and blues My mother was all alone when I was born The windows echoed her mantras our cries warmed the air The radio started playing rhythm and blues She had me in a car I came forward like a song Duy Doan 2018 image Spring Summer 2018 issue of American Poets signup <ORGANIZATION>Academy of American Poets Newsletter Academy of American Poets Educator Newsletter</ORGANIZATION> Teach This Poem Poem a Day Leave this field blank support us Become a Member Donate Now Get Involved Make a Bequest Advertise with <ORGANIZATION>Us Poets Shop</ORGANIZATION> follow us <ORGANIZATION>Facebook Twitter Tumblr Pinterest Soundcloud YouTube</ORGANIZATION> poets org Poems Love poems Audio Poems for Kids Poets Poetry Near You Stanza Texts Jobs for Poets Materials for Teachers academy of american poets Programs Prizes <PERSON>Walt Whitman</PERSON> Award <PERSON>James Laughlin</PERSON> Award Ambroggio Prize Chancellors Mission amp History Staff national poetry month Poetry amp the Creative Mind Dear Poet Project Poster 30 Ways to Celebrate Sponsorship american poets Books Noted Essays Back Issues Advertise poem index occasions <ORGANIZATION>Anniversary Asian Pacific American Heritage Month Autumn Birthdays Black History Month</ORGANIZATION> Breakfast Breakups Chanukah Christmas Dinner Earth Day Easter Election Day Farewell Father s Day Fourth of July Funerals Graduation Halloween Hispanic Heritage Month LGBTQ Pride Month Lunch Martin Luther King Jr Day Memorial Day Mother s Day Native American Heritage Month New Year s September 11 Spring Summer Thanksgiving Vacations Valentine s Day Veterans Day Weddings Winter Women s History Month themes Afterlife Aging Ambition America American Revolution Americana Ancestry Anger Animals Anxiety Apocalypse Audio Beauty Beginning Birds Body Brothers Buildings Carpe Diem Cats Childhood Cities Clothing Cooking Creation Dance Daughters Death Deception Desire Despair Divorce Dogs Doubt Dreams Drinking Drugs Earth Eating Economy Enemies Environment Existential Family Fathers Flight Flowers For Children For Mom For Teens Friendship Future Gardens Gender Ghosts Gratitude Grief Gun Violence Happiness Heartache Heroes High School History Home Hope Humor Identity Illness Immigration Infidelity Innocence Jealousy Landscapes Language LGBTQ Loneliness Loss Love Love Contemporary Luck <ORGANIZATION>Lust Marriage Math Memories Migration Miracles Money Mothers Mourning Movies Moving Music Myth National Parks Nature New York City</ORGANIZATION> Night Nostalgia Oblivion Oceans Old Age Pacifism Parenting Past Pastoral Patience Pets Plants Politics Popular Culture Public Domain Reading Rebellion Regret Religion Romance Sadness School Science Self Sex Silence Sisters Social Justice Sons Space Spanish Spirituality Sports Storms Suburbia Survival Teaching Technology Theft Thought <ORGANIZATION>Time Tragedy Travel Turmoil Underworld Vanity Violence Visual</ORGANIZATION> Art War Weather Work Writing forms Abecedarian Acrostic <ORGANIZATION>Anaphora Ars Poetica Ballad Ballade Blues Poem Bop Cento Chance Operations Cinquain Doha Dramatic Monologue Ekphrastic Elegy Epic Epigram Epistle Erasure Found Poem Ghazal Haiku Limerick Ode Pantoum Prose Poem Renga Rondeau Sapphic Sestina Sonnet Tanka Terza Rima Triolet Villanelle</ORGANIZATION> schools amp movements Nuyorican Poetry Objectivists <ORGANIZATION>OULIPO Poets of Exile Romanticism New York School New Formalism Misty Poets Modernism Modernismo</ORGANIZATION> N gritude <LOCATION>San Francisco</LOCATION> Renaissance Slam Spoken Word Surrealism Symbolists Translators Victorian Metaphysical Poet Language Poetry Confessional Poetry Contemporary Cowboy Poetry Dark Room Collective Concrete Poetry Conceptual Poetry <ORGANIZATION>Augustan Beat Black Arts Black Mountain Ethnopoetics Fireside Poet Harlem Renaissance Imagism Jazz Poetry Kanaka Maoli</ORGANIZATION> poetry Futurism Fugitives First World War Flarf Formalism <ORGANIZATION>Acmeism Poets org Academy of American Poets National Poetry Month American Poets Magazine Poets Shop Main Footer Menu Contact About Us For Advertisers Press Center Sign Up Credits Privacy Policy Academy of American Poets</ORGANIZATION> 75 <LOCATION>Maiden Lane Suite 901 New York NY</LOCATION> 10038 X Register Login with Register Login with Username Password Create new account Request new password</ner>
