<ner>Home Search Browse Collections My Account About image DC Network Digital Commons Network Skip to main content image <ORGANIZATION>DigitalCommons University of Nebraska Lincoln DigitalCommons University of Nebraska Lincoln My Account FAQ About Home Home</ORGANIZATION> gt Libraries gt E Texts in American Studies image Electronic Texts in American Studies Libraries at <ORGANIZATION>University of Nebraska Lincoln Electronic Texts</ORGANIZATION> in American Studies The following materials are electronic texts of documents primary texts and literature associated with the history and culture of the <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> All materials are open access full text PDF editions and are presented for the use of teachers students and researchers Users are invited to browse download save print and link to any of these documents but are asked not to re post or re publish them elsewhere without permission of the depositor This series is administered by <PERSON>Paul Royster</PERSON> proyster unl edu Persons wishing to deposit additional materials are encouraged to contact him Follow index Jump to 1588 1588 PDF A Brief and True Report of the New Found Land of <LOCATION>Virginia</LOCATION> 1588 <PERSON>Thomas Hariot</PERSON> and <PERSON>Paul Royster</PERSON> editor 1616 1616 PDF A Description of New England 1616 An Online Electronic Text Edition <PERSON>John Smith</PERSON> Captain amp Admiral and <PERSON>Paul Royster</PERSON> editor 1630 1630 PDF Gods Promise to His Plantation 1630 <PERSON>John Cotton</PERSON> and <PERSON>Reiner Smolinski</PERSON> Editor 1637 1637 PDF A True Relation of the Late <PERSON>Battell</PERSON> fought in <LOCATION>New England</LOCATION> between the English and the Salvages With the present state of things there 1637 <PERSON>Philip Vincent P Vincentius</PERSON> and <PERSON>Paul Royster</PERSON> editor 1638 1638 PDF Newes from <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> Or A New and Experimentall Discoverie of <LOCATION>New England</LOCATION> Containing A Trve Relation of Their War like Proceedings These Two Yeares Last Past with a Figure of the Indian Fort or Palizado <PERSON>John Underhill</PERSON> and <PERSON>Paul Royster</PERSON> editor 1646 1646 PDF Milk for Babes Drawn Out of the Breasts of Both Testaments Chiefly for the <ORGANIZATION>Spirituall Nourishment of Boston Babes</ORGANIZATION> in Either <LOCATION>England</LOCATION> But May Be of Like Use for Any Children 1646 <PERSON>John Cotton</PERSON> B D and <PERSON>Paul Royster</PERSON> editor 1649 1649 PDF <PERSON>Samuel Danforth</PERSON> s Almanack Poems and Chronological Tables 1647 1649 <PERSON>Samuel Danforth</PERSON> and <PERSON>Paul Royster</PERSON> transcriber amp editor 1656 1656 PDF The Case of <ORGANIZATION>Ann Hibbins Executed for Witchcraft</ORGANIZATION> at <LOCATION>Boston</LOCATION> in 1656 <PERSON>William F Poole Justin Winsor</PERSON> and <PERSON>Paul Royster</PERSON> depositor 1659 1659 PDF The Christian Commonwealth or The Civil Policy Of The Rising Kingdom of Jesus Christ An Online Electronic Text Edition <PERSON>John Eliot</PERSON> and <PERSON>Paul Royster</PERSON> editor amp depositor 1660 1660 PDF Relation of the Pequot Warres 1660 Lion Gardener and <ORGANIZATION>W N Chattin Carlton</ORGANIZATION> editor 1661 1661 PDF A Declaration of the Sad and Great Persecution and Martyrdom of the People of God called Quakers in <LOCATION>New England</LOCATION> for the Worshipping of God 1661 <PERSON>Edward Burrough</PERSON> and <PERSON>Paul Royster</PERSON> editor 1662 1662 PDF God s Controversy with <LOCATION>New England</LOCATION> 1662 1871 <PERSON>Michael Wigglesworth</PERSON> and <PERSON>Reiner Smolinski</PERSON> Editor 1665 1665 PDF An Astronomical Description of the Late Comet or Blazing Star As it appeared in <LOCATION>New England</LOCATION> in the 9th 10th 11th and in the beginning of the 12th Moneth 1664 Together with a Brief Theological Application thereof 1665 An Online Electronic Text Edition <PERSON>Samuel Danforth</PERSON> and <PERSON>Paul Royster</PERSON> editor 1670 1670 PDF A <ORGANIZATION>Brief Recognition of New</ORGANIZATION> Englands Errand into the Wilderness An Online Electronic Text Edition <PERSON>Samuel Danforth</PERSON> and <PERSON>Paul Royster</PERSON> transcriber amp editor PDF A SERMON Preach d at The Election of the Governour AT <LOCATION>BOSTON</LOCATION> IN <LOCATION>New England</LOCATION> May 19th 1669 <PERSON>John Davenport</PERSON> and <PERSON>Paul Royster</PERSON> editor PDF A <ORGANIZATION>Brief Description of New York Formerly Called New Netherlands</ORGANIZATION> 1670 <PERSON>Daniel Denton</PERSON> and <PERSON>Paul Royster</PERSON> editor amp depositor 1674 1674 PDF The Cry of Sodom Enquired Into Upon Occasion of the Arraignment and Condemnation of <PERSON>Benjamin Goad</PERSON> for His Prodigious Villany 1674 An Online Electronic Text Edition <PERSON>Samuel Danforth</PERSON> and <PERSON>Paul Royster</PERSON> editor 1675 1675 PDF A Relation of the Indian War by Mr <PERSON>Easton</PERSON> of <LOCATION>Rhode Island</LOCATION> 1675 <PERSON>John Easton</PERSON> and <PERSON>Paul Royster</PERSON> editor 1676 1676 PDF A Brief History of the <PERSON>Warr</PERSON> with the Indians in <LOCATION>New England</LOCATION> 1676 An Online Electronic Text Edition Increase Mather and <PERSON>Paul Royster</PERSON> editor PDF An Earnest Exhortation To the Inhabitants of <LOCATION>New England</LOCATION> 1676 Increase Mather and <PERSON>Reiner Smolinski</PERSON> Editor 1690 1690 PDF The Widdow Ranter or The <ORGANIZATION>History of Bacon</ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION>Virginia</LOCATION> 1690 <PERSON>Aphra Behn</PERSON> and <PERSON>Paul Royster</PERSON> editor 1691 1691 PDF Old Mens TEARS For their own DECLENSIONS Mixed with FEARS Of their and Posterities further falling off from <LOCATION>New England</LOCATION> s PRIMITIVE CONSTITUTION <PERSON>Joshua Scottow</PERSON> and <PERSON>Paul Royster</PERSON> editor 1693 1693 PDF The Wonders of the Invisible World Observations as Well Historical as Theological upon the Nature the Number and the Operations of the Devils 1693 <ORGANIZATION>Cotton Mather</ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON>Reiner Smolinski</PERSON> Editor 1694 1694 PDF A NARRATIVE Of The Planting of the <LOCATION>Massachusets</LOCATION> COLONY Anno 1628 With the LORDS Signal Presence the First Thirty YEARS Also a Caution from New Englands APOSTLE the GREAT COTTON How to Escape the Calamity which might Befall them or their POSTERITY And Confirmed by the EVANGELIST NORTON With Prognosticks from the FAMOUS Dr OWEN Concerning the Fate of these Churches and Animadversions upon the Anger of God in sending of Evil Angels among us Published by Old Planters the Authors of the Old Mens Tears <PERSON>Joshua Scottow</PERSON> and <PERSON>Paul Royster</PERSON> transcribed amp edited by 1695 1695 PDF New Yorke Considered and Improved A D 1695 <PERSON>John Miller Victor Hugo Paltsits</PERSON> and <PERSON>Paul Royster</PERSON> Depositor 1696 1696 PDF <LOCATION>MASSACHUSETTS</LOCATION> or The first Planters of New England The End and Manner of their coming thither and Abode there In several EPISTLES 1696 <PERSON>John Winthrop Thomas Dudley John Allin Thomas Shepard John Cotton Joshua Scottow</PERSON> and <PERSON>Paul Royster</PERSON> Editor of the Online Electronic Edition 1697 1697 PDF Phaenomena quaedam Apocalyptica ad aspectum Novi Orbis configurata Or some few lines towards a description of the New Heaven 1697 <PERSON>Samuel Sewall</PERSON> and <PERSON>Reiner Smolinski</PERSON> Editor 1700 1700 PDF The Selling of Joseph A Memorial 1700 <PERSON>Samuel Sewall</PERSON> 1701 1701 PDF A two Years Journal in <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> And part of its Territories in <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> 1701 <PERSON>Charles Wolley</PERSON> A M <PERSON>Edward Gaylord Bourne</PERSON> and <PERSON>Paul Royster</PERSON> depositor 1706 1706 PDF The Negro Christianized An Essay to Excite and Assist that Good Work the Instruction of Negro Servants in Christianity 1706 <ORGANIZATION>Cotton Mather</ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON>Paul Royster</PERSON> editor 1710 1710 PDF Theopolis Americana An Essay on the <LOCATION>Golden Street</LOCATION> of the Holy City 1710 <ORGANIZATION>Cotton Mather</ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON>Reiner Smolinski</PERSON> Editor 1727 1727 PDF The Threefold Paradise of Cotton Mather An Edition of Triparadisus Reiner Smolinski 1734 1734 PDF The Constitutions of the Free Masons 1734 An Online Electronic Edition <PERSON>James Anderson</PERSON> A M <PERSON>Benjamin Franklin</PERSON> and <PERSON>Paul Royster</PERSON> editor amp depositor PDF A Divine and Supernatural Light Immediately imparted to the Soul by the Spirit of God Shown to be both a Scriptural and Rational Doctrine <PERSON>Jonathan Edwards</PERSON> and <PERSON>Reiner Smolinski</PERSON> 1736 1736 PDF A Brief History of the Pequot War 1736 <PERSON>John Mason</PERSON> and <PERSON>Paul Royster</PERSON> editor 1741 1741 PDF Sinners in the Hands of an Angry God A Sermon Preached at <ORGANIZATION>Enfield</ORGANIZATION> July 8th 1741 <PERSON>Jonathan Edwards</PERSON> and <PERSON>Reiner Smolinski</PERSON> Editor 1745 1745 PDF Marvellous Things done by the right Hand and holy Arm of God in getting him the Victory 1745 <PERSON>Charles Chauncy</PERSON> and <PERSON>Reiner Smolinski</PERSON> Editor 1750 1750 PDF A Discourse concerning Unlimited Submission and Non Resistance to the Higher Powers With some Reflections on the <ORGANIZATION>Resistance</ORGANIZATION> made to King <PERSON>Charles</PERSON> I And on the Anniversary of his Death In which the Mysterious Doctrine of that <PERSON>Prince</PERSON> s <LOCATION>Saintship</LOCATION> and Martyrdom is Unriddled 1750 An Online Electronic Text Edition <PERSON>Jonathan Mayhew</PERSON> A M D D and <PERSON>Paul Royster</PERSON> Editor amp Depositor 1751 1751 PDF De <PERSON>Bestiis Marinis</PERSON> or The Beasts of the Sea 1751 <PERSON>Georg Wilhelm Steller Walter Miller Translator Jennie Emerson Miller Translator</PERSON> and <PERSON>Paul Royster</PERSON> Transcriber and editor 1754 1754 PDF The Journal of Major <PERSON>George Washington</PERSON> 1754 <PERSON>George Washington</PERSON> and <PERSON>Paul Royster</PERSON> editor 1771 1771 PDF The Life and Spiritual Sufferings of That Faithful Servant of <PERSON>Christ Jane Hoskens</PERSON> a Public Preacher among the <ORGANIZATION>People Called Quakers</ORGANIZATION> 1771 <PERSON>Jane Fenn Hoskens</PERSON> and <PERSON>Paul Royster</PERSON> editor 1775 1775 PDF Some Strictures upon the Sacred Story Recorded in the Book of Esther 1775 Oliver Noble M A and <PERSON>Reiner Smolinski</PERSON> Editor 1776 1776 PDF A Charge on the Rise of the American Empire 1776 <PERSON>William Henry Drayton</PERSON> and <PERSON>Reiner Smolinski</PERSON> Editor PDF The Church s Flight into the Wilderness An Address on the <ORGANIZATION>Times</ORGANIZATION> containing Some very interesting and important Observations on Scripture Prophecies 1776 <PERSON>Samuel Sherwood</PERSON> A M and <PERSON>Reiner Smolinski</PERSON> Editor 1777 1777 PDF God Arising and Pleading His People s Cause or The American War in Favor of <ORGANIZATION>Liberty Against the Measures</ORGANIZATION> and Arms of <LOCATION>Great Britain Shewn</LOCATION> to Be the Cause of God 1777 <PERSON>Abraham Keteltas</PERSON> and <PERSON>Reiner Smolinski</PERSON> Editor 1783 1783 PDF The <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> Elevated to Glory and Honor 1783 <PERSON>Ezra Stiles</PERSON> D D and <PERSON>Reiner Smolinski</PERSON> Editor 1784 1784 PDF The Discovery Settlement and Present State of Kentucke 1784 An Online Electronic Text Edition <PERSON>John Filson</PERSON> and Paul Royster Editor 1787 1787 PDF An Address to the Negroes in the State of <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> 1787 <PERSON>Jupiter Hammon</PERSON> and <PERSON>Paul Royster</PERSON> editor 1792 1792 PDF The Conspiracy of Kings A Poem Addressed to the Inhabitants of <LOCATION>Europe</LOCATION> from Another Quarter of the World <PERSON>Joel Barlow</PERSON> and <PERSON>John D Baird</PERSON> 1793 1793 PDF The Remarkable Adventures of <PERSON>Jackson Johonnet</PERSON> of <LOCATION>Massachusetts</LOCATION> 1793 <PERSON>Jackson Johonnet</PERSON> and <PERSON>Paul Royster</PERSON> editor 1808 1808 PDF An Oration on the Abolition of the Slave Trade Delivered in the African Church in the City of <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> January 1 1808 <PERSON>Peter Williams Jr</PERSON> and <PERSON>Paul Royster</PERSON> Editor 1809 1809 PDF The Life and Surprising Adventures of <PERSON>Mary Ann Talbot</PERSON> in the Name of <PERSON>John Taylor</PERSON> 1809 <PERSON>Mary Ann Talbot</PERSON> and <PERSON>Paul Royster</PERSON> transcribed and edited by 1816 1816 PDF Memoir of <PERSON>Joshua Scottow</PERSON> 1816 Sigma pseudonym and <PERSON>Paul Royster</PERSON> transcribed and deposited by 1822 1822 PDF A <ORGANIZATION>Knickerbocker</ORGANIZATION> tour of <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> State 1822 Our Travels Statistical Geographical Mineorological Geological Historical Political and Quizzical Written by Myself XYZ etc <PERSON>Johnston Verplanck</PERSON> and <PERSON>Louis Leonard Tucker</PERSON> editor 1824 1824 PDF Notes Geographical and Historical relating to the Town of <LOCATION>Brooklyn</LOCATION> in <LOCATION>Kings County</LOCATION> on <LOCATION>Long Island</LOCATION> 1824 An Online Electronic Text Edition <PERSON>Gabriel Furman</PERSON> and <PERSON>Paul Royster</PERSON> transcriber amp depositor 1828 1828 PDF <PERSON>David Cusick</PERSON> s Sketches of Ancient History of the Six Nations 1828 <PERSON>David Cusick</PERSON> and <PERSON>Paul Royster</PERSON> editor amp depositor 1830 1830 PDF Walker s Appeal in Four Articles Together with a Preamble to the <ORGANIZATION>Coloured Citizens of the World Boston</ORGANIZATION> 1830 <PERSON>David Walker</PERSON> and <PERSON>Paul Royster</PERSON> editor amp depositor 1831 1831 PDF The Confessions of <ORGANIZATION>Nat Turner</ORGANIZATION> 1831 <PERSON>Thomas R Gray Nat Turner</PERSON> and <PERSON>Paul Royster</PERSON> Depositor 1833 1833 PDF Appeal to the Wealthy of the Land Ladies as Well as Gentlemen on the Character Conduct Situation and Prospects of Those Whose Sole Dependence for Subsistence Is on the Labour of Their Hands 1833 <PERSON>Mathew Carey</PERSON> and <PERSON>Paul Royster</PERSON> transcriber amp depositor 1836 1836 PDF A Synopsis of the Indian Tribes Within the <LOCATION>United States East</LOCATION> of the <LOCATION>Rocky Mountains</LOCATION> and in the British and Russian Possessions in <LOCATION>North America Albert Gallatin</LOCATION> 1838 1838 PDF History of the <LOCATION>Captivity</LOCATION> and Providential Release Therefrom of Mrs <PERSON>Caroline Harris Caroline Harris</PERSON> PDF Narrative of the <LOCATION>Captivity</LOCATION> and Extreme Sufferings of Mrs <PERSON>Clarissa Plummer Clarissa Plummer</PERSON> 1840 1840 PDF <PERSON>Strauss</PERSON> s Life of <PERSON>Jesus Theodore Parker</PERSON> and <PERSON>Paul Royster</PERSON> depositor 1841 1841 PDF A DISCOURSE OF THE TRANSIENT AND PERMANENT IN CHRISTIANITY Theodore Parker 1842 1842 PDF Primitive Christianity <PERSON>Theodore Parker</PERSON> and <PERSON>Paul Royster</PERSON> annotator 1843 1843 PDF An Address to the Slaves of the <ORGANIZATION>United States of America Buffalo N</ORGANIZATION> Y 1843 <PERSON>Henry Highland Garnet</PERSON> 1845 1845 PDF Address Delivered before the <ORGANIZATION>Queens County Agricultural Society</ORGANIZATION> at Its Third Anniversary at <LOCATION>Jamaica</LOCATION> Thursday October 10th 1844 <PERSON>Gabriel Furman</PERSON> PDF Introduction and Notes to 1845 <PERSON>Gowans</PERSON> edition of <PERSON>Daniel Denton</PERSON> s A Brief Description of <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> 1670 <PERSON>Gabriel Furman Daniel Denton</PERSON> and <PERSON>Paul Royster</PERSON> Transcriber amp Depositor 1847 1847 PDF Peace with <LOCATION>Mexico</LOCATION> <PERSON>Albert Gallatin</PERSON> 1848 1848 PDF The Past and the Present Condition and the Destiny of the Colored Race 1848 <PERSON>Henry Highland Garnet</PERSON> and <PERSON>Paul Royster</PERSON> edited by PDF LABOR ITS HISTORY AND ITS PROSPECTS 1848 <PERSON>Robert Dale Owen</PERSON> and <PERSON>Paul Royster</PERSON> edited by 1850 1850 PDF A Lecture on the Railroad to the <LOCATION>Pacific</LOCATION> 1850 <PERSON>Calvin Colton</PERSON> and <PERSON>Paul Royster</PERSON> editor 1856 1856 PDF Dissent in Dred <PERSON>Scott</PERSON> v <ORGANIZATION>Sandford</ORGANIZATION> 1856 <PERSON>John McLean</PERSON> 1865 1865 PDF Two Biographical Sketches of <PERSON>Gabriel Furman</PERSON> The <ORGANIZATION>Faust Club</ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION>Brooklyn</LOCATION> <PERSON>William Gowans</PERSON> and <PERSON>Paul Royster</PERSON> transcriber amp depositor 1867 1867 PDF An Address on Success in Business 1867 <PERSON>Horace Greeley</PERSON> and <PERSON>Paul Royster</PERSON> depositor 1872 1872 PDF Narrative of My Captivity Among the <ORGANIZATION>Sioux Indians Fanny Kelly</ORGANIZATION> 1875 1875 PDF The Perfectionists of <LOCATION>Oneida</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Wallingford</LOCATION> <PERSON>Charles Nordhoff</PERSON> and <PERSON>Paul Royster</PERSON> Depositor 1877 1877 PDF Sketch of the Life and Writings of <PERSON>John Davenport Franklin B Dexter</PERSON> 1888 1888 PDF <PERSON>John Marr</PERSON> and Other Sailors An Online Electronic Facsimile Text of the First Edition 1888 <PERSON>Herman Melville</PERSON> and <PERSON>Paul Royster</PERSON> editor amp depositor 1891 1891 PDF Timoleon Etc An online electronic text of the first edition 1891 <PERSON>Herman Melville</PERSON> and <PERSON>Paul Royster</PERSON> editor amp depositor 1892 1892 PDF A REVIEW Of the Cattle Business in <LOCATION>Johnson County Wyoming</LOCATION> SINCE 1882 And the Causes that Led to the Recent Invasion Oscar H <PERSON>Jack Flagg</PERSON> 1897 1897 PDF The Heaven of the Bible Ida C <PERSON>Craddock</PERSON> and <PERSON>Paul Royster</PERSON> Editor 1898 1898 PDF Early <ORGANIZATION>New England Catechisms Wilberforce Eames</ORGANIZATION> 1899 1899 PDF Tales of the Enchanted Islands of the <LOCATION>Atlantic</LOCATION> <PERSON>Thomas Wentworth Higginson</PERSON> and <PERSON>Albert Herter</PERSON> 1902 1902 PDF The Wedding Night Ida C <PERSON>Craddock</PERSON> and <PERSON>Paul Royster</PERSON> editor 1904 1904 PDF Modern Methods of Book Composition <PERSON>Theodore Low De Vinne</PERSON> 1906 1906 PDF Sketch of <PERSON>Joshua Scottow</PERSON> with his Petition to the <ORGANIZATION>General Court of Massachusetts</ORGANIZATION> 1906 <PERSON>Henry Herbert Edes</PERSON> and <PERSON>Paul Royster</PERSON> transcribed and deposited by 1909 1909 PDF 1609 1909 The Dutch in <LOCATION>New Netherland</LOCATION> and the <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> 1913 1913 PDF <ORGANIZATION>Connecticut Soldiers</ORGANIZATION> in the Pequot War of 1637 1913 <PERSON>James Shepard</PERSON> 1919 1919 PDF <ORGANIZATION>America s Mission to Serve Humanity Wilson</ORGANIZATION> a Prophet in a Line of Prophets Frank Moss 1941 1941 PDF A History of the Churches of Christ in <ORGANIZATION>Morgan County Kentucky Luke Bolin</ORGANIZATION> 1961 1961 PDF The Records of the <ORGANIZATION>First Church</ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION>Boston</LOCATION> 1630 1868 volume 1 <PERSON>Richard D Pierce</PERSON> editor 1970 1970 PDF <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> s First Negro Poet The Complete Works of <PERSON>Jupiter Hammon</PERSON> of <LOCATION>Long Island Jupiter</LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION>Hammon Stanley Austin Ransom Jr Oscar Wegelin</ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON>Vernon Loggins</PERSON> 1998 1998 PDF The Kingdom the Power amp the Glory The Millennial Impulse in Early American Literature General Introduction <PERSON>Reiner Smolinski</PERSON> Editor PDF The Kingdom The Power amp The Glory The Millennial Impulse in <ORGANIZATION>Early American Literature Questions for Discussions Research and Writing Reiner Smolinski</ORGANIZATION> Editor 2006 2006 PDF The Five Editions of Old Mens Tears <PERSON>Paul Royster</PERSON> 2007 2007 PDF Electronic Texts in American Studies <PERSON>Paul Royster</PERSON> 2009 2009 PDF Digitally Re Publishing Franklin s 1734 Edition of <PERSON>James Anderson</PERSON> s Constitutions of the Free Masons Typographical Challenges and Unexpected Rewards Paul Royster Search Enter search terms Select context to search in this series in this repository across all repositories Advanced Search Search Help Notify me via email or RSS How to Cite Items From This Repository Copyright Information Browse Collections Disciplines Authors Author Corner Author FAQ Guide to Submitting Submit your paper or article Links Libraries Website Digital Commons Home About FAQ My Account Accessibility Statement Privacy Copyright</ner>
