<ner><ORGANIZATION>Ohio State</ORGANIZATION> nav bar Skip to main content The <ORGANIZATION>Ohio State University Help BuckeyeLink Map Find People Webmail Search Ohio State</ORGANIZATION> The <ORGANIZATION>Ohio State University Libraries Home Find Borrowing amp Lending Collections People Resources Rooms Services Help Tutorials Library Instruction</ORGANIZATION> Ask Us Help With How Do I Troubleshooting Locations Weekly Hours A Z Locations Map News Events Science Cafe Calendar Blogs Giving to the Libraries Projects Initiatives Affordability Exhibits Knowledge Bank Center Open Access Monograph Initiative Special Collections Copyright <ORGANIZATION>OSU Records Mgmt About Us Administration Committees Jobs Contact Us Departments Locations Hours Map Partners Policies amp Procedures Staff Directory My Account Student Services Faculty Services Alumni amp Friends Services My Library Account Pay</ORGANIZATION> Fines Appeal Fines Off Campus Sign In Search this site Search this site Close or ESC Search all pages on this website Search Query Sitemap Find Borrowing amp Lending Collections People Resources Rooms Services Help Tutorials Library Instruction Ask Us Help With How Do I Troubleshooting Locations Weekly Hours A Z Locations Map News Events Science Cafe Calendar Blogs Giving to the Libraries Projects Initiatives Affordability Exhibits Knowledge Bank Center Open Access Monograph Initiative Special Collections Copyright <ORGANIZATION>OSU Records Mgmt About Us Administration Committees Jobs Contact Us Departments Locations Hours Map Partners Policies amp Procedures Staff Directory My Account Student Services Faculty Services Alumni amp Friends Services My Library Account Pay</ORGANIZATION> Fines Appeal Fines Off Campus Sign In <ORGANIZATION>William Charvat Collection of American Literature Hours</ORGANIZATION> and Location Services Contact Us Visit Us Teach With Us Subcollections Literary Manuscripts Contact <PERSON>Jolie Braun</PERSON> Assistant Professor Curator of American Literature 119B Thompson Library 1858 Neil Avenue Columbus OH 43210 Office 614 688 4980 braun 338 osu edu bookmark content Nineteenth Century American Fiction and Poetry Resources in The <ORGANIZATION>Charvat Collection of American Literature</ORGANIZATION> amp The Rare Books and Manuscripts Library The <PERSON>Sarah</PERSON> M B Piatt Collection <PERSON>Paula Bernat Bennett</PERSON> s research materials for her selection of <PERSON>Sarah</PERSON> M B Piatt Poems Palace Burner The Selected Poetry of <PERSON>Sarah Piatt</PERSON> 2001 Please note that this finding aid ws revised in 2018 Consult with a curator if you have references pointing to an earlier version Later additions from Professor <PERSON>Bennett</PERSON> that she wished to highlight Finding List for <PERSON>Sarah Piatt</PERSON> s Poetry Dec 2013 Index to the Juvenilia Feb 2014 Chronological Index to the Variorum Feb 2014 Alphabetical Index to the Variorum Feb 2014 The <ORGANIZATION>Larry R Michaels Collection Books</ORGANIZATION> and serials donated by <PERSON>Larry R Michaels</PERSON> for research on <PERSON>Sarah Piatt</PERSON> may be found with a keyword search of the catalog on gift of <PERSON>Larry R Michaels</PERSON> The finding aid lists his collection of biographic research notes related to <PERSON>Piatt</PERSON> SPEC RARE 0222 Ohio Memory See the Ohio Memory Project A Collaborative Project of the Ohio History Connection and the <ORGANIZATION>State Library</ORGANIZATION> of <LOCATION>Ohio</LOCATION> for more on the <ORGANIZATION>Piatt Family</ORGANIZATION> as well as other resources for the history of <LOCATION>Ohio</LOCATION> A CD of selected contributions is available in Rare Books and Manuscripts PS586 O35 2002 The Capital <LOCATION>Washington</LOCATION> D C newspaper <PERSON>Donn Piatt</PERSON> was editor off and on until 1879 and published the work of newly discovered authors on its pages Early volumes held at <ORGANIZATION>Piatt Castles</ORGANIZATION> were loaned to <ORGANIZATION>OSU</ORGANIZATION> and scanned They are available online in a searchable database Some visual clarity is lost in this delivery system The original scans are available for consultation on request if required for a project Some gaps in coverage may be filled by our microfilm holdings Request and view the following issues in the Thompson Library Special Collections Reading Room January 4 1880 March 13 1881 microfilm January 14 May 27 1883 microfilm March 2 August 17 1884 microfilm June 20 1886 microfilm January 1 1888 microfilm January 6 1889 June 23 1889 microfilm The Jerry Tarver Elocution Rhetoric and Oratory Collection See the guides on the collection page to access this collection of books serials manuscripts photographs and ephemera <PERSON>Tuttle</PERSON> American Poetry Collection This was a special purchase of 19th and early 20th century books of poetry The complete list is a scan of our old typewritten record Please note that there are two separate alphabetical listings plus some unordered items in between To pull up a complete list from the catalog search for the title Tuttle American Poetry Collection Visual Materials The Photograph Collection Daguerreotypes ambrotypes tintypes and calotypes are listed in the inventory Check with curator about browsing the collection of cabinet cards cartes de visite and stereocards Trade Catalogs The Dr <PERSON>Ivan</PERSON> S <ORGANIZATION>Gilbert Trade Catalog Collection</ORGANIZATION> includes catalogs for any consumable one can imagine Many date to the 19th century The researcher my be particularly interested in such categories as carriages and carts or clothing and dress Ancillary Resources Almanacs The Kevin Elder Almanac Collection may provide some useful information Children s Science Texts The <ORGANIZATION>Emanuel Rudolph Children s Science Collection</ORGANIZATION> includes over 1200 19th century texts One may limit a title search on the emanuel rudolph children s science collection to just those dating from the 19th century Cookbooks The Peter D Franklin Cookbook Collection includes some from the 19th century After performing a title search in the library catalog for peter d franklin cookbook collection limit the results to those predating 1900 Nineteenth century Newspapers Various issues of approximately 45 newspapers predominantly dated between 1810 1870 This is a boxed collection of selected issues See also individual titles such as Every Saturday Sheet Music The Fanny Arms collection of American popular sheet music ca 1865 1950 is an enormous collection Please consult a curator for assistance in locating desired pieces Personal Correspondence Journals and Papers The following collections provide personal accounts of life in the 19th century <PERSON>Anderson William</PERSON> B Civil War Correspondence 1862 1864 <ORGANIZATION>Cox Samuel Sullivan Journal</ORGANIZATION> of a tour to <LOCATION>Europe</LOCATION> 1851 <PERSON>Doane Louisa</PERSON> A Manuscript diary of <PERSON>Louisa A Doane</PERSON> on two voyages <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> to <LOCATION>Marseilles</LOCATION> and return and <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> to <LOCATION>Chinchas Islands</LOCATION> and return 1852 <PERSON>Dumaresq Philip K Philip Kearney</PERSON> Daily Diary 1879 Diary of an American working as a special agent for the <ORGANIZATION>Pacific Mail Steamship Company</ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> primarily in <LOCATION>Shanghai</LOCATION> including details of his family social life and work <ORGANIZATION>Hawthorne Sophia Peabody Letters</ORGANIZATION> to <PERSON>Elizabeth Palmer Peabody</PERSON> ca 1837 1868 Newlon William Day Books 1843 1891 The books contain financial records as well as some poems and drawings <ORGANIZATION>Peers Valentine Valentine Peers</ORGANIZATION> papers 1777 1854 <PERSON>Sherrard Thomas</PERSON> J Correspondence Collection Personal family correspondence to or from <PERSON>Thomas Sherrard</PERSON> his wife <PERSON>Mary Campbell Sherrard</PERSON> and his wife s immediate family <PERSON>Rev Thomas J Sherrard</PERSON> led several Presbyterian congregations in the second half of the 19th century See finding aid on the web <ORGANIZATION>Smith Lucius Clark Diaries</ORGANIZATION> 1859 1862 Two volumes of the manuscript diaries of school teacher and farmer <PERSON>Lucius Clark Smith</PERSON> resident of <LOCATION>New Albany Plain Township Franklin County Ohio</LOCATION> <ORGANIZATION>Navigation Nineteenth Century Home Find Collections William Charvat Collection of American Literature Subcollections Literary Manuscripts Nineteenth Century American Fiction</ORGANIZATION> and Poetry This page last modified March 27 2018 The <ORGANIZATION>Ohio State University</ORGANIZATION> Libraries 2015 The <ORGANIZATION>Ohio State University University</ORGANIZATION> Libraries 1858 <LOCATION>Neil Avenue Mall Columbus Ohio</LOCATION> 43210 614 292 OSUL 6785 Request an alternate format of this page Privacy Policy Contact Us image Except where otherwise noted this work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution 4 0 <ORGANIZATION>International License Copyright Information Details</ORGANIZATION> and Exceptions image <ORGANIZATION>Facebook</ORGANIZATION> image Twitter image Youtube image RSS image Give Today</ner>
