<ner>Main Page From <ORGANIZATION>Meta a Wikimedia</ORGANIZATION> project coordination wiki Jump to navigation search Meta Wiki Mission Projects complete list <ORGANIZATION>Research Translation</ORGANIZATION> requests Vision Welcome to Meta Wiki the global community site for the Wikimedia projects and the <ORGANIZATION>Wikimedia</ORGANIZATION> movement in general <PERSON>Meta Wiki</PERSON> s discussions range from coordination and documentation to planning and analysis of future <ORGANIZATION>Wikimedia</ORGANIZATION> activities Other meta focused wikis such as Wikimedia Outreach are specialized projects that have their roots in Meta Wiki Related discussion also takes place on <ORGANIZATION>Wikimedia</ORGANIZATION> mailing lists particularly wikimedia l with its low traffic equivalent WikimediaAnnounce IRC channels on freenode individual wikis of Wikimedia affiliates and other places image Goings on image Requests Edit Translate April 2018 image <ORGANIZATION>Wikimedia</ORGANIZATION> logo svg April 1 May 15 The draft Annual Plan of the <ORGANIZATION>Wikimedia Foundation</ORGANIZATION> is open for comments January 2018 image <ORGANIZATION>Wikimedia</ORGANIZATION> logo svg Jan 15 The Community Capacity Map experiment is announced Details in the about page <ORGANIZATION>Cross</ORGANIZATION> wiki issues Bot status CheckUser Speedy deletions Username changes Permissions Spam blacklist Title blacklist Other Translations Logos Wikimedia Grants funding New languages Project closures Deletions Deleteme category Undeletions More overview image Community and communication image Core issues and collaboration Babel a discussion place for Meta Wiki matters Mailing lists and IRC Meetups a list of offline events <ORGANIZATION>Wikimedia Embassy</ORGANIZATION> a list of local contacts by language Wikimedia Forum a multilingual forum for Wikimedia projects Wikimedians Wikimedia Resource Center a hub for <ORGANIZATION>WMF</ORGANIZATION> resources Community Dispute resolution Growing Wikimedia Interlingual coordination Requests for comment Wikimedia principles image <ORGANIZATION>Wikimedia Foundation Meta Wiki</ORGANIZATION> and its sister projects The <ORGANIZATION>Wikimedia Foundation</ORGANIZATION> is the overarching non profit foundation that owns the <ORGANIZATION>Wikimedia</ORGANIZATION> servers along with the domain names logos and trademarks of all Wikimedia projects and MediaWiki Meta Wiki is the coordination wiki for the various Wikimedia wikis Content projects image <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> logo v2 svg <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> The free encyclopedia image Wiktionary small svg Wiktionary Free dictionary and thesaurus image Commons logo svg Wikimedia Commons Free media repository image Wikibooks logo svg Wikibooks Free textbooks and manuals image Wikisource logo svg Wikisource Free content library image <ORGANIZATION>Wikidata</ORGANIZATION> logo svg Wikidata Free knowledge base image <ORGANIZATION>Wikiversity</ORGANIZATION> logo svg Wikiversity Free learning materials and activities image Wikiquote logo svg Wikiquote Collection of quotations image Wikispecies logo svg Wikispecies Free directory of species image Wikinews logo svg Wikinews Free content news image Wikivoyage Logo v3 icon svg Wikivoyage Free travel guide Outreach and administration projects image <ORGANIZATION>Wikimedia</ORGANIZATION> logo black svg <ORGANIZATION>Wikimedia Foundation Foundation</ORGANIZATION> public relations image <ORGANIZATION>Wikimedia Outreach svg Wikimedia Outreach Wikimedia</ORGANIZATION> outreach wiki image Wikimania svg Wikimania The International Conference image Wikimedia Community Logo Mailservices svg Wikimedia Mailservices Wikimedia Mailing Lists image Nuvola mimetypes log svg <ORGANIZATION>Wikistats Wikimedia</ORGANIZATION> statistics image Incubator logo svg Incubator For language versions in development Technical and development projects image MediaWiki notext svg MediaWiki MediaWiki software documentation image <ORGANIZATION>Wikitech</ORGANIZATION> logo svg <ORGANIZATION>Wikitech Wikimedia</ORGANIZATION> technical documentation image Wikimedia Phabricator logo svg Phabricator A bug tracker for MediaWiki image <ORGANIZATION>Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> logo test v2 svg Test Wikipedia For testing software changes image <ORGANIZATION>Wikimedia Cloud Services</ORGANIZATION> logo svg Wikimedia Cloud Services Hosting environment for community managed software projects tools and data analysis image Geographylogo png In other languages Afrikaans Alemannisch asturianu az rbaycanca <ORGANIZATION>Bahasa Indonesia Bahasa Melayu Basa Jawa Boarisch</ORGANIZATION> bosanski catal e tina corsu dansk <PERSON>Deutsch</PERSON> eesti English espa ol Esperanto fran ais galego hrvatski isiZulu slenska italiano la lojban kurd Latina latvie u lietuvi magyar <PERSON>Malti Mirand</PERSON> s <LOCATION>Napulitano Nederlands Nordfriisk</LOCATION> norsk bokm l norsk nynorsk polski portugu s portugu s do Brasil rom n <PERSON>Runa Simi</PERSON> shqip sicilianu sloven ina sloven ina <PERSON>Soomaaliga</PERSON> suomi svenska Kiswahili tarand ne Tagalog T rk e Ti ng Vi t V ro <LOCATION>Zazaki</LOCATION> srpski tatar a Hak k ng Uyghurche Old style nglisc Afrikaans B n l m g <ORGANIZATION>Basa Sunda</ORGANIZATION> brezhoneg Cymraeg euskara estreme u f royskt Gaeilge hrvatski Ido Igbo interlingua occitan <ORGANIZATION>Runa Simi</ORGANIZATION> v neto Yor b sou tgl <PERSON>Skandinavisk Skanwiki Slovio Slavopedia</PERSON> image Retrieved from https meta wikimedia org w index php title Main_Page amp oldid 15514880 Categories Main page en Categories en Navigation menu Personal tools English Not logged in Talk Contributions Create account Log in Namespaces Main Page Discussion Variants Views Read View source View history More Search Navigation Main page Wikimedia News Translations Recent changes Random page <ORGANIZATION>Help Babel Community Wikimedia Resource Center Wikimedia Forum Mailing</ORGANIZATION> lists Requests Babylon Reports Research Planet Wikimedia Beyond the Web Meet Wikimedians Events Movement affiliates Donate Print export Create a book Download as PDF Printable version In other projects Wikimedia Commons MediaWiki Wikispecies Wikibooks <ORGANIZATION>Wikidata Wikinews Wikipedia</ORGANIZATION> Wikiquote Wikisource Wikiversity Wikivoyage Wiktionary Tools What links here Related changes Special pages Permanent link Page information Wikidata item Cite this page In other languages Qaf r af <ORGANIZATION>Ac</ORGANIZATION> h Afrikaans Akan Alemannisch Aragon s nglisc Asturianu Atikamekw Aymar aru Az rbaycanca Boarisch emait ka <ORGANIZATION>Bikol Central Bislama Bahasa Banjar Bamanankan Brezhoneg Bosanski Catal Chavacano de Zamboanga</ORGANIZATION> M ng d ng ng Cebuano Chamoru Tsets hest hese Corsu N hiyaw win Q r mtatarca e <PERSON>tina Kasz</PERSON> bsczi Cymraeg Dansk Deutsch Thu j <PERSON>Zazaki Dolnoserbski</PERSON> E egbe Emili n e rumagn l English Esperanto Espa ol Eesti Euskara Estreme u <ORGANIZATION>Fulfulde Suomi</ORGANIZATION> V ro Na Vosa Vakaviti F royskt Fran ais Arpetan Nordfriisk Furlan Frysk Gaeilge Gagauz G idhlig <PERSON>Galego Ava</PERSON> e G ychi <PERSON>Konknni Gaelg Hausa Hak</PERSON> k ng <LOCATION>Hawai</LOCATION> i Fiji Hindi Hrvatski <PERSON>Hornjoserbsce Krey</PERSON> l ayisyen <ORGANIZATION>Magyar Otsiherero Interlingua Bahasa Indonesia Interlingue Igbo</ORGANIZATION> I upiak <LOCATION>Ilokano Ido slenska Italiano</LOCATION> inuktitut Patois La lojban Basa Jawa Qaraqalpaqsha Taqbaylit Kab y Kongo G k y Kalaallisut Kanuri Ripoarisch Kurd Kernowek Latina Ladino L tzebuergesch <ORGANIZATION>Luganda Limburgs Ligure Lumbaart Ling la Lietuvi Latga</ORGANIZATION> u Latvie u Basa Banyumasan Malagasy M ori <PERSON>Baso Minangkabau Bahasa Melayu Malti Mirand</PERSON> s Dorerin Naoero N huatl Napulitano Plattd tsch <LOCATION>Nedersaksies Nederlands Norsk</LOCATION> nynorsk <ORGANIZATION>Norsk Novial Nouormand Sesotho</ORGANIZATION> sa <PERSON>Leboa Din bizaad Chi Chewa Occitan Livvinkarjala Oromoo Pangasinan Kapampangan Papiamentu Picard Deitsch</PERSON> P lzisch Norfuk Pitkern Polski Piemont is Portugu s <PERSON>Runa Simi Rumantsch Romani Kirundi Rom</PERSON> n Arm neashti <ORGANIZATION>Tarand ne Kinyarwanda Sardu Sicilianu Scots</ORGANIZATION> Davvis megiella S ng Srpskohrvatski Simple English <LOCATION>Sloven ina Sloven ina Gagana Samoa</LOCATION> ChiShona Soomaaliga Shqip srpski Sranantongo SiSwati <ORGANIZATION>Sesotho Seeltersk Basa Sunda Svenska Kiswahili</ORGANIZATION> l nski Tetun T rkmen e <ORGANIZATION>Tagalog Setswana Lea</ORGANIZATION> faka <LOCATION>Tonga</LOCATION> Tok Pisin T rk e <PERSON>Xitsonga</PERSON> tatar a ChiTumbuka Twi Reo tahiti Uyghurche O zbekcha Tshivenda V neto Veps n kel Ti ng Vi t West Vlams Volap k Walon Winaray Wolof IsiXhosa Yor b <PERSON>Vahcuengh Ze</PERSON> uws B n l m g IsiZulu Edit links This page was last edited on 10 April 2016 at 14 35 Text is available under the Creative Commons Attribution ShareAlike License additional terms may apply See Terms of Use for details Privacy policy About Meta Disclaimers Developers Cookie statement Mobile view image <ORGANIZATION>Wikimedia Foundation</ORGANIZATION> image Powered by <PERSON>MediaWiki</PERSON></ner>
