<ner>NYTimes com no longer supports Internet Explorer 9 or earlier Please upgrade your browser LEARN MORE Sections Home Search Skip to content Skip to navigation View mobile version The <ORGANIZATION>New York Times Books In Vietnam Stars</ORGANIZATION> and Stripes and Innocence Undone Search Subscribe Now Log In 0 Settings Close search Site Search Navigation Search NYTimes com Clear this text input Go Loading See next articles See previous articles Site Navigation Site Mobile Navigation Advertisement Supported by Books In <LOCATION>Vietnam</LOCATION> Stars and Stripes and Innocence Undone Books of The Times By <PERSON>MICHIKO KAKUTANI</PERSON> AUG 31 2007 Continue reading the main story Share This Page Continue reading the main story Photo image <PERSON>Denis Johnson</PERSON> Credit <PERSON>Cindy Johnson Denis Johnson</PERSON> s wildly ambitious new novel Tree of Smoke reads like a whacked out hallucinogenic variation on such whacked out hallucinogenic <LOCATION>Vietnam</LOCATION> classics as <PERSON>Francis Ford Coppola</PERSON> s Apocalypse Now <PERSON>Michael Herr</PERSON> s Dispatches <PERSON>Robert Stone</PERSON> s Dog Soldiers and <PERSON>Stephen Wright</PERSON> s Meditations in Green It features a central character who comes to see himself as a combination of the Quiet American and the Ugly American and another who comes across as a latter day version of <PERSON>Kurtz</PERSON> in <PERSON>Conrad</PERSON> s Heart of Darkness What s amazing is that Mr <PERSON>Johnson</PERSON> somehow manages to take these derivative elements and turn them into something highly original and potent Though Tree of Smoke is hobbled by a plot that starts and stops and lurches wildly about it s a powerful story about the American experience in <LOCATION>Vietnam</LOCATION> with unsettling echoes of the current American experience in <LOCATION>Iraq</LOCATION> It is a story about bad intelligence and military screw ups and people who have lost their way a story like so many of Mr <PERSON>Johnson</PERSON> s earlier novels about Americans in purgatory waiting impatiently even expectantly for the coming apocalypse This has been Mr <PERSON>Johnson</PERSON> s preoccupation throughout his career from early incantatory books like <ORGANIZATION>Angels</ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON>Fiskadoro</PERSON> through later tendentious works like Already Dead Whether the backdrop is a futuristic <LOCATION>United States Fiskadoro Nicaragua</LOCATION> in the 1980s The Stars at Noon or in the case of this latest novel <LOCATION>Vietnam</LOCATION> in the 1960s he has consistently promoted a vision of <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> as a country in the grip of misplaced dreams and outright delusions intent on exporting its madness abroad His cast of characters too is similar from book to book an alarming spectrum of madmen and deadbeats and drifters the lost the damned and the dispossessed all yearning for salvation or release In Tree of <ORGANIZATION>Smoke Skip Sands</ORGANIZATION> initially seems like a very different sort of Johnsonian hero Skip is young na ve and eager to prove himself as a C I A operative He is convinced that the <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> is going to defeat the Communists in <LOCATION>Vietnam</LOCATION> and wants to be there for that victory And he hopes to emulate his larger than life uncle <PERSON>Col Francis Sands</PERSON> a Flying Tiger who escaped from the Japanese during World War II and made a swaggering legend of himself Advertisement Continue reading the main story Most of all <PERSON>Skip</PERSON> believes in the goodness and promise of <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> with boyish innocence and ardor In the Stars and Stripes Mr <PERSON>Johnson</PERSON> writes all the passions of his life coalesced to produce the ache with which he loved the <LOCATION>United States of America</LOCATION> with which he loved the dirty plain honest faces of G I s in the photographs of World War II with which he loved the sheets of rain rippling across the green playing field toward the end of the school year with which he cherished the sense memories of the summers of his childhood Photo image Tree of Smoke by <PERSON>Denis Johnson</PERSON> Credit <PERSON>Lars Klove</PERSON> for The <ORGANIZATION>New York Times Skip</ORGANIZATION> s innocence however is tarnished when he witnesses the agency s brutal assassination of a priest falsely suspected of running guns in the <LOCATION>Philippines</LOCATION> and in <LOCATION>Vietnam</LOCATION> he quickly becomes lost in the wilderness of mirrors created by his fellow intelligence officers He is drawn willy nilly into a complicated plot involving a double agent a Vietcong sympathizer who apparently agrees to carry out a mission for the Americans and finds himself increasingly unable to distinguish between the good guys and the bad guys the earnest and the duplicitous the idealistic and the mercenary Continue reading the main story Advertisement Continue reading the main story As for Skip s mentor the colonel he too loses his way or rather comes to believe that his superiors have lost their way In a secret memo he suggests that the intelligence functions of the agency are being perverted that they are being used to provide rationalizations for policy much the way flawed intelligence was used in the walk up to the <LOCATION>Iraq</LOCATION> war to provide a rationale for invasion Eventually he concocts an elaborate plan to test his hypotheses a plan that will make him the target of some of his own colleagues For that matter the colonel and Skip both learn that they can trust no one least of all those who are supposedly their comrades in arms in the cold war Newsletter Sign Up Continue reading the main story Please verify you re not a robot by clicking the box Invalid email address Please re enter You must select a newsletter to subscribe to Sign Up You agree to receive occasional updates and special offers for The <ORGANIZATION>New York Times</ORGANIZATION> s products and services Thank you for subscribing An error has occurred Please try again later You are already subscribed to this email View all <ORGANIZATION>New York Times</ORGANIZATION> newsletters See Sample Manage Email Preferences Not you Privacy Policy Opt out or contact us anytime Mr <PERSON>Johnson</PERSON> intercuts the stories of Skip and the colonel with those of half a dozen other people caught up in the war There s <PERSON>James Houston</PERSON> a young drifter who has followed his brother into the military and finds himself in the midst of a war with no rules a war in which the heat and the jungle and the confusions of fighting a guerrilla enemy lead to acts of startling brutality and horror There s <PERSON>Kathy Jones</PERSON> a nurse who winds up in <LOCATION>Vietnam</LOCATION> after her husband a missionary is killed and who has a brief seemingly desultory affair with Skip And there s <PERSON>Hao</PERSON> a Vietnamese functionary who dreams of a better life in <LOCATION>Singapore</LOCATION> or the <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> and uses his boyhood friendship with a member of the Vietcong to try to advance his interests with the Americans Mr <PERSON>Johnson</PERSON> s orchestration of these characters intersecting lives is often graceless as his last couple of novels have demonstrated plotting has never been one of his strengths and he has an unfortunate tendency to embroider their adventures with lots of portentous philosophizing about good and evil and religious faith His heat seeking eye for detail and his ability to render those observations in hot tactile prose however immerse us so thoroughly in the fetid world of the war and the even more noxious world of espionage that they effectively erase the book s occasional longueurs Mr <PERSON>Johnson</PERSON> not only succeeds in conjuring the anomalous hallucinatory aura of the Vietnam War as authoritatively as <PERSON>Stephen Wright</PERSON> or <PERSON>Francis Ford Coppola</PERSON> but he also shows its fallout on his characters with harrowing emotional precision He has written a flawed but deeply resonant novel that is bound to become one of the classic works of literature produced by that tragic and uncannily familiar war TREE OF SMOKE By <PERSON>Denis Johnson</PERSON> 614 pages <ORGANIZATION>Farrar Straus amp Giroux</ORGANIZATION> 27 Follow <PERSON>Michiko Kakutani</PERSON> on Twitter michikokakutani A version of this review appears in print on on Page E25 of the <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> edition with the headline In <LOCATION>Vietnam</LOCATION> Stars and Stripes and Innocence Undone Today s Paper Subscribe Continue reading the main story We re interested in your feedback on this page Tell us what you think Books of The Times Book reviews by The <ORGANIZATION>Times</ORGANIZATION> s critics <PERSON>Barbara Ehrenreich</PERSON> Urges Us to Accept Accept the Dying of the Light APR 10 <PERSON>Berenice Abbott</PERSON> Captures a Large and <ORGANIZATION>Star Studded Life APR</ORGANIZATION> 9 Inseparable Finds Pride Indignity and Irony in the <ORGANIZATION>Lives of Siamese Twins</ORGANIZATION> <PERSON>Chang</PERSON> and Eng APR 4 Two Sisters About Teenage Girls Who Left <LOCATION>Norway</LOCATION> to Fight With <ORGANIZATION>ISIS</ORGANIZATION> APR 3 <PERSON>Leslie Jamison</PERSON> s Memoir Finds Its Footing in Sobriety APR 2 See More What s Next Loading Go to Home Page Site Index The <ORGANIZATION>New York Times Site Index Navigation News World U S Politics N Y Business Tech Science Health Sports Education Obituaries Today</ORGANIZATION> s Paper Corrections Opinion Today s Opinion Op Ed Columnists Editorials Op Ed Contributors Letters Sunday Review Video Opinion Arts Today s Arts Art amp Design Books Dance Movies Music N Y <ORGANIZATION>C Events Guide Television Theater Video Arts Living Automobiles Crossword Food Education Fashion amp Style Health Jobs Magazine N Y C Events Guide Real Estate T Magazine Travel Weddings amp Celebrations Listings amp More Reader Center Classifieds Tools amp Services N Y C Events Guide Multimedia</ORGANIZATION> Photography Video NYT Store Times Journeys Subscribe Manage My Account NYTCo Subscribe Subscribe Home Delivery Digital Subscriptions <ORGANIZATION>Crossword Email Newsletters Alerts Gift Subscriptions Group Subscriptions Education Rate Mobile</ORGANIZATION> Applications Replica Edition Site Information Navigation 2018 The <ORGANIZATION>New York Times Company Home</ORGANIZATION> Search Accessibility concerns Email us at accessibility nytimes com We would love to hear from you Contact Us Work With Us Advertise Your Ad Choices Privacy Terms of Service Terms of Sale Site Information Navigation Site Map Help Site Feedback Subscriptions</ner>
