<ner>image boston com image News image your connection to The <ORGANIZATION>Boston Globe</ORGANIZATION> image image image News image A amp E image Business image Sports image Travel image Your Life image Cars image Jobs image Personals image Real estate image image image image image image image image image image image Today s Globe Latest News Local Nation World NECN Education Obituaries Special sections Traffic Weather image image image Home gt News gt <ORGANIZATION>Boston Globe</ORGANIZATION> gt Editorial Opinion gt Op ed image The <ORGANIZATION>Boston Globe</ORGANIZATION> HAROLD BLOOM Dumbing down American readers By <PERSON>Harold Bloom</PERSON> 9 24 2003 THE DECISION to give the National Book Foundation s annual award for distinguished contribution to <PERSON>Stephen King</PERSON> is extraordinary another low in the shocking process of dumbing down our cultural life I ve described <PERSON>King</PERSON> in the past as a writer of penny dreadfuls but perhaps even that is too kind He shares nothing with <PERSON>Edgar Allan Poe</PERSON> What he is is an immensely inadequate writer on a sentence by sentence paragraph by paragraph book by book basis The publishing industry has stooped terribly low to bestow on King a lifetime award that has previously gone to the novelists <PERSON>Saul Bellow</PERSON> and <PERSON>Philip Roth</PERSON> and to playwright <PERSON>Arthur Miller</PERSON> By awarding it to King they recognize nothing but the commercial value of his books which sell in the millions but do little more for humanity than keep the publishing world afloat If this is going to be the criterion in the future then perhaps next year the committee should give its award for distinguished contribution to <PERSON>Danielle Steel</PERSON> and surely the Nobel Prize for literature should go to J K Rowling ADVERTISEMENT What s happening is part of a phenomenon I wrote about a couple of years ago when I was asked to comment on <PERSON>Rowling</PERSON> I went to the <ORGANIZATION>Yale University</ORGANIZATION> bookstore and bought and read a copy of <PERSON>Harry Potter</PERSON> and the Sorcerer s Stone I suffered a great deal in the process The writing was dreadful the book was terrible As I read I noticed that every time a character went for a walk the author wrote instead that the character stretched his legs I began marking on the back of an envelope every time that phrase was repeated I stopped only after I had marked the envelope several dozen times I was incredulous <PERSON>Rowling</PERSON> s mind is so governed by cliches and dead metaphors that she has no other style of writing But when I wrote that in a newspaper I was denounced I was told that children would now read only <PERSON>J K Rowling</PERSON> and I was asked whether that wasn t after all better than reading nothing at all If <PERSON>Rowling</PERSON> was what it took to make them pick up a book wasn t that a good thing It is not <PERSON>Harry Potter</PERSON> will not lead our children on to Kipling s Just So Stories or his Jungle Book It will not lead them to <PERSON>Thurber</PERSON> s Thirteen Clocks or <PERSON>Kenneth Grahame</PERSON> s Wind in the Willows or <PERSON>Lewis Carroll</PERSON> s <PERSON>Alice</PERSON> Later I read a lavish loving review of <PERSON>Harry Potter</PERSON> by the same <PERSON>Stephen King He</PERSON> wrote something to the effect of If these kids are reading <PERSON>Harry Potter</PERSON> at 11 or 12 then when they get older they will go on to read <PERSON>Stephen King</PERSON> And he was quite right He was not being ironic When you read <PERSON>Harry Potter</PERSON> you are in fact trained to read Stephen King Our society and our literature and our culture are being dumbed down and the causes are very complex I m 73 years old In a lifetime of teaching English I ve seen the study of literature debased There s very little authentic study of the humanities remaining My research assistant came to me two years ago saying she d been in a seminar in which the teacher spent two hours saying that <PERSON>Walt Whitman</PERSON> was a racist This isn t even good nonsense It s insufferable I began as a scholar of the romantic poets In the 1950s and early 1960s it was understood that the great English romantic poets were <PERSON>Percy Bysshe Shelley William Wordsworth</PERSON> Lord <PERSON>Byron John Keats William Blake Samuel Taylor Coleridge</PERSON> But today they are <PERSON>Felicia Hemans Charlotte Smith Mary Tighe Laetitia Landon</PERSON> and others who just can t write A fourth rate playwright like <PERSON>Aphra Behn</PERSON> is being taught instead of Shakespeare in many curriculums across the country Recently I spoke at the funeral of my old friend <PERSON>Thomas M Green of Yale</PERSON> perhaps the most distinguished scholar of Renaissance literature of his generation I said I fear that something of great value has ended forever Today there are four living American novelists I know of who are still at work and who deserve our praise <PERSON>Thomas Pynchon</PERSON> is still writing My friend <PERSON>Philip Roth</PERSON> who will now share this distinguished contribution award with <PERSON>Stephen King</PERSON> is a great comedian and would no doubt find something funny to say about it There s <PERSON>Cormac McCarthy</PERSON> whose novel Blood Meridian is worthy of <PERSON>Herman Melville</PERSON> s Moby <PERSON>Dick</PERSON> and <PERSON>Don DeLillo</PERSON> whose Underworld is a great book Instead this year s award goes to King It s a terrible mistake <PERSON>Harold Bloom</PERSON> is a professor at <ORGANIZATION>Yale University</ORGANIZATION> and author of The Western Canon He wrote this column for the <ORGANIZATION>Los Angeles Times Copyright 2003 Globe Newspaper Company</ORGANIZATION> image PRINTER FRIENDLY VERSION image E MAIL TO A FRIEND image TOOLS image image PRINTER FRIENDLY VERSION image E MAIL TO A FRIEND image TOP E MAILED ARTICLES SEARCH GLOBE ARCHIVES image image Globe Archives Today free Yesterday free Past 30 days Last 12 months image Advanced search image image image Sponsored Links feedback help site map advertising globe archives 2003 The <ORGANIZATION>New York Times Company</ORGANIZATION> image image image image image census</ner>
