<ner>The A V Club Deadspin Earther Gizmodo Jalopnik Jezebel Kotaku Lifehacker Splinter The Takeout The Root The <ORGANIZATION>Onion Video Film TV Club Music Games AUX News TV Reviews Reviews Video Film TV Club Music Games AUX News TV Reviews Reviews Interview Harold Bloom</ORGANIZATION> on Blood Meridian image <PERSON>Leonard Pierce</PERSON> 6 15 09 12 00pmFiled to BooksFiled to Books Books Interview 177 Edit Send to Editors Promote Share to Kinja Toggle Conversation tools Go to permalink image <PERSON>Harold Bloom</PERSON> is one of the most towering figures in American literary theory and criticism Currently the <ORGANIZATION>Sterling Professor of the Humanities</ORGANIZATION> at <ORGANIZATION>Yale University Bloom</ORGANIZATION> a fierce defender of the canon and a proponent of aesthetic reading at a time when more politicized approaches hold sway in academia has written dozens of books including important theoretical works like The Anxiety of Influence A Theory of Poetry and A Map of Misreading in the 1970s Later works like Ruin the Sacred Truths and The American Religion The Emergence of the <ORGANIZATION>Post Christian Nation</ORGANIZATION> displayed his wide ranging interests and fascination with the religious experience in <ORGANIZATION>America Bloom</ORGANIZATION> was also one of the first champions of <PERSON>Cormac McCarthy</PERSON> s Blood Meridian Or The Evening Redness In The West the most recent selection in the A <ORGANIZATION>V Club</ORGANIZATION> s Wrapped Up In Books feature He took a few minutes recently to talk about the novel and its place in American literature The A V Club Talk a bit about how you came to read Blood Meridian You apparently had a hard time getting through it the first time <PERSON>Harold Bloom</PERSON> I read it on the recommendation of a friend <PERSON>Gordon Lish</PERSON> a <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> book editor and a specialist in fiction He said that it was a very splendid work but that he was always appalled by the violence of it and I wondered what he meant I think I had read some earlier <PERSON>McCarthy</PERSON> and had mixed feelings about it it seemed to me to be Faulknerian in a way that was not really integrated in a way that made it <PERSON>McCarthy</PERSON> s own It may have been <PERSON>Suttree</PERSON> in fact a book that I haven t read since It was a strong book but you had the feeling at times that it was written by <PERSON>William Faulkner</PERSON> and not by <PERSON>Cormac McCarthy He</PERSON> tends to carry his influences on the surface quite honestly The first time I read Blood Meridian I was so appalled that while I was held I gave up after about 60 pages I don t think I was feeling very well then anyway my health was going through a bad time and it was more than I could take But it intrigued me because there was no question about the quality of the writing which is stunning So I went back a second time and I got I don t remember 140 150 pages and then I think it was the Judge who got me He was beginning to give me nightmares just as he gives the kid nightmares And then the third time it went off like a shot I went straight through it and was exhilarated I said My God This reminds me of <PERSON>Thomas Pynchon</PERSON> at his best or <PERSON>Nathanael West</PERSON> It was the greatest single book since <PERSON>Faulkner</PERSON> s As I Lay Dying In fact I taught it for several years in a class I gave here at <ORGANIZATION>Yale</ORGANIZATION> interestingly enough in a sequence starting with <PERSON>Faulkner</PERSON> s As I Lay Dying moving on to Miss Lonelyhearts then The Crying of Lot 49 and the fourth in the sequence was Blood Meridian I finally wrote something about it and I was contacted by his people at <ORGANIZATION>Random House</ORGANIZATION> they were going to put out a nice cloth bound library version of it and they requested to put what I had to say about it in a book called How To Read And Why in as an introduction and I of course consented Certainly the book holds up I wish that the rest of <PERSON>McCarthy</PERSON> both before and after was that good I think the <ORGANIZATION>Border Trilogy</ORGANIZATION> has its moments especially the first volume All The Pretty Horses but the second The Crossing and third Cities Of The Plain especially the third were disappointments I was not one of the admirers of No Country For Old Men which I found strained and the brutality coming through it all so Nothing really mitigated it The negative protagonist has none of the legitimacy or grandeur that Judge <PERSON>Holden</PERSON> has And The Road I ll have to visit again because it really wore me down that book until the last 40 or 50 pages where the father son bond I felt was conveyed with real beauty and majesty I want to make sure my impressions of it were correct But to have written even one book so authentically strong and allusive and capable of the perpetual reverberation that <ORGANIZATION>Blood Meridian</ORGANIZATION> possesses more than justifies him I don t think <PERSON>McCarthy</PERSON> will ever match it but still He has attained genius with that book Advertisement AVC When you called it the ultimate Western did you mean merely the paramount example of the genre or its final expression HB No I meant the final one It culminates all the aesthetic potential that Western fiction can have I don t think that anyone can hope to improve on it that it essentially closes out the tradition And in the sense that it serves as an extension of the pastoral tradition it provides an interesting and ironic contrast with American Pastoral by my friend <PERSON>Philip Roth</PERSON> AVC The violence in Blood Meridian is uncharacteristic It s not used as a cheap metaphor or a means of catharsis or transformation Advertisement HB Oh no no The violence is the book The Judge is the book and the Judge is short of Moby <PERSON>Dick</PERSON> the most monstrous apparition in all of American literature The Judge is violence incarnate The Judge stands for incessant warfare for its own sake AVC So you think that despite your own initial reaction to it <PERSON>McCarthy</PERSON> is successful in the way he uses violence in the book HB More than successful It s not only the ultimate Western the book is the ultimate dark dramatization of violence Again I don t see anyone surpassing it in that regard Advertisement AVC You placed <ORGANIZATION>Blood Meridian</ORGANIZATION> not only firmly in the Western canon but in your own canon of the American Sublime Have there been any books since that time that you d consider to be part of that canon HB Well we have four living writers in <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> who have in one way or another touched what I would call the sublime They are <PERSON>McCarthy</PERSON> of course with Blood Meridian <PERSON>Philip Roth</PERSON> particularly with two extraordinary novels the very savage Sabbath s Theater and American Pastoral which I mentioned before <PERSON>Don DeLillo</PERSON> s Underworld which is a little long for what it does but nevertheless is the culmination of what <PERSON>Don</PERSON> can do and of course the mysterious figure of Mr <PERSON>Pynchon</PERSON> I don t know what I would choose if I had to select a single work of sublime fiction from the last century it probably would not be something by <PERSON>Roth</PERSON> or <PERSON>McCarthy</PERSON> it would probably be <ORGANIZATION>Mason</ORGANIZATION> amp <PERSON>Dixon</PERSON> if it were a full scale book or if it were a short novel it would probably be The Crying Of Lot 49 <PERSON>Pynchon</PERSON> has the same relation to fiction I think that my friend <PERSON>John Ashbery</PERSON> has to poetry he is beyond compare <ORGANIZATION>AVC Blood Meridian</ORGANIZATION> is a book that s filled with all sorts of religious symbolism and mysticism but it s often difficult to discern its exact attitude towards religion Advertisement HB The citations and references to the work of <PERSON>Jacob B</PERSON> hme who is after all a very specific type of Kabbalistic Gnostic I think you would have to say that they re something of an evasion of the themes in Blood Meridian <PERSON>McCarthy</PERSON> knows exactly what Gnosticism is and he could have made Judge <PERSON>Holden</PERSON> into an explicitly Gnostic figure if he d wanted to He wants to keep Judge <PERSON>Holden</PERSON> completely inexplicable Saying that he is a sort of Gnostic demiurge is too facile for <PERSON>McCarthy</PERSON> s portrayal of him AVC You ve been extremely critical of the politicization of teaching literature HB Critical young man is hardly the word I stand against it like <PERSON>Jeremiah</PERSON> prophesying in <LOCATION>Jerusalem</LOCATION> It has destroyed most of university culture The teaching of high literature now hardly exists in the <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> The academy is in ruins and they ve destroyed themselves Advertisement AVC Do you have a similar resistance to political readings of literature For example do you have a problem with those who have read <ORGANIZATION>Blood Meridian</ORGANIZATION> as a critique of American imperialism HB I don t think it s that at all I think that s too simplistic an understanding of <PERSON>McCarthy</PERSON> When he issued that unforgettable vision of the Apaches advancing into battle against the cutthroat desperadoes who are going to cut them down Who are after all these invincible monsters and in the end all but the Judge will be dead I don t think that the aesthetically minded reader is trying to think of that as a sociological commentary on the degradation of the Apache Nation It s a grand picaresque in its own right I don t think <PERSON>McCarthy</PERSON> was interested at least at that point in his career in moral judgments any more than <PERSON>Melville</PERSON> was involved in moral judgments or <PERSON>Faulkner</PERSON> was involved in moral judgments at least until he got soft later on and produced a beastly book like A Fable The kind of apocalyptic moral judgments made in No Country For Old Men represents I think a sort of falling away on <PERSON>McCarthy</PERSON> s part Blood Meridian is too grand for that bookmark replies You may also like Jezebel Men s Favorite Ages Are 20 21 22 and 23 A Data Dive by the Co Founder of <ORGANIZATION>OKCupid Christian Rudder</ORGANIZATION> 9 20 15 2 15pm The A V Club Mike Judge spills the beans on T <PERSON>J Miller</PERSON> s departure from <LOCATION>Silicon Valley</LOCATION> <PERSON>Danette Chavez</PERSON> 3 07 18 11 57am <LOCATION>Kotaku</LOCATION> The Simpsons Pokes Fun At Documentary That Criticized <PERSON>Apu Gita Jackson</PERSON> Yesterday 10 01am Recent from <PERSON>Leonard Pierce</PERSON> 235 image <PERSON>Miles Davis Miles Davis Leonard Pierce</PERSON> 12 09 10 12 00pm <PERSON>Jennifer Armstrong</PERSON> Why Because We Still Like You <PERSON>Leonard Pierce</PERSON> 12 09 10 12 00am 218 image December 2010 The Best Of 2010 December 2010 The Best Of 2010 <PERSON>Leonard Pierce</PERSON> 12 08 10 12 00am ShareTweet image Kinja is in read only mode We are working to restore service image image</ner>
