<ner>NYTimes com no longer supports Internet Explorer 9 or earlier Please upgrade your browser LEARN MORE Sections Home Search Skip to content Skip to navigation View mobile version The <ORGANIZATION>New York Times Archives</ORGANIZATION> BOOKS OF THE TIMES Seeking Salvation On the <ORGANIZATION>Silver Screen Search Subscribe Now Log In</ORGANIZATION> 0 Settings Close search Site Search Navigation Search NYTimes com Clear this text input Go https nyti ms 297DCQ9 Loading See next articles See previous articles Site Navigation Site Mobile Navigation Advertisement Archives 1996 BOOKS OF THE TIMES Seeking Salvation On the Silver Screen By <PERSON>MICHIKO KAKUTANI</PERSON> Continue reading the main story Share This Page Continue reading the main story image The article as it originally appeared View page in TimesMachine Page 00001 The <ORGANIZATION>New York Times Archives</ORGANIZATION> IN THE BEAUTY OF THE LILIES By <PERSON>John Updike</PERSON> 491 pages <PERSON>Alfred A Knopf</PERSON> 25 95 YEARS ago in one of his glittering essays <PERSON>John Updike</PERSON> wrote of his admiration for novels that give us through the consciousness of characters a geography amplified by history a chunk of the planet Up until now the chunk of planet Mr <PERSON>Updike</PERSON> has chosen to explore himself 20th century <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> as colonized by the middle class has been most knowingly and most intimately chronicled in his Rabbit novels a quartet of books that gave us four decades of American life as seen through the experiences of a high school basketball star turned car salesman <PERSON>Harry Rabbit Angstrom</PERSON> Now in his dazzling new novel In the Beauty of the Lilies Mr <PERSON>Updike</PERSON> takes on an even more daunting project to chart the fortunes of an American family through four generations and some 80 years and in doing so create a portrait of the country from its nervous entry into the 20th century to its stumbling approach to the millennium In the Beauty of the Lilies which takes its clumsy title from a line in The Battle Hymn of the Republic is not only Mr <PERSON>Updike</PERSON> s most ambitious novel to date but arguably his finest a big generous book narrated with Godlike omniscience and authority and populated by a wonderfully vivid cast of dreamers wimps social climbers crackpots and lost souls a book that forces us to reassess the <ORGANIZATION>American Dream</ORGANIZATION> and the crucial role that faith and the longing for faith has played in shaping the national soul Advertisement Continue reading the main story Religion of course has rumbled through the pages of Mr <PERSON>Updike</PERSON> s fiction from the start from books like The Poorhouse Fair and A Month of Sundays through Couples and <PERSON>Roger</PERSON> s Version Most of Mr <PERSON>Updike</PERSON> s heroes feel themselves torn between their spiritual aspirations and their fleshly compulsions between their yearning for redemption and their dark suspicion that no meaning exists Like <PERSON>Henry Bech</PERSON> they worry that they are nothing but a fleck of dust condemned to know it is a fleck of dust Like the witches of Eastwick they see that the outside of things was sunshine and scatter while the inside of everything was death Continue reading the main story Advertisement Continue reading the main story These existential anxieties culminate in the opening pages of The Lilies when the progenitor of Mr <PERSON>Updike</PERSON> s American family the <PERSON>Rev Clarence Arthur Wilmot</PERSON> suffers an acute spiritual crisis It is 1910 and at 2 o clock one fine spring afternoon in <PERSON>Paterson N J Clarence</PERSON> feels the last particles of his faith leave him forever The loss comes as a palpable physical sensation and it leaves <PERSON>Clarence</PERSON> adrift in a universe suddenly rendered empty and devoid of hope A Presbyterian minister by vocation <PERSON>Clarence</PERSON> realizes that his loss of faith will have worldly consequences for his family as well namely the loss of their parish owned house and their social standing in the community In fact employment for a lapsed minister is hard to come by and <PERSON>Clarence</PERSON> soon finds himself going door to door hawking cheap encyclopedias items he regards as vaguely blasphemous products a commercially inspired attempt to play God by creating in print a replica of Creation In his free time <PERSON>Clarence</PERSON> goes to the movies where he watches the world being created anew in newsreels and features and shorts <PERSON>Clarence</PERSON> s youngest son <PERSON>Teddy</PERSON> inherits his sense of defeat his desire to survive this vale of tears with minimal damage Though he suspects that the only way to be an American is to go out into the world and compete he prefers to sit at home collecting innocent things stamps from foreign countries that gave pieces of paper the power to fly around the globe He will eventually become a postman in the small <LOCATION>Delaware</LOCATION> town of <LOCATION>Basingstoke Teddy</LOCATION> is defiant in only one area he cannot forgive God for failing to give his father <PERSON>Clarence</PERSON> a sign some small encouragement that might have enabled him to hold on to his elusive faith The closest Teddy ever expects to come to a religious experience is the blinding realization that he should forsake his flailing efforts to pursue a career in <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> and instead return home and marry his old sweetheart <PERSON>Emily</PERSON> a pretty girl with a clubfoot who shares his sense of diminished expectations It is Teddy and <PERSON>Emily</PERSON> s beautiful daughter <PERSON>Essie</PERSON> who approaches life and faith with supreme self confidence an attitude of entitlement that enables her to glide from experience to experience undamaged by disappointment or fear or ordinary mortal doubt Convinced of her own perfection <PERSON>Essie</PERSON> leaves <LOCATION>Basingstoke</LOCATION> for a modeling career in <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> and from <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> makes the leap to <LOCATION>Hollywood</LOCATION> where she becomes however briefly a screen goddess on a par with Grace Kelly <PERSON>Rita Hayworth</PERSON> and Doris Day She stars in movies with <PERSON>Clark Gable Bing Crosby</PERSON> and <PERSON>William Holden</PERSON> racks up a series of disappointing marriages and in 1959 gives birth to a son named <PERSON>Clark</PERSON> Newsletter Sign Up Continue reading the main story Please verify you re not a robot by clicking the box Invalid email address Please re enter You must select a newsletter to subscribe to Sign Up You agree to receive occasional updates and special offers for The <ORGANIZATION>New York Times</ORGANIZATION> s products and services Thank you for subscribing An error has occurred Please try again later You are already subscribed to this email View all <ORGANIZATION>New York Times</ORGANIZATION> newsletters See Sample Manage Email Preferences Not you Privacy Policy Opt out or contact us anytime For <PERSON>Essie</PERSON> or <ORGANIZATION>Alma</ORGANIZATION> as she has become known in the business God is simply a benign heavenly presence dedicated to fulfilling her wishes For her the <ORGANIZATION>Protestant</ORGANIZATION> work ethic has become simple ambition while faith has devolved into a kind of good luck charm a token of her belief in her own and <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> s manifest destiny Faith does not come so easily to <PERSON>Essie</PERSON> s son <PERSON>Clark</PERSON> though he has inherited her yearning for purpose and her talent for self reinvention After years of drifting vaguely through the movie business <PERSON>Clark</PERSON> winds up in <LOCATION>Colorado</LOCATION> where a pretty young woman named <PERSON>Hannah</PERSON> introduces him to <PERSON>Jesse Smith</PERSON> a <PERSON>David Koresh</PERSON> like cult leader who preaches an apocalyptic doctrine of sin salvation and wrath <PERSON>Clark</PERSON> who is rechristened <PERSON>Esau</PERSON> at the commune doesn t completely buy <PERSON>Jesse</PERSON> s preaching but he s interested in sleeping with <PERSON>Hannah</PERSON> and in participating in something that sets him apart from his famous mother His decision to join <PERSON>Jesse</PERSON> s cult will later make headlines when a bloody <LOCATION>Waco</LOCATION> like showdown with the police ensues Advertisement Continue reading the main story Although Mr <PERSON>Updike</PERSON> credits a huge number of books including Mad Man in <LOCATION>Waco</LOCATION> by <PERSON>Brad Bailey</PERSON> and <PERSON>Bob Darden</PERSON> Inside the Cult by <PERSON>Marc Breault</PERSON> and Martin King The Story of Cinema by <PERSON>David Shipman</PERSON> and Grace by <PERSON>Robert Lacey</PERSON> as source material for his saga of the <PERSON>Wilmots</PERSON> there is nothing the least bit forced or contrived about his use of this information Unlike his last novel <LOCATION>Brazil</LOCATION> 1994 which read like a hastily assembled compendium of undigested material The Lilies possesses the hard diamond radiance of a fully imagined work of art While seamlessly weaving the private travails of his characters into the public tapestry of history Mr <PERSON>Updike</PERSON> has also managed to endow them with a genuine sense of familial history subtly showing us how emotions habits and weaknesses are handed down generation to generation like expensive fragile antiques We see how <PERSON>Essie</PERSON> mistakes her grandfather s sad broken faith for something saintlike and divine and how her son in turn mistakes passion and anger for true belief We see how the <PERSON>Wilmots</PERSON> cranky individualism propels them out of a small town in the <LOCATION>East</LOCATION> into the wide open spaces of the West and how their sense of apartness that floating sensation that there was nowhere in mankind where they comfortably fit leads to achievement pain and grief While the presiding image of Rabbit Redux 1971 was the moonshot in all its hope and glory the informing metaphor of The Lilies is a more ambiguous one the metaphor of the movies which are for Mr <PERSON>Updike</PERSON> s characters a secular substitute for religion promising eternal life on celluloid in place of real redemption narrative order in place of Calvinist predestination In tracing the history of the <PERSON>Wilmot</PERSON> family from <PERSON>Clarence</PERSON> who trades the pulpit for an anonymous seat in a dark theater to <PERSON>Clark</PERSON> who becomes the star in a bloody shootout shown on the evening news Mr <PERSON>Updike</PERSON> has written an important and impressive novel a novel that not only shows how we live today but also how we got there We are continually improving the quality of our text archives Please send feedback error reports and suggestions to archive_feedback nytimes com A version of this review appears in print on January 12 1996 on Page C00001 of the National edition with the headline BOOKS OF THE TIMES Seeking Salvation On the <ORGANIZATION>Silver Screen Today</ORGANIZATION> s Paper Subscribe Continue reading the main story What s Next Loading Go to Home Page Site Index The <ORGANIZATION>New York Times Site Index Navigation News World U S Politics N Y Business Tech Science Health Sports Education Obituaries Today</ORGANIZATION> s Paper Corrections Opinion Today s Opinion Op Ed Columnists Editorials Op Ed Contributors Letters Sunday Review Video Opinion Arts Today s Arts Art amp Design Books Dance Movies Music N Y <ORGANIZATION>C Events Guide Television Theater Video Arts Living Automobiles Crossword Food Education Fashion amp Style Health Jobs Magazine N Y C Events Guide Real Estate T Magazine Travel Weddings amp Celebrations Listings amp More Reader Center Classifieds Tools amp Services N Y C Events Guide Multimedia</ORGANIZATION> Photography Video NYT Store Times Journeys Subscribe Manage My Account NYTCo Subscribe Subscribe Home Delivery Digital Subscriptions <ORGANIZATION>Crossword Email Newsletters Alerts Gift Subscriptions Group Subscriptions Education Rate Mobile</ORGANIZATION> Applications Replica Edition Site Information Navigation 2018 The <ORGANIZATION>New York Times Company Home</ORGANIZATION> Search Accessibility concerns Email us at accessibility nytimes com We would love to hear from you Contact Us Work With Us Advertise Your Ad Choices Privacy Terms of Service Terms of Sale Site Information Navigation Site Map Help Site Feedback Subscriptions</ner>
