<ner>Skip to main content We use cookies to distinguish you from other users and to provide you with a better experience on our websites Close this message to accept cookies or find out how to manage your cookie settings image Close cookie message Cancel Log in image Home Only search content I have access to Home Log in Register Browse subjects What we publish <ORGANIZATION>Services About Cambridge Core Cart Institution</ORGANIZATION> login Register Log in Cart lt Back to search results Home Series The <ORGANIZATION>Cambridge History of American Literature The Cambridge History of American Literature Download</ORGANIZATION> list of titles Other actions Download list of titles About The <ORGANIZATION>Cambridge History of American Literature Visit The Cambridge History of American Literature</ORGANIZATION> addresses the broad spectrum of new and established directions in all branches of American writing and will include the work of scholars and critics who have shaped and who continue to shape what has become a major area of literary scholarship These authors who speak for the continuities as well as the disruptions sustained between generations of scholarship represent the achievements of the last half century in Americanist literary criticism Generously proportioned narratives allow at once for a broader vision and more magisterial sweep of American literary history than has been possible previously and while the voice of traditional criticism is implicit in these narratives it joins forces with the diversity of interests that characterise contemporary literary studies <ORGANIZATION>General Editors Sacvan Bercovitch Harvard University Refine</ORGANIZATION> search Refine search Content type Chapters 272 Books 8 Publication date Over 3 years 8 Subject Show more Area Studies 8 History 8 Literature 8 Tags Journals Show more <ORGANIZATION>Publishers Show</ORGANIZATION> more <ORGANIZATION>Cambridge University Press</ORGANIZATION> 8 Series Show more The Cambridge History of American Literature 8 Collections Show more <ORGANIZATION>Cambridge Histories</ORGANIZATION> 8 <ORGANIZATION>Cambridge Histories Literature</ORGANIZATION> 8 Actions for selected content Select all Deselect all View selected items Save to my bookmarks Export citations Download PDF zip Send to Kindle Send to Dropbox Send to <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION> Drive Send content to To send content items to your account please confirm that you agree to abide by our usage policies If this is the first time you use this feature you will be asked to authorise <ORGANIZATION>Cambridge Core</ORGANIZATION> to connect with your account Find out more about sending content to To send content items to your Kindle first ensure no reply cambridge org is added to your Approved Personal Document E mail List under your Personal Document Settings on the Manage Your Content and Devices page of your <ORGANIZATION>Amazon</ORGANIZATION> account Then enter the name part of your Kindle email address below Find out more about sending to your Kindle Note you can select to send to either the free kindle com or kindle com variations free kindle com emails are free but can only be sent to your device when it is connected to wi fi kindle com emails can be delivered even when you are not connected to wi fi but note that service fees apply Find out more about the Kindle Personal Document Service Please be advised that item s you selected are not available You are about to send Your Kindle email address Please provide your Kindle email free kindle com kindle com service fees apply By using this service you agree that you will only keep articles for personal use and will not openly distribute them via <ORGANIZATION>Dropbox Google</ORGANIZATION> Drive or other file sharing services Please confirm that you accept the terms of use Cancel Send Save Search You can save your searches here and later view and run them again in My saved searches Search Title required Please provide a title maximum of 40 characters Cancel 8 results in The Cambridge History of American Literature Relevance Title Sorted by Date Save search image The <ORGANIZATION>Cambridge History of American Literature The Cambridge History of American Literature Volume</ORGANIZATION> 3 Prose writing 1860 1920 Edited by <PERSON>Sacvan Bercovitch</PERSON> https doi org 10 1017 CHOL9780521301077 Published online 28 March 2008 Print publication 15 September 2005 Book Get access Buy the print book Check if you have access via personal or institutional login Log in Register Recommend to librarian Export Citation View description This volume covers a pivotal era in the formation of American identity Four leading scholars connect the literature with the massive historical changes then underway <PERSON>Richard Brodhead</PERSON> describes the foundation of a permanent literary culture in <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> <PERSON>Nancy Bentley</PERSON> locates the origins of nineteenth century Realism in an elite culture s responses to an emergent mass culture embracing high literature writers like <PERSON>William Dean Howells</PERSON> and <PERSON>Henry James</PERSON> as well as a wide spectrum of cultural outsiders African Americans women and Native Americans <PERSON>Walter Benn Michaels</PERSON> emphasizes the critical role that turn of the century fiction played in the re evaluation of the individual at the advent of modern bureaucracy <PERSON>Susan L Mizruchi</PERSON> analyzes the literary responses to a new national heterogeneity that helped shape the multicultural future of modern <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> Together these narratives constitute the richest most detailed account to date of American literature and culture between 1860 and 1920 image The <ORGANIZATION>Cambridge History of American Literature The Cambridge History of American Literature Volume</ORGANIZATION> 4 Nineteenth Century Poetry 1800 1910 Edited by <PERSON>Sacvan Bercovitch</PERSON> https doi org 10 1017 CHOL9780521301084 Published online 28 March 2008 Print publication 04 November 2004 Book Get access Buy the print book Check if you have access via personal or institutional login Log in Register Recommend to librarian Export Citation View description This is the first complete narrative history of nineteenth century American poetry <PERSON>Barbara Packer</PERSON> explores the neoclassical and satiric forms mastered by the early Federalist poets the creative reaches of once celebrated and still compelling poets like <PERSON>Longfellow</PERSON> and <LOCATION>Whittier</LOCATION> the distinctive lyric forms developed by <PERSON>Emerson</PERSON> and the Transcendentalists <PERSON>Shira Wolosky</PERSON> provides a new perspective on the achievement of female poets of the period as well as a close appreciation of African American poets including the collective folk authors of the Negro spirituals She also illuminates the major works of the period from <PERSON>Poe</PERSON> through <LOCATION>Melville</LOCATION> and <PERSON>Crane</PERSON> to <PERSON>Whitman</PERSON> and <PERSON>Dickinson</PERSON> The authors of this volume discuss this extraordinary literary achievement both in formal terms and in its sustained engagement with changing social and cultural conditions In doing so they recover and elucidate American poetry of the nineteenth century for our twenty first century pleasure profit and renewed study image The Cambridge History of American Literature The Cambridge History of American Literature Volume 5 Poetry and Criticism 1900 1950 Edited by <PERSON>Sacvan Bercovitch</PERSON> https doi org 10 1017 CHOL9780521301091 Published online 28 March 2008 Print publication 16 January 2003 Book Get access Buy the print book Check if you have access via personal or institutional login Log in Register Recommend to librarian Export Citation View description This is the fullest account to date of American poetry and literary criticism in the Modernist period <PERSON>Andrew Dubois</PERSON> and <PERSON>Frank Lentricchia</PERSON> examine the work of <PERSON>Robert Frost</PERSON> T S <PERSON>Eliot Ezra Pound</PERSON> and <PERSON>Wallace Stevens</PERSON> They show how the conditions of literary production in a democratic market driven society forced the boldest of the Modernists to try to reconcile their need for commercial remuneration with their knowledge that their commitment to high art might never pay <PERSON>Irene Ramalho Santos</PERSON> broadens the scope of the poetic scene through attention to a wide diversity of writers with special emphasis on writers including <PERSON>Gertrude Stein Marianne Moore</PERSON> and <PERSON>Langston Hughes William Cain</PERSON> traces both the rise of an internationalist academic aesthetics and the process by which the study of a distinctive national literature was instituted Considered together these three narratives convey the astonishing Modernist poetic achievement in its full cultural institutional and aesthetic complexity image The <ORGANIZATION>Cambridge History of American Literature The Cambridge History of American Literature Volume</ORGANIZATION> 6 Prose Writing 1910 1950 Edited by <PERSON>Sacvan Bercovitch</PERSON> https doi org 10 1017 CHOL9780521497312 Published online 28 March 2008 Print publication 28 November 2002 Book Get access Buy the print book Check if you have access via personal or institutional login Log in Register Recommend to librarian Export Citation View description Volume 6 of The <ORGANIZATION>Cambridge History of American Literature</ORGANIZATION> explores the emergence and flowering of modernism in the <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> <PERSON>David Minter</PERSON> provides a cultural history of the American novel from the lyric years to World War I through post World War I disillusionment to the consolidation of the Left in response to the mire of the Great Depression <PERSON>Rafia Zafar</PERSON> tells the story of the <ORGANIZATION>Harlem Renaissance</ORGANIZATION> detailing the artistic accomplishments of such diverse figures as Zora <PERSON>Neal Hurston</PERSON> W E B <PERSON>Du Bois Langston Hughes Nella Larsen</PERSON> and <PERSON>Richard Wright Werner Sollors</PERSON> examines canonical texts as well as popular magazines and hitherto unknown immigrant writing from the period Taken together these narratives cover the entire range of literary prose written in the first half of the twentieth century offering a model of literary history for our times focusing as they do on the intricate interplay between text and context image The <ORGANIZATION>Cambridge History of American Literature The Cambridge History of American Literature Volume</ORGANIZATION> 7 Prose Writing 1940 1990 Edited by <PERSON>Sacvan Bercovitch</PERSON> https doi org 10 1017 CHOL9780521497329 Published online 28 March 2008 Print publication 28 June 1999 Book Get access Buy the print book Check if you have access via personal or institutional login Log in Register Recommend to librarian Export Citation View description Volume VII of the <ORGANIZATION>Cambridge History of American Literature</ORGANIZATION> examines a broad range of American literature of the past half century revealing complex relations to changes in society <PERSON>Christopher Bigsby</PERSON> discusses American dramatists from <PERSON>Tennessee Williams</PERSON> to August <PERSON>Wilson</PERSON> showing how innovations in theatre anticipated a world of emerging countercultures and provided <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> with an alternative view of contemporary life <PERSON>Morris Dickstein</PERSON> describes the condition of rebellion in fiction from 1940 to 1970 linking writers as diverse as <PERSON>James Baldwin</PERSON> and <PERSON>John Updike John Burt</PERSON> examines writers of the American South describing the tensions between modernization and continued entanglements with the past <PERSON>Wendy Steiner</PERSON> examines the postmodern fictions since 1970 and shows how the questioning of artistic assumptions has broadened the canon of American literature Finally <PERSON>Cyrus Patell</PERSON> highlights the voices of Native American Asian American Chicano gay and lesbian writers often marginalized but here discussed within and against a broad set of national traditions image The Cambridge History of American Literature The Cambridge History of American Literature Volume 8 Poetry and Criticism 1940 1995 Edited by <PERSON>Sacvan Bercovitch</PERSON> https doi org 10 1017 CHOL9780521497336 Published online 28 March 2008 Print publication 29 March 1996 Book Get access Buy the print book Check if you have access via personal or institutional login Log in Register Recommend to librarian Export Citation View description The Cambridge History of American Literature addresses the broad spectrum of new and established directions in all branches of American writing and includes the work of scholars and critics who have shaped and who continue to shape what has become a major area of literary scholarship The authors span three decades of achievement in Americanist literary criticism thereby speaking for the continuities as well as the disruptions sustained between generations of scholarship Generously proportioned narratives permit a broader vision of American literary history than has previously been possible allowing the implicit voice of traditional criticism to join forces with the diversity of interests that characterise contemporary literary studies Volume VIII concerned with works of poetry and criticism written between 1940 and the present brings together two different sets of materials and narrative forms the aesthetic and the institutional Discarding the traditional synoptic overview of major figures von <PERSON>Hallberg Graff</PERSON> and Carton settle in favour of a history from the inside a history of interstices and relations equal to the task of considering the contexts of art power and criticism in which it is set image The Cambridge History of American Literature The <ORGANIZATION>Cambridge History of American Literature Volume</ORGANIZATION> 2 Prose Writing 1820 1865 Edited by <PERSON>Sacvan Bercovitch</PERSON> https doi org 10 1017 CHOL9780521301060 Published online 28 March 2008 Print publication 27 January 1995 Book Get access Buy the print book Check if you have access via personal or institutional login Log in Register Recommend to librarian Export Citation View description This is the fullest and richest account of the American Renaissance available in any literary history The narratives in this volume made for a four fold perspective on literature social cultural intellectual and aesthetic <PERSON>Michael D Bell</PERSON> describes the social conditions of the literary vocation that shaped the growth of a professional literature in the <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> <PERSON>Eric Sundquist</PERSON> draws upon broad cultural patterns his account of the writings of exploration slavery and the frontier is an interweaving of disparate voices outlooks and traditions <PERSON>Barbara L Packer</PERSON> s sources come largely from intellectual history the theological and philosophical controversies that prepared the way for transcendentalism <PERSON>Jonathan Arac</PERSON> s categories are formalist he sees the development of antebellum fiction as a dialectic of prose genres the emergence of a literary mode out of the clash of national local and personal forms Together these four narratives constitute a basic reassessment of American prose writing between 1820 and 1865 It is an achievement that will remain authoritative for our time and that will set new directions for coming decades in American literary scholarship image The <ORGANIZATION>Cambridge History of American Literature The Cambridge History of American Literature Volume</ORGANIZATION> 1 1590 1820 Edited by <PERSON>Sacvan Bercovitch</PERSON> https doi org 10 1017 CHOL9780521301053 Published online 28 March 2008 Print publication 25 February 1994 Book Get access Buy the print book Check if you have access via personal or institutional login Log in Register Recommend to librarian Export Citation View description Volume I of The <ORGANIZATION>Cambridge History of American Literature</ORGANIZATION> was originally published in 1997 and covers the colonial and early national periods and discusses the work of a diverse assemblage of authors from Renaissance explorers and Puritan theocrats to Revolutionary pamphleteers and poets and novelists of the new republic Addressing those characteristics that render the texts distinctively American while placing the literature in an international perspective the contributors offer a compelling new evaluation of both the literary importance of early American history and the historical value of early American literature image Recommend this Email your librarian or administrator to recommend adding this to your organisation s collection Your name Please enter your name Your email address Please enter a valid email address Who would you like to send this to Your administrator s email You can enter one or more administrator email addresses Please enter a valid email address Email already added Optional message CAPTCHA Skip to the audio challenge Cancel Send Librarians Authors Publishing partners Agents Corporates Additional Information Accessibility Our blog News Contact and help <ORGANIZATION>Cambridge Core</ORGANIZATION> legal notices Feedback Sitemap Join us online <ORGANIZATION>Legal Information image Cambridge University Press Rights</ORGANIZATION> amp Permissions Copyright Privacy Policy Terms of use <ORGANIZATION>Cookies Policy Cambridge University Press</ORGANIZATION> 2018 Back to top <ORGANIZATION>Cambridge University Press</ORGANIZATION> 2018 Back to top Cancel Confirm</ner>
