<ner>NYTimes com no longer supports Internet Explorer 9 or earlier Please upgrade your browser LEARN MORE Sections Home Search Skip to content Skip to navigation View mobile version The <ORGANIZATION>New York Times Sunday Book Review Peace</ORGANIZATION> and War Search Subscribe Now Log In 0 Settings Close search Site Search Navigation Search NYTimes com Clear this text input Go Loading See next articles See previous articles Site Navigation Site Mobile Navigation Advertisement Supported by Sunday Book Review Peace and War By <PERSON>SAM TANENHAUSAUG</PERSON> 19 2010 Continue reading the main story Share This Page Continue reading the main story <PERSON>Jonathan Franzen</PERSON> s new novel Freedom like his previous one The Corrections is a masterpiece of American fiction The two books have much in common Once again <PERSON>Franzen</PERSON> has fashioned a capacious but intricately ordered narrative that in its majestic sweep seems to gather up every fresh datum of our shared millennial life <PERSON>Franzen</PERSON> knows that college freshmen are today called first years like tender shoots in an overplanted garden that a high minded mom however ruthless in her judgments of her neighbors ethical lapses will condemn them with no epithet harsher than weird that reckless drivers who barrel across lanes are almost always youngish men for whom the use of blinkers was apparently an affront to their masculinity These are not gratuitous observations They grow organically from the themes that animate Freedom beginning with the title a word that has been elevated throughout American history to near theological status and has been twinned for most of that same history with the secularizing impulses of power That twinning is where the trouble begins As each of us seeks to assert his personal liberties a phrase <PERSON>Franzen</PERSON> uses with full command of its ideological implications we helplessly collide with others in equal pursuit of their sacred freedoms which more often than not seem to threaten our own It is no surprise then that the personality susceptible to the dream of limitless freedom is a personality also prone should the dream ever sour to misanthropy and rage as <PERSON>Franzen</PERSON> remarks And the dream will always sour for it is seldom enough simply to follow one s creed others must embrace it too They alone can validate it The dream power ratio is lived out most acutely most oppressively but also most variously and dynamically within the family since its members orbit one another at the closest possible range The family romance is as old as the English language novel itself indeed is ontologically inseparable from it But the family as microcosm or micro history has become <PERSON>Franzen</PERSON> s particular subject as it is no one else s today Advertisement Continue reading the main story The Corrections saturated in the socio cultural atmosphere of the 1990s described the hopeful corrections improvised by the three lost <PERSON>Lambert</PERSON> siblings adults manqu s lured to the voluptuary capitals of the <LOCATION>Eastern Seaboard</LOCATION> escaping the Depression ethic of their Midwestern parents who continue to loom over their lives disapproving gods though themselves weakened by senescence and its attendant ills Locked together in obligation and duty assailed by guilt and love the <ORGANIZATION>Lamberts</ORGANIZATION> thrash against the cycle of needs to forgive to explain to solve the riddle of unacknowledged hurts buried under thick layers of half repressed memory Continue reading the main story Advertisement Continue reading the main story In lesser hands this might have devolved into clich Also the timing looked ominous Published a week before 9 11 <PERSON>Franzen</PERSON> s novel set against a panorama of 90s excesses promiscuous sex and rampant drug use trendy <LOCATION>East Coast</LOCATION> restaurants high tech gadgetry all outgrowths of the rambunctious American economy might have seemed fatally out of step with the somber new mood Instead The Corrections towered out of the rubble at once a monument to a world destroyed and a beacon lighting the way for a new kind of novel that might break the suffocating grip of postmodernism whose most adept practitioners were busily creating as <PERSON>James Wood</PERSON> objected at the time curiously arrested books that know a thousand different things the recipe for the best Indonesian fish curry the sonics of the trombone the drug market in <LOCATION>Detroit</LOCATION> the history of strip cartoons but do not know a single human being Photo image <PERSON>Jonathan Franzen</PERSON> Credit Illustration by <PERSON>Joe Ciardiello</PERSON> The Corrections did not so much repudiate all this as surgically correct it <PERSON>Franzen</PERSON> cracked open the opaque shell of postmodernism tweezed out its tangled circuitry and inserted in its place the warm beating heart of an authentic humanism His fictional canvas teemed with information about equity finance railroad engineering currency manipulation in <LOCATION>Eastern Europe</LOCATION> the neurochemistry of clinical depression But the data flowed through the arteries of narrative just as it had done in the novels of <PERSON>Dickens</PERSON> and <PERSON>Tolstoy Bellow</PERSON> and <PERSON>Mann</PERSON> Like those giants <PERSON>Franzen</PERSON> attended to the quiet drama of the interior life and also recorded its fraught transactions with the public world Even as his contemporaries had diminished the place of the single human being <PERSON>Franzen</PERSON> miraculously had enlarged it Freedom is a still richer and deeper work less glittering on its surface but more confident in its method This time the social history has been pushed forward from the <PERSON>Clinton</PERSON> to the <PERSON>Bush</PERSON> years and the generational clock has been wound forward too There is again a nuclear family though the hopeful aspirants are not children but parents They are the Berglunds young pioneers who renovate a Victorian in <LOCATION>Ramsey Hill</LOCATION> a neighborhood of decayed mansions in St <PERSON>Paul Franzen</PERSON> assuredly knows that F <PERSON>Scott Fitzgerald</PERSON> grew up there on Summit Avenue the street is mentioned in the opening paragraph and then float upward on drafts of unassailable virtue <PERSON>Patty</PERSON> is a sunny carrier of sociological pollen an affable bee buzzing at the back door with a plate of cookies or a card or some lilies of the valleys in a little thrift store vase that she told you not to bother returning her husband <PERSON>Walter</PERSON> is a lawyer of such adamant decency that his employer 3M has parked him in outreach and philanthropy a corporate cul de sac where niceness was an asset and where commuting by bicycle each day he nurtures his commitment to the environmentalist causes he will eventually pursue with messianic and mis begotten fervor To their envious neighbors a step behind the golden couple there had always been something not quite right about the Berglunds They are the super guilty sort of liberals who needed to forgive every body so their own good fortune could be forgiven who lacked the courage of their privilege These heckling strophes drip with spite but spite is often the vehicle of premonitory truth The Berglunds really are headed for disaster though not because there s something wrong with them They are after all fully the thing that was just starting to happen to the rest of the street and much of <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> too They resemble any number of well meaning couples for whom the home has become a citadel of aspirational self regard and family life a sequence of ennobling rites each act of overparenting wreathed in civic import the issues involving cloth versus disposable diapers or the political rectitude of the Boy Scouts or the imperative to recycle batteries and the long siege of the day heroically capped by Goodnight Moon and a self congratulatory glass of zinfandel <PERSON>Franzen</PERSON> grasps that the central paradox of modern American liberalism inheres not in its doctrines but in the unstated presumptions that govern its daily habits Liberals no less than conservatives and for that matter revolutionaries and reactionaries in other words all of us believe some modes of existence are superior to others But only the liberal committed to a vision of harmonious communal pluralism is unsettled by this truth This is why a <LOCATION>Ramsey Hill</LOCATION> pioneer like <PERSON>Patty Berglund</PERSON> will suffer torments of indecision when thinking how best to respond when a poor person of color accused you of destroying her neighborhood Advertisement Continue reading the main story But in an inspired touch <PERSON>Patty</PERSON> is a former All American basketball player and her competitive drive overcomes her inhibitions when the adversary is plainly her inferior for instance the loutish next door neighbor in a <ORGANIZATION>Vikings</ORGANIZATION> jersey with his work boots unlaced and a beer can in his fist who noisily molests his backyard trees with a chainsaw clearing space for a vinyl sided boat shed that disfigures the collective efforts of urban renovation In retaliation <PERSON>Patty</PERSON> slashes the snow tires on the villain s pickup truck and then goes door to door like a petitioner to justify the vandalism she will not own up to The reckoning begins at home Just as the complacent upright parents in <PERSON>Philip Roth</PERSON> s American Pastoral see their world capsized by their own children who become militant leftists so the Berglunds inadvertently have bred a native rebel their son <PERSON>Joey</PERSON> Bright handsome personable preternaturally adept at getting his way all thanks to his doting mother he defies her by moving next door to live with the enemy the disheveled right wing household where the chainsaw tree murderer cohabits with a blowzy single mother and her blameless teenage daughter who worships <PERSON>Joey</PERSON> and showers love on <PERSON>Patty</PERSON> or would if only <PERSON>Patty</PERSON> didn t coldly rebuff her Photo image Credit Illustration by <PERSON>Rodrigo Corra</PERSON> This idyll related with brilliant economy establishes the themes explored over the course of a narrative that moves at once backward forward inward and outward with hypnotic force and with none of the literary flourishes that faintly marred The Corrections The Berglunds introduced as caricatures gradually assume the gravity of fully formed people not rounded characters in the awful phrase but misshapen and lopsided like actual humans And as it happens they are willfully self invented in the classic American vein <PERSON>Walter</PERSON> from rural <LOCATION>Minnesota</LOCATION> the small town son of an angry drunk has made himself into a model of self sacrifice and self discipline but remains captive to the bludgeoning daily misery and grievance that depressive male Berglunds evidently needed to lend meaning and substance to their lives <PERSON>Patty</PERSON> by means of the novel s most ingenious device a third person autobiography secretly written at her therapist s suggestion describes herself as the self exiled daughter of <LOCATION>Westchester County</LOCATION> do gooders her mother a professional Democrat immersed in state politics her father a lawyer with family money who is a hero to his many pro bono clients most of them black or Hispanic or otherwise ethnic Newsletter Sign Up Continue reading the main story Please verify you re not a robot by clicking the box Invalid email address Please re enter You must select a newsletter to subscribe to Sign Up You agree to receive occasional updates and special offers for The <ORGANIZATION>New York Times</ORGANIZATION> s products and services Thank you for subscribing An error has occurred Please try again later You are already subscribed to this email View all <ORGANIZATION>New York Times</ORGANIZATION> newsletters See Sample Manage Email Preferences Not you Privacy Policy Opt out or contact us anytime <PERSON>Patty</PERSON> s robust athleticism violates the family creed I don t see the fun in defeating a person just for the sake of defeating them her mother complains after watching <PERSON>Patty</PERSON> chase down a timid runner on the softball basepath Wouldn t it be much more fun to all work together to cooperatively build something And yet when <PERSON>Patty</PERSON> is date raped her parents solicitude extends to the culprit the son of wealthy political activists while they are merely embarrassed by their daughter s physical and psychic distress Assaultive sex reverberates through Freedom and why not Sex is the most insistent of the personal liberties and for <PERSON>Franzen</PERSON> the most equalizing One is at a loss to think of another male American writer so at ease with that is so genuinely curious about the economy of female desire the pull and tug of attraction and revulsion the self canceling wants There are three intersecting love triangles in Freedom The pivotal one involves <PERSON>Walter</PERSON> s college roommate <PERSON>Richard Katz</PERSON> an outsize rock musician with an ominous resemblance to <PERSON>Muammar el Qaddafi</PERSON> to whom <PERSON>Patty</PERSON> like any number of other women is attracted even as <PERSON>Katz</PERSON> saturnine and sarcastic is tightly bonded for some deep chemical reason to the almost virginally earnest <PERSON>Walter</PERSON> The many vivid scenes in Freedom include one in the Berglunds lakeside cottage in northern <LOCATION>Minnesota</LOCATION> where <PERSON>Patty</PERSON> now married and <PERSON>Richard</PERSON> resolutely single circle each other like matched predators It is <PERSON>Patty</PERSON> who exults more fully in the pure exhilaration of appetite though she has been reading War and Peace a touchstone for Freedom and has just finished the pages in which <PERSON>Natasha Rostov</PERSON> who was obviously meant for the goofy and good <PERSON>Pierre</PERSON> falls in love with his great cool friend <PERSON>Prince Andrei Patty</PERSON> had not seen this coming she records in her secret memoir <PERSON>Pierre</PERSON> s loss unfolded as she read it like a catastrophe in slow motion Yet she will heedlessly plunge into the same error This is <PERSON>Franzen</PERSON> s self mocking acknowledgment that not even the greatest literature can save us from ourselves because nothing finally can override the imperative to be free This seemed to her in any case the first time she d properly had sex Yet soon after she startles her lover by asking Do you think it s possible you re homosexual The reasoning is axiomatic I m sure you d get tired of me very soon You d see me naked when I m 45 and you d be thinking Hmm Do I still want this I don t think so Whereas <PERSON>Walter</PERSON> you never have to get tired of because you don t feel like kissing him You can just be close to him forever Sexual freedom for women no less than men the default gender to borrow a term from <PERSON>Franzen</PERSON> s second novel Strong Motion is yet another form of entrapment Photo image Credit Illustration by <PERSON>Rodrigo Corra</PERSON> Thus does <PERSON>Franzen</PERSON> wring multiple meanings from his theme particularly once the Berglunds story merges with the encompassing history he tells much of it set in <LOCATION>Washington</LOCATION> where the <LOCATION>Berglunds</LOCATION> move after <PERSON>Walter</PERSON> gets a lucrative job with a nature conservancy It comes with spacious living quarters in a <LOCATION>Georgetown</LOCATION> mansion with daffodils and jonquils in the backyard a fresh opportunity for the Berglunds after the disappointments in <LOCATION>St Paul</LOCATION> to indulge their excellent urban gentry taste Advertisement Continue reading the main story It is now 2004 the peak moment of the <PERSON>Bush</PERSON> phantasmagoria when it was possible to think of <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> as still a rich and relatively young country and of the <LOCATION>Iraq</LOCATION> adventure as an odd sort of war in which within a rounding error the only casualties were on the other side There is no mistaking <PERSON>Franzen</PERSON> s own view of these matters even without the evidence of his journalism from this period including Inauguration Day 2001 a report he wrote for The New Yorker on the bus trip he took to <LOCATION>Washington</LOCATION> with a group of protesting young socialists Freedom abounds in journalistic touches some of them slapdash most obviously when <PERSON>Franzen</PERSON> revisits quarrels over the <PERSON>Bush Cheney</PERSON> venture in <LOCATION>Iraq</LOCATION> and the sinister role of <ORGANIZATION>Halliburton</ORGANIZATION> whose former C E O was now running the nation Yet <PERSON>Franzen</PERSON> equipped with the novelist s investigatory gene knows that every man has his reasons If his wicked portrait of a neoconservative sage steeped in dime store <PERSON>Leo Strauss</PERSON> who dazzles <PERSON>Joey</PERSON> at a dinner party with gnomic mentions of the philosopher flirts with burlesque <PERSON>Franzen</PERSON> has nonetheless caught the tone of those <PERSON>Bush</PERSON> administration auxiliaries who fluently made the case for the <LOCATION>Iraq</LOCATION> cakewalk and as <PERSON>Franzen</PERSON> writes referred to members of the president s cabinet by their first names explaining how we had been leaning on the president to exploit this unique historical moment to resolve an intractable geopolitical deadlock and radically expand the sphere of freedom <PERSON>Franzen</PERSON> is best always when he returns to the Berglunds Their uneasy peace roiled by strife dating back to <PERSON>Joey</PERSON> s rebellion feels increasingly warlike as they too breathe the fanatical air that has toxically invaded the land <PERSON>Walter</PERSON> greener than <ORGANIZATION>Greenpeace</ORGANIZATION> strangely colludes with a superrich Texan to despoil a <LOCATION>West Virginia</LOCATION> mountaintop though it means uprooting 200 local families most of them very poor all to create a sanctuary for a species of warbler not even on the federal endangered list The scenes set in <LOCATION>West Virginia</LOCATION> and <PERSON>Walter</PERSON> s clashes with hard edged locals the proud embittered descendants of <PERSON>Jefferson</PERSON> s yeoman farmers clinging tenaciously to their wasteland the scabby rock littered pastures the spindly canopies of young second growth the gouged hillsides and mining damaged streams the spavined barns and paintless houses the trailer homes hip deep in plastic and metallic trash the torn up dirt tracks leading nowhere bristle with conviction Meanwhile <PERSON>Patty</PERSON> is reduced to a parody of the Beltway wife and finds solace at the gym where when not toning she holds down a desk job mainly to escape the presence of <PERSON>Walter</PERSON> s assistant an adoring and nubile Bengali American And <PERSON>Joey</PERSON> now a Young Republican paid 8 000 a month to concoct fraudulent reports for something called Restore Iraqi Secular Enterprise Now will soon get involved in a boondoggle involving the transshipment of corroded tank parts from <LOCATION>Paraguay</LOCATION> to <LOCATION>Iraq</LOCATION> His motives aren t purely mercenary he also yearns to impress the Straussian s luscious daughter a materialistic tease captured by <PERSON>Franzen</PERSON> in all her narcissism She gave <PERSON>Joey</PERSON> a once over head to toe the way a person might confirm that a product she d ordered had arrived in acceptable condition and then removed her hand luggage from the seat beside her and a little reluctantly it seemed pulled the iPod wires from her ears The magic is in a little reluctantly one sees the fleeting look of displeasure the slow tug on the wires rather remembers it from similar images stored in one s mind and awaiting release There are numberless such moments in Freedom crystalline instances of precise notation shaped by imaginative sympathy <PERSON>Franzen</PERSON> s world historical preoccupations also shape though less delicately his big account of the home front the seething national peace that counter poises the foreign war Himself a confirmed and well informed environmentalist <PERSON>Franzen</PERSON> gives full voice to <PERSON>Walter</PERSON> s increasingly extreme preachments on the subjects of overpopulation and endangered species WE ARE A CANCER ON THE PLANET he declares at one point in a rant that goes viral on the Internet as his dream sours into a nightmare vision of a land in which the winners who own the future trample over the dead and dying and forgotten the endangered species of the world the nonadaptive The apocalpyse when it comes clears the way for a postlude set in <LOCATION>Minnesota</LOCATION> that is as haunting as anything in recent American fiction In these pages <PERSON>Walter</PERSON> a fanatic gray stubble on his cheeks seizes hold of the novel and <PERSON>Franzen</PERSON> makes us see as the best writers always have that the only pathway to freedom runs through the maze of the interior life <PERSON>Walter</PERSON> groping toward deliverance mourns a fatal defect in his own makeup the defect of pitying even the beings he most hated But of course it is no defect at all It is the highest most humanizing grace And it cares nothing about power Like all great novels Freedom does not just tell an engrossing story It illuminates through the steady radiance of its author s profound moral intelligence the world we thought we knew FREEDOM By <PERSON>Jonathan Franzen</PERSON> 562 pp <ORGANIZATION>Farrar Straus amp Giroux</ORGANIZATION> 28 <PERSON>Sam Tanenhaus</PERSON> is the editor of the Book Review A version of this review appears in print on August 29 2010 on Page BR1 of the Sunday Book Review with the headline Peace and War Today s Paper Subscribe Continue reading the main story We re interested in your feedback on this page Tell us what you think Related Coverage EXCERPT Freedom By <PERSON>Jonathan Franzen</PERSON> AUG 15 2010 PAPER CUTS BLOG <PERSON>Franzen</PERSON> in Webster Groves AUG 17 2010 PAPER CUTS BLOG <PERSON>Jonathan Franzen</PERSON> Time Cover Boy AUG 16 2010 image BOOKS OF THE TIMES <PERSON>Jonathan Franzen</PERSON> s Freedom Follows Family s Quest AUG 15 2010 TIMES TOPIC <PERSON>Jonathan Franzen</PERSON> Related Coverage EXCERPT Freedom By <PERSON>Jonathan Franzen</PERSON> AUG 15 2010 PAPER CUTS BLOG <PERSON>Franzen</PERSON> in Webster Groves AUG 17 2010 PAPER CUTS BLOG <PERSON>Jonathan Franzen</PERSON> Time Cover Boy AUG 16 2010 BOOKS OF THE TIMES <PERSON>Jonathan Franzen</PERSON> s Freedom Follows Family s Quest AUG 15 2010 image TIMES TOPIC <PERSON>Jonathan Franzen</PERSON> Show All What s Next Loading Go to Home Page Site Index The <ORGANIZATION>New York Times Site Index Navigation News World U S Politics N Y Business Tech Science Health Sports Education Obituaries Today</ORGANIZATION> s Paper Corrections Opinion Today s Opinion Op Ed Columnists Editorials Op Ed Contributors Letters Sunday Review Video Opinion Arts Today s Arts Art amp Design Books Dance Movies Music N Y <ORGANIZATION>C Events Guide Television Theater Video Arts Living Automobiles Crossword Food Education Fashion amp Style Health Jobs Magazine N Y C Events Guide Real Estate T Magazine Travel Weddings amp Celebrations Listings amp More Reader Center Classifieds Tools amp Services N Y C Events Guide Multimedia</ORGANIZATION> Photography Video NYT Store Times Journeys Subscribe Manage My Account NYTCo Subscribe Subscribe Home Delivery Digital Subscriptions <ORGANIZATION>Crossword Email Newsletters Alerts Gift Subscriptions Group Subscriptions Education Rate Mobile</ORGANIZATION> Applications Replica Edition Site Information Navigation 2018 The <ORGANIZATION>New York Times Company Home</ORGANIZATION> Search Accessibility concerns Email us at accessibility nytimes com We would love to hear from you Contact Us Work With Us Advertise Your Ad Choices Privacy Terms of Service Terms of Sale Site Information Navigation Site Map Help Site Feedback Subscriptions</ner>
