<ner>NEX T PAGE gt 2NEX T A RT I C L E gt lt PRE V I OUS PAGECONTENTS IRENE L TRAVIS Editor Bulletin of the <ORGANIZATION>Association for Information Science and Technology Bulletin</ORGANIZATION> lt at gt asis org B U L L E T IN O F T H E A S S O C IA T IO N F O R I N F O R M A T IO N S C IE N C E A N D T E C H N O L O G Y JU N E J U LY 2 0 1 7 V O L U M E 4 3 N U M B E R 5 E D I T O R S D E S K T O P T he timely and important focus of this issue is open sciencein the humanities Our coverage draws from the third annual Virtual Symposium on <ORGANIZATION>Information amp Technology in the Arts amp Humanities</ORGANIZATION> presented on April 18 and 19 2017 by the <ORGANIZATION>ASIS amp T Special Interest Groups Arts and Humanities SIG</ORGANIZATION> AH and Visualization Images and Sound SIG VIS Special section editor <PERSON>Jeremy McLaughlin</PERSON> provides an extensive Introduction including a synopsis of all the talks In addition papers based on four of the presentations are included in the section Together they touch on many of the recurring issues in adapting aspects of open science to the humanities including open access publishing collaboration introducing students to born digital publishing and the role of metrics in academic evaluation in the humanities <ORGANIZATION>In Association</ORGANIZATION> news as part of its tradition of striving to increase diversity and enhance inclusion across boundaries including international and cultural differences ASIS amp T held a Diversity and Inclusion Luncheon for the first time at the 2016 Annual Meeting The purpose was both to celebrate our successes in this area and to generate ideas for improvement and expansion going forward Annual Meeting co chairs <PERSON>Diane Sonnenwald</PERSON> and <PERSON>Lauren Harrison</PERSON> designed and organized the luncheon while eight colleagues <PERSON>Judit Bar Ilan Harry Bruce Toni Carbo Lynn Silipigni Connaway Ixchel Faniel Sandra Hirsch Fidelia Ibekwe SanJuan</PERSON> and <PERSON>Adam Worrall</PERSON> led discussions at the lunch tables In 2016 ASIS amp T Annual Meeting Diversity and Inclusion Luncheon Report and Recommendations the organizers include details of the event as well many of the thoughtful recommendations for both the <ORGANIZATION>Annual Meeting</ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION>ASIS</ORGANIZATION> amp T as a whole generated by the table discussions On the President s Page <PERSON>Lynn Silipigni Connaway</PERSON> introduces new <ORGANIZATION>ASIS amp T</ORGANIZATION> executive director <PERSON>Lydia Middleton</PERSON> who started work at the <ORGANIZATION>Association</ORGANIZATION> on May 8 She announces the plenary speakers for the Annual Meeting details plans for our 80 Anniversary celebration there and reminds us of deadlines associated with the meeting program Other topics include her two weeks as a visiting professor at the <ORGANIZATION>University of Hong Kong</ORGANIZATION> promoting information science research and ASIS amp T and her attendance with past president <PERSON>Nadia Caidi</PERSON> at the meeting of the <ORGANIZATION>Council for Scientific Society Presidents</ORGANIZATION> by <PERSON>Irene L Travis</PERSON> mailto Bulletin asist org</ner>
