<ner>I have so many great developments to share with you in thisissue of my column Top on my list is the hire of <ORGANIZATION>ASIS</ORGANIZATION> amp T s new executive director <PERSON>Lydia Middleton</PERSON> www linkedin com in lydiamiddleton I am thrilled to welcome <PERSON>Lydia</PERSON> to ASIS amp T <PERSON>Lydia</PERSON> s first day with us was on May 8 I have had the opportunity to orient <PERSON>Lydia</PERSON> with <ORGANIZATION>ASIS</ORGANIZATION> amp T and to work with her in the <ORGANIZATION>ASIS</ORGANIZATION> amp T office in <LOCATION>Silver Spring Maryland</LOCATION> in May and it has been a fulfilling and worthwhile experience <PERSON>Lydia</PERSON> joins <ORGANIZATION>ASIS</ORGANIZATION> amp T at a critical juncture in our history the 80th anniversary and the end of <PERSON>Dick Hill</PERSON> s 27 years as executive director which brought growth and financial stability to the <ORGANIZATION>Association She</ORGANIZATION> is poised to lead and manage <ORGANIZATION>ASIS</ORGANIZATION> amp T being guided by its strategic plan which includes membership growth a stronger global presence greater opportunities to connect academic and professional interests pursuit of new sources of revenue and implementation of new modes of communication and engagement with technology to support member interests <PERSON>Lydia</PERSON> not only values the diversity of <ORGANIZATION>ASIS</ORGANIZATION> amp T staff and members but also looks forward to enhancing the <ORGANIZATION>Association</ORGANIZATION> s value to its members and its presence in our professional and academic communities As a member of the <ORGANIZATION>ASIS amp T Executive Director Search Committee</ORGANIZATION> I want to take this opportunity to thank <PERSON>Sandy Hirsh</PERSON> and <PERSON>Clara Chu</PERSON> co chairs of the <ORGANIZATION>Search Committee</ORGANIZATION> the other <ORGANIZATION>Search Committee</ORGANIZATION> members <PERSON>Jamshid Beheshti Nadia Caidi Lisa Given</PERSON> and <PERSON>Marjorie Hlava</PERSON> and the executive search firm <PERSON>Isaccson Miller</PERSON> whose expertise and P R E S I D E N T S P A G E by <PERSON>Lynn Silipigni Connaway LYNN SILIPIGNI</PERSON> CONNAWAY 2017 ASIS amp T President Senior Research Scientist and Director of User Research OCLC Research connawal lt at gt oclc org NEX T PAGE gt N EX T A RT I C L E gt lt PRE V I OUS PAGECONTENTS EDITOR S SUMMARY ASIS amp T president <PERSON>Lynn Silipigni Connaway</PERSON> announced the new executive director of <ORGANIZATION>ASIS amp T Lydia Middleton Lydia</ORGANIZATION> joined <ORGANIZATION>ASIS</ORGANIZATION> amp T ready to lead after <PERSON>Dick Hill</PERSON> s 27 years of service as executive director Also announced are the keynote speakers for the 2017 Annual Meeting <PERSON>Richard Marks</PERSON> head of <ORGANIZATION>Playstation Magic Lab</ORGANIZATION> at <ORGANIZATION>Sony Interactive Entertainment</ORGANIZATION> and <PERSON>William Powers</PERSON> best selling author and research scientist at <ORGANIZATION>MIT Media Lab</ORGANIZATION> The Annual Meeting will also have an 80th Anniversary Welcome Reception and panel session and work is underway for an interactive history exhibit at the meeting coordinated by <PERSON>Kathryn La Barre Lynn Silipigni Connaway</PERSON> was invited to spend April 26 through May 7 in <LOCATION>Hong Kong</LOCATION> as a visiting professor working with the master of library and information management program at the <ORGANIZATION>University of Hong Kong Connaway</ORGANIZATION> and past president <PERSON>Nadia Caidi</PERSON> also attended the <ORGANIZATION>Council for Scientific Society Presidents</ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION>Washington</LOCATION> D C May 2017 and ASIS amp T partnered with the <ORGANIZATION>American Association for the Advancement of Science</ORGANIZATION> and the Earth Day Network for the <ORGANIZATION>March for Science KEYWORDS Association for Information Science amp Technology</ORGANIZATION> news collaboration meetings B U L L E T IN O F T H E A S S O C IA T IO N F O R I N F O R M A T IO N S C IE N C E A N D T E C H N O L O G Y JU N E J U LY 2 0 1 7 V O L U M E 4 3 N U M B E R 5 3 mailto connawal oclc org www linkedin com in lydiamiddleton We are very excited to announce our two keynote speakers for the Annual Meeting <PERSON>Richard Marks</PERSON> and <PERSON>William Powers</PERSON> excellent service throughout the search was key to our success in identifying qualified candidates and in hiring <PERSON>Lydia</PERSON> The committee thanks the <ORGANIZATION>ASIS amp T</ORGANIZATION> staff and members for their valuable input during the search process Two hundred fifty two individuals were considered in the search either as sources or as candidates This appointment may be one of the most critical decisions of my presidential term and I feel privileged to have been a part of this important hire I also have had the opportunity to work with our ASIS amp T Annual Meeting co chairs and <ORGANIZATION>80th Anniversary Advisory Group</ORGANIZATION> members We are very excited to announce our two keynote speakers for the Annual Meeting <PERSON>Richard Marks</PERSON> and <PERSON>William Powers Marks</PERSON> is the head of <ORGANIZATION>Playstation Magic Lab</ORGANIZATION> at <ORGANIZATION>Sony</ORGANIZATION> Interactive Entertainment His area of expertise is social aspects of virtual reality and augmented reality Powers is the best selling author of <PERSON>Hamlet</PERSON> s Blackberry and research scientist at <ORGANIZATION>MIT Media Lab</ORGANIZATION> His area of expertise is work life balance in a technologically connected world The members of the <ORGANIZATION>80th Anniversary Advisory Group</ORGANIZATION> have been busy planning the Annual Meeting This group is chaired by <PERSON>Kathryn La Barre</PERSON> and members include <PERSON>Michael Buckland Toni Carbo Ken Herold Dania Bilal Javed Mostafa Nouf Khashman</PERSON> and <PERSON>Tatjana Aparac</PERSON> Details about our invited 80th Anniversary themed panel session will be available soon and the plans for the 80th Anniversary themed Welcome Reception are ongoing Please forward names of ASIS amp T friends and members who have died recently to <PERSON>Kathryn</PERSON> at klabarre lt at gt illinois edu to be honored with a moment of silence at the reception Time will be devoted during the reception to honor <PERSON>Gene Garfield</PERSON> s contributions to ASIS amp T <PERSON>Kathryn</PERSON> also is facilitating efforts to create an interactive exhibit honoring 80 years of ASIS amp T to debut at the reception and to be available throughout the conference If you have images videos or audio you would like to share please contact her at klabarre lt at gt illinois edu Our ASIS amp T members in <LOCATION>Asia</LOCATION> also have been quite busy I was invited to spend two weeks March 26 April 7 at the <ORGANIZATION>University of Hong Kong</ORGANIZATION> as a visiting professor in the <ORGANIZATION>Faculty of Education</ORGANIZATION> working with the master of library and information management <ORGANIZATION>MLIM</ORGANIZATION> program faculty and students I began my visit by participating in the two day Symposium on Research Design Paper Writing and Publishing in Information Science that was hosted at <ORGANIZATION>HKU</ORGANIZATION> and sponsored by the <ORGANIZATION>ASIS amp T Asia Pacific</ORGANIZATION> Chapter <PERSON>Christopher Khoo</PERSON> chair and the <ORGANIZATION>Taipei Chapter Ming Hsin Phoebe Chiu</ORGANIZATION> chair and <PERSON>Tien I Tsai</PERSON> vice chair and <PERSON>Sam Chu</PERSON> paper co chair for the <ORGANIZATION>ASIS</ORGANIZATION> amp T 2017 Annual Meeting I discussed qualitative research methods and also had the opportunity to lead a breakout session with students The students discussed their research and I provided feedback on how to make the paper publishable in the <ORGANIZATION>ASIS</ORGANIZATION> amp T journal JASIST and or to submit a paper for review for the <ORGANIZATION>ASIS</ORGANIZATION> amp T 2017 Annual Meeting I am thrilled to report that one of the doctoral students in my breakout session did submit a paper proposal for the <ORGANIZATION>ASIS</ORGANIZATION> amp T 2017 Annual Meeting I hope it gets accepted <PERSON>Javed Mostafa</PERSON> the editor of JASIST also attended the symposium and advised students and faculty on preparing and submitting papers for review for publication in JASIST PRESIDENT S PAGE CONTINUED NEX T PAGE gt N EX T A RT I C L E gt lt TOP O F A RT I C L E lt PRE V I OUS PAGECONTENTS B U L L E T IN O F T H E A S S O C IA T IO N F O R I N F O R M A T IO N S C IE N C E A N D T E C H N O L O G Y JU N E J U LY 2 0 1 7 V O L U M E 4 3 N U M B E R 5 4 Attendees at the Symposium on <ORGANIZATION>Research Design Paper Writing and Publishing in Information Science</ORGANIZATION> hosted at <ORGANIZATION>Hong Kong University</ORGANIZATION> in April 2017 mailto klabarre illinois edu mailto klabarre illinois edu Since <ORGANIZATION>ASIS</ORGANIZATION> amp T is a prominent society for the advancement of information science and technology we officially partnered with the <ORGANIZATION>American Association for the Advancement of Science AAAS</ORGANIZATION> and the Earth Day Network for the March for Science During my two week visit I was honored to meet with many students faculty and practicing professionals in <LOCATION>Hong Kong</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Macau</LOCATION> Dr <PERSON>Chu</PERSON> made sure I worked and played hard He scheduled hikes with students and faculty so I was able to work in a beautiful outdoor environment with stimulating discussions I learned so much from everyone and got to do so with wonderful colleagues in a gorgeous setting while eating delicious food When I returned from <LOCATION>Hong Kong Nadia Caidi ASIS</LOCATION> amp T past president and I attended the <ORGANIZATION>Council for Scientific Society Presidents</ORGANIZATION> meeting in <LOCATION>Washington</LOCATION> D C May 6 8 This meeting is an opportunity for <ORGANIZATION>ASIS</ORGANIZATION> amp T presidents to meet with presidents and executive directors of other scientific associations It s good to share challenges and opportunities and learn about different ways to lead change The speakers are excellent and this year we heard speakers from <ORGANIZATION>Harvard Yale Rutgers Universities the Massachusetts Institute of Technology the University of California Berkeley National Public Radio the National Aeronautics and Space Administration the Department of Agriculture and the National Institutes of Health</ORGANIZATION> as well as other government scientific agencies The speakers introduced such diverse topics as the factors that count as evidence in the world of fake news the current challenges facing the sciences building with 3 D printed renewable resources building with recycled tires 3 D cell neurobiology and gene editing computer models the national strategy to improve safety testing addressed testing skin lotions perfumes and so forth and data driven public engagement initiatives <PERSON>Nadia Lydia</PERSON> and I attended the Kavli Lecture to hear <ORGANIZATION>George M Church</ORGANIZATION> professor of genetics at <ORGANIZATION>Harvard Medical School</ORGANIZATION> and professor of health sciences and technology at <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION>Massachusetts Institute of Technology MIT</ORGANIZATION> He also is director of the <ORGANIZATION>U S Department of Energy Center on Bioenergy</ORGANIZATION> at <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> and <ORGANIZATION>MIT</ORGANIZATION> and director of the <ORGANIZATION>National Institutes of Health Center</ORGANIZATION> of Excellence in Genomic Science at <ORGANIZATION>Harvard</ORGANIZATION> We even had a photo op with Dr Church PRESIDENT S PAGE CONTINUED NEX T PAGE gt N EX T A RT I C L E gt lt TOP O F A RT I C L E lt PRE V I OUS PAGECONTENTS B U L L E T IN O F T H E A S S O C IA T IO N F O R I N F O R M A T IO N S C IE N C E A N D T E C H N O L O G Y JU N E J U LY 2 0 1 7 V O L U M E 4 3 N U M B E R 5 5 <ORGANIZATION>ASIS</ORGANIZATION> amp T leaders in <LOCATION>Hong Kong</LOCATION> April 2017 Left to right <PERSON>Tien I Tsai</PERSON> vice chair of the <ORGANIZATION>Taipei Chapter Lynn Silipigni Connaway ASIS</ORGANIZATION> amp T president and <ORGANIZATION>Javed Mostafa</ORGANIZATION> editor <ORGANIZATION>Journal of the Association for Information Science and Technology JASIST</ORGANIZATION> At the <ORGANIZATION>Council for Scientific Society Presidents</ORGANIZATION> meeting in <LOCATION>Washington</LOCATION> D C May 2017 Left to right <ORGANIZATION>Kavli Lecture</ORGANIZATION> speaker <PERSON>George</PERSON> <ORGANIZATION>M Church of Harvard ASIST</ORGANIZATION> past president <PERSON>Nadia Caidi</PERSON> 2017 <ORGANIZATION>ASIS amp T</ORGANIZATION> president <PERSON>Lynn Connaway Silipigni</PERSON> and <PERSON>Lydia Middleton</PERSON> ASIST executive director I also want to encourage each of you to share your accomplishments with <ORGANIZATION>ASIS amp T</ORGANIZATION> so that we are able to celebrate with you Since <ORGANIZATION>ASIS</ORGANIZATION> amp T is a prominent society for the advancement of information science and technology we officially partnered with the <ORGANIZATION>American Association for the Advancement of Science AAAS</ORGANIZATION> and the Earth Day Network for the March for Science Check out the story videos and photos of <ORGANIZATION>ASIS</ORGANIZATION> amp T member participation in Inside ASIS amp T Volume 1 Issue 2 <PERSON>Don</PERSON> t miss the events that are available to you as ASIS amp T members since several important deadlines are approaching One deadline of critical importance is for the <ORGANIZATION>ASIS</ORGANIZATION> amp T awards The award descriptions and deadlines are available at www asist org about awards These awards provide the <ORGANIZATION>ASIS</ORGANIZATION> amp T membership an opportunity to nominate and honor fellow members for their professional and scholarly work and contributions to ASIS amp T and the information science community I encourage you to nominate colleagues for these prestigious awards The Member Get A Member Recruitment Drive https www asist org 8 for our 80th anniversary ended June 1st with 54 new members We want to thank all the members whose dedication and loyalty made this campaign a success For their efforts they will receive a membership renewal discount and a chance to win a free registration to the 2017 Annual Meeting There will also be 2nd and 3rd prizes of a gift basket containing limited edition 80th anniversary merchandise Thanks much to all those who participated And for the Annual Meeting you still have time to submit your visual presentations formerly known as posters The deadline is June 23 and we are encouraging different types of visualizations in addition to traditional posters I also want to encourage each of you to share your accomplishments with <ORGANIZATION>ASIS amp T</ORGANIZATION> so that we are able to celebrate with you Please send your news to yolande asist org or use the website feedback form at www asist org new site feedback And speaking of sharing news please remember to list your summer professional activities that are of interest to the membership on the Events Calendar that is available to all members on the homepage of the <ORGANIZATION>ASIS amp T</ORGANIZATION> website www asist org asist events calendar To add an event simply login using your ASIS amp T account information and click on the Add Event icon Remember you are <ORGANIZATION>ASIS amp T Make</ORGANIZATION> it the association that meets your professional and scholarly interests and ambitions PRESIDENT S PAGE CONTINUED NEX T PAGE gt N EX T A RT I C L E gt lt TOP O F A RT I C L E lt PRE V I OUS PAGECONTENTS B U L L E T IN O F T H E A S S O C IA T IO N F O R I N F O R M A T IO N S C IE N C E A N D T E C H N O L O G Y JU N E J U LY 2 0 1 7 V O L U M E 4 3 N U M B E R 5 6 www asist org asist events calendar www asist org new site feedback www asist org new site feedback mailto yolande asist org https www asist org 8 for our 80th anniversary https www asist org about awards https www asist org publications inside asist inside asist volume 1 issue 2</ner>
